LETTER TO SHAREHOLDERS
Dear Fellow Shareholder: 2003 was the best year ever for the American housing market and for the nation’s number one source of mortgage funds to buy or refinance a home.
I want to review Fannie Mae’s 2003 accomplishments with you, and also share with you how we go about delivering results — to you and to the American home buyer.
An outstanding year for Fannie Mae and its mission
Here are some of the highlights of Fannie Mae’s core business results for 2003:1
3 Total business volume grew by 68 percent for another new record of $1.423 trillion.
3 Total book of business grew by over 20 percent to $2.199 trillion.
3 Core taxable-equivalent revenue grew to $14.8 billion, up over 24 percent.
3 Record core net interest income grew to $10.5 billion, up almost 20 percent.
3 Record guaranty fee income grew to $2.4 billion, up nearly 33 percent.
3 Core business earnings grew to $7.3 billion, up over 14 percent. 3 Credit-related expenses totaled $112 million
compared with $92 million in 2002.
3 Core business diluted earnings per share grew by
over 15 percent — our 17th consecutive year of double-digit growth.
As these numbers indicate, 2003 was a very good year for the financial bottom line at Fannie Mae. The strength of our financial results is especially gratifying given the extreme financial market volatility over the past year, with interest rates declining to 45-year lows in mid-June before rebounding sharply over the balance of the summer.
For Fannie Mae, however, our business success derives solely from our success in achieving our mission of expanding homeownership and affordable housing. By this measure as well, 2003 was an extraordinary year:
3 We achieved the top-line goals for our ten-year American Dream Commitment plan by reaching over $2 trillion in financing to serve over 18 million underserved families since 2000. We also made significant progress on the wide range of goals within the plan.
3 We provided $1.4 trillion in financing to help a record 10.4 million families, including over $246 billion to serve more than 1.6 million minority families. This brought
us over 70 percent of the way toward our $700 billion commitment to the Bush Administration’s Minority Homeownership Initiative.
3 For the tenth consecutive year we met our affordable housing goals, as set by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), even though the record wave of home refinancing in America produced a high volume of business that included fewer underserved families.
The power of housing in the American economy
Our record-breaking business and mission performance was driven by the strongest housing and mortgage markets in U.S. history. Housing sales hit record levels; mortgage interest rates fell to 45-year lows, fueling a flurry of refinancing; and mortgage originations hit a stunning $3.7 trillion, more than a 40 percent increase from 2002. Thanks in great part to Fannie Mae’s technology-driven innovations, our industry handled this unprecedented surge in business with aplomb and housing continued to be the star of the national economy.
Fannie Mae is at the center of a vital sector of the nation’s economy, and the sector is growing. Thanks in large part to the growth of the secondary mortgage market over the past 20 years, housing has not only maintained its equilibrium through a series of economic downturns, it has become the economy’s ballast.
During times of economic stress, such as the global credit crunch of 1998 and just after the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001, Fannie Mae was able to boost the flow of capital, keeping the mortgage market going, and making housing finance a force for stability and liquidity.
  2
FANNIE MAE 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
1 Our core business measures are non-GAAP (generally accepted accounting principles) financial measures we use to evaluate our performance. See “Management’s Discussion and Analysis of Financial Condition and Results of Operations — Core Business Earnings and Business Segment Results” in the Form 10-K included in this report for more information about these measures.

Over the past few years, when workers faced massive layoffs, and the U.S. financial markets lost much of their value, housing not only survived the recession, it softened its effect. Housing construction stayed strong, offsetting job losses in other sectors. Families were able to access the wealth in their homes to see themselves through tough times, which boosted consumer spending and supported the economy.
Consumers were able to cut hundreds of dollars from their monthly payments and lock into the cheapest mortgage money we have seen in decades. They also readjusted their personal balance sheets by cashing out some of the home equity wealth they built up as the value of their homes increased to pay down other higher cost debt.
Since the beginning of 2000, the residential mortgage market (measured by total residential mortgage debt outstanding) has expanded by over 50 percent. At the same time, homeowners have gained $2.6 trillion in home equity wealth — a gain that helped to offset the $3.2 trillion equity loss in the stock market. In 2003 alone, homeowners tapped into about $130 billion of their home equity wealth. They plowed 60 percent of it — about $80 billion — back into the economy by fixing up their homes and spending on other goods and services.
What has made this massive refinance boom possible? The secondary mortgage market in America and its power to provide low-cost housing finance to consumers in all places, at all times, under all economic circumstances. Everyone involved in Fannie Mae’s success — including you — should be justly proud of this accomplishment, helping put the power of housing to work for both homeowners and the American economy.
The First Principles of Fannie Mae and our mission
Given Fannie Mae’s unique role in the U.S. housing sector, the mortgage industry, the financial markets, and in the plans of American home buyers, it is important for us to return from time to time to what I call the First Principles of Fannie Mae: to describe to the world who we are, what we do, how we do it, what are the results, and why they are important — to you and to the country.
This back-to-basics approach is particularly relevant and useful right now as Congress considers legislation to strengthen the financial regulator of Fannie Mae and our competitors, Freddie Mac and the Federal Home Loan Banks.
Fannie Mae has made clear that we support having a strong, credible, well-funded regulator because it is in the best interests of housing, home buyers, and our company. At this writing, Congress is still working on legislation. I believe any remaining issues regarding our new regulator are bridgeable. I also believe that the best way to build that bridge (and avoid harmful unintended consequences) is to make sure that all of us —
investors, regulators, legislators, and employees — have a sound understanding of the fundamentals of the secondary mortgage market.
My goal is to give you, our investors, a greater understanding of the Fannie Mae investment proposition — and to give
you a framework for understanding — and explaining — the Fannie Mae public policy proposition.
Principle I: Fannie Mae is a private company
with a public mission
Fannie Mae is a purpose-driven company. All that we are, all that we do, and all that we seek to become revolves around an elementary proposition: that owning a home is a defining element of the American Dream.
FRANKLIN D. RAINES
Chairman and
Chief Executive Officer
LETTER TO SHAREHOLDERS
 3

4
FANNIE MAE 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
Fannie Mae is an instrument of national policy
In 1968, the United States Congress reaffirmed its belief in homeownership by re-chartering the Federal National Mortgage Association as a private, shareholder-owned corporation with the ability to pull in private capital from all over the world to fulfill the public purpose of promoting affordable housing and homeownership here in America.
Expanding homeownership has been an important public policy goal for over three generations. The policy manifests itself in a variety of ways (e.g., the tax code and the HUD budget) and it rests on the knowledge that homeownership is good for families, communities, the economy and thus the nation, and should be supported and encouraged.
Fannie Mae’s mission is to ensure that America has a strong mortgage market, one that makes funds widely available in all communities, in all economic conditions, for lenders to lend to home buyers. Through the hard work of our employees and the capital of investors like you, we do an outstanding job of accomplishing that mission, year in and year out.
Our people are mission-driven, diverse, and values oriented
Fannie Mae’s mission of expanding homeownership and affordable housing to all Americans, especially to underserved Americans, is a powerful motivating force for the approximately 5,000 Fannie Mae employees. Our high employee motivation provides an important window into Fannie Mae’s success.
As one Fannie Mae employee recently put it: “Everyone at Fannie Mae believes in what we do and they have such passion in what they do and how they do it ... We are very driven employees who truly believe in the mission and don’t want anything to get in the way of achieving that mission.”
We also realized many years ago that in addition to having mission-driven employees, we needed a diverse group of employees. For us diversity is not a political luxury, it’s a practical necessity given the realities of 21st century America.
Over the next two decades, the Hispanic population is expected to grow by 75 percent, the African-American population by 28 percent, and the Asian-American population by 80 percent. In short, minority families will drive the housing market. The so-called “emerging markets” of today will be the surging markets of tomorrow. For us to succeed in an increas- ingly diverse economy, we need a diverse set of voices, values, and points of view to help us see and serve untapped markets.
Thanks to this longstanding, corporate-wide commitment to diversity, women now make up half our work force and nearly 39 percent of our officers. About 45 percent of our employees are minorities, and minorities represent over
25 percent of our officers. Every year, our efforts in this area are given high marks by outside observers.
“Best-in-class” corporate governance and disclosure
Another defining element of our company is that we are committed to “best-in-class” corporate governance and financial disclosure practices.
As a private company with a public mission, we have a two-fold obligation: We have to demonstrate our value and integrity both to the public we serve, and to the private investors that supply the capital we raise. Before they entrust us with their money, investors need to trust Fannie Mae.
Almost four years ago, Fannie Mae adopted a series of voluntary initiatives that opened the books on our business in ways that still are not matched by other financial companies. When we announced these initiatives, Moody’s called them “a new standard ... for the global financial market,” and said our leadership “could prove difficult for other firms to ignore, and could usher in a wave of enhanced financial risk disclosure.”
After problems came to light at Enron, we quickly adopted other leading best practices, including expensing our stock options, disclosing insider stock transactions in real time, and having our CEO and CFO certify our financial statements.
In 2003, we took further steps to strengthen our leadership on corporate governance and transparency:
3 We became a Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) registrant. By completing the landmark registration
of our common stock with the SEC and filing the company’s Form 10 and our first 10-K, we placed Fannie Mae
under the agency’s oversight and disclosure requirements
permanently.
3 We enhanced disclosures related to our issuances of our
mortgage–backed securities.
3 We also adopted a stronger code of conduct for our
management, employees, and board of directors, and updated our board’s corporate governance policies to reflect best practices and increase the board’s independence from management.
Today, we meet or exceed the requirements of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act and the New York Stock Exchange. The Corporate Library — a tough judge of corporate governance — named our board of directors the best “stakeholder
board,” citing “its explicit commitment to setting the standard for outstanding corporate governance.” We also asked Standard & Poor’s to examine and grade us. They gave us a score of 9.0 out of 10, and said that our “corporate governance practices are judged ... to be at a very strong level on a global basis of comparison” and that our degree of financial disclosure is “unavailable from other, similar financial institutions.”
A good measure of a company’s conscience and character
LETTER TO SHAREHOLDERS

can be found in how the company responds when it makes a mistake. In late 2003, we discovered a series of computational errors in our application of new accounting rules for mortgage purchase commitments found in our October quarterly earnings press release. Once we discovered the mistake, we promptly announced and corrected it. We are certainly not happy that the errors occurred, but I am proud of the way we handled the situation. Fannie Mae strives to make our accounting systems 100 percent error free and we continuously review and update our processes and procedures so that we can meet and exceed the high standards of transparency and accuracy that our investors expect and deserve.
❋ ❋ ❋
So that’s who we are: a private company with a public mission of expanding opportunities for homeownership and affordable housing — one that takes our mission and high standards of integrity very seriously. Which leads to the second question to be addressed: What does Fannie Mae do?
THOMAS E. DONILON
Executive Vice President – Law and Policy and Secretary to the Board of Directors
DANIEL H. MUDD
Vice Chairman and Chief Operating Officer
TIMOTHY HOWARD
Vice Chairman and Chief Financial Officer
Principle II: Fannie Mae creates a market-based
housing finance system
The second principle of Fannie Mae is that we help create a market-based, consumer-oriented housing finance system. This system arose as an alternative to the bank-based system that existed before our creation, and which still exists in most countries around the world.
Some historical background is in order.
Why the secondary mortgage market was created
In the mortgage market of the 1930s, most families borrowed from their local savings and loan to buy their homes. Lending institutions relied on bank deposits to fund mortgage lending. Loan terms were less than ten years and at the end of
the term, a big balloon payment would come due that included the entire remaining principal owed. When the Great Depression hit, more than 1.5 million families lost their homes — even though many never missed a mortgage payment.
LETTER TO SHAREHOLDERS
 5
