  STEADY PROGRESS IN VOLATILE TIMES
“As a young boy growing up in a harbor town not far from the North Sea coast, I was intrigued by adventure stories about sea captains and explorers. Stormy seas, dangerous currents and stubborn headwinds seemed to be part of their daily lives. Uncertain what the next day would bring, they always had to be ready to respond quickly and confidently. No matter how bad things were, the call from the ship’s bridge, “Steady as she goes!” kept the crew focused on their work as they dealt with the dangers and uncertainties of their voyage.
That image of plowing through stormy seas came to mind as I thought of the theme for this year’s shareholder report. For Alcoa in 2012, “steady as she goes” was the call to action as we worked to keep the Company on course in the face of major headwinds and market turbulence. We succeeded because we had a strong team of Alcoans that had been tested in the economic crisis of 2009. We succeeded because our businesses leveraged Alcoa’s unique strengths and staying power to gain advantages that none of their competitors enjoy. We succeeded because we stayed focused on what we do best: create value for our customers and manage well those operational and financial factors we can control.
Despite exceeding our 2012 goals and outperforming many of our peers,
it is disappointing that factors we cannot control resulted in barely any
appreciation in our stock price. The threat of the U.S. fiscal cliff, the worry over defaults in several European countries, and a once- in-a-century leadership change in China all created tremendous business uncertainty. It’s not surprising that economic and political volatility had a major impact on an industry that provides a metal that is vital to so many other industries. It also created volatility in the price of aluminum, which trades as a commodity on the London Metal Exchange (LME) and which has become a proxy for uncertainty in the world economy. Building on the sharp decline in the LME price in 2011, the average LME price dropped 16% further in 2012 and had several swings of more than 30%. That aluminum price volatility and decline had a $1 billion negative impact on Alcoa’s 2012 results, created significant headwinds for our businesses and had a major impact on the stock price of Alcoa and our aluminum peers.
       YEAR END FINANCIAL RESULTS*
Income from continuing operations of $191 million, or $0.18 per share
Excluding impact of special items, income from continuing operations of $262 million, or $0.24 per share
Revenue of $23.7 billion, despite lower metal prices
Adjusted EBITDA of $2.0 billion
Cash from operations of $1.5 billion; free cash flow of $236 million
Days working capital an all-time record low of 24 days Debt-to-capital of 34.8%
Strong cash on hand of $1.9 billion
Reduced net debt more than $450 million; year-end balance 29% lower than 2008
Achieved cash sustainability targets for the fourth consecutive year
Each of our four business segments contributed to our 2012 financial performance and made substantial progress toward their long-term organic growth and profitability goals.
* See Calculation of Financial Measures, at the end of this report for reconciliations of certain non-GAAP financial measures (adjusted income, adjusted EBITDA, free cash flow, and net debt amounts) presented in this letter.
ALCOA 2012 Annual Report 1
Klaus Kleinfeld
Chairman of the Board
and Chief Executive Officer
 
  REDUCED DAYS WORKING CAPITAL TO RECORD LEVELS
When increases in the cost of energy, raw materials, labor and pensions, among others, were added to the net impact of the aluminum price decline and foreign currency movements, the total negative impact to Alcoa’s 2012 income from continuing operations was $1.6 billion. Fortunately, we were able to stay on course by following the three strategic priorities we committed to in 2007: profitable growth, the Alcoa Advantage and disciplined execution. One of the main examples of disciplined execution continues to be our Cash Sustainability Program initiatives. We used this approach successfully during the 2009 economic crisis to reduce costs, improve productivity and generate cash; and we have made it part of our way of doing business ever since. Thanks to the rigorous execution of those initiatives by every Alcoa employee, and improvements in volume, price and mix, we offset the cost headwinds and more than 35% of the net market impact of LME price and foreign currency movements.
INCOME FROM CONTINUING OPERATIONS EXCLUDING RESTRUCTURING & OTHER SPECIAL ITEMS
 43
  33
-3 days
 30
27
  24
     2008 2009 2010
2011 2012
 EXCEEDED PRODUCTIVITY* GAIN TARGETS
$ in millions
1,000
760
520
280
40
-200
 $ in millions
742 2,410
1,291
5,542
20
     786
91
         1,014
559
 1,099
    $850 target for 2012
                    2009 2010 2011 2012
Total
2011 LME
129
Currency
-$885
Market
Volume
Price/Mix
+$1,005
Performance
Productivity
Cost Increases/ 2012 Other
Cost Headwinds
* All figures are pretax and pre-minority interest. 2009/2010 represent net productivity; 2011/2012 represent gross productivity.
DISCIPLINED CAPITAL AND INVESTMENT SPEND
Energy Raw Materials
-$670
    $ in millions
3,438
Capital Expenditures
Saudi Arabia JV*
After four consecutive years of achieving our cash sustainability targets, Alcoa is in a significantly stronger liquidity position than it was four years ago. We achieved free cash flow of $236 million by capturing productivity improvements, managing total spend of capital expenditures and reducing days working capital to a record low. Nowhere has the hard work and achievements of Alcoans been more evident than in driving down days working capital by nearly 45% in the last four years. We ended the year with less debt and a strong cash position, resulting in the lowest year-end net debt level since 2006.
By successfully addressing the factors that we can control – operational, commercial and financial – we were able to compensate for the impact of those beyond Alcoa’s influence: the economic and political volatility affecting our industry coupled with the decline in the LME price of aluminum.
1,622
160
177
1,287 1,261 1,015
249
          2008 2009 2010 2011 2012 2010 2011 2012
* Includes spend related to the rolling mill automotive expansion project.
REDUCED NET DEBT BY 29% SINCE 2008
Alumina
Offsetting price declines, we held steady on the refining cost curve by capturing $190 million in productivity improvements and by curtailing 390,000 metric tons per year of high-cost refinery capacity. To reach our goal of moving seven points down the cost curve by 2015, we will be optimizing our refinery portfolio, moving to less expensive energy, sustaining existing cost reductions and bringing on line the Ma’aden- Alcoa joint venture refinery in Saudi Arabia. We are also increasing margins by shifting the pricing of smelter-grade alumina to an Alumina Price Index (API) that better reflects market fundamentals than the LME. We increased external sales of API or spot-priced smelter-grade alumina to approximately 40% in the fourth quarter of 2012, a jump of 12 percentage points over the previous year. In 2013, we forecast that on average 48% of our external smelter-grade alumina sales will be priced against the API or spot price.
   $ in millions
10,578
 762
2008
9,819
9,371
9,165
8,829
       Following the refining process, alumina is shipped from dedicated port facilities
to Alcoa’s smelters
and customers.
        Cash
2009 2010
Net Debt
2011 2012
Debt to Cap
 2
ALCOA 2012 Annual Report
812
 262
  127
 92
           1,481
  1,543
1,939
  42.5%
9,816
38.7%
8,338
1,861
    34.9%
7,622
35.3%
7,432
   34.8%
6,968
FINANCIAL PERFORMANCE

                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 Primary Metals
Our smelter portfolio is on course to achieve our 2015 targets, moving four percentage points down the cost curve in 2012. We made $245 million in productivity improvements, curtailed 240,000 metric tons of European smelter capacity, permanently closed 291,000 metric tons of smelter capacity in the United States, secured beneficial long-term power contracts and produced first metal ahead of
Global Rolled Products
By driving the flat-rolled portfolio to higher value-add products and growing market share, our Global Rolled Products (GRP) business achieved a 35% increase in after-tax operating income (ATOI) and a 19% increase in adjusted EBITDA per metric ton, another year of historically high returns. GRP continues to make progress against its three-year $2.5 billion organic revenue growth target. We expect to achieve $1.5 billion targeted growth from regions, new customers, share gains, new products and innovation by the end of 2013. The remaining organic revenue growth depends on the LME metal price and end-market growth. To accelerate future growth, we are expanding our Davenport, Iowa, facility to meet demand as the U.S. automotive industry
ALUMINA: COST CURVE HOLDING STEADY
 $/mt
700 schedule from the smelter coming online in 700
ALUMINA COST CURVE ALUMINA COST CURVE
    Saudi Arabia, which will be the lowest-cost
smelter in the world. We are also improving
margins in the Primary Metals segment by 400 converting more of the output from our cast 400
600
-7 points -7 points
600 500
500
23 Perc
20,000
Alcoa 2015 23rd APlceorcae2n0ti1le5
  houses to value-add products, resulting in a 300
30th Percentile
30th Percentile
40,000 60,000
   65% increase in value-add volume to external
customers and a 51% profit increase since 100
2009.
300 200
200
100 0
0
PRIMARY METALS:
COST CURVE DOWN 4% POINTS
ALUMINUM COST CURVE AlcoaA2L0U1M2INUM COST CURVE
 3$,/5m0t0 3,500
3,000
47
th
Alcoa 2010 51st
40,000
-10 points -10 points
60,000 60,000
0 0
80,000
100,000 120,000 100,000 120,000
2 273
253
rd entile
 Alcoa 2012 30th APlceorcae2n0ti1le2
   Alcoa 2010 30th APlceorcae2n0ti1le0
 Every year, more than 200 teams of Alcoa employees are nominated for extraordinary achievements producing substantial business results. The teams compete for Alcoa Impact Awards in six categories, and the winners are recognized at the annual Alcoa Leadership Conference.
A team from Alcoa Global Primary Products in Europe won the 2012 Alcoa Impact Award in the Asset Management category for implementing a project to improve forecasting accuracy and free cash flow. The project resulted in a $67 million improvement in accounts receivable.
CUMULATIVE PRODUCTION (000MT)
20,000 40,000 60,000 80,000
 CUMULATIVE PRODUCTION (000MT)
  APlceorcae2n0ti1le2
47th Percentile
      shifts to aluminum to achieve light weighting and significantly higher fuel efficiency. We are also building a rolling mill in Saudi Arabia to produce sheet for packaging, automotive, building and construction and foil with our joint venture partner, Ma’aden. This will be an integral part of the lowest-cost aluminum
3,000 2,500
2,500 2,000
2,000 1,500
1,500 1,000
1,000 500
500 0
0
0 0
20,000
 complex in the world.
700 600
600 500
500 400
400 300
300 200
400
43050
10-YR 390 Average
$
CUMULATIVE PRODUCTION (000MT)
20,000 40,000
CUMULATIVE PRODUCTION (000MT)
GRP: GROWING PROFITABILITY AT RECORD LEVELS
  700
ALUMINA COST CURVE ALUMINA COST CURVE
Adjusted EBITDA/MT Adjusted EBITDA/MT
 23
273
X.X
Percentile
 Alcoa 2010 51st Percentile
     Alcoa 2015 41st APlceorcae2n0ti1le5 41st
Percentile
   ~ $235/MT 10-YR
  Alcoa 2015 rd
-7 points -7 points
$X.X
276
Average 314 327 ~ $235/MT
 3500 rd53
 Percentile Alcoa 2015
$
314
327
390
  23
300 250
250 200
21050 1500 100
24
Alcoa 2012 Percentile th
226
  100
Percentile Alcoa 2010
50
Alcoa is expanding the rolling mill at Daven
30 APlceorcae2n0t1ile2 30th Percentile
201
249
9
276
                                       200
Alcoa 2010
30th
aluminum coils for an automotive market shifting from steel to aluminum.
100 Percentile 0
30
th
port, Iowa, to produce
50 00
2002
2004 2006
2008 2010 2012
226
 201
108
119
  108
119
               Engineered Products and Solutions
CUMULATIVE PRODUCTION (000MT)
100,000
2003 2005 2007 2009 2011 2002 2004 2006 2008 2010 2012
2003 2005 2007 2009 2011
EPS: RECORD MARGINS EXCEEDING HISTORICAL LEVELS
0 20,000 40,000 60,000 80,000 100,000
120,000 120,000
0 20,000 40,000 60,000 80,000
CUMULATIVE PRODUCTION (000MT)
 After using the downturn to reposition its
portfolio, reduce costs and prepare for
profitable growth, this segment continues to win
new business and improve adjusted EBITDA
margins year-over-year. Our downstream 2,500
billion in targeted growth from regions, new
custom3,5e00rs, share gains, new products and AlcoaA2L0U1M2INUM COST CURVE
ALUMINUM COST CURVE
20 Adjusted EBITDA Margin 19 % 18
 innova3t,5io00n. The remaining organic growth will
3,000 47th Alcoa 2010 -10 points
20 17
 depend on end-market growth.
Adjusted EBITDA Margin
18 19
  3,000 2,500
st 51
15 17
15 1212
11 13 13
8
10 9
8
0 2003     2005   2007   2009   2011 2002 2004 2006 2008 2010 2012
2003 2005 2007 2009 2011 ALCOA 2012 Annual Report 3
APlceorcae2n0t1ile2 15
47th
Percentile APlceorcae2n0t1ile0
51st Percentile
Alcoa 2015 41st APlceorcae2n0t1ile5
-10
points
13 15 13
   businesses increased ATOI by 14% in 2012 2,000 and achieved a full-year record high 19.2% 2,000
1,500
10 9 121112
     adjusted EBITDA margin, which is more than
double the margins of 10 years ago. With
organic revenue growth of $180 million in
2012, we made progress toward our three- year$1.6billionrevenuegrowthtargetforour020,00040,00060,0002
1,500 1,000
1,000 500
st 5 41
  Percentile
5 00
2002
2004
2006
2008
2010
201
  five industry-leading downstream business units. By the end of 2013, we expect $1.0
500
0 CUMULATIVE PRODUCTION (000MT)
       0 20,000
40,000 60,000
Alcoa aluminum is the metal of choice for building durable structures and striking designs for buildings liCkeUMthUisLACTaIVnEcePrRCOeDnUtCeTrIiOnNC(l0e0v0eMlaTn) d, Ohio.
   4 34 3 23 2 12 1 1

 LEVERAGING THE ALCOA PLATFORM FOR PROFITABLE GROWTH
While driving performance in each of those four businesses, we also are rebalancing Alcoa’s portfolio through organic growth, acquisitions and divestitures. Our goal is to make ourselves less dependent on the commodity and LME changes in the upstream business and increase our value-add mid-stream and downstream businesses. Each sector continues to draw on a powerful array of competitive advantages unique to Alcoa – three strategic priorities, a strong global presence in growth markets, the parental benefits we call the Alcoa Advantage and a solid foundation of values that have guided Alcoa for 125 years in good times and bad. For example, during the economic crisis of 2009 we launched the Cash Sustainability Program that guided Alcoa successfully through the downturn while also driving systemic changes to our cost structure. As that program continued to drive the improvements to our businesses, it enabled us to achieve all of our cash sustainability targets in 2012.
  Achieved All 2012 Cash Sustainability Targets
  Positive Free
Cash Flow
Target: 1.5 days
✓
Actual: 3.5 days
Productivity & Overhead Working Capital
Capital Spend and Investments Maintain Debt-to-Capital
Target: $850m ✓ Actual: $1.3b
✓
✓
Target: 30%-35%✓ Actual: 34.8%
  Target: $1.7b Actual: $1.4b
  The signing of a joint venture with China Power Investment Corporation is a major step for Alcoa’s future growth in China.
Alcoa is bringing its popular aluminum wheels to the growing commercial transportation industry in Brazil.
The Fjarðaál smelter in Iceland is one of the highly profitable Northern European smelters in Alcoa’s Primary Metals portfolio.
In December 2012, the Ma’aden-Alcoa Joint Venture produced the first metal in Saudi Arabia, only 25 months after construction began.
Regional Growth and Profitability
  In each of our global regions, we have built on Alcoa’s local relationships and reputation to improve the profitability of our existing operations and to introduce our business units to new opportunities.
In China, we are developing plans with our new joint venture partner, China Power Investment Corporation (CPI), for expansion in the world’s fastest-growing market. We are shifting our rolling business to focus on the tremendous potential in China’s automotive and packaging markets. As a result of the solid performance of our fasteners business in China, Commercial Aircraft of China (COMAC) recently contracted with Alcoa to partner in the development and production of the new C-919 aircraft. Our new wheel production facility in China continues to expand its capacity, supporting more than half of our sales to the growing Chinese commercial vehicle market within months of its opening.
In Brazil, where we have a substantial upstream presence, our initiative to introduce and grow our mid-stream and downstream businesses produced $256 million in organic growth in 2012. To establish a presence in the Brazilian commercial transportation business, we are opening a forged wheels facility and are partnering with the country’s largest bus manufacturer to build and test a prototype
for what will be the world’s first all-aluminum bus. We are expanding sales of aluminum risers to the country’s major off-shore oil drilling program and are increasing sales to the Brazilian commercial aerospace industry.
In Europe, we had a tale of two worlds. In Southern Europe, where energy is expensive, we worked with government officials in Italy to obtain approval to curtail our smelter in Portovesme and in Spain to gain support for more affordable electricity rates. In Norway and Iceland, affordable energy and technical advancements have helped our smelter operations to be profit leaders among our global primary businesses.
In the Middle East, the construction of our Ma’aden-Alcoa joint venture facilities is progressing well. In fact, on December 12, 2012, we produced the first hot metal only 25 months after we broke ground, an extraordinary achievement. On the same day, we broke ground for a rolling mill expansion targeted at the automotive market. When fully operational, the integrated aluminum facility will be the lowest-cost and most-efficient in the world. The Government of Saudi Arabia is in discussions with manufacturers planning to establish operations in the region, who would become customers of the aluminum joint venture.
  4 ALCOA 2012 Annual Report
 
   The Alcoa Advantage
Of Alcoa’s three strategic priorities, I consider the Alcoa Advantage the priority that provides the stable foundation for Alcoa’s continued performance. This is all about Alcoa’s unique attributes that make each one of our business units better – creating an unbeatable competitive edge for Alcoa’s businesses and unmatched value for Alcoa’s customers. That parental advantage consists of five major levers.
OPERATING SYSTEM
The productivity and working capital savings that enabled Alcoa’s businesses to manage costs and cash despite the challenges of 2012 are outcomes of the Company-wide business systems grounded in regular performance reviews with clear metrics. This provides a means for the leaders of the separate businesses to benefit from proven processes, a sophisticated information technology infrastructure and corporate centers of excellence that set best-in-class standards for both quality and savings.
PROCUREMENT
As a buyer of more than $18 billion annually of materials and services worldwide, Alcoa has major purchasing scale and a global footprint that is producing value in new ways. In 2012, we upgraded our procurement processes and business intelligence systems, providing us the foundation to accelerate our productivity efforts. For example, we recently recognized $48 million in savings by leveraging our Ma’aden-Alcoa joint venture and developed an integrated carbon strategy that will provide Alcoa over $100 million annually in reduced raw material costs.
CUSTOMER
To measure customer satisfaction and loyalty, Alcoa uses a process called Net Promoter Score (NPS). During 2012, our NPS score improved by 9.5% and 14 of our 24 business units now have higher scores than their direct competitors. A unique strength of Alcoa is our deep and enduring relationships – from the C-Level of our customers to the shop floor – with global leaders in aerospace, transportation, power generation and packaging. These relationships help Alcoa’s businesses to anticipate emerging customer needs and introduce to them the innovations and solutions to meet those needs and make our customers more competitive.
TECHNOLOGY
The strong organic growth of our businesses in 2012 is due in large measure to innovation that provides a major competitive advantage
Values
In anticipation of Alcoa’s 125th Anniversary celebration this year, we took time to reexamine the principles upon which the Company was founded and thrives to the present day. We spoke to thousands of Alcoans around the world to identify their hopes and dreams for Alcoa’s future and to ask them how Alcoa’s enduring values can best be expressed to guide future Alcoans.
The vision that best defined our employees’ hope for the future is an inspiring recognition of Alcoa’s contributions to mankind: Alcoa.
to Alcoa’s customers and businesses. Pulling experience from each of our markets, the Alcoa Technical Center (ATC) is our innovation cornerstone, developing the next generation of Alcoa products, processes and services. The ATC has become a busy forum for visits by customers seeking to draw on the benefits of our metals research and development of proprietary alloys, processes and finishing technologies. During 2012, ATC made major strides in a wide range of areas, from advancing jet engines to breakthrough aluminum die casting technology to using byproducts of our production process to safely clean waste water. Since appointing a new Chief Technology Officer from one of the Alcoa business units, we’ve dramatically accelerated commercial technology applications across all our business sectors and strengthened external licensing of technology to generate additional revenue for Alcoa.
TALENT
In today’s world, where
information circles the
globe in nano-seconds,
I firmly believe that
people are the only
sustainable advantage.
We are finding that
Alcoa has become a
magnet for top talent
aspiring to join a high-
performance team. Ambitious professionals see a company with a can-do attitude and tremendous career opportunities, with mobility across diverse businesses and growth regions. Alcoans in plants and offices around the world are energized and motivated, as reflected in the 40% rise of our employee engagement scores in the past five years. Because strong leadership is key to maintaining a highly motivated and productive workforce, in 2012 we accelerated training for supervisors at all our global locations. We also expanded Alcoa Academy, our leadership learning school with a faculty of successful leaders from across the Company, by adding a program for emerging leaders to the existing executive and plant manager curriculum. Besides the cross-fertilization and best practice sharing that takes place in our training programs, we also are increasingly moving talent across business sectors through a disciplined succession planning process that ensures we have successors ready to move into our 300 most-critical positions.
Advancing Each Generation. In acknowledging that vision, we recognize that today’s Alcoans stand on the shoulders of the generations of Alcoans who came before us, and we are committing to carry on that legacy for future generations.
The value statement that emerged from our examination is a reaffirmation of those principles that guided us for the past 125 years. The statement focuses on the five enduring values that our employees told us should remain Alcoa’s True North for centuries to come.
  Alcoa participated in the National Society of Black Engineers’ annual convention and career fair in Pittsburgh.
    ALCOA 2012 Annual Report 5
 
 LEVERAGING THE ALCOA PLATFORM FOR PROFITABLE GROWTH
Integrity is the fundamental principle that guides everything we do. During 2012, we hired an expert on corporate governance, Audrey Strauss, as our Chief Legal and Compliance Officer. Audrey’s mission is to ensure that every Alcoan understands and lives by both the spirit and the laws that form our concept of integrity at Alcoa.
Innovation is the core value upon which our Company was founded by inventor Charles Martin Hall, along with the dedicated support of his sister Julia. With a greater emphasis on commercial applications and licensing, Alcoans are innovating to continuously create growth opportunities for our customers and our Company.
Respect is a very personal value defined by an appreciation for human dignity and diversity. We are proud that Alcoa was chosen in 2012 for the coveted Catalyst award, which is given each year to only three companies worldwide who are deemed best-in-class for providing opportunities to women in the workplace.
2013 Focus
Our strategic direction is clear. We have a long-term view and the demonstrated ability to adjust quickly to changing conditions and deliver continuous and sustainable improvement. In this volatile and uncertain economic environment, Alcoa is focusing on the things we can control.
We will continue to execute our long-term strategy, driving profitable growth by improving our cost competitiveness, growing in our strong end markets and gaining share through product innovation.
We remain focused on annual financial targets with the overarching goal of positive free cash flow regardless of metal price.
Alcoa’s Bright Future
You can see in the adjoining pages how Alcoans live our vision to create innovations for our customers. This is why I am so optimistic about Alcoa’s future. Alcoa is a great company, built on strong values and run by excellent people. We make a product for the ages. More than a century ago, Alcoa’s aluminum enabled the Wright brothers to build an aircraft that could fly just a few hundred feet off the ground. Half a century ago, Alcoa’s aluminum enabled astronauts to fly hundreds of miles into the unknown of outer space. Today, Alcoa’s aluminum is millions of miles away on a vehicle called Curiosity, exploring the surface of the planet Mars. In every market we serve – from aerospace to automotive, from construction to consumer electronics, from industrial to packaging – Alcoa is literally “reaching for the stars.”
Thanks to the light weight, recyclability and durability of aluminum, we expect strong growth in each of our end-markets through 2020. While LME prices are currently driven by macroeconomic factors that largely ignore underlying market fundamentals, we have every confidence that customer needs will once again drive the markets. And when they do, aluminum will be the metal of choice. It is this bright future for Alcoa and for our miracle metal that should give our shareholders confidence that their investment in Alcoa will grow for
Environment, Health and Safety is a combined value for which Alcoa is widely known and respected. Building on our reputation for being best-in-class for safety, during 2012 we launched a global wellness program to improve the health and longevity of every Alcoan.
Excellence is a broad term that is lived by Alcoans who go the extra mile in whatever they do. It explains why Alcoa exceeded our financial goals in this very challenging year. And it explains why our vision of Advancing Each Generation will remain believable and achievable for the next 125 years and beyond.
On the back cover of this report, you can find an exact replica of the values statement that is framed on the walls of every Alcoa plant and office around the world. Following this letter, we highlight some examples of how Alcoans lived the values every day, everywhere during 2012.
• We have a target to capture productivity gains and overhead savings of $750 million.
• We will remain focused on disciplined spend with specific targets established for growth capital ($550 million), sustaining capital ($1 billion), and on the Ma’aden-Alcoa joint venture ($350 million).
• We will continue to manage our capital structure and maintain a debt-to-capital ratio in the range of 30%-35%.
We are committed to investment-grade credit status. Alcoa’s balance sheet and liquidity position are strong, and we will continue to decrease debt and manage cash conservatively to ensure ongoing liquidity.
many years to come. And, it is the steady progress in the face of the economic volatility of the past year that should give our shareholders confidence that Alcoa has the structure, strategy and leadership to ensure that, in good times and bad, their investment will prosper.
I am firmly committed to that goal. In the meantime, our investors can be assured that “steady progress” does not mean simply hanging on to the wheel and hoping for fair weather. It means holding to our tried and true values during adversity as we pursue new approaches to value creation with determination and urgency.
”
Klaus Kleinfeld
Chairman of the Board and Chief Executive Officer
March 2013
   6
ALCOA 2012 Annual Report
 