 DEAR FELLOW SHAREOWNERS,
We had a great year in 2005 and I am excited about the
long-term future of ADC. In 2005, we successfully executed
our growth strategy and strengthened ADC’s position as a
global leader in communications network infrastructure so-
lutions. Our mission for fiscal 2005 was to achieve strong
and profitable year-over-year growth. We achieved that goal by growing faster than the overall market and surpassing $1 billion in sales. Reported sales for our continuing operations grew 51% in fiscal 2005 to $1.2 billion and diluted earnings per share increased 148% to $0.72. Excluding our acquisitions in fiscal 2004 and 2005, our sales growth was 22%, significantly exceeding the industry growth rate of global commu- nications equipment sales at approximately 9% and our peers’ sales growth of approximately 3%-13%, excluding their 2004-2005 acquisitions. Our 2005 growth was driven by broad-based customer demand across ADC’s comprehensive telephone, wireless, cable, broadcast and enterprise solutions. This was a tremendous accomplishment given the industry’s growth rate, industry consolidation among our custom- ers, increased price pressures and transformations to new network architectures, including fiber-to-the-x, Internet Protocol service delivery, next-generation wireless and high-speed enterprise connectivity.
Looking ahead to 2006, our goal is to continue growing at rates faster than the overall industry. We remain focused on becoming the global leader in communications net- work infrastructure solutions and positioning our products and services to be the foundation of powerful and reliable communications networks. We are working with service providers, equipment suppliers and enterprises in building networks that will continue to transform the way the world communicates. Every day, ADC employees around the globe are focused on the mission of creating exceptional value for our customers by delivering world-class communi- cations network infrastructure solutions through:
2005 GROWTH EXCEEDED
INDUSTRY AND PEER GROWTH RATES
We were able to drive growth at rates faster than our indus- try and peers in fiscal 2005 through the following sales ac- complishments and strong operating income improvements:
• Fiber-to-the-X (FTTX) and Connectivity Sales. Globally, communications providers are deploying fiber deeper into their networks to enable the delivery of enhanced broadband services to homes and businesses. Sales of our OmniReachTM FTTX products grew 245% (excluding the Fiber Optic Network Solutions (FONS) acquisition) as we continued to penetrate the large and growing FTTX market with our comprehensive solutions. OmniReach solutions provide the end-to-end network in- frastructure for our customers to deliver the “triple-play” of advanced voice, data and video services. ADC supplied OmniReach FTTX equipment to 169 customers
• • • •
Extraordinary customer relationships; Innovative and impactful products and services; Industry cost leadership; and
Highly talented people working as a team.
4
Robert E.
(Bob) Switz
President and
Chief Executive Officer
 
 in fiscal 2005. We are working with major U.S. telephone carriers, independent telephone companies, municipali- ties and international customers as they expand their net- works. Our August 2005 acquisition of FONS is expected to more than double our FTTX outside plant sales, which may surpass 10% of total ADC sales in 2006. We also grew sales of ADC’s global fiber connectivity solutions
by 40% (excluding FTTX products) and global copper connectivity solutions by 10% (excluding the KRONE acquisition) to support a broad range of communications services. KRONE’s copper connectivity sales also increased to $185 million for full-year fiscal 2005 compared to
$67 million for the second half of fiscal 2004 following the acquisition in May 2004. In 2005, we introduced approximately 80 new connectivity products to meet the needs of our customers.
• Wireless Sales. Our Digivance® distributed antenna system sales grew 99% (excluding the OpenCell ac- quisition) in fiscal 2005 as major U.S. wireless carriers increased deployment of this coverage and capacity solu- tion. Digivance is the industry leader in all-digital distrib- uted antenna systems and is positioned well in a growth market because of increasing bandwidth applications
for wireless data, video and next-generation services worldwide. In May 2005, we acquired OpenCell to en- hance our ability to offer a Digivance solution that works across a wider range of communications frequencies and network protocols. This will allow us to address new international markets and a broader range of customer performance requirements.
• Enterprise Sales. Global sales of our enterprise solutions increased to $181 million for full-year fiscal 2005 compared to $79 million for the second half of fiscal 2004 following the KRONE acquisition. Our TrueNet® Structured Cabling Solutions are being installed by large businesses in their office buildings and campus set-
tings to create flexible voice, data and video networks. ADC’s CopperTenTM products, the world’s first 10-Gigabit Ethernet UTP cabling solution, enable our customers worldwide to future-proof their networks for emerging ultra-high speed applications.
• Professional Services Sales. Sales in our Professional Services business grew 34% (excluding the KRONE acquisition) in fiscal 2005 as we gained market share and expanded into data and wireless networks in the United States. We also reported a full year of KRONE services sales in Europe of $57 million in fiscal 2005 compared
•
to $22 million for the second half of fiscal 2004 follow- ing the acquisition. Our Professional Services business plans, deploys and maintains communications networks, which compliments our equipment business by creating a channel to customers and pulling through sales of ADC’s products.
Operating Income Growth. We increased operating income by 194% to $72 million in fiscal 2005 from strong sales growth combined with worldwide operating synergies that lowered our operating expenses to 30% of sales in fiscal 2005 compared to 36% in fiscal 2004.
2006 GLOBAL GROWTH STRATEGY TO BECOME A BIGGER AND STRONGER COMPANY
Boosted by our 2004 acquisition of KRONE, we grew ADC’s sales outside the United States in fiscal 2005 by 73%. We expect continued growth in our major product areas in fiscal 2006. Global sales growth is critical to our long-term future as it builds operational scale, enables cost advantag- es and expands our geographical presence allowing us to respond quickly and efficiently to customers’ needs world- wide. As a result of ADC’s global operations in the Ameri- cas, Europe and Asia-Pacific, we expect to benefit from moving certain production processes and shared services to countries with cost advantages, leveraging global syner- gies for acquisitions, and building strategic alliances with distributors and channel representatives worldwide. The key elements of our 2006 global growth strategy are:
•
•
•
•
Focus on the Customer. Deliver extraordinary customer service, be responsive to our customers’ needs and ensure customer satisfaction.
Gain Market Share. Grow ADC revenues faster than the market through share gains in our products and services across global operating regions.
Innovate in Key Strategic Growth Areas. Continue to invest in and grow sales worldwide in the strategic areas of FTTX solutions, Digivance wireless systems and enter- prise connectivity.
Progress Toward Cost Leadership. Work toward an operating margin of 14% or better in the next three years (excluding impairment, restructuring and acquisition-re- lated charges, amortization of purchased intangibles and stock-based compensation expenses) by:
− Transitioning our operations in Europe and Asia-Pacific onto ADC’s single worldwide enterprise resource planning system; and
5

 − Implementing shared service centers and lower-cost manufacturing sites in those regions.
• Build Operating Scale Efficiencies. Acquire companies and products that complement our growth strategy and enable economies of scale, satisfy our customers’ needs or extend our global presence.
ADC’s LONG-TERM GROWTH POTENTIAL
OF BUILDING NETWORKS FOR THE FUTURE
We believe that network evolutions will drive our growth. Looking ahead, we expect that many of ADC’s 3,000-plus customers in more than 140 countries will continue to evolve their networks for next-generation voice, data and video services. This creates exciting growth opportunities for ADC’s comprehensive infrastructure products and services in the following areas:
• New network builds are underway and expected for FTTX, Internet Protocol TV, carrier Ethernet, Voice-over-IP, wire- less data and distributed antenna systems, and high- definition video services. These network builds are driven by competition among our customers to win and retain voice, data and video subscribers, as well as improved economics and regulations.
• Most major wireline and wireless carriers throughout the world have begun or are expected to build next-generation broadband networks. As we already have sales to nearly all of the top 100 communications carriers globally, we believe that future investments by these carriers will pro- vide us with a broad base for growth potential.
• Ongoing demand for greater levels of communications network capacity provided at lower costs is expected to continue creating new opportunities to supply evolving network architectures from circuit to packet, copper to optical, core networks to edge networks, old networks to new networks and acquired networks to acquirer net- works.
As networks continue to evolve, we believe our breadth of solutions and experience will be a major driver in our ability to meet the needs of our customers and grow faster than indus- try capital spending rates. As the chart demonstrates, we have a history of such performance during industry growth years.
Year-over-Year Growth Rates
  60% 40% 20%
0% -20% -40% -60%
2004 2005
         2001 2002 2003
          1995 1996 1997 1998 1999 2000
                       Industry: Global Communications Capital Expenditures
(Sources: UBS, Bank of America, Morgan Stanley, Merrill Lynch)
ADC Sales (without 2004-2005 acquisitions) ADC Sales (with 2004-2005 acquisitions)
  In closing, there are many people to whom I am truly grateful for helping ADC to excel in achieving profitable growth in 2005 and positioning us well for future growth. First, I would like to thank our customers for the opportunity to serve them with ADC’s people and comprehensive network infrastruc- ture solutions. Second, I thank our highly talented employ- ees worldwide for their commitment to the “ADC Way” of customer focus, quality, teamwork, innovation, and integrity to build ADC into a leading global network infrastructure company. And to our shareowners, I thank you for your continued support as ADC became a $1-billion-plus growth company in 2005 with exciting opportunities to build long- term value. Finally, I thank the entire ADC board of directors for their guidance and support of our vision to become the global leader in creating network infrastructure.
On behalf of your board and ADC’s employees worldwide, we remain committed to growing ADC bigger and stronger for the benefit of all of our stakeholders.
Robert E. Switz
President and Chief Executive Officer
 6
