REAL PEOPLE. REAL VALUE. REAL ENERGY.
To My Fellow Shareholders,
Two-thousand-six was a critical year of transition for Ameren.
Our Illinois utilities prepared to move to market rates for power supply in Illinois while pursuing their first electric delivery service rate increases in that state in the past 15 to 25 years. At the same time, our Missouri utility, AmerenUE, filed for its first general electric rate increase in almost 20 years.
In the midst of these major initiatives, the year also brought three historic storms. During the summer, two storms – just days apart – disrupted electric service for nearly 950,000 customers, many for several days. Then, in early December, the worst ice storm in nearly 30 years affected about 520,000 customers. These storms were in addition to tornados and other severe weather in March and April.
We know that these extended outages were very difficult for our customers. That is why we drew on the strength of our own employees – and that of utility workers from across more than a dozen states –
to mobilize more than 5,500 people in the summer and 7,200 people in the winter to restore power as quickly as possible.
Our stated vision for the past several years has been to be a “performance leader” – among the best of the best – in all areas of our operations. Data compiled by the Edison Electric Institute (EEI) indicates that Ameren performed better than other utilities encountering similar-sized, weather-related outages in recent years. In fact, EEI recognized Ameren with its Emergency Recovery Award for our response to the July storms.
Nevertheless, there is always room for improvement. In January 2007, at the request of the Missouri Public Service Commission (PSC), we submitted a list of recommendations to limit the number and duration of storm-related outages. Those recommendations included more aggressive tree removal and tree trimming, comprehensive pole and line inspections and changes in regulatory tariffs to require burial of all new electric distribution services. We look forward to working with the PSC, the Missouri state legislature and other stakeholders on these initiatives.
The bottom line is that despite these challenges, we remained focused throughout the year on our core business of providing real energy and real value to real people – our 2.4 million electric and nearly 1 million natural gas customers in Missouri and Illinois.
   10 2006 Ameren
 
Our ongoing challenge in 2007 will be to deliver value to our customers and to you, our owners, as we manage significant environmental compliance programs, evaluate options to address rising operating costs, actively work on a host of regulatory and legislative matters and continue the cleanup and restoration efforts resulting from the December 2005 failure of our Taum Sauk pumped-storage hydroelectric plant.
I am confident we will once again rise to these challenges. It will take hard work, persistence and dedication, but in 2006 our employees demonstrated that these qualities are in great supply as they worked to serve our customers while adhering to our values of integrity, respect, stewardship, teamwork and commitment.
MOVING TO MARKET RATES IN ILLINOIS
Almost without a doubt, the transition to market rates for power in Illinois was the most significant issue facing our company in 2006, and it will continue to be a significant issue well into 2007.
At year-end 2006, a 10-year-old rate freeze in Illinois expired, as did the power purchase contracts Ameren’s Illinois utilities had in place to provide power for their customers.
Throughout the rate freeze period, which brought
$1 billion in savings to our customers, costs continued
to rise as Ameren invested more than $1.7 billion
in Illinois’ energy delivery systems and infrastructure.
In addition, during these ten years Ameren moved its Illinois power plants into separate, non-rate-regulated generation companies and invested in new power plants that compete with other suppliers. We made this move to comply with the 1997 Electric Service Customer Choice and Rate Relief Law, which was crafted to encourage the development of competitive markets for power in Illinois.
With the Ameren Illinois utilities owning no generation, these companies were required to seek new contracts to purchase power in the wholesale markets.
For Ameren and our many stakeholders, this issue boiled down to one question: What power purchase mechanism would best allow us to continue delivering low-cost, safe and reliable power to our 1.2 million electric customers in Illinois?
After months of study and analysis, in September 2006 an independently managed and monitored
 Ameren remains focused on providing real energy and real value to real people.
 Ameren works diligently to find solutions that add value for its business customers and help the environment. At AmerenUE’s Labadie Plant, a new concrete packaging facility (far left) recycles annually more than 60,000 tons of fly and bottom ash previously sent to landfills into two million bags of high-quality Quikrete® concrete mix – a unique partnership between AmerenUE, Charah®, Inc. of Louisville, Ky., and The Home Depot®. ■ AmerenUE’s Meramec Plant, meanwhile, became the first power plant in the nation to generate electricity by burning recovered paint solids from an automotive manufacturing plant – DaimlerChrysler’s Fenton, Mo., facility (left). Over the life of the project 1,000 tons of waste paint will be blended with coal and burned in Meramec’s boilers, keeping the material out of local landfills, lowering disposal costs and helping to generate electricity.
 2006 Ameren 11
 
REAL PEOPLE. REAL VALUE. REAL ENERGY.
declining-price auction to procure the power needed on behalf of Ameren’s Illinois utility customers was completed. In this highly transparent, competitive process – approved by the Illinois Commerce Commission – more than 20 power companies, brokers and others competed for contracts to supply the Ameren Illinois utilities’ 7,200 megawatts of load.
As expected, the auction clearing price was significantly above the Illinois utilities’ fixed-price supply contracts, which expired at year-end 2006. Those higher costs are now being passed on to our customers – dollar-for-dollar, with no markup.
Including a $97 million aggregate increase in our delivery service tariffs, our Illinois residential rates are now near the national average. However, in late 2006 the Illinois Commerce Commission approved our vol- untary deferral plan for residential customers, eligible schools, local governments and small commercial customers. Called the Customer Elect Plan, it allows timely recovery of our purchased power costs while easing the impact on our Illinois customers.
We will continue to listen carefully to our customers’ concerns, and work constructively with legislators, regulators and other stakeholders, in order that we may successfully manage this important transition for our company. We remain
committed to providing safe, reliable delivery of power in Illinois in the years ahead.
RECOVERING COSTS AND INVESTING WISELY IN MISSOURI
As I have mentioned, in July AmerenUE filed for its first general electric rate increase in almost
20 years with the PSC. At that time, AmerenUE also filed for an increase in its natural gas delivery service rate.
We have been able to keep rates low by remaining focused for decades on our core energy business, cost control and operating efficiencies. We have invested more than $2.5 billion in new power lines, generating facilities and other infrastructure in Missouri since 2002 alone. On the gas side, we have invested $40 million since 2003 in gas system improvements and expansions to improve service reliability and keep pace with growing customer needs.
As a result, our customers have come to
expect AmerenUE to deliver a highly reliable, environmentally friendly supply of electricity and natural gas at reasonable prices. We are committed to continuing to meet their expectations.
The July filings – which are subject to the customary rate review process, including review and approval
 Our companies add value for residential customers by providing them with tools to manage their energy wisely and supporting local communities. Introduced to AmerenUE customers in 2004, the online Energy Savings Toolkit (right) provides a full suite of energy management tools, from appliance calculators to bill analyzers. ■ In Edwardsville, Ill., a $90,000 grant from the Ameren Charitable Trust is making possible the construction of a 3,800-square-foot multi-purpose program area at the Edwardsville YMCA (far right). The new area, called the Ameren Program Center, will be used for a wide range of YMCA programs and services, including programs that promote individual character development and personal growth for teens
– as well as programs for people of all ages.
 12 2006 Ameren
 
by the PSC – proposed an increase in electric revenues of $361 million and natural gas revenues of $11 million.
In the intervening months, the PSC staff, the Missouri attorney general and other stakeholders have proposed instead electric rate decreases
for AmerenUE of over $150 million in some cases. However, we believe that we have made
a strong case that without appropriate rate relief, AmerenUE will be presented with significant risks and challenges in continuing to maintain and invest in critical energy infrastructure in a timely fashion, inhibiting the company’s ability to provide reliable service.
We look forward to working with key stakeholders to resolve this important matter. We expect a ruling no later than June 2007.
It is important to note that even if the PSC were
to approve the full electric increase, the typical AmerenUE residential customer would still be paying rates that are not only below AmerenUE’s 1991 lev- els, but also well below the national average and the average of other Missouri investor-owned utilities.
Nevertheless, we recognize that our customers are experiencing meaningful increases in many of their monthly costs. Because we are concerned
2006 in Review
Despite facing significant challenges in 2006, Ameren marked several milestones during the year that demonstrated our dedication to providing superior service, working safely and meeting our environmental and community commitments.
■ The Edison Electric Institute recognized Ameren with its prestigious Emergency Recovery Award for extraordinary efforts to restore power following the July 2006 storms.
■ Ameren and Cellnet Technology, Inc., began expanding Ameren’s automated meter reading system to an additional 1.1 million electric and natural gas meters in Ameren’s Illinois service territory.
■ AmerenUE purchased three combustion turbine generating facilities – 1,490 megawatts – to meet increasing capacity needs and provide flexibility in determining future baseload generating capacity additions.
■ The renowned global marketing information firm known for surveys of customer satisfaction – J.D. Power and Associates – certified our customer contact centers for providing “An Outstanding Customer Service Experience.” Our call centers join a select few electric or natural gas utility companies in the nation to receive this certification.
■ AmerenUE’s Callaway Nuclear Plant received the prestigious Edison Electric Institute Safety Achievement Award for outstanding worker safety. Callaway Plant employees worked nearly 4.9 million hours during the period from March 15, 2004, through Oct. 5, 2006, with no lost-workday-away accidents.
■ Ameren entered into a unique alliance agreement with Hitachi Power Systems America, Ltd. that will allow both companies to benefit from technology exchange in the areas of air quality control and efficient power generation.
■ In a settlement with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, Ameren resolved all outstanding potential federal liability associated with the Dec. 14, 2005, failure of AmerenUE’s Taum Sauk pumped- storage hydroelectric plant.
           2006 Ameren 13
  
REAL PEOPLE. REAL VALUE. REAL ENERGY.
about how these increases will affect each family’s budget, our electric rate proposal caps residential increases at 10 percent and includes a commitment to help our most vulnerable customers pay their electric bills, including additional contributions to low-income energy assistance and energy conservation programs.
Two-thousand-seven will also be a significant year because it marks the beginning of a multi- year commitment to invest in new emission- control technologies at our existing plants. These investments are necessary to comply with federal regulations, passed in 2005, and related state implementation plans that call for significant reductions in emissions of sulfur dioxide (SO2), nitrogen oxide (NOx) and mercury.
To begin meeting the new SO2 requirements, in 2006 we announced that we had signed an agreement with Hitachi Power Systems America, Ltd. to design and supply scrubbers at three of our plants – AmerenUE’s Sioux Plant, AmerenEnergy Generating Company’s Coffeen Plant and AmerenEnergy Resources Generating Company’s Duck Creek Plant. Because these scrubbers can remove SO2 from either low- sulfur or high-sulfur coals, they will provide flexibility for Ameren to use the lowest-cost fuel for each plant.
Additional scrubbers and other emission-control equipment will be needed to help us meet all of the federal requirements – as well as the terms of an agreement between our Illinois-based generating subsidiaries and the state of Illinois.
This innovative agreement accelerates the Illinois subsidiaries’ emission reduction compliance program for SO2, NOx and mercury to a level well ahead of
 Ameren is committed to providing top-tier service for customers and bottom-line results for shareholders.
PLANNING FOR FUTURE GENERATION NEEDS AND ENVIRONMENTAL COMPLIANCE
In late 2005, AmerenUE submitted an integrated resource plan to the PSC. That plan described the company’s need to add new baseload capacity by 2018.
However, because of the long lead-time needed
to build a baseload power plant, in the next few years we will need to decide which fuel source
will be the best option for this significant capital investment. Options under consideration include new coal, new nuclear or one of the developing “clean-coal” technologies, like integrated gasification combined cycle.
  14 2006 Ameren
 
that required by the federal standards. It presents an approach to multi-pollutant emission reduction that we believe will serve as a model nationally – also part of our vision to be a performance leader in all areas of our operations.
KEEPING OUR COMMITMENTS
An ongoing commitment in 2006 was to the areas affected by the year-end 2005 breach at AmerenUE’s Taum Sauk pumped-storage hydroelectric plant.
We accepted full responsibility for the effects of the breach the day that it happened, and we have not backed away from that responsibility.
In fact, almost immediately after the breach, more than 100 Ameren staff, temporary employees,
and contractors began removing tons of soil and hundreds of felled trees to restore Johnson’s Shut-Ins State Park.
And throughout the year, we worked to settle claims associated with the incident, worked to restore water quality in the lower reservoir and the Black River, cooperated fully with state and federal investigators and provided promotional support to tourism- dependent businesses in the Taum Sauk Plant area.
Most importantly, we have put processes in place to guard against such an incident ever happening again at any of our facilities, including the creation
of a dam safety team led by a dedicated group of highly qualified dam safety engineers.
Recently, AmerenUE announced its intent to rebuild this important source of low-cost power, assuming successful resolution of outstanding issues with state authorities. The plan we proposed meets or exceeds all modern safety criteria.
Finally, at year-end 2006 we announced a new management structure that will align our company’s organization and financial reporting more closely with our three distinct areas of business – Missouri regulated operations, Illinois regulated operations and non-rate-regulated generation operations.
The goal in this reorganization, as in all our actions throughout the year, is to improve the company’s commitment to providing top-tier service for customers and bottom-line results for shareholders.
I look forward to updating you about all of these matters and answering your questions at our annual shareholders meeting. This year’s meeting will be held at The Saint Louis Art Museum on April 24, 2007.
Gary L. Rainwater
Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer Ameren Corporation
  The Ameren Executive Leadership Team: Left to right: Thomas R. Voss, Ameren executive vice president and chief operating officer, AmerenUE president and chief executive officer; Gary L. Rainwater, chairman, president and chief executive officer; Warner L. Baxter, Ameren executive vice president and chief financial officer, Ameren Services president and chief executive officer; Scott A. Cisel, AmerenCILCO, AmerenCIPS and AmerenIP president and chief executive officer; Donna K. Martin, Ameren Services senior vice president and chief human resources officer; R. Alan Kelley, AmerenEnergy Resources president and chief executive officer; and Steven R. Sullivan, Ameren senior vice president, general counsel and secretary.
2006 Ameren 15
 