   Delivering on Our Commitments
In 2018, we delivered on all of our commitments, including achieving our financial guidance, hitting key milestones on our strategy and positioning AES for long-term, sustainable growth. Some key accomplishments this year included:
 Adjusted EPS of $1.24, compared to guidance of $1.15 to $1.25;
 Parent Free Cash Flow of $689 million, compared to our expectation of $600 to $675 million;
 Total Shareholder Return (TSR) of 39%, outperforming the S&P 500 and S&P Utilities Indexes;
 Signed long-term Power Purchase Agreements (PPA) for approximately 2 GW of renewable capacity, increasing our backlog to almost 6 GW;
 Completed construction of 1.3 GW across our portfolio;
 Paid down $1 billion in Parent debt, enabling us to achieve a key investment grade financial metric of
3.95x Parent leverage one year early; and
 Expanded our world-leading battery-based energy storage business, including the launch of our joint venture with Siemens, Fluence, which was awarded 286 MW of new projects.
Strong Backlog Drives Future Growth
Our strong backlog of 5,787 MW includes both our conventional and renewable capacity under construction, as well as our renewables under signed PPAs that are not yet under construction. During the year, we completed construction of an additional 1,278 MW, including several transformative projects.
At our utility, Indianapolis Power and Light (IPL) in Indiana, we completed the 671 MW Eagle Valley combined cycle gas plant. The completion of Eagle Valley also represents the conclusion of a significant investment program at IPL, wherein we have replaced nearly half of IPL’s coal-fired generation with cleaner and more efficient natural gas.
In Panama, we completed the 381 MW AES Colón combined cycle gas plant and regasification terminal, and made the first shipment of LNG in Central America’s history. The LNG storage tank is expected to come on- line in the middle of 2019, with approximately 60% of the terminal’s capacity still available to be contracted. We expect that the entry of low-cost U.S. LNG will transform the Central American energy sector, much as it has in the Dominican Republic.
We believe the integration of renewables and energy storage is the key to accelerating a cleaner energy future. In Hawaii, we are delivering two solar plus storage facilities for a total of 34 MW of solar capacity and 170 MWh of five-hour energy storage on the island of Kaua’i. The first of these pioneering projects, Lāwa’i was completed in December 2018 and will satisfy energy demand during peak hours in the evening, as well as the rest of the day. The second, Kekaha, is under construction and expected to be on-line later in 2019.
We have 4,440 MW of capacity under construction and expected to come on-line through 2021. Our primary projects under construction include: the 1,320 MW OPGC 2 project in India, the 1,384 MW Southland repowering in Southern California and the 531 MW Alto Maipo project in Chile.
In 2018 we signed 1,946 MW of renewables under long-term PPAs and expect to sign an additional 2,000 to 3,000 MW per year through 2022. This capacity should be split equally between the U.S. and internationally,
and similarly between solar and wind. In the U.S., the majority
of our expected growth will come from our sPower and AES Distributed Energy (AES DE) businesses. We are also focusing on our “Green Blend and Extend” strategy,
where we are enhancing some of our current
contracts by blending and extending existing PPAs, by adding renewable energy. We see potential opportunities to execute this strategy across many of our markets, including Chile and Mexico. In fact, in
2018 we signed our first two “Green Blend and Extend” contracts, for 576 MW in Chile and Mexico. In the near-term, we see an addressable
 38.99%
  S&P 500
4.11%
   AES
S&P Utility
-4.39%
Figure 1. 2018 Total Shareholder Return
  $1.08 $0.98
$1.24
        2016 2017 2019 Figure 2. 2016-2018 Adjusted EPS1 by year
1 A non-GAAP financial measure. See Financial Notes on page 8 for definition and reconciliation to the nearest GAAP number
  2018 ANNUAL REPORT 5
     
                                                                                            universe of 7 GW across our portfolio, which could substantially increase as our markets capitalize on the economic benefit of renewables.
Our total backlog of 5,787 MW will be a key contributor for our expected earnings and cash flow growth of 7% to 9% per year through 2022.
Reducing Carbon Intensity by 50% by 2022 and 70% by 2030
We recently announced that based on our renewable growth plans, we expect to reduce our carbon intensity (tons of CO2/MWh of generation) by 70% from 2016 to 2030. This is an improvement from our prior goal of 50% over the same period. Furthermore, we also announced a near-term target of reducing our carbon intensity by 50% from 2016 to 2022, compared to our prior goal of 25% over the same period.
In November 2018, we published the AES Climate Scenario Report, which includes an impact analysis
of a 2° Celsius scenario on our strategy and business, fulfilling our April 2018 commitment to adopt the recommendations of the Task Force on Climate-related Financial Disclosures (TCFD). AES was the first publicly-traded owner of utilities and power companies based in the U.S. to disclose its portfolio’s resilience consistent with the TCFD recommendations and third-party scenarios. The report shows that AES’ portfolio is resilient against the assessed climate risks and demonstrates the significant upside for AES in a lower carbon future.
In 2018, AES was named to the Dow Jones Sustainability Index (DJSI) for North America for the fifth year in a row by RobecoSAM. We were also named by Ethisphere as one of the World’s Most Ethical Companies for the fifth year in a row. These recognitions validate the degree to which every member of the AES team lives by our values.
AES Values
 SAFETY: We will always put safety first–for our people, contractors and communities.
 INTEGRITY: We are honest, trustworthy and dependable. Integrity is at the core of all we do–how we
conduct ourselves and interact with all of our stakeholders.
 AGILITY: We move with vision, speed and flexibility to adapt to our dynamic and rapidly changing world.
 FUN: We work because work can be fun, fulfilling and exciting.
 EXCELLENCE: We strive to be the best in all that we do and to perform at world-class levels.
Investing in Innovative Technologies for Additional Upside
We continue to invest in innovative technologies, such as battery-based energy storage, drone applications and digital customer interfaces. These initiatives have already allowed us to reduce O&M costs,
improve customer experiences and deliver new solutions to the market.
In January 2018, we formed Fluence, our energy storage joint venture with Siemens. During the year, Fluence delivered or was awarded 80 projects in 17 countries, with a total capacity of 766 MW. Notably, Fluence was also
named the #1 utility energy storage integrator by Navigant.
We are also implementing a corporate-wide digital transformation, including becoming a strategic investor in Simple Energy.
 6 2018 ANNUAL REPORT
                        AES CLIMATE SCENARIO REPORT
1 | © 2018 The AES Corporation
                    AES_Draft_57.indd 1 12/4/18 4:27 PM
  
Simple Energy provides a digital platform that allows our IPL and DPL utilities to accelerate energy efficiency and demand response programs, while improving customer experience.
Although not in our guidance, we expect our new digital initiatives to materially benefit both our top and bottom lines.
Achieved a Key Investment Grade Financial
Metric and Expect to Attain Ratings in 2020
In the third quarter of 2016, we established a goal of reaching investment grade.
At that time, we had $5 billion in Parent debt and a Parent Debt/EBITDA coverage
ratio of 4.9x. Since then, we have reduced debt by $1.3 billion and ended this year with a Parent leverage ratio of 3.95x, achieving our goal a year ahead of our plan. We are now very well-positioned to attain investment grade ratings in 2020.
  Fitch
BB-
Moody’s
S&P
BB BB+
  2016
New
2018
    BB+
Ba3
Ba1
 Figure 3. Achieved a key Investment Grade Metric and Expect to Attain Ratings in 2020 Offering Double-Digit Total Return Annually Through 2022
We continued to improve the returns from our existing portfolio and position AES for long-term, sustainable growth. We will achieve this objective as we continue to optimize our costs, strengthen our Balance Sheet, reduce our carbon intensity and deploy new technologies in our existing markets. Combining our current dividend yield of 3.2%, and our 7% to 9% average annual growth in Adjusted EPS and Parent Free Cash Flow, will yield a double-digit total return annually through 2022.
Thank you for your continued support.
Jay Morse
Chairman and Lead Independent Director March 1, 2019
Andrés Gluski
President and Chief Executive Officer March 1, 2019
     2019 EXPECTED
2018 2017 2016 2015 2014 2013 2012
$0.04
Jay Morse and Andrés Gluski
       $0.20
$0.44
$0.546
 $0.52
 $0.48
  $0.40
   $0.16
  Figure 4. 2012-2019 Shareholder Dividend by year
 2018 ANNUAL REPORT 7
  