                 2
2008 AMETEK Annual Report
 Letter to Shareholders
                    We Are Confident About Our Future.
We Performed Well in 2008
Despite an extremely difficult eco- nomic environment, we continued to do well and enjoyed a very good year overall. We had record sales, operating income, net income
and earnings per share. We expe- rienced solid internal growth in each of our business segments. Our strategy to acquire differenti- ated businesses continued to work well. And, our relentless focus on Operational Excellence continued to drive our profitability and earn- ings performance.
We had sales of $2.53 billion,
up 18% from 2007. Including the impact of a fourth-quarter restruc- turing charge, net income was $247.0 million and diluted earnings per share were $2.30, compared with $228.0 million and $2.12 respectively in 2007. Excluding this charge, net income was $274.2 million and diluted earnings per share were $2.55.
Outlook for 2009
We expect 2009 to be a very chal- lenging year given the continuing global economic downturn, al- though we believe that AMETEK’s strong business portfolio, proven operational capabilities, lower cost structure and successful focus on strategic acquisitions will enable us to perform well in 2009.
As we put together our plans for 2009, it became apparent that we needed to align our cost structure with expected market conditions. As a result, we recorded a pre- tax restructuring charge in the fourth quarter of 2008 of approxi- mately $40 million, or $0.25 per
diluted share, to cover the costs of employee reductions, facility closures and asset write-downs.
We expect to reduce our Compa- nywide headcount by more than 10%, close or significantly reduce ten manufacturing facilities, and reduce other spending across the Company. We expect to generate approximately $75 million in sav- ings from these activities in 2009.
While these actions are difficult, particularly for the colleagues and communities affected, they are necessary to maintain our financial and competitive position. Impor- tantly, we do not believe these reductions will harm the long-term growth prospects of our Company.
We Have a Clear Vision of
Our Future
We remain committed to achieving our vision to double the size and profitability of AMETEK over the next five years and to achieving our goal of double-digit percentage growth in earnings per share over the business cycle.
To achieve our vision and goal, we remain focused on acquiring differentiated businesses, pursuing opportunities in new and emerging technologies, and establishing new platforms for growth.
We continue to emphasize
the differentiated businesses within our portfolio, which cur- rently account for nearly 90% of our total sales. These are busi- nesses that compete on the basis of product capability, have higher growth rates, and generate supe- rior returns to our shareholders. As for our cost-driven businesses,

                 2008 AMETEK Annual Report
3
 principally our global floor care motors, which account for about 10% of sales, we will manage them to ensure maximum operating effi- ciency and strong cash generation.
In recent years, we have trans- formed the Company by expanding beyond our core businesses and building entirely new platforms
for growth.
We added to our position in aero- space by establishing a global network of maintenance, repair and overhaul (MRO) facilities
that allow us to participate in the attractive aviation aftermarket.
We established a sizeable pres- ence in high-end instruments
for elemental analysis, nano- technology and ultra-precise manufacturing that fits well with our core competencies and pro- vides us valuable opportunities for growth in new and emerging technologies.
We tapped growing energy production and electric power markets by expanding the range of products and technologies we offer that are used for the explora- tion, production, distribution and transmission of oil, gas and elec- tric power.
We added to our position in highly engineered technical motors and motion control systems and built a new business platform
in advanced microelectronics packaging for sophisticated aero- space, defense and industrial applications.
We are expanding our global reach and strengthening our mar- keting and distribution capabilities
worldwide. In 2008, our interna- tional sales totaled $1.23 billion, up 16% from 2007.
Our Success Is Founded on Sound Strategies
Guiding our efforts is a Corpo-
rate Growth Plan built around the framework of our Four Growth Strategies: Operational Excellence, Global & Market Expansion, New Products, and Strategic Acquisi- tions & Alliances.
The continued solid execution of those strategies by AMETEK col- leagues across the Company is
the principal reason for the results we’ve achieved and our confidence in our success going forward. Each strategy plays an important role in achieving our vision for the Company.
Operational Excellence is our cor- nerstone strategy. Our relentless focus on cost and asset man- agement has been a key driver of both our competitive and financial success.
Operational Excellence is essen- tial in achieving profitability improvements in our businesses, creating value from acquisi-
tions, and allowing us to operate our businesses efficiently. It has enabled us to grow our group operating margins, excluding
the fourth-quarter restructur-
ing charge, from 14.6% in 2001 to 20.6% in 2008, despite a weaken- ing economy.
Throughout 2008, we were pro- active in reducing costs, and the restructuring activities we are undertaking will further ensure that our current cost structure is
Our Executive Office (from left to right): Frank S. Hermance, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer; John J. Molinelli, Executive Vice President— Chief Financial Officer; Timothy N. Jones, President, Electromechanical Group; David A. Zapico, President, Electronic Instruments; John Wesley Hardin, President, Electronic Instruments

                 4
2008 AMETEK Annual Report
 $400
 350
 300
 250
 200
 150
 100
  50
   0
Total Return to Shareholders
  12/31/03
12/31/04
12/31/05
Russell 1000
12/31/06
12/31/07
12/31/08
The chart depicts the performance
of $100 invested in AMETEK, Inc.,
the Russell 1000 and the Dow Jones U.S. Electronic Equipment Indexes on 12/31/03, including reinvestment of dividends.
 Xantrex Programmable Power, a leader in programmable power supplies used to test electrical and electronic products
Our acquisition pipeline is
strong. We have both the finan- cial resources and the managerial capabilities to acquire additional businesses and believe the current economy provides us with a host of opportunities.
Already in 2009, we acquired High Standard Aviation, a Miami-based provider of aftermarket repair ser- vices to the aerospace industry that gives us a valuable presence in the southeastern United States as well as Latin America and adds to our position in the air cargo seg- ment of the MRO business.
Global & Market Expansion is critical to our corporate growth. In recent years, we have reshaped AMETEK into a global company. We have expanded sales and manufacturing in key regions of the world and acquired businesses with significant overseas markets. As a result, we have a diversified global customer base with 48% of our revenue generated from inter- national markets.
In 2008, we opened a product demonstration and training facil- ity for our instruments in Shanghai, China, and an aerospace MRO
AMETEK, Inc.
Dow Jones U.S. Electronic Equipment
Turning to acquisitions, we acquired seven businesses in 2008 representing approximately $300 million in annualized revenue. All are differentiated businesses that expand our positions in analyti-
cal instrumentation, aerospace MRO services, power instruments, technical motors and engineered materials.
They are:
 Drake Air, a Tulsa-based pro- vider of MRO services to the aerospace market
 Motion Control Group, a leader in motors and motion control products for highly engineered applications
 Muirhead Aerospace, a leader in motion technology products and a provider of MRO services to aerospace and defense markets
 Newage Testing, a manu- facturer of hardness testing equipment for the aerospace, oil exploration and defense industries
 Reading Alloys, a leading pro- ducer of specialty titanium master alloys and engineered metal powders
 Vision Research, a manufac- turer of high-speed digital imaging systems used for motion capture and analysis
   properly aligned with expected market conditions.
At every AMETEK business, we are implementing initiatives to improve productivity, reduce costs and increase capital efficiency. In addition to those activities, sev- eral Companywide initiatives are expected to achieve significant results.
Our Global Sourcing and Stra- tegic Procurement Initiative generated $21 million in incremen- tal savings in 2008, compared with savings of $11 million in 2007, and is expected to yield an additional $20 million in savings in 2009.
We also are continuing the migration of manufacturing to our low-cost plants in Mexico, China and the Czech Republic. Revenue from those facilities totaled $356 million in 2008, an increase of $30 million from 2007.
As we move through 2009, we will continue to aggressively pursue productivity improvements and cost reductions. This approach has served us well in the past, and we believe it will continue to do so. We are very well positioned to weather a weak economic environment
and believe our current initiatives alone will have over a $100-million positive operating income impact in 2010.

                 2008 AMETEK Annual Report
5
 facility in Singapore. Both reflect the growing importance of our Asian customer base. We also further bolstered sales and mar- keting resources elsewhere in China and in Japan and added to our presence in Russia and the Middle East.
Among our recently acquired businesses are several European aerospace MRO operations and a French-based manufacturer
of high-end elemental analysis systems.
New Product Development is a key internal growth driver. Among our greatest strengths is the ability to develop innovative new prod- ucts and bring them to market successfully. Over the past five years, we have invested more than $400 million in new product devel- opment and introduced a steady stream of new products.
While no single product is sig- nificant to AMETEK overall, sales of products introduced in the last three years represented more than 18% of our total revenues in 2008 and reflect our ability to introduce the right products to serve our customers’ needs.
We’ve gained further traction from new product development by implementing Design for Six Sigma, a proven methodology for enhancing the pace and quality of innovation.
Among our most recent product introductions are state-of-the-art metal analyzers, multicomponent emissions monitors, advanced microanalysis systems, ultra- lightweight radiation detectors, high-performance technical
motors, motion control products, and ultra-precise surface analysis and machining systems.
Our Outlook Is Based on
Solid Performance
Our outlook is positive. We are cer- tain there will be challenges ahead, and we are very cautious about
the economic outlook, near term. However, we also believe we have excellent reasons to be confident about our future.
We are financially strong. We have a solid Corporate Growth Plan
built around the framework of our Four Growth Strategies. We have a proven record of success and the strongest, most experienced man- agement team in our history.
Our disciplined approach to busi- ness, along with a focus on our Growth Strategies, has produced consistent results. We were among the few industrial companies to improve profit margins during the previous economic downturn.
We have reacted swiftly to align our cost structure with current economic realities, and that streamlined cost structure will ben- efit us as the economy improves.
We are confident that our strat- egies will create additional value for our shareholders in the years ahead. I appreciate your con- fidence and, on behalf of my colleagues, thank you for your con- tinued support.
Frank S. Hermance
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer March 4, 2009
 