 Letter to Stockholders
 Dear Stockholders,
2010 was a year of challenges met and promises delivered for Amgen’s patients, stockholders, and staff. We delivered an important, innovative bone health therapy, denosumab, in the form of two novel medicines: Prolia®, approved in Europe, the United States, and several other countries for postmenopausal osteoporosis, and XGEVATM, approved in the United States for the prevention of skeletal-related events in patients with bone metastases from solid tumors. We grew revenues 3 percent, adjusted earnings per share* 6 percent, and generated nearly $6 billion in operating cash flow, despite continuing global economic turmoil and a $200 million adverse impact to revenues from U.S. healthcare reform and reimbursement headwinds. In sum, it was a superb operational year.
Developing Denosumab: Amgen at Its Best
The story of the development of denosumab is an excellent example of Amgen at its best. After 15 years of extraordinary effort from molecule to medicine, nearly $1.5 billion of investment, millions of staff hours, and complex clinical trials with thousands of patients around the world, Amgen delivered two medicines for patients that are seen by many as one of the biggest therapeutic opportunities in our industry. We could not be prouder of our ability to serve patients with these Amgen-discovered, -developed, and -delivered therapeutics.
Aranesp® (darbepoetin alfa) Enbrel® (etanercept) EPOGEN® (Epoetin alfa) Neulasta® (pegfilgrastim) NEUPOGEN® (Filgrastim) Nplate® (romiplostim) Prolia® (denosumab) Sensipar® (cinacalcet) Vectibix® (panitumumab) XGEVATM (denosumab)
Robert A. Bradway, President and
Chief Operating Officer
Products
Kevin W. Sharer, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
                     06 07 08 09 10
06 07 08 09 10
06 07 08 09 10
06 07 08 09 10
2010 $15,053 2009 14,642 2008 15,003 2007 14,771 2006 14,268
2010 $5.21 2009 4.91 2008 4.55 2007 4.29 2006 3.90
2010 2009 2008 2007 2006
$5,787 6,336 5,988 5,401 5,389
2010 2009 2008 2007 2006
$2,773 2,739 2,910 3,064 3,191
    Total revenues ($ in millions)
* “Adjusted” earnings per share and “adjusted” R&D expenses are non-GAAP financial measures. See page 12 for reconciliations to U.S. Generally Accepted Accounting Principles (GAAP).
“Adjusted” earnings per share (EPS)*
Cash flow from operations ($ in millions)
“Adjusted” research and development (R&D) expenses* ($ in millions)

 From left, Amgen CEO Kevin Sharer, Dr. David Lacey, Dr. Scott Simonet, and Roger M. Perlmutter, M.D., Ph.D., executive vice president of Research and Development, at the presentation of the George B. Rathmann Award for Scientific Excellence.
Honoring Scientific Innovation
The George B. Rathmann Award for Scientific Excellence, named for the visionary entrepreneur who established Amgen and served as its first CEO, is Amgen’s top honor and is given for breakthrough science.
This year Amgen is proud to recognize two pioneering scientists with this prestigious award: David Lacey, senior vice president of Research, and Scott Simonet, vice president of Research. Lacey and Simonet were instrumental in the discovery and development of the bone therapy denosumab, now marketed as Prolia® and XGEVATM.
Lacey and Simonet are joint recipients of the second Rathmann Award. The first recipient was Fu-Kuen Lin, the Amgen scientist who first successfully cloned the erythropoietin gene.
For their outstanding contribution and unfailing dedication to the innovative discovery and development of denosumab, we recognized two senior scientists, David Lacey and Scott Simonet, with our most prestigious internal scientific award, the George B. Rathmann Award for Scientific Excellence (see article at left).
Other 2010 Accomplishments
We advanced our pipeline significantly in 2010 with 13 international approvals, 37 marketing applications filed, four new molecules in clinical trials, and eight new cross-functional product teams formed that have responsibility for the global design and implementation of a new product’s development and commercialization strategy. We garnered a number of prestigious scientific awards (see Awards and Recognition box on page 3).
We continued to expand globally, providing our vital medicines for more patients around the world. We maintained very high compliance standards and performance in an increasingly challenging environment, and ended the year with strong momentum and a powerful base from which to grow revenues and earnings again.
Leadership Changes
During the year, our management team was strengthened by naming Bob Bradway as our president and chief operating officer and Jon Peacock as our new executive vice president and chief financial officer. George Morrow, executive vice president, began his transition to retirement from Amgen. George is one of the most respected executives in our industry, and his contributions to building the modern Amgen were immense. We look forward to his continued consultation and friendship.
Delivering Growth in 2011
Delivering financially, delivering the best pipeline, and capturing growth opportunities are the goals we have set for 2011. Beyond the successful launches of Prolia® (denosumab) and XGEVATM (denosumab)—our most important growth drivers this year—we will sustain and enhance the value of our existing $15 billion business. We will focus on growing our existing products, such as Neulasta® (pegfilgrastim), Sensipar® (cinacalcet), Nplate® (romiplostim), and Vectibix® (panitumumab), and invest in them to capture the opportunities.
In 2011, we will grow our investment in R&D with additional funding in discovery research, as well as our pivotal phase 3 trials, such as AMG 386 for the treatment of advanced ovarian cancer and ganitumab (previously known as AMG 479), used in combination with existing therapeutics for pancreatic cancer. We are excited about the potential of our pipeline in
a number of therapeutic areas, including oncology, inflammation, bone disease, and cardiovascular disease.
We also expect to achieve important regulatory goals this year. For example, we reported landmark clinical trial data for XGEVATM in December, showing significant improvement in bone-metastasis-free survival in men with prostate cancer, thereby adding to the potential of XGEVATM to benefit patients.

We expect to file for approval of a new indication in prostate cancer in the United States in the first half of 2011.
Innovation from Inside and Out to Drive Growth
We will also use our considerable financial strength to acquire or license innovative molecules that address important unmet medical needs. The BioVex acquisition, which we announced in January 2011 and expect to close in the first quarter of 2011, supports this strategy by further strengthening our late-stage oncology pipeline. BioVex’s lead product candidate, OncoVEXGM-CSF, is a novel oncolytic virus in phase 3 testing that has demonstrated encouraging antitumor activity in clinical studies for the treatment of metastatic melanoma and head and neck cancer. We are very impressed with the science behind this innovative therapeutic and believe it holds substantial promise to help patients with malignant disease.
With a focus on growth in 2011, we are accelerating our entry into faster-growing markets such as Brazil, Turkey, Mexico, and Russia. In 2010, we conducted business in 50 countries, and our aim is to operate in 75 countries by 2015. This means many more patients could access our medicines, and we could add meaningful incremental revenue by that time.
On Course with Our Mission to Serve Patients
One of our greatest rewards is helping patients. So when we learned through media interviews that professional golfer Phil Mickelson is using Enbrel® (etanercept) to treat his psoriatic arthritis, we were gratified he felt it was making a positive difference in his life. Having discovered that Phil is on ENBREL, we are now partnering with him to help people learn more about psoriatic arthritis and other inflammatory diseases as well as the treatments available for them.
Our mission to serve patients and our aspiration to be the best human therapeutics company are what drive and sustain us. Continuing to deliver against this mission and aspiration by growing our company, products, and pipeline is the best way we know to serve society, stockholders, and staff. In 2011, we have the energy, resources, and opportunities to deliver, and we are very optimistic about our prospects.
KEVIN W. SHARER
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
ROBERT A. BRADWAY
President and Chief Operating Officer
        February 9, 2011
 Awards and Recognition
• Prolia® (denosumab) wins Scrip’s Best New Drug award, one of the industry’s highest global accolades.
• Amgen receives the International Prix Galien award for Best Biopharmaceutical Research and Development for Nplate® (romiplostim). Nplate® also wins
Prix Galien awards in France, the Netherlands, and Spain.
• Med Ad News ranks Amgen number one on its list of Top 10 Most Admired Biotechnology Companies.
• Amgen is once again included on Fortune’s list of the most admired companies and contenders in America.
• Amgen receives Best Biotechnology Pipeline ranking from R&D Directions.
• The Scientist places Amgen sixth among large biotech and pharmaceutical companies—and number 16 overall—on its Best Places to Work in Industry list.
• Amgen places among the top
10 percent on the Forbes Global 2000 list of the world’s leading companies.
• Science magazine ranks Amgen number 10 on its list of top employers in the biotechnology and pharmaceutical industry.
• World Finance magazine (Europe) names Amgen as the Best Biotechnology Innovation Company of 2010.
• Amgen educational website “Pioneering New Frontiers in Tumor Angiogenesis” wins Webby Award.
AMGEN 2010 ANNUAL REPORT ■ 3
