                                               Dear Shareholders,
Let me begin by expressing how excited I am to
be part of the
Big Lots team.
I’m an Ohio native, born and raised, and have known the Company my whole life.
                                                                 Bruce K. Thorn President and CEO
 Growing up, my mother used to take me shopping at our stores on a regular basis. She was always about making our lives better with new home décor, festive holiday celebrations, and treats and toys for life’s special moments. So you can imagine how thrilled I am to have the opportunity to serve this great Company and our customers.
In recent months, we have invested a great deal of time as a Leadership Team working with some of the best retail consultants in the industry to develop a roadmap to transform our strategy and competitively position our business for long-term success. We’re enhancing our strengths and working hard to identify, prioritize, and launch new initiatives to accelerate sales and bend the cost curve. Essentially, we’re developing a three- year playbook on how to WIN in an ever-changing retail environment.
The first step in the process was defining our North Star — an internal aspiration that guides how we serve our customers and provides direction or a path for our teams to follow when making decisions. It identifies “our reason to exist,” “where to play,” and “how to win.” In order to better answer these questions, we conducted extensive customer research to gain unique insights. The survey used a psychographic lens to put ourselves in the mind of Jennifer and better understand her perspective. Over 5,000 customers, or potential customers, participated and clarified for us “what we are known for,” “where we get credit,” and “where we do not get credit.”
At a high level, we learned customers have a strong association with Big Lots when it comes to price, value, and treasure hunt ... with more emphasis on “the treasure” than “the hunt.” There is an opportunity for
us to more clearly shout value and our great prices while working to improve the quality of our product where it matters most. We verified our long-standing belief that we have a “right to play” in the Furniture, Home, and Seasonal categories. We also learned Jennifer has a stronger association with what we offer in Consumables than she does with our current Food assortment. These key insights present opportunities for us to gain market share in certain categories while adjusting other categories and balancing the critical need for customer traffic drivers to our stores. The research was also very clear we are getting credit and high marks for a better in-store experience with Store of the Future, and we have an opportunity to improve our accessibility as an omni-channel retailer.
BIG LOTS, INC. | 2018 ANNUAL REPORT
 
                                                                                                                          The customer insights go much deeper than how we should operate or go to market. They have provided rich and actionable information to help us further define new Mission, Vision, and Values statements for the Company as well as critical elements of our Customer Value Proposition, or CVP.
❚ Our Mission is simple...We help people Live BIG and Save LOTS.
❚ Our Vision for the future...Be the BIG difference for a better life by delivering unmatched value through surprise and delight, by being a “best places to work” culture, by rewarding shareholders with consistent growth and top tier returns, and by doing good as
we do well.
❚ And our Values embody the essence of how we intend to work together at Big Lots... Leading with Jennifer, treating all like a friend, succeeding together, and playing to win!
Utilizing our customer insights and building off our new Mission, Vision, and Values, we established the three critical elements of our new CVP which will serve as the anchor for our growth strategy:
1) be the authority on price & value, 2) increase accessibility of surprise & delight, and 3) grow home & life’s occasions. Growing over the next three years will require significant focus and the need to act
on some big choices. We’ve identified several key platforms designed to accentuate our CVP while providing Jennifer the accessibility she is looking for:
❚ First, grow Home as a destination leveraging our already strong product associations in Furniture, Seasonal, and Home Furnishings & Décor and further strengthening our position as a destination for all things home. These categories have represented over half of our sales and our largest comp sales growth in recent years, and we believe we have significant market share opportunities remaining. Our strategic acquisition of Broyhill®, a long-standing, iconic brand in the furniture industry, will be one of several catalysts to grow our offering in these categories, enhance our value proposition, elevate our quality perception, and increase the surprise and delight factor in our stores.
❚ The next platform is to drive increased traffic to our stores with enhanced product, price, and promotion. This will likely mean shifting space
from less productive elements of our assortment to either categories with higher sales productivity where we have the “right to play,” or potentially introducing new merchandise categories which are growing in the marketplace and potentially better resonate with Jennifer.
❚ The third platform focuses on life’s occasions or events by delivering the treasure hunt through newness and excitement for distinct periods in time. This could involve new or expanded merchandise categories, changes in placement or presentation in store, a different marketing approach or advertising cadence, or all of the above.
In terms of accessibility, we understand the need to make it easier for Jennifer, and new customers, to pick Big Lots. We see an expanded opportunity for store growth encompassing new markets as well as relocations. Based on customer density studies and current market conditions, we believe we’re ready to grow intelligently as locations become available in the ever-changing retail landscape.
Our Store of the Future concept focuses more
on the in-store experience and merchandise presentation and placement in our stores. However, to the extent customers have not shopped us recently because of how our stores used to present, this new format will increase access or potentially get us back on her shopping list by giving customers the treasure hunt they want ... accessible, yet fun, easy, and exciting.
Our online business presents an opportunity
to expand access by re-engaging with lapsed customers, extending aisles, and helping them shop on their terms when convenient. Later this summer, we will launch Buy Online Pickup In Store, or BOPIS, in our fleet of stores in an effort to appeal to our busiest customers. The launch will make available thousands of additional SKUs on our website to grow accessibility, increase our price
and value perception, and
enhance the surprise
and delight factor along
with customer satisfaction.
I am very excited about
this new opportunity to
leverage our brick and
mortar locations and our
friendly, hard-working
store associates.
 BIG LOTS, INC. | 2018 ANNUAL REPORT
        350101_BLAR18_NARR.indd 2
3/29/19 2:41 PM
                                  
                                     Fund the Journey
In order to fund all of these tremendous growth levers, we need to unlock value and lower our overall cost structure. Over the past several months, we conducted a holistic assessment looking at every single cost element of our business, including cost of goods sold, store labor, organization size and structure, supply chain, and all our indirect expenses. It was not just a top-down exercise, but we triangulated the opportunity with external and internal benchmarking and select detailed, bottom-up deep dives for understanding. We see the need to operate the business differently going forward in order to support improving our price/value proposition, enhancing customer
traffic drivers, and increasing the surprise and delight factor in stores. Through our efforts, we identified a $100 million cost reduction opportunity and established targets for each of the next three years... 2019, 2020, and 2021. We are already seeing the benefits of this effort in our results in certain areas of our business, and we expect some cost-saving opportunities will need investment first before seeing efficiencies.
Best Places to Work Culture
Throughout my career, I have long believed
people are the greatest asset of a company, and our research clearly indicates Big Lots is known for friendly associates. Our goal is to build upon this strength and create an environment, recognized throughout the industry, as having a “best places
to work” culture. This can be accomplished, in part, by living day-to-day our new Values of leading
with Jennifer, treating all like a friend, succeeding together, and playing to win! In addition, it is critical to have the right leaders with the right skill sets
and focus. We recently reorganized our executive structure, added new talent to the organization, and realigned roles and responsibilities to capture synergies and improve the opportunity for professional development and succession planning.
Doing Good as we Do Well
Doing the right thing is at the heart of our culture, and giving back to the communities we serve —
nationally, locally, and personally—is important. The Big Lots Foundation focuses on Healthcare, Housing, Hunger, and Education by supporting well-known national organizations including Nationwide Children’s Hospital, YWCA, Feeding America, the American Heart Association, and the National Veterans Memorial and Museum. We serve locally by investing in communities near
our stores, and personally through point-of-sale donation campaigns. In addition, our associates are encouraged to volunteer, and in the last year alone contributed over 7,500 hours to the causes most important to them.
Our Shareholders
For our shareholders, we understand it is your money fueling our enterprise and it is your trust and expectation we will deliver consistent growth and top-tier returns. Big Lots has a long history
of generating excess cash and returning it to you through our capital allocation strategy. In the years to come, we expect this to continue, balanced with investment in our operations and strategies to support future growth.
As I look forward, I’m excited about the future of the Company. We have a lot of work ahead of us, and we all know it will not be easy. Getting the right strategy and transformation plan put in place is the first critical step in this journey as we look to invest in growth, bend the cost curve, and deliver great value to our customers, our associates, and our shareholders.
On behalf of the entire Big Lots organization, our Board of Directors, and all our associates, I thank you for your support.
Sincerely,
Bruce K. Thorn President and CEO
                       Our Mission
is simple...
We help people Live BIG and Save LOTS.
                                    350101_BLAR18_NARR.indd 3
3/29/19 2:41 PM
                                  