   earning customer trust every day
   ANNUAL REPORT 2002

 OUR VISION
Comerica is in business to help people be successful.
We are committed to delivering the highest quality financial services by:
●
Providing outstanding value and building enduring customer relationships
●
Creating a positive environment for our colleagues, built on trust, teamwork and respect ●
Demonstrating leadership in our communities
●
Ensuring a consistent, superior return for our owners
OUR CORE VALUES
CORPORATE PROFILE
FAST FACTS ON COMERICA
◗ More than 11,000 employees focused on relationship management
◗ Among the 20 largest banking companies in the U.S., with $53 billion in total assets at December 31, 2002
◗ 3rd largest SBA 7(a) lender in the nation, and among the top 20 U.S. bank holding companies in small business loans
◗ No.1 and 10 among the top 50 U.S. bank holding companies, in commercial loans as a percent of total assets and commercial loans, respectively
Comerica Incorporated (NYSE: CMA) is a financial services company focused on business banking and asset gathering. Through its more than 500 customer-service locations, including branch, lending and investment offices, Comerica helps businesses and people be successful. Comerica is ideally positioned to deliver high quality financial services in Michigan, California and Texas, as well as in Florida, and numerous other states, Canada and Mexico. Munder Capital Management and Comerica Securities are investment services affiliates of Comerica.
Customer Service
●
Teamwork
●
Flexibility/Adapting to Change
●
Trust/Integrity
●
Ownership
●
Learning and Personal Growth
●
CONTENTS
1 2 4 8 16 22
Financial At a Glance Letter to Earning Our Financial Review Highlights Shareholders Customer Trust Leadership Team and Reports
  
   FINANCIAL HIGHLIGHTS
(dollar amounts in millions, except per share data)
Years Ended December 31
INCOME STATEMENT
Net interest income
Net income
Basic net income per common share Diluted net income per common share Cash dividends per common share Book value per common share
Market value per common share
RATIOS
Return on average assets
Return on average common shareholders’ equity
Average common shareholders’ equity as a percentage of average assets
Tier 1 common capital as a percentage of risk-weighted assets
BALANCE SHEET (AT DECEMBER 31)
Total assets
Total earning assets
Loans 42,281 41,196 Business loans 39,954 38,933 Deposits 41,775 37,570
Change Amount Percent
$30 1% (109) (15) (0.50) (13) (0.48) (12)
  Common shareholders’ equity
4,947 4,807
2002 2001 $ 2,132 $ 2,102
601 710 3.43 3.93 3.40 3.88 1.92 1.76
28.31 27.17 43.24 57.30
1.18% 1.43% 12.31 15.16
9.55 9.27 7.39 7.30
0.16 9
1.14 4 (14.06) (25)
2,551 5% 1,214 3 1,085 3 1,021 3 4,205 11
140 3
 $53,301 $50,750 47,780 46,566
$
      $759 $651
$791
$4.13 $4.31
21.16% 21.78% 19.52%
15.16% 12.31%
1998 1999 2000 2001 2002
Return on Average Common Shareholders’ Equity
(in percentages)
1998 1999 2000 2001 2002
Net Income
(in millions)
1998 1999 2000 2001 2002
$710
$3.88
$601
$3.51
$3.40
Diluted Net Income per Common Share
(in dollars)
1

 AT A GLANCE
 BUSINESS BANK
Comerica’s Business Bank provides companies with an extensive array of credit and non-credit financial products and services. It builds long-lasting relationships with business customers, with an emphasis on middle market companies. The Business Bank offers highly professional business lending, international banking and cash management services.
 INDIVIDUAL BANK
The professionals of Comerica’s Individual Bank deliver diverse products and services to consumers, and owners and managers of small businesses. Comerica’s extensive network of branch offices, automated teller machines and supermarket locations, along with web banking, gives customers easy, convenient access to the bank’s portfolio of products. A host of private banking services, including personal trust, private lending and financial planning, round out the Individual Bank’s complement of financial services.
 INVESTMENT BANK
Comerica’s Investment Bank offers a full range of institutional trust, investment and insurance services to individuals, companies, labor unions and other entities. Major areas of focus include institutional trust, retirement services, full- service brokerage services and insurance. The Investment Bank continues to be a driving force in managing client assets.
 2
  
 ORGANIZATION STRENGTHS STRATEGIES
Middle Market Banking
◗ includes Private Equity National Business Finance
◗ Commercial Real Estate
◗ National Dealer Services
◗ Comerica Leasing Services Global Corporate Banking
◗ U.S. Banking
◗ International Finance
◗ Treasury Management Services ◗ Corporate Finance
W.Y. Campbell & Co.
Private Banking
Small Business Banking Personal Financial Services
◗ Strong underwriting skills; consistent provider of credit
◗ Flexibility and responsiveness
◗ Experienced and seasoned staff
◗ Leading-edge Internet-based treasury management products and services
◗ North American platform fulfills U.S., Canadian and Mexican dollar-based needs of commercial customers
◗ Nationally recognized leader in small business banking
◗ Complete portfolio of diverse, competitively priced products
◗ Proven leader in gathering consumer assets
◗ Leading-edge sales and service culture, driven by a commitment to build strong customer relationships
◗ Connectivity approach ensures clients benefit from all Comerica products and services
◗ Service is a key differentiating factor in client retention
◗ Experienced and knowledgeable staff with the ability to meet customers’ expectations through all economic cycles
◗ Outstanding trust/custodial capabilities designed for distinct client segments
◗ Solid partnerships with Business Bank and Individual Bank customers
◗ One-stop shop for customized company and union retirement plans
◗ Emphasize relationship-focused business rather than transactional business
◗ Focus on high growth urban markets and industries
◗ Deepen relationships vertically with businesses and their owners through Connectivity* initiative
◗ Leverage depth of experience, industry knowledge and local decision making
◗ Grow middle market relationships
◗ Invest in new branches and additional delivery channels in high growth urban markets
◗ Introduce new deposit products, web-banking services and promotional programs
◗ Maximize the wealth management opportunities from strategic business alliances, including Dain Rauscher and PaineWebber
◗ Leverage referrals, both internally and externally, through Connectivity initiative
◗ Target small-business opportunities via comprehensive niche marketing initiatives
◗ Continue to broaden product offerings and delivery channels
◗ Maintain efficient, effective technology platforms for brokerage and trust services
◗ Focus on niche business opportunities in Institutional Trust and Retirement Services
◗ Continue to focus on staff development to provide exceptional client service
◗ Deepen existing partnerships and establish new partnerships both within and outside of Comerica
*Connectivity is a corporate-wide initiative to maximize the potential of customer relationships
  Investment Services
◗ Comerica Securities
◗ Munder Capital Management ◗ Wilson, Kemp & Associates Comerica Insurance Services
Institutional Trust Retirement Services
  3

 LETTER TO SHAREHOLDERS
We believe we have the right business model and the right strategy to capitalize on an improving economy when improvement does come.
 Ralph W. Babb Jr.
Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer
 4
  
 Dear Fellow Shareholders,
2002 was a difficult year for the nation’s economy, the banking sector and Comerica. We addressed the many challenges presented by a slow economy and weak financial markets, and we made progress on many fronts, including credit quality.
This is my first annual report to you as chairman of Comerica. Therefore, it’s an appropriate opportunity to present my views of where our company is today, where it’s going, and what that is likely to mean for your investment in Comerica.
First and foremost, we are a lender – specifically to middle market and small business customers. Some banks have de- emphasized their focus on lending. We haven’t. We are good at commercial lending to small and middle market companies in urban markets, primarily because we deliver true relationship banking combined with solid credit management. Lending is a cyclical business, but we believe that our approach to this business has and will continue to generate attractive returns for our shareholders over time.
Our other lines of business in the Individual and Investment Banks dovetail nicely with our lending business. We offer a broad range of asset management and personal financial services to entrepreneurs, business owners and other affluent individuals with the same dedication to relationship management that is the hallmark of our commercial lending business.
We believe these principal lines of business, combined with enhanced risk management processes, create a platform with significant competitive advantages for Comerica. Fundamentally, we like the position
we’re in.
Our difficulties in 2002 should not obscure the fact that on many fronts Comerica took steps that we believe will benefit the company when the economy improves.
Our commercial lending business generated modest growth at a time when many banks were unable to grow. Because we seek to lend in a measured but consistent way through all phases of the economic cycles, we expect, as we have in the past, to gain market share in the middle market. At the same time, we took steps to adjust our mix of commercial loans by reducing our exposure to large corporate and international loans that did not fit with
our focus on true relationship banking.
Customer Focus
We are constantly fine-tuning our products for our commercial customers. For example, we made significant enhancements to the flexibility and functionality of our image services in 2002. Commercial customers can now access a wide array of image services over the Internet or through Comerica’s proprietary network. Since the creation of our image archive in 1997, we have built an active inventory of more than 2.4 billion
5

 images, providing customers and employees access to every deposit and check presented to any of our image capture sites over the last five years.
We also continued to help business owners and managers eliminate costly time spent preparing, distributing and reconciling paper checks through use of our Comerica CompCARDSM, which enables companies to disburse funds to their employees without using a paper check.
We know our customers like what we do. Our middle market customer satisfaction rankings were among the highest of national and regional banks in all our major markets, according to a survey conducted by a global financial services research firm.
And, our Treasury Management customers gave Comerica the highest marks in product rankings (e.g., accuracy, timeliness, overall capabilities), relationship management, and sales and service, according to another survey of regional and national banks.
We invested $20 million to renovate branches and open new ones. This investment is key to sustaining a market- leading position in the Michigan retail banking market. Over time, we also believe it will help us enhance the performance
of our other lines of business which are focused on our affluent customers, business owners and entrepreneurs. For example,
branches are particularly important to our small business customers, who tend to visit a branch 12 times per month.
Equally gratifying, we witnessed improved rates of growth in 2002 in small business banking, private banking, asset management businesses, and retail transaction accounts, which translate into relationships. In many cases, these were double digit rates of growth, which reinforces our view that the best of these businesses is yet to come.
With our primary footprint in Michigan, California, Texas and Florida, we have the critical mass to continue to grow these core businesses.
At the heart of our success is relationships.
During these challenging economic times, we continue to earn our customers’
trust and build and strengthen those relationships. I invite you to read about four of our customers – Dr. Toni Hoover, Wallace Tsuha of Saturn Electronics & Engineering, Luis Spinola of Azteca Enterprises & Omega Contracting, and Mark Brody of Cline Cellars – following this letter.
Finally, in 2002 we took the steps we had to take to address the credit quality issues created by continued economic weakness that year. An effective emphasis on credit quality has long been a competitive advantage for Comerica and we are committed to sustaining and enhancing that competitive edge.
2003 Priorities
Let me now address our priorities for 2003 in more detail.
We know the economy will improve, but none of us knows when, so 2003 is a year in which we will focus on strengthening the fundamentals so that, when the economy does rebound, Comerica will be ready
to grow.
This year, we will maintain our focus on our core strategy – relationship-based middle
   $1.44 $1.28
$1.92
 $1.76 $1.60
    1998 1999 2000 2001 2002
Dividends per Common Share
(in dollars)
6

                                               Comparison of Five Year Cumulative Total Return Among Comerica Incorporated,
Keefe 50-Bank Index and S&P 500 Index
(assumes $100 invested on 12/31/97 and reinvestment of dividends)
market lending – and continue to lend during the current economic environment, while remaining alert and disciplined about credit quality. We will continue to grow the Individual and Investment Banks to meet the needs of our small business and private banking customers, building new branches and refurbishing existing ones. Our colleagues have embraced Connectivity,
our national initiative to increase fee income and our share of new and current customers’ business through cross-selling. This year, we will continue to build on their enthusiasm and success, and provide additional tools and training. And, we
will strengthen our historically strong risk management process.
This is a challenging environment for
large, complex banks like Comerica. Consequently, we are building a strong, effective Enterprise-Wide Risk Management Program to manage risk on a consistent, coordinated basis across our company, rather than within individual operating units. During 2003, this multi-year effort will focus on designing and implementing a system to enhance our measurement and management of credit and operational risk.
By continuing a strong emphasis on credit risk management, and building upon our successful management of operational and interest rate risk, we will reinforce an historic advantage over our competitors, while giving our colleagues new tools to help our customers ‘make it work.’
The outcome of all of this will be better information for making strategic decisions and allocating resources.
Other Highlights
In 2002, we marked the end of an era. Comerica’s leadership transition was successfully completed when Gene Miller retired October 1 after 47 years at Comerica, including the last nine as chairman and chief executive officer. Gene was a principal architect of today’s Comerica and all of my colleagues and I are deeply grateful to
Gene for his leadership. We wish him well as he embarks on this new phase of his life.
As we have in each of the past 34 consecutive years, Comerica increased its annual dividend. In January 2003, we raised the quarterly dividend for common stock by four percent to $0.50 per share.
We know improvements in growth and credit quality will parallel improvement in the economy. We are well aware that we enter 2003 with a great deal of economic and national uncertainty. Nonetheless, we believe we have the right business model and the right strategy to capitalize on an improving economy when improvement does come.
Comerica has a proud 154-year history of service through many trying times for our country, our economy and the world around us. Our talented colleagues are dedicated to our core values and committed to delivering the highest quality financial services for all of our customers. I am confident that this dedication will translate into attractive future returns for our shareholders.
Ralph W. Babb Jr. Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer
 7

Ann Arbor
 I trust their advice.
 8
      
 TONI HOOVER
The first order of business was to create a detailed financial plan to give Hoover a solid understanding of her financial picture and a framework to
Toni Hoover knows that life doesn’t always go according to plan. Following the unexpected death of her husband, Hoover realized she needed assistance with her personal finances. Referred to Comerica by her legal counsel, Hoover met with Deb Jones and Jim Pollock of Comerica’s Private Banking group.
meet future goals. Next, Jones and Pollock helped Hoover with her investment portfolio, estate and family gift-planning, wire transfer services, mortgage refinancing and general banking needs.
As vice president of project management at Pfizer Global Research and Development, Hoover travels the world constantly. “I need advisors who can meet my hectic schedule,” Hoover said. “Deb and Jim often meet me at my office which is very convenient.
“I now have the tools to build and protect my financial security,” Hoover said. “With the private bankers at Comerica, I feel like I have a whole team working on my behalf.”
9
       
Auburn Hills
 We trust each other.
 10
    
 SATURN ELECTRONICS & ENGINEERING, INC.
Saturn Electronics & Engineering, Inc., was a five-year-old company with just under $10 million in annual revenue when Tsuha and Comerica Bank first forged a financial relationship in 1990.
Since then, Saturn has grown to become a $375 million, full-service global supplier of electronic components and assemblies.
Among Saturn’s biggest customers are the Big Three automakers and other key Tier 1 suppliers.
“Comerica understands the ups and downs of our industry, and is willing to work with us, side by side,” Tsuha said. “Unlike larger transaction-oriented banks, Comerica is all about long-term relationships, and that is important to us.
“We appreciate the support of Dave and his
“When two people know each other, they can speak frankly to one another, and that is what Dave and I have done these past 12 years,” said Wallace “Wally” Tsuha Jr., chairman and chief executive officer of Saturn Electronics & Engineering, Inc. “Dave” is Dave Marvin, a Comerica Middle Market Banking senior manager in Michigan.
11
team, and the fine work of the Business & Development Services area, too.“
       
Dallas
 He’s a trusted consultant.
12
      
 AZTECA ENTERPRISES &
OMEGA CONTRACTING, INC.
 Spinola started his first company in 1983 with just two employees.
“I used to bank elsewhere, but when I asked for an increased credit line, they turned me down,” Spinola said. “A colleague suggested I meet with the team at Comerica and I’m glad I did. They were willing
to work with the construction
industry, they were straightforward
and very fast.”
Soon, Spinola’s company won contracts throughout Texas. Azteca Enterprises & Omega Contracting now has more than 450 employees and annual revenues of some
$31 million.
“I have a tremendous group of employees who look for ways to accelerate growth and minimize risk. Plus,
I count on Jesus Guevara for recommendations on all sorts of financial issues. He’s more than a banker, he’s a trusted consultant.”
“Cash flow is the life-blood of any small business,” said
Luis Spinola, president of Azteca Enterprises & Omega Contracting, Inc., Dallas-based construction contracting firms. “Jesus Guevara and the Small Business group at Comerica understand this. We’ve built a solid relationship which enables us to think outside the box to get the financing done.”
13
      
Sonoma
 We trust them to deliver what we need.
14
      
 CLINE CELLARS
 Cline Cellars is recognized for its rich, quality wines, including its highly acclaimed zinfandels and syrahs. Named as a 2002 “Winery of the Year” by Wine and Spirits magazine, Cline produces some 175,000 cases annually from
its 1,000 acres of exceptional vineyards.
“From industry knowledge to responsiveness, Greg, Russ Colombo, Misako Noda and the entire Comerica team have been great,” Brody said. “They ask good questions, which I appreciate.”
Comerica has put together a flexible financing package for the winery, which was founded by Fred and Nancy Cline.
“Comerica understands how specific products fit our distinct needs, so the bank offers us solutions that work,” Brody said.
“They’re good after the sale as well as before, which I think is pretty darn important.”
They worked together in the early 1980s and in the next decade, veteran bankers Mark Brody and Greg Belanger were tough competitors. Today, Brody is chief executive officer of Cline Cellars,
a Sonoma, California winery. Belanger heads Middle Market Banking-North for Comerica Bank- California. Brody selected Comerica as the winery’s primary banker.
“It made sense to go with people we knew well and a bank with a proven track record,” he said.
15
      
 OUR LEADERSHIP TEAM
COMERICA INCORPORATED BOARD OF DIRECTORS
    RALPH W. BABB JR.
Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer Comerica Incorporated and Comerica Bank
(d, e, f, g)
LILLIAN BAUDER, PH.D.
Vice President Corporate Affairs Masco Corporation (a, c)
JOSEPH J. BUTTIGIEG III
Vice Chairman
Comerica Incorporated and Comerica Bank
(g)
JAMES F. CORDES
Retired Executive Vice President The Coastal Corporation
(g)
PETER D. CUMMINGS
Chairman
Ram Development Company (c, f)
J. PHILIP DINAPOLI
President
J.P. DiNapoli Companies, Inc. (a, c)
 ANTHONY F. EARLEY JR.
Chairman and
Chief Executive Officer DTE Energy Company (b)
MAX M. FISHER
Investor (b)
ROGER FRIDHOLM
President
St. Clair Group (e)
TODD W. HERRICK
President and
Chief Executive Officer Tecumseh Products Company (g)
DAVID BAKER LEWIS
Chairman and Founder Lewis and Munday, P.C. (f)
JOHN D. LEWIS
Vice Chairman
Comerica Incorporated and Comerica Bank
(f)
           16
  
     WAYNE B. LYON
Retired Chairman Lifestyle Furnishings International, Inc. (b)
ALFRED A. PIERGALLINI
Retired Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Novartis Consumer Health WorldWide
(b)
HOWARD F. SIMS
Chairman
Sims Design Group, Inc. (c)
ROBERT S. TAUBMAN
President and
Chief Executive Officer
The Taubman Company, Inc. (g)
WILLIAM P. VITITOE
Retired Chairman and
Chief Executive Officer Washington Energy Company (a)
       BOARD COMMITTEES
(a) Audit & Legal
(b) Compensation
(c) Corporate Governance & Nominating (d) Executive
(e) Public Responsibility
(f) Trust & Investment
(g) Risk Asset
MARTIN D. WALKER
Retired Principal MORWAL Investments (a, b)
PATRICIA M. WALLINGTON
President
CIO Associates (f)
GAIL L. WARDEN
President and
Chief Executive Officer Henry Ford Health System (e)
KENNETH L. WAY
Retired Chairman Lear Corporation (b)
   17

 COMERICA BANK-CALIFORNIA COMERICA BANK-TEXAS DIRECTORS DIRECTORS
 THEODORE J. B I A G I N I Principal
Biagini Properties
JACK C. CARSTEN
Managing Director Horizon Ventures
LEO E. CHAVEZ, PH.D.
Executive Vice President Community Foundation Silicon Valley
JACK W. CONNER
Chairman
Comerica Bank-California
NORMAN P. CREIGHTON
Vice Chairman
Comerica Bank-California
J. MICHAEL FULTON
President and
Chief Executive Officer Comerica Bank-California
WALTER T.
K A C Z M A R E K
Executive Vice President Comerica Bank-California
ELINOR WEISS MANSFIELD Attorney
CHARLES T. OWEN
President and Publisher
San Diego Business Journal
EDWARD P. ROSKI JR.
President
Majestic Realty Company
DAVID C. WHITE
Executive Vice President Comerica Bank-California
LEWIS N. WOLFF
Chairman and
Chief Executive Officer Wolff DiNapoli
JAMES F. CORDES
Retired Executive
Vice President
The Coastal Corporation
THOMAS M. DUNNING
Chairman and
Chief Executive Officer Lockton Dunning Benefit Company
RUBEN E. ESQUIVEL
Vice President Community and Corporate Relations University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center
JAKE KAMIN
Chairman
South Texas Advisory Board Comerica Bank-Texas
W. THOMAS MCQUAID
Chairman and
Chief Executive Officer Performance Properties Corporation
RAYMOND D. NASHER
Chairman
Comerica Bank-Texas Chairman
The Nasher Company
CALVIN E. PERSON
Owner
Calvin E. Person and Associates
BOONE POWELL JR.
Retired Chairman
Baylor Health Care System
J. PHILIP
DI NAPOLI
REV. ZAN
HOLMES
JR.
President
J.P. DiNapoli Companies, Inc.
N. JOHN DOUGLAS
President and
Chief Executive Officer AM Power Radio
Retired Senior Pastor
St. Luke Community United Methodist Church
IN MEMORIAM
George L. Graziadio Jr., who passed away in
June 2002, served with dedication and distinction as chairman of Comerica Bank-California. We remember and honor his service to our company, including his leadership in helping bring together Imperial Bancorp with Comerica Bank-California, a combination that created the fourth largest banking company in the Golden State.
18
CHARLES L.
GUMMER
President and
Chief Executive Officer Comerica Bank-Texas
  
 MANAGEMENT COUNCIL
RALPH W. BABB JR.
Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer
JOSEPH J. BUTTIGIEG III Vice Chairman Business Bank
JOHN D. LEWIS
Vice Chairman Individual and Investment Banks
ELIZABETH S. ACTON
Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer
JOHN R. BERAN
Executive Vice President and Chief Information Officer
JON W. BILSTROM
Executive Vice President and Chief Governance and Regulatory Affairs Officer
RICHARD A. COLLISTER
Executive Vice President Corporate Staff
GEORGE C. ESHELMAN
Executive Vice President Investment Bank
J. MICHAEL FULTON
President and
Chief Executive Officer Comerica Bank-California
DALE E. GREENE
Executive Vice President and Chief Credit Officer
CHARLES L. GUMMER
President and
Chief Executive Officer Comerica Bank-Texas
JOHN R. HAGGERTY
Executive Vice President Small Business Banking and Personal Financial Services
THOMAS R. JOHNSON
Executive Vice President Enterprise-Wide
Risk Management Program
SUSAN R. JOSEPH
Senior Vice President and General Auditor
GEORGE W. MADISON
Executive Vice President Corporate Secretary and General Counsel
RONALD P. MARCINELLI
Executive Vice President National Business Finance
DAVID B. STEPHENS
Executive Vice President Private Banking
19
  
  COMMERCIAL BANKS
OTHER UNITS
COMERICA
SECURITIES, INC.
A full-service broker-dealer that offers stocks, bonds, mutual funds and annuities to individual investors, along with investment banking services.
COMERICA INSURANCE SERVICES, INC.
Offers life, disability, long-term care, group benefits, and property and casualty insurance to businesses and individuals.
PROFESSIONAL LIFE UNDERWRITERS SERVICES, INC. (PLUS) Provides life insurance, annuities and disability insurance products to independent insurance agents.
MUNDER CAPITAL MANAGEMENT
Provides investment advisory services to institutions, municipalities, unions, charitable organizations and individuals across North America. Also serves as investment manager for The Munder Funds. Framlington Holdings Limited, a London-based international investment advisor, is a subsidiary of Munder.
WILSON, KEMP & ASSOCIATES, INC.
Provides account management services to private investors, corporations, municipalities and charitable institutions throughout the United States.
W.Y. CAMPBELL
& COMPANY
Provides investment banking and corporate finance services to Fortune 500 companies and middle-market firms.
COMERICA WEST INCORPORATED
U.S. Banking-West Group originates mid-sized loans to business customers with specific emphasis on the Western United States.
COMERICA LEASING CORPORATION
Provides equipment leasing and financing services for businesses throughout the United States.
 COMERICA BANK
Comerica Tower at Detroit Center 500 Woodward Avenue, MC 3391 Detroit, Michigan 48226
(313) 222-4000 (248) 371-5000
Ralph W. Babb Jr. Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer
Full-service bank headquartered in Detroit with 219 branch offices, 36 ComeriMARTs and 526 ATMs at year-end 2002 in metropolitan Detroit and Ann Arbor, Battle Creek, Grand Rapids, Jackson, Kalamazoo, Lansing, Midland
and Muskegon.
Comerica is the largest bank headquartered in Detroit. Comerica is Michigan’s oldest banking company (1849).
Florida region
1800 Corporate Blvd., N.W. Suite 100, MC 5172
Boca Raton, Florida 33431
(800) 777-7198
Specializes in Private Banking services, with 9 office locations,
4 of which are full-service branches, and 2 ATMs at year-
end 2002, in Boca Raton, Fort Lauderdale, Palm Beach Gardens, Naples, Sarasota and Tampa. Other national businesses also operate in Florida. Comerica entered the Florida market in 1979.
Canadian region
Royal Bank Plaza, South Tower 200 Bay Street, Suite 2210 P.O. Box 61
Toronto, Ontario M5J2J2
(416) 367-3113
Specializes in providing a wide range of corporate banking, treasury, cash management and trade services in Canada.
COMERICA BANK MEXICO, S.A. Edificio Forum
Andres Bello No. 10 Piso 17
Col. Chapultepec Polanco Mexico, D.F. 11560
(011) 525-279-3700
Claude H. Miller Managing Director
Headquartered in Mexico City, with additional offices in Monterrey, Querétaro and Guadalajara. Comerica Bank Mexico, S.A. provides a wide range of corporate banking and trade finance services to middle market and large corporate companies.
COMERICA BANK- CALIFORNIA
333 W. Santa Clara Street MC 4805
San Jose, California 95113 (408) 556-5000
J. Michael Fulton President and
Chief Executive Officer
Full-service bank headquartered in San Jose with 41 branch offices and 36 ATMs at year-end 2002 in San Jose, Sacramento, Fresno, the greater San Francisco Bay/San Jose area, Santa Cruz Coastal, greater Los Angeles/Orange County, and San Diego. Additional regional banking offices in Phoenix, Denver, and Kirkland, Wash. SBA Lending offices are located around the country, and Technology and Life Sciences Division offices serve technology centers nationwide.
Comerica Bank-California is the 4th largest bank in California. Comerica entered the California market in 1991.
COMERICA BANK-TEXAS
1601 Elm Street, MC 6507 Dallas, Texas 75201
(214) 589-1400
Charles L. Gummer President and
Chief Executive Officer
Full-service bank headquartered in Dallas with 47 branch offices, 3 ComeriMARTs and 57 ATMs at year-end 2002 in the Dallas/Fort Worth Metroplex, Austin and the greater Houston area. Comerica Bank-Texas targets owner- managed businesses by actively lending to middle market businesses, small businesses
and local entrepreneurs.
Comerica Bank-Texas is the 6th largest bank in Texas. Comerica entered the Texas market in 1988.
COMERICA BANK
& TRUST
Provides a national platform for the delivery of trust, investment management and other banking services.
(Select businesses also having locations outside of Comerica’s primary markets)
MIDDLE MARKET BANKING Cincinnati
Cleveland
Denver Indianapolis Kirkland, Wash. Phoenix Portland
INSTITUTIONAL TRUST
Chicago
INTERNATIONAL FINANCE
Chicago
Hong Kong
Sao Paulo, Brazil
NATIONAL DEALER SERVICES
Chicago
Denver
PRIVATE BANKING CENTERS
Chicago
Cleveland
Denver Memphis Minneapolis New York City Phoenix
SBA LENDING
Barrington, Ill. Charlotte, N.C. Chicago Cincinnati Cleveland Denver
New Orleans Olympia, Wash. Phoenix Raleigh-Durham, N.C.
TECHNOLOGY & LIFE SCIENCES Atlanta
Boston
Denver
Kirkland, Wash.
New York City Philadelphia
Phoenix Raleigh-Durham, N.C. Reston, Va.
U.S. BANKING
Chicago Las Vegas
 20
 
                           21

   Elizabeth S. Acton
Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer
FINANCIAL REVIEW AND REPORTS
24 24 32 33 36
Financial Results Earnings Strategic Lines Balance Sheet and Risk
and Key Corporate Performance of Business Capital Funds Analysis Management
Initiatives
46 50 76 76 77
Consolidated Notes to Consolidated Report of Report of Historical Financial Statements Financial Statements Management Independent Auditors Review
   22
