Fellow Stockholders:
In 1998, for the fourth straight year, Capital One broke records across the board and broke them by wide margins. We see this long winning streak as testimony to the power of our Information-Based Strategy, our success in executing it and the commitment we have made to innovation in every part of the company.
At the time of our initial public offering in November 1994, we announced two highly ambitious goals for Capital One: annual per share earnings growth and annual return on equity of at least 20%. We have surpassed both goals for four consecutive years and have already announced that we expect to surpass them again in 1999. Our consumer franchise now includes one of every seven U.S. households, and our loan portfolio has grown to $17.4 billion. We were delighted that a share of Capital One stock, worth $16 on the day we went public, traded for $115 on December 31, 1998.
The company’s 1998 net income of $275.2 million, or $3.96 per share, was up more than 40% from $189.4 million, or $2.80 per share, in 1997. In addi- tion, we doubled our marketing investment to $446 million, particularly note-
worthy in a year of such
strong earnings growth.
This investment, which
funds current marketing
efforts and the vast testing we do to find and pursue new opportunities, generates a steady stream of innovation and growth for Capital One.
Total revenue (managed net interest income plus non- interest income) also reached record levels, rising 33% to $2.8 billion in 1998 from $2.1 billion in 1997. Managed net interest income was up 31% to $1.7 billion, the result
of an increase of 109 basis points in the net interest mar- gin and a 22% increase in managed loans. Managed non- interest income was up 38% to $1.1 billion.
For the third consecutive year, Capital One’s rate of account growth (42%) set a record. We added an impres- sive 14,000 net new accounts a day. In the last quarter, the pace accelerated to 20,000 a day. We ended the year with 16.7 million customers—almost 5 million more than we had at the end of 1997.
Credit performance was outstanding. Delinquencies declined throughout the year to 4.70% as of December 31, 1998, compared with 6.20% a year earlier. Charge-offs improved 186 basis points to 4.51% for the fourth quarter of 1998, compared with 6.37% in the fourth quarter 1997. Capital One’s fourth quarter net charge-offs as a percent- age of managed loans were among the industry’s lowest.
While 1998’s credit performance benefited from an improved consumer credit environment, it also reflects the success of Capital One’s approach to credit and mar- keting. We couple highly sophisticated credit modeling with credit policies and pricing closely matched to the
risk profile of each cus- tomer. And our marketing success with customers that we have dubbed “superprime” has signifi-
cantly changed the mix of our loan portfolio: 30% of our loans now represent borrowings by these customers. These are high-income, very low-risk customers who are even more attractive than the “prime” customers that are the target of most of our industry’s marketing efforts. Over the last two years, with innovative products designed for the highly diverse needs of superprime customers, we
 In 1998, for the fourth straight year, Capital One broke records across the board and broke them by wide margins.
3

have grown their loans by $5.0 billion. As expected, our superprime loans are performing very well.
Capital One’s risk-adjusted margin widened to a record 12.21% for the fourth quarter of 1998 from 9.10% a year earlier. Risk-adjusted margin (total managed revenue less managed net charge-offs as a percentage of average managed earning assets) is a key measure of profitability in the credit card industry, and ours is one of the best.
The company has a strong balance sheet, with a high ratio of capital to managed assets and substantial liquid- ity. In good times our
balance sheet liquidity
creates great flexibility in
raising the funds required
to meet the borrowing
needs of our growing customer base. In times of turmoil, such as last fall’s global liquidity crisis, it enables Capital One to continue business without interruption.
Capital One’s success continues to be powered by the very same strategy we developed more than a decade ago, our Information-Based Strategy. The strategy is to leverage technology, information and scien- tific testing to create a quantum improvement in market- ing capability. Our goal: to leapfrog high-priced, one-size- fits-all marketing with “mass customization,” delivering the right product to the right consumer at the right time and at the right price.
At the heart of the strategy is the use of scientific test- ing on a massive scale. We use testing to learn how to customize products and services to the individual consumer; we also use testing to build an innovation laboratory capable of creating a steady stream of new ideas to stay ahead of the competition. Testing also
allows us to cost-effectively explore many possibilities, and to know in advance the likely results of the products and programs we are rolling out.
We have literally turned the business into a scientific laboratory. In 1998, we conducted 27,000 tests of prod- ucts, prices, features, packages, marketing channels, credit policies, account management, customer service, collections and retention.
We have always recognized that rapid technological advances create an “innovation imperative.” Product life cycles are getting shorter and shorter, pushing
marketers to move faster and faster to stay ahead of the competition. Capital One is specifically designed for this environ-
ment. Our strategy, people, technology, operations and culture are built to deliver on the innovation imperative.
We chose credit cards as our initial focus because they are ideal for direct marketing and because they present- ed an opportunity to use our Information-Based Strategy to transform an industry. The strategy has been rewarding for Capital One and beneficial to consumers. The thou- sands of product variations we offer have created more choice, wider access to credit and lower borrowing costs for most consumers.
Although Capital One’s revenues still come primar- ily from U.S. credit cards, we are successfully applying our strategy to other geographies and businesses. In the United Kingdom and Canada, our credit cards are winning market share through customization and lower prices. With America One, we are reinventing the marketing of wireless phone service by selling directly to consumers and mass customizing
Our strategy, people, technology, operations and culture are built to deliver on the innovation imperative.
 4

our service to expand their choices. America One opens a major avenue of diversification for us and has the poten- tial to produce a large and profitable annuity-like stream of income.
In July 1998, we also entered the auto lending busi- ness with the acquisition of Summit Acceptance Corporation of Dallas, Texas. Summit gives us a testing platform in a financial sector we believe is well suited to our Information-Based Strategy and ready for fundamen- tal change.
The broad applicability of our strategy puts Capital One in an excellent position to capitalize on macrotrends that have been reshaping the world for the last decade and will continue to shape it in the next:
■ Direct marketing, which opens up the opportunity to test and customize, to capture information and to roll out innovations quickly and inexpensively.
■ The Internet, the ultimate direct marketing channel which brings our Information-Based Strategy into real time.
■ Information technology, as continuing advances in the ability to collect, process, store and use information are accelerating the opportunities for technology-based marketing.
■ Globalization, which gives rise to marketing opportuni- ties all over the world.
■ Excellent product growth trends. The credit card is steadily replacing cash and checks as the preferred medi- um of exchange. Wireless
phones are becoming a
mass consumer product
as the cost of service
becomes more affordable.
With the information-based company we’ve built, and the broad, rapid innovation it supports, we see an out-
standing future for Capital One. We are aligned to ride the macrotrends. And we’re moving toward our vision of a company that is not dependent on the fortunes of a sin- gle industry or geography.
Our confidence in the company’s long-term success is so strong that the two of us continue to forgo current compensation in exchange for the possi- bility of greater rewards in the future. In June 1998, having already given up our salaries and bonuses, we traded vested stock options, valued at $8.8 million, for new options that will not vest unless Capital One’s stock price reaches $175 by June 11, 2001. (This represents a compound annual increase of 20% for three years.) Our options are part of a compensation plan that, in 1998, allowed 273 senior managers to forgo up to half their annual cash bonuses for options. An overwhelming major- ity (82%) chose to participate.
More than 40% of our associates take part in the com- pany’s stock purchase plan, one of the highest participa- tion levels in corporate America. Last spring, to foster the entrepreneurial spirit that goes hand in hand with ownership, we once again granted stock options to all associates (excluding senior executives). The option and compensation plans are described on pages 47–49.
Knowing the success of our strategy depends entirely on the caliber of our people, we have always seen recruit- ing as our most important business. We are deeply
committed to finding and empowering world-class talent. To attract the best of the best, we’ve created a company that offers
associates unusually broad opportunities to pursue their entrepreneurial dreams, develop their leadership
Knowing the success of our strategy depends entirely on the caliber of our people, we have always seen recruiting as our most important business.
 5

potential and move up. As a result, Capital One has quickly earned a reputation as a place to build a great career. Fortune mag- azine now ranks us as one of the 100 Best Companies to Work for in America. Quite a change from just four years ago, when recruits were inclined to ask “Capital Who?” Our associates have always given the company high marks
in satisfaction surveys
conducted by an indepen-
dent research firm, and in
1998, the scores hit all-
time highs. In fact, our
scores are among the highest of any U.S. company.
With unemployment at a 28-year low in 1998, com- petition for talent was stiff. But our retention rate was the best ever and we added 4,526 associates—an increase of 77%—without lowering our high standards by an inch. We’re extremely proud of those accomplishments. We’re also very gratified by the energy, creativity and excellence our associates showed in driving the year’s rapid growth and innovation.
The top-flight performance of our associates con- tinues to win awards for Capital One. In 1998, our excellence in financial management was recog- nized with not one but three Alexander Hamilton Awards from Treasury & Risk Management magazine. Innovation in cross-selling, and the technology behind it, earned an Enterprise Value Award from CIO magazine. And Future Banker magazine named us Future Bankers of the Year.
As a company, and through the individual efforts of our associates, we’re making a long-term social investment that is already paying major dividends in the communities where we do business. Each year, we contribute our time,
skills, technology and funds to organiza- tions that are improving opportunities for children at risk. For example, in 1998, we reaffirmed our commitment to our innovative $1.5 million Leadership Grants program which enhances the effectiveness of five service agencies in Richmond, Virginia, by furthering collaboration among them.
Our associates are help- ing them as volunteer tutors, mentors and com- puter consultants. We also joined a partnership to teach basic job skills to
high school and community college students. And we started a scholarship program that rewards improvement in math and science grades.
As we begin 1999, Capital One is stronger than ever. We’re building on four years of record earnings, record marketing investments and record levels of innovation. But in all our businesses, competition is fierce. We wel- come the challenge. And we intend to meet it in the future as we have in the past: by constantly reinventing ourselves, our products and our company.
Richard D. Fairbank
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
Nigel W. Morris
President and Chief Operating Officer
   Capital One has earned a reputation as a place to build a great career. Fortune magazine now ranks us as one of the 100 Best Companies to Work For in America.
  6
