   $11.3 FY ’00
$5.1* FY ’99
$2.2 FY ’98
  $9.4 FY ’00
$8.1 FY ’99
$7.0 FY ’98
To Our Shareholders,
This past fiscal year demonstrated more clearly than ever the key qualities that have enabled CSC to
(in billions)
ANNOUNCED MAJOR
NEW BUSINESS AWARDS
New global commercial outsourcing contracts were among the key contributors to our growth. Major new contracts included AT&T, United Technologies Corp., Enron Energy Services, Raytheon, General Electric, Equiva, San Diego County and Old Mutual.
that provides IT services to BHP and other commercial clients in Australia. With this acquisition, our Australian workforce of 5,700 makes us one of the most formidable IT services providers in the country.
*excluding IRS award
produce strong growth while our industry navigates the forces of change.
government employees to CSC. These men and women join an estimated 35,000 employees who also have come to us over the years through commercial outsourcing agreements and acquisitions.
Issues such as uncertainty around the impact of Y2K on information technology spending, and a tidal wave of energy—some well-directed, some pure noise—around e-business created new challenges for CSC and our clients last year.
These people represent a critical source of talent to us. We are committed to continuing on this path, offering opportunities to both commercial and federal employees as the outsourcing market thrives.
Our performance points to the durability and strength of CSC. Our ability to traverse the uncertain terrain of our industry stems from our diverse and broad-based range of services; our geographic span; and our culture, which allows us to quickly adapt to shifting demands.
Internationally, our results were solid as well. In Europe, we grew 12 percent,
Turning to our financial results for the year just ended, we reported revenue of $9.4 billion, an increase of 16 percent over the prior year. Net earnings before special items were $433 million, up 22 percent.
In Asia, our acquisition of CSA Holdings in Singapore was a catalyst for growth. We also entered into a strategic partnership with Hitachi to better position CSC for growth in the Japanese market.
Major new business awards announced during the year totaled an impressive $11.3 billion, more than double those of our previous fiscal year (not including a large U.S. Internal Revenue Service contractthatwasawardedtoCSCinfiscal1999,buthasnotbeenvaluedpublicly). Ofthoseawards, 21 major contracts were over $100 million each.
In Australia, we significantly increased our revenue and resources with the acquisition of the Australian operationsofGECapitalITS,aninformationtechnologysuppliertocommercialandgovernment organizations. In addition, in May 2000, we announced an agreement with Australian-based Broken Hill Proprietary Co. Limited (BHP), a global natural resources company, to provide a full range of consulting, systemsintegrationandoutsourcingservices. Aspartofthepact,CSCacquiredaBHPsubsidiary
(in billions)
Our U.S. federal government business also delivered excellent results, with revenue up eight percent over the last year. We expect the U.S. federal market to continue to be an important source of revenue as the government enlists the help of the private sector to adapt commercial best practices such as outsourcing.
A key acquisition on the domestic front was Nichols Research Corporation, a leading information technology services provider to the U.S. federal government, with strong expertise in supporting the Army and NASA. Our recent success winning a major award with the U.S. Army Aviation and Missile Command can be attributed in part to our Nichols acquisition.
We were pleased to be awarded the first major federal outsourcing contract in December 1999, calling for us to modernize the U.S. Army’s wholesale logistics business processes. We believe this contract sets the stage for more opportunities of this kind in the future. As part of the Army contract, we welcomed 300 former
In e-business, CSC’s revenue exceeded $700 million in fiscal 2000, more than 3.5 times the prior year. While e-business marks a major turning point in our industry, we are not reinventing our company around e-business. Over the course of more than forty years in the IT services and consulting business, we have seen many critical technology turning points: the advent of timesharing,
23
REVENUES
while other international revenue in Asia and Australia grew 81 percent, in part due to acquisitions, underscoring again the importance of geographic balance.

   $3.0
FY ’00
$2.6 FY ’99
$2.2 FY ’98
58,000
FY ’00
50,000 FY ’99
45,000 FY ’98
  the invention of the PC, the birth of reengineering. E-business is yet another. It is not the first upheaval in our industry. It is not the last.
In addition, a major key to our success with Net markets is our ability to forge strong partnerships and alliances with other e-business and industry leaders. Traditionally, our skill in partnering and assembling teams has been a strength on large, complex integration deals. Today, it’s a key ingredient for success in the new e-business world as well.
AuniquestrengthofCSCisourabilitytomaneuverandthriveamidchange. Inthe case of e-business, we are in the right place, at the right time, with the right skills, and the right resources.
Specifically, as more global companies embrace e-business as integral to their operations and as successful start-ups mature, the requirements for e-business success broaden. Issues such as innovation, speed, global scale, industrial-strength performance, full life-cycle support and the need for tangible business results are critical. These are precisely CSC’s strengths.
In the area of Web hosting, e-business is driving demand for outsourcing of both informationtechnologyinfrastructureandbusinessprocesses. Firmsseekingtouse Internet technologies are outsourcing their legacy systems, along with their newest, most mission-critical Internet applications. Hosting is the fastest-growing segment of the IT outsourcing market today. The Internet allows us to standardize our offerings
Our strategies for e-business leverage these strengths. We are focusing primarily on the business-to-business (B2B) market, which offers the promise of a single platform where organizations can coordinate the entire chain of commerce, enabling customers, suppliers and trading partners to quickly transact business. And these opportunities are not just limited to commercial organizations. For example, in San Diego County, we are helping an entire county government rebuild its systems –– creating a next-generation e-business technology infrastructure that allows the county to provide Web-based services to its clients. CSC is uniquely equipped
and leverage our skill and experience in managing mission-critical, highly secure data. Currently, we are in the process of opening hosting sites in the U.S., Europe and Australia, offering a full range of global services.
STOCKHOLDERS’ EQUITY
to provide complete, end-to-end solutions that integrate strategy with implementation and ongoing management.
Another constant is our dedicated workforce. I’d like to offer my thanks to our outstanding team of 58,000 employees by highlighting the diversity of challenges and opportunities they deal with at CSC each day. For example:
(in billions)
Two other areas of e-business hold particular promise for CSC: Net markets and Web hosting.
While our industry travels the challenging road to achieve true business-to-business connectivity, we’ve made a critical first step with the emergence of Net markets, which use the Internet to bring buyers and sellers together in real time. Right now, CSC is the Net markets leader, with more than 60 clients in more than a dozen different industries. Net markets may not represent huge megadeals to CSC; but they do give us the opportunity to advance the industry by furthering the technologies and standards required to support true business-to-business e-commerce.
■ At Goddard Space Flight Center, CSC scientists are helping NASA use the Internet to cut costs and simplify the way they control and communicate with spacecraft.
45
GLOBAL EMPLOYEES
While our marketplace undergoes dramatic change, there are some things we intend not to change: our focus on clients, our agility, our performance. We have built our reputation by treating each client uniquely and by tackling some of the toughest, most complex jobs in our industry.
That’s our value proposition –– and we believe it’s more essential than ever in a turbulent marketplace.
■ At the Pentagon and other U.S. Department of Defense locations, CSC security experts are monitoring and advising the DoD on computer virus attacks that could threaten our nation’s security.
■
In Spain, CSC systems integrators are developing a new financial system to help the Spanish postal service compete in a new deregulated world.

        ■ At Stapleton Airport in Denver, CSC systems engineers are installing a system for the FAA to help controllers make the most of runway space and thus more efficiently sequence airplane arrivals to reduce delays.
In millions March 31, 2000 Revenues $9,371
April 2, 1999
April 3, 1998
■ In New York, CSC health care specialists are helping a leading HMO use a CSC-developed Internet tool that lets providers, employer groups and members quickly handle transactions over the Web.
Income before taxes* 611 Net income* 403 Diluted earnings per share* 2.37
$8,111 535 356 2.12
$7,028 214 275 1.67
■ In Denmark, CSC outsourcing specialists are running the first Web-based tax filing system that enables Danish citizens to file tax returns online.
Working capital 782 Stockholders’ equity 3,044 Total assets 5,874
661 2,589 5,260
846 2,171 4,274
■ In San Francisco, CSC management consultants are helping a major petroleum company build a Web-driven virtual distribution network to help U.S. retailers buy and sell lubricants and diesel fuels.
* Fiscal 2000 and 1998 operating results above include special items.
A discussion of “Income Before Taxes,” “Net Income and Earnings per Share” before and after special items is included on pages 33–34 of this annual report. Computer Sciences Corporation’s fiscal year ends the Friday closest to March 31.
■ In Ohio, CSC insurance specialists are helping a leading property and casualty firm reach settlements in a Web-enabled claims operation.
■ And in Hong Kong, CSC banking experts are assisting a leading financial services firm expand by globalizing its information technology systems.
I hope you share our excitement and pride at CSC over the remarkablerangeoftasksweperformeachday. Wearewell positioned to continue bringing value to our clients and shareholders with superior IT solutions and to further enhance CSC’s role as a leader in information technology services.
Van B. Honeycutt Chairman, President
and Chief Executive Officer June 16, 2000
67
FINANCIAL HIGHLIGHTS
Number of employees 58,000
50,000
45,000
Fiscal Year Ended
