         LETTER TO STOCKHOLDERS
WE MAKE® TIRES FOR
  PEOPLE.
TO OUR STOCKHOLDERS:
The past year was one for the record books as Cooper ended 2012 with record full-year net sales of $4.2 billion—7 percent higher than 2011— and record operating profit of $397 million. The people of Cooper stepped up to the challenges in the global economy and the tire industry to perform at levels never before achieved. Our teams around the globe aligned with, executed, and delivered the goals of our strategic plan, a plan that has resulted in the positive transformation of our company’s business model. Today, our business model is stronger, more resilient and more sustainable, better positioning Cooper to drive value in the years to come. Employees throughout our organization have my sincere thanks for producing results that not only set company records, but also often outpaced the industry and peer companies in volume growth within key product categories.
As I look back on 2012, I cannot help but think about how the tire making process parallels what it takes for a tire company to deliver long-term value within the ever more competitive, globally expansive and technology-fueled tire business. While products and manufacturing processes vary, Cooper tires don’t leave the plant—whether in Rongcheng City, China or Tupelo, Mississippi—until they pass numerous quality checks. Along the way in the manufacturing process, there are tolerances and specifications our materials must meet, standards our processes must adhere to, and quality tests our finished products must surmount before they head out to the door to our customers.
Like the tires we make, the tire industry of today tests us in numerous ways. To borrow an iconic auto industry advertising line, this is ‘not your father’s tire business.’ While the tire industry is certainly mature, having been around for more than 160 years, it is a vastly different business today than it was even five years ago. The challenges are many, but so are the opportunities.
For Cooper, driving growth within an industry and a global economy where customers are looking for new ways to get an edge, where new competitors from around the world continue to enter the market, where the speed of technology demands constant innovation, and where upcoming government
regulations and requirements could be game-changers, 2012 was a proving ground. A proving ground that tested us, but also allowed us to demonstrate that the Cooper of today is capable of mastering the toughest challenges and delivering strong value to our stakeholders.
We met nearly all of the ambitious financial and performance goals set within our strategic plan of 2008, reaching many ahead of schedule.
          GOAL: Stockholder Value Creation
✓RESULT:
1st quartile stockholder value creation over last three years*
*Using the S&P 500 as a comparative base
2008 PLAN TARGETS
Sustainable Cost-Competitive Position and Improved Profitability: 7-8% Operation Profit
Top-Line Profitable Growth 6-7% Revenue CAGR
Orgainizational Capabilities
RESULTS 9% OPERATING
PROFIT 2012
8% CAGR
from 2007-2012
ERP deployment - North America Developing competencies (Six Sigma) Performance-driven culture
         
Of course, like all companies within our industry, we benefitted from lower raw material prices in 2012. Yet, we believe that it was a year of distinction for Cooper that demonstrated we can meet or beat the competition across a wide range of industry and global economic conditions.
Delivering innovative, high quality products is key to our success and central to our value proposition. During 2012, we continued to see strong consumer demand for tires such as the Cooper Zeon RS3-A and the Discoverer A/T3, which continued to take hold in the marketplace and earned significant third- party endorsements. In fact, the RS3-A is the tire selected by Ford Motor Company as original equipment on its 2013 Ford Focus Titanium and SE models. This represents Cooper’s first ever U.S. passenger car OE tire fitment and we are excited about the benefits of this new relationship. Our Ford agreement adds to OE work we are doing with our Roadmaster brand tires within the truck-bus radial segment in North America as well as OE passenger tire fitments in China.
We intend to remain primarily a replacement tire company—where we’ve built enduring customer relationships and see runway for further growth—yet we are pleased with the added momentum and channel diversity that this new OE customer brings.
One cannot talk about the tire industry in 2012 without addressing the September expiration of the special U.S. tariff on tires manufactured in China. We explained at the time that it would take some time for the full effects of the tariff expiration to emerge and the near-term effect would be additional variability in volumes. This was the situation we experienced as we closed out 2012 and we expect it could continue into the first quarter of 2013. Overall, we continue to believe we are well positioned to deal with these effects.
Raw material prices in 2012 demonstrated volatility as prices started the year at an elevated level and declined steadily through the end of the year with the full-year average index down 7% compared to 2011. However, on a longer term basis, we expect prices to generally increase as the global economy gains momentum.
Volatility in raw material pricing is a factor in our pursuit of alternative material sources that require innovative technology. In 2012, Cooper, along with partner organizations, received a $6.9 million grant from the United States Department of Agriculture to evaluate the U.S.-grown guayule plant as an alternative source of natural rubber.
We continued to reinvest in our business throughout 2012, with capital investments that were higher than historical norms, but necessary to maintain growth momentum. These investments included initiatives such as our ERP deployment, which will ultimately provide a seamless flow of information on a global basis in real time, greatly enhancing the efficiency of our operations. We also invested in the continued ramp-up of our tire manufacturing facility in Serbia, which we purchased in January 2012. This facility ended the year by producing its one millionth tire and was a factor, along with operations in China, in the 12% year-over-year sales growth our International segment achieved in 2012. In North America, we maintained vigilance in driving cost reductions and invested in automation, equipment and other enhancements while achieving a 4% sales increase. The increase was led by strong performance in premium passenger, light truck and truck-bus radial tires.
Once again, Cooper ended the year with a strong balance sheet. We closed 2012 with $352 million in cash. This strong financial foundation is important as we must reinvest in our business to continue to meet ambitious growth goals and deliver value to you, our stockholders.
Manufacturing Facilities
Clarksdale, Mississippi - bladders/mixing Findlay, Ohio - tires
Guadalajara, Mexico* - tires
Kruševac, Serbia - tires
Kunshan, China - tires
Melksham, United Kingdom - tires Rongcheng City, China* - tires Texarkana, Arkansas - tires Tupelo, Mississippi - tires
Distribution Centers
  Albany, Georgia Allentown, Pennsylvania Baotou, China Changchun, China Chengdu, China Chongqing, China Compiegne, France Corona, California Findlay, Ohio
Franklin, Indiana
Grand Prairie, Texas
Guadalajara, Mexico Guiyang, China Kruševac, Serbia Kunming, China Kunshan, China Lanzhou, China Liuzhou, China Madrid, Spain Melksham,
United Kingdom Milan, Italy
Münster-Breitefeld, Germany
Nanchang, China Ormalingen, Switzerland Rancho Cucamonga,
California Shijiazhuang, China Shanghai, China Stow, Ohio
Sumner, Washington Tangshan, China
Texarkana, Arkansas Tupelo, Mississippi Urumuqi, China Wuhan, China
Xi’An, China
Xiamen, China
Zhang Jiagang, China Zhengzhou, China
*Operations in Rongcheng City, China, and Guadalajara, Mexico are majority-owned joint ventures.

LOOKING FORWARD
 With the success of our 2008 strategic plan as a platform to build upon for driving value over the coming years, we have developed a next-level strategic plan that remains focused on the priorities that were at the center of our 2008 plan, but we have updated the specific goals and initiatives supporting those priorities.
Our 2013 initiatives in the North American segment focus on driving process efficiencies, continuous improvement and profitable growth. We will invest back into our operations with increased emphasis on automation and stay focused on efficiency and safety in our plants. In fact, in early 2013, our Tupelo tire manufacturing plant achieved two million work hours without a lost-time accident, the first of our U.S. facilities to reach this milestone.
We will continue to focus on channel and product mix with the goal of driving higher volumes in tires within premium categories. In addition, we will focus on being a stronger market force in certain major metropolitan markets throughout the U.S. and Canada where we believe our products are under-represented. Our efforts to expand our truck-bus radial tire business, which grew significantly in 2012, will continue into 2013.
In our International segment, we are looking to optimize and grow distribution including in Eastern Europe and Russia, and
passenger car radial tire distribution in China. We also plan to increase truck-bus radial tire distribution in China.
In both of our segments, we will grow house brands and continue to drive innovation and technology to keep new and exciting products in the pipeline. In fact, we are establishing a new Global Technology Center to concentrate and accelerate applied research and support existing regional Technical Centers in the U.S., Europe, and Asia.
Key to our future success will be efforts to leverage even further our global capacity to provide a high-quality, low-cost, near-sourced manufacturing footprint.
As we drive this step-change in our global capabilities, we will maintain our focus on increasing margin levels, reducing operating costs and improving cash flow.
Our management team, Board of Directors and employees around the world are committed to continuing the momentum we have established over the past five years and enabling a performance level that keeps Cooper among the top in value creation. Thank you for your continued confidence in our team and our strategic direction.
  Sales Offices
Compiegne, France Corona, California Findlay, Ohio,
Company headquarters Guadalajara, Mexico Madrid, Spain
Melksham, United Kingdom,
European headquarters
Milan, Italy Münster-Breitefeld, Germany Ormalingen, Switzerland Rongcheng City, China Shanghai, China
Asian headquarters Stow, Ohio
Technical Centers
Findlay, Ohio (2) Melksham, United Kingdom Pearsall, Texas
Shanghai, China
Cooper Service Stores
Findlay, Ohio Texarkana, Arkansas Tupelo, Mississippi
Roy Armes Chairman, Chief Executive Officer and President
Purchasing Office
Singapore, Southeast Asia
    