                                                           To Our Shareholders
1999 was a year of steady
growth and increasingly
profitable operation for
Coventry Health Care. It
was a year in which the final
pieces of our restructuring
plan were put into place,
providing a strong growth
platform for the coming year.
And it was a year that
underscored the wisdom of
our merger with Principal
Health Care, the results of
which include our steadily
improving performance, the
strengthening of our management team and our expanding potential for continued growth.
Net Worth and Tangible Net Worth
million, or $0.69 per diluted share, compared with net losses in 1998 of $11.7 million,
or $0.22 per share.
Our financial achievements are even more dramatic when compared with where we were just three years ago when the current manage- ment team came on board.
Operating revenues for the year ended December 31, 1999, for example, were $2.2 billion, more than double the 1996 figure of $1.1 billion. Since year-end 1996, cash and investments have increased from $168 million to $615 million. Long-term debt has decreased from $94 million to zero. Tangible net worth has grown from a negative $18 million to a positive $212 million and book value has gone from $3.04 to $8.12 per share.
Contributing to our solid financial base has been a concentrated effort to reduce expenses. As one example, we are in
the process of reducing the number of local
       in millions
      Net Worth
Tangible Net Worth
        $100
[$18]
1996
$118
$9
1997
$437
$141
1998
$480
1999
   $212
  Results of Operations
Notable among the financial results for 1999 was a return to profitability, with net income, including non-recurring items, rising to $43.4
 Brought to you by Global Reports

 Brought to you by Global Reports
customer service centers from 21 to 3 resulting in savings that will approach $7 million. We expect to achieve another $10 million in savings by spring 2000 through reductions in headcount and other economies.
We are similarly committed to maintaining pricing discipline, as reflected in an average commercial rate increase of 10% in 1999 and an additional increase of 8-10% projected for 2000.
While cost reduction remains a major goal, we are vigilant that savings not be achieved at the expense of customer service or quality.
Services to customers and providers, in fact, were upgraded in many areas during the year, notably by speeding up claims payments and cutting the response time to telephone inquiries dramatically.
Acquisitions
Our growth was also spurred by two acquisitions during the year.
In October, Coventry acquired Carelink Health Plans of Charleston, West Virginia, with membership of 58,000, making Coventry the largest such plan in the state.
In November, we vastly improved our position in Charlotte, North Carolina by acquiring the Kaiser Foundation Health Plan of North Carolina’s commercial
Cash & Investments in millions
4
$168 $240
1996 1997
$615 $615
1998 1999
membership in that market. Besides adding its 25,000 members, the Kaiser membership acqui- sition opened the doors to larger employer accounts, significantly improved our operating leverage and competitive position in the market and should add operating income of $3 to $4 million in 2000.
Also in 1999 we announced two transactions that have since been finalized. First, we further expanded our West Virginia presence by acquiring PrimeONE, adding another 18,000- members and expanding our West Virginia service area to cover the entire state.
The second transaction involved Prudential Health Care, a member company of Aetna U.S. Healthcare. We acquired their 11,800 member Medicaid business in St. Louis, strengthening our market leadership position in an area where we have proven to be successful.
The Managed Care Industry
While 1999 was a noteworthy and highly successful year for Coventry, the managed care industry continued to be the subject of

 Brought to you by Global Reports
1996 1997
1998 1999
Book Value
Per Common Share
delivering quality health care to the largest number of our citizens at costs they can afford.
Customer Service
One of the cornerstones on which the man- aged care industry was built is the simplification of the health care system, making such care easier to obtain and more affordable.
In the early days of health insurance cover- age, patients had to pay for doctor visits out of their own pockets and then seek reimbursement from their insurance providers, often involving some kind of paperwork.
Managed care made that process infinitely simpler by establishing contracts with doctors, enabling patients to pay those doctors a token
$3.04 $3.54 $7.42
$8.12
intense scrutiny by legislative bodies, by public interest groups and by the media. Class action litigation was instituted against several HMOs across the nation resulting in a great deal of publicity, much of it negative.
Questions were also raised in many quarters about patient rights, referral procedures, prescription drug availability, pricing and other concerns.
We take this criticism very seriously and recognize that some of the complaints are justified. Many others, however, are not, often arising from a lack of knowledge or a misinterpretation of the facts.
We find the accusation that managed
care companies put profits before patients particularly distasteful. It is simply untrue and does a great disservice to the overwhelming majority of payors who, like Coventry, see the well-being of our members as our first and highest priority.
While we know our industry can do better, it is our firm conviction that managed care remains the best vehicle now available for
amount, often as little as $5 or $10 for a visit, with the doctor’s office, rather than the patient, undertaking to do the paperwork.
Since that first giant step forward in the delivery and financing of health care, the man- aged care industry has continued to add new services and improve access to quality care, with no payor being more innovative in this area than Coventry.
Coventry’s achievements in providing quali- ty care to our members have, in fact,
5

                                              COVENTRY’S 13 STATE SERVICE AREA
 Markets
By State
Coventry’s service area includes counties in the following states:
North Carolina, Delaware, Georgia, Illinois, Iowa, Louisiana, Missouri, Nebraska, Kansas, Ohio, Pennsylvania, Virginia,
and West Virginia
Customer Servive Centers
★ Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania Harrisburg, Pennsylvania
★Newark, Delaware
   been well documented, most recently by Newsweek magazine. In its November 8, 1999 issue, the publication ranked HealthAmerica Pennsylvania, our largest health plan, as the best health plan in the state and the sixth best health plan in the entire nation.
Having always been committed to meeting the highest possible standards of quality in all our products and services, the vote of confi- dence represented by
such external and
impartial analysis is
gratifying and will spur
us on toward even
greater accomplishment
as we move forward.
This emphasis on service and quality is nothing more than sound business practice. By providing quality service to the
individual members, employers, brokers, physicians and hospitals who constitute our customer base, we increase their level of satisfaction, bolster loyalty and foster the long-term relationships which are basic to success, now and in the future.
Evidence of Coventry’s devotion to a high level of service, and the success it has engendered,
is visible in every customer group we serve.
 6
Brought to you by Global Reports

 Member Service
Toward the midpoint of
1998, Coventry undertook a
24-month initiative aimed at streamlining its customer
service. Among other things,
this initiative involved
consolidating various
operations, setting new
standards and incorporating the newest advances in technology.
Attesting to its success, claims today are paid 29% faster, and response time to telephone inquiries has been reduced by two thirds. At the same time, we have lowered the cost to process each claim significantly. To further improve ser- vice, in March, 2000, Coventry signed an agree- ment with GeoAccess to provide expanded online access and search capabilities to our provider directories.
Provider Service
Bolstering our continuing progress in making it easier for doctors and other healthcare providers to work with us, Coventry set a new precedent early this year by initiating the processing of claims, and similar transactions, via the Internet.
In February, 2000, Coventry signed an agreement with Healtheon/WebMD, the first end-to-end Internet healthcare company connecting physicians and consumers to the healthcare industry.
The agreement, covering the next three years, will initially allow Coventry to use Healtheon/Web MD’s Internet services to manage the electronic submission and processing of eligi- bility determination, referrals and authorizations, claims submission, claim status and reporting. Using this system, Coventry will ultimately be able to pay certain claims within 48 hours.
Under the agreement, our new partner’s
electronic transaction services will be rolled
out in phases. When the rollout is completed, Healtheon/WebMD services will be available to the entire Coventry network of 20,000 primary care and 50,000 specialty physicians.
While undoubtedly a major step forward, this agreement is only the beginning of Coventry’s venture into e-commerce and the eventual reconfiguration of our business as new technology becomes available.
Membership
in thousands, continuing operations
Brought to you by Global Reports
866
915 1357
1440
1996 1997
1998 1999
Employer and Broker Service
The small-group health insurance market, consisting of employers with 2 to 50 employees, is the fastest growing employer segment and a significant source of revenue for Coventry. The segment is primarily served through third party insurance brokers and agents. At present, Coventry provides managed care products and
7

 8
Brought to you by Global Reports
services to approximately 16,000 small group employers, representing 245,000 members.
To further improve our service to this impor- tant segment, Coventry, in February, 2000, signed a two-year agreement with Workscape, a leading application service provider, to offer an online Internet-based rate quoting system.
This new capability will make it possible to provide benefits information, generate cus- tomized proposals, register agents, complete medical questionnaires and applications, underwrite risk, calculate rates and enroll groups via the Internet.
Community Involvement
While our relationship with employers and members remains paramount, the relationship Coventry maintains with the communities in which we operate is nonetheless vital and will continue to be a major priority.
Community involvement for Coventry takes many forms.
Our Medicaid program, HealthCare USA, for example, uses a colorful mascot, Doc Bear, to reach out to children and teach them health habits that will contribute to a healthier and happier lifestyle as they grow into adulthood.
Group Health Plan in St. Louis set up a wide range of community activities including
Earnings Per Share-Diluted
Including non-recurring items
$1.00
$0.00
($2.00)
($1.87)
1996
$0.35 ($0.22) $0.69
1997 1998 1999
employer health fairs, a Juvenile Diabetes Walk, and a Fall Foot Drive as well as maintain- ing a Health Education Coordinator on staff to participate in employer health functions, pro- vide blood pressure testing and offer nutrition counseling. In the Western and Central regions of Pennsylvania served by our HealthAmerica plan, employees have demonstrated their commitment to their communities by volun- teering their time and energy for such worth- while activities as the American Red Cross CPR Day, Big Brothers/Big Sisters, the Carlisle/YMCA
Downtown Mile, the HealthAmerica Kid’s Run to benefit an area hospital, and the United Way.
In addition, all of our plans routine- ly participate in employer health fairs, combining health testing, preventive care and general health information in a festive atmosphere.
Coventry also serves its local com- munities through its investment in research. One of these research

                                                  projects, Senior Life Management, has as its aim to seek out alterna- tive, and more effective, means of delivering care to older citizens. Under this research program, a coordinated system is set up to manage the health of seniors by using comprehensive medical, edu- cational and health improvement interventions for seniors, be they in good health or chronically ill.
It is hoped that this research,
being conducted with 5000
Medicare members in our
Pittsburgh market, will demonstrate
the potential advantages of using non-traditional services such as transportation, telephone, social interactions and exercise as well as the advantages of increased drug com-
pliance and increased medical staff-to-patient ratios. If the results meet our expecta- tions, we plan to expand the system to include all our Medicare members.
Looking to the Future
New concepts in financing, globalization and, most notably, technology, have all conspired to make the way business is done today seem very different from how business was transacted even a few years ago.
I have just indicated how the Internet, as one example, is impacting our relationship with providers and brokers. I have no doubt that, in the months to come, it will transform our relationship with members and other customers just as dramatically.
Despite this and other changes, I believe the basic truth of business success remains the same; the businesses that succeed are the businesses that are good at what they do.
On the business side, we are moving forward with a solid and talented management team. We are debt-free, growing with increasing quarterly profits and are showing excellent cash flow results.
We have embraced new technologies and will be introducing new products that will underscore our reputation as innovators and address some of the managed care concerns expressed by elements of our society.
In short, I see a company that is financially sound, well managed and poised for an exciting and rewarding future. I look forward to sharing that future with you.
Sincerely,
Allen F. Wise
President and Chief Executive Officer
     Brought to you by Global Reports
9
