08 DOMINION RESOURCES, INC.
   EVERY DAY WE ARE COMMITTED TO OUR CUSTOMERS, OUR INVESTORS AND OUR PEOPLE
  THOMAS F. FARRELL II
CHAIRMAN, PRESIDENT AND CHIEF EXECUTIVE OFFICER

09 DOMINION RESOURCES, INC.
   DEAR INVESTORS
Every day Dominion delivers on our promises to provide reliable electric and gas service at reasonable rates and leverage business opportunities to add shareholder value.
In 2007, your company embarked on a long-term regulated growth plan to meet the heightened demand of our customers while remaining flexible to take advantage of new possibilities as they arise. Dominion has executed and will continue to execute that plan on time and on budget.
All told, we have spent billions of dollars to expand our electric and gas infrastructure throughout the mid-Atlantic. And, over the next five years, we plan to spend nearly $14 billion more for growth in assets with long-term contracts and in businesses whose returns are subject to federal and/or state oversight. Last year, and into the future, 80 percent to 90 percent of our operating earnings have and will come from these stable businesses.
APPALACHIAN OPPORTUNITY
Dominion has had good fortune to be in the right place.
Our company traces its ancestry to the Colonial era in Virginia, and we found our calling in the electric utility business in 1909. A merger with Consolidated Natural Gas (CNG) in 2000 brought to Dominion a century of valuable experience in the gas- production and gas-transportation areas of the Appalachian Basin.
While we will spend growth capital at our electric and gas utilities to provide service to new customers and businesses and enhance the reliability of those systems, new business opportunities lie in the Marcellus and Utica Shale regions of the Appalachian Basin. It is an area where we have done business since 1891 and where natural gas production is expected to more than double over the next 10 years.
Our century of excellent service in the area and our rock-solid reputation as a gas infrastructure company have earned us trust among producers and have put us in a good position to maximize our opportunities there.
We have been in the right place and have done the job well for more than 100 years. Combine new and exciting gas business development with the stable yet always growing Dominion Virginia Power utility, and you can expect (a) solid returns on your investment, (b) strong earnings per share growth and (c) commensurate increases in the dividend.*
FINANCIAL REVIEW OF 2013
Dominion is different not only because we have electric and gas businesses, but also because both sides of your company are growing.
Dominion Virginia Power is expanding to serve new customers and heavy data center load. And there is a dire need for more infrastructure where our natural gas businesses reside.
In 2013, Dominion earned $3.25 per share in operating earnings, up from $3.09 per share in 2012, and within our guidance range of $3.20 per share to $3.50 per share.** Earnings under Generally Accepted Accounting Principles (GAAP) in 2013 were $2.93 per share, up from 53 cents per share in 2012.
Operating earnings per share increased in part because of a regulated infrastructure growth plan we began in earnest in 2007. Also contributing to higher earnings
per share in 2013 were cost-control and cost-cutting measures.
* All dividend declarations are subject to Board of Directors approval.
** Based on non-GAAP Financial Measures. See page 22 for GAAP Reconciliations.
 
10 DOMINION RESOURCES, INC.
    “SAFETY IS THE MOST IMPORTANT VALUE.
WE WANT ALL EMPLOYEES TO RETURN HOME AFTER A DAY ON THE JOB WITHOUT INCIDENT. EVERY EMPLOYEE MUST TAKE PERSONAL RESPONSIBILITY FOR SAFETY TO ENSURE THAT NO ONE IS HARMED. ”
Our total shareholder return — the combination of one share of common stock’s price change over a year plus its dividend payout — ended 2013 at 29.7 percent, which barely beat that of the Dow Jones Industrial Average at 29.6 percent and was slightly less than that of the S&P 500, which returned 32.4 percent. The total shareholder return of our peers in the Philadelphia Stock Exchange Index (UTY) was 11.0 percent. In 2013, Dominion’s total return ranked second among that of the 20 utilities that are part of the UTY.
Last year Dominion returned $2.25 per share in dividends to shareholders,
a 6.6 percent increase from 2012. We paid out 69 percent of operating earnings per share, within the 65 percent to 70 percent payout target range set by the company’s board of directors in December 2012.*
SAFETY METRICS IMPROVE
Our growth opportunities arise from our base of operations — vibrant communities and savvy customers requiring state-of- the-art facilities, wires and pipes that can move electricity and natural gas seamlessly, without interruption.
Yet we cannot achieve targeted growth rates and meet market demand without the hard work, faithfulness and integrity of our 14,500 employees.
Whenever meeting with investors or potential investors in our company, I discuss Dominion’s four core values—safety, ethics, excellence and One Dominion, our term for teamwork.
We expect everyone at Dominion
to live these values each and every day. Indeed, an ethical company whose employees do their jobs safely and well not only is a less risky proposition for your hard-earned money but also bolsters our relationships with lawmakers, regulators, customers and other stakeholders.
Safety is the most important value. We want all employees to return home after a day on the job without incident. Every employee must take personal responsibility for safety to ensure that no one is harmed. Internally, we call this a drive to zero.
Companywide in 2013, Dominion recorded all-time bests for OSHA recordable and
lost time/restricted duty rates, reducing 2012 rates by 10 percent and 6 percent, respectively. Dominion East Ohio had its best safety performance in its 115-year history. And Dominion Virginia Power’s rate of lost-day incidents and serious injuries dropped to its lowest-ever level.
This performance, while outstanding, provides room for improvement in our drive to zero.
STRATEGIC HIGHLIGHTS
Your company’s attributes include its desirable location and its dedicated employees. Achieving desired results also includes a vision, a path forward — our multibillion-dollar, energy infrastructure growth plan.
Our desired results? Customer satisfaction and service reliability. Earnings-per-share growth. Dividend increases. Solid returns for you, our shareholders.
Dominion’s promise is an operating earnings mix consisting of 80 percent to 90 percent from businesses such as our electric and gas utilities and our natural gas interstate pipeline and storage system. In 2013, 84 percent of your company’s primary operating segment earnings were derived from businesses such as those.
Our sale of two merchant coal-fired power stations and our 50 percent ownership stake in a gas-fired facility helped us achieve that goal. The sale reduced commodity risk, and the company will use the proceeds— about $650 million after taxes, including cash tax benefits from the sale — to finance further growth in our regulated
and contracted enterprises.
In 2013, your company also took steps to provide more transparency and clarity in our regulated gas businesses — gas transmission pipeline and storage assets and natural gas distribution companies—by creating Dominion Gas Holdings, LLC, a subsidiary that, like Virginia Power, will have the ability to issue debt to finance maintenance and growth. Because the new entity will be filing financial information with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, investors will be presented a clearer picture of the overall financial performance of these operations.
  * See page 22 for GAAP Reconciliation of Operating Dividend Payout Ratio (non-GAAP) to Reported Payout Ratio (GAAP).

 11 DOMINION RESOURCES, INC.
      MARCELLUS AND UTICA SHALE
MARCELLUS AND UTICA SHALE PRODUCTION VS. INCREMENTAL PIPELINE CAPACITY TO EXTERNAL MARKETS*
Billion cubic feet per day (Bcf/d)
25 20 15 10 5 0
Future Pipeline Takeaway Opportunities
Marcellus Production**
Utica Production**
Incremental Firm*** Pipeline Take Away Capacity 9.4 Bcf/d
Potential Reallocation of Traditional Gulf to Appalachian Pipelines ~ 3.0 Bcf/d
* External markets include New England, Mid-Atlantic, South Atlantic, Gulf Coast, Midwest and Canadian markets.
** Wood Mackenzie, Fall 2013 natural gas long-term view.
*** Projects under construction or fully subscribed.
Pipeline capacity source, company websites and internal research revised Jan. 20, 2014.
PENNSYLVANIA
FARMOUT ACREAGE
    FUTURE
 PIPELINE
 TAKEAWAY OPPORTUNITIES
      2008 2009 2010 2011 2012 2013 2014 2015 2016 2017 2018 2019 2020 2021 2022 2023 2024 2025
 GROWTH PLAN UPDATE: MARCELLUS FARMOUT
• Agreements with CONSOL Energy and Triana Energy LLC to lease about 100,000 acres under Dominion’s gas storage fields.
• Payments to Dominion totaling about $200 million over the next nine years.
• Overriding royalty interest in any gas produced there.
• 250,000 dekatherms per day in firm transportation associated with the project.
UTICA SHALE DEVELOPMENT*
1000 800 600 400 200
0
JAN FEB MAR APR MAY JUNE JULY AUG SEPT OCT NOV DEC
2013 Data
* Due to the 2010 sale of our Appalachian E&P operations,
Dominion no longer has any significant gas and oil production properties.
OHIO
                                        WEST VIRGINIA
              Permitted Drilled Producing
   Number of Wells Bcf/d

 12 DOMINION RESOURCES, INC.
      CONSOLIDATED FINANCIAL HIGHLIGHTS
Year ended Dec. 31,
FINANCIAL RESULTS (MILLIONS)
Operating revenue
Operating expenses
Amounts attributable to Dominion:
Income from continuing operations, net of tax Loss from discontinued operations, net of tax Reported earnings
Operating earnings*
DATA PER COMMON SHARE
Reported earnings
Operating earnings*
Dividends paid
Market value (intraday high) Market value (intraday low) Market value (year-end)
Book value (year-end)
Market to book value (year-end)
FINANCIAL POSITION (MILLIONS)
Total assets
Total debt
Common shareholders’ equity Equity market capitalization
CASH FLOWS (MILLIONS)
Net cash provided by operating activities
Net cash used in investing activities
Net cash provided by (used in) financing activities
OTHER STATISTICS (SHARES IN MILLIONS)
Common shares outstanding–average, diluted Common shares outstanding–year-end Number of full-time employees
* Based on non-GAAP Financial Measures. See page 22 for GAAP Reconciliations. ** Recast to reflect Brayton Point and Kincaid as discontinued operations.
$
$ $ $ $ $ $ $
$
$
2013
13,120 9,804
1,789 (92)
1,697 1,881
2.93 3.25 2.25
67.97
51.92 64.69 20.02
3.23
50,096 22,776 11,642 37,615
3,433 (3,458)
93
579.5 581.5 14,500
$
$ $ $ $ $ $ $
$
$
2012**
12,835 9,977
1,427 (1,125) 302 1,774
0.53 3.09 2.1 1 55.62 48.87 51.80 18.34 2.82
46,838 21,486 10,568 29,842
4,137 (3,840) (151)
573.9 576.1 15,500
% Change
2.2% -1.7%
25.4% -91.8% 461.9% 6.0%
452.8% 5.2% 6.6% 22.2% 6.2% 24.9% 9.2% 14.5%
7.0% 6.0% 10.2% 26.0%
           OPERATING EARNINGS*
Dollars per Share
13 3.25
12 3.09 11 3.03 10 3.27
YEAR-END STOCK PRICE
Dollars per Share
13
12 51.80
2013 OPERATING EARNINGS MIX*
  64.69
84%
REGULATED**
16%
UNREGULATED
* Does not include Corporate and Other.
** The Regulated mix includes Electric Transmission, Electric Distribution, Utility Generation,
Gas Transmission and Gas Distribution.
    11
10 42.72
53.08
     09
3.34 09
38.92
     * Based on non-GAAP Financial Measures. See page 22 for GAAP Reconciliations. 2009–2012 recast to reflect Brayton Point and Kincaid as discontinued operations.

13 DOMINION RESOURCES, INC.
    “WE WILL CONTINUE TO DEVELOP LONG-TERM GROWTH PLANS THAT SERVE THE INTERESTS OF EACH OF OUR STAKEHOLDERS, WHILE CREATING JOBS IN OUR COMMUNITIES. ”
In further seeking to maximize the value of our gas assets, we announced plans to form a master limited partnership (MLP).
A commonly used financing vehicle in the natural gas industry, the MLP would include certain gas assets and allow the company to maintain operating control while raising capital by selling a portion of the limited partnership interests to public investors. We will have more to say about the process and which businesses we will contribute in 2014.
AGREEMENTS BENEFIT SHAREHOLDERS
Additional shareholder value will also
be derived from leasing approximately 100,000 acres of Marcellus Shale development rights underneath several of our natural gas storage fields in West Virginia to two gas producers — CONSOL Energy and Triana Energy LLC. Geological studies have proved the storage fields’ structural stability to withstand drilling far below them.
These farmout agreements are expected to result in payments to Dominion of about $200 million over the next nine years, with an additional overriding royalty interest in any gas produced there.
FINANCIAL OUTLOOK FOR 2014
The groundwork laid over the past few years has fostered Dominion’s enviable position among American gas and electric utilities. We achieved operating earnings growth of 5–6 percent in 2013.* Our total shareholder return ranked Dominion second of 20 utilities in our peer group. And we returned 69 percent of our operating earnings in dividends to you.**
We expect this growth to continue based on our plan to invest nearly $14 billion between 2014 and 2018 in energy infrastructure projects that make up our portfolio of diverse and growing business lines.
Our guidance for 2014 contemplates operating earnings in the range of $3.35 per share to $3.65 per share.*** And, contingent on quarterly declaration by the board, your company plans to raise the dividend rate from $2.25 per share in 2013 to $2.40 per share in 2014—a 6.7 percent increase that is expected to fall within our targeted dividend payout ratio of 65 percent to 70 percent of operating earnings per share.
NEW INFRASTRUCTURE COMES ONLINE
While reducing commodity risk through asset sales in 2013, we also invested about $2.5 billion in growth capital for energy infrastructure projects that we expect to begin serving our customers over the next decade. These outlays will also bolster our efforts to provide higher earnings per share in future years.
Every day, Dominion strives to meet our customers’ demands. In Virginia, North Carolina, West Virginia and Ohio, that means reliable utility service in all weather conditions, at all times. For our Dominion Transmission (DTI) customers — whether gas producers, shippers or end-user utilities — we must provide a steady flow of gas from point
A to point B, and have sufficient capacity to handle their needs.
So we are investing in new electric wires, substations, power stations, pipelines and related natural gas developments and upgrading existing energy infrastructure to help ensure service reliability and customer satisfaction today and decades henceforth.
Fundamentally, any expenditures we consider must satisfy a market need and benefit our customers, shareholders and company alike. For instance, the New Market Project, expected to come online in 2016 and cost about $160 million, will provide Marcellus gas supply to customers of two local distribution companies in New York state while producing solid returns for Dominion.
We will continue to develop long-term growth plans that serve the interests of each of our stakeholders, while creating jobs in our communities.
POWER STATIONS AND POWER LINES
In order to reliably serve our Dominion Virginia Power customers, we must continue building new power stations and power lines, while upgrading existing facilities. Over the next five years, we anticipate spending more than $8 billion for electric utility growth projects.
The regulatory environment in Virginia is important in light of this massive buildout.
The regulations provide balanced benefits for our company, our ratepayers and the Commonwealth of Virginia.
I am not sure you can point to another regulatory framework in the country allowing for fair returns on investment for the billions
  * Based on non-GAAP Financial Measures. See page 22 for GAAP Reconciliations.
** See page 22 for GAAP Reconciliation of Operating Dividend Payout Ratio (non-GAAP) to Reported Payout Ratio (GAAP).
*** See page 22 for GAAP Reconciliation of 2014 Operating Earnings Guidance.

14 DOMINION RESOURCES, INC.
   of dollars spent for new and improved infrastructure, while creating thousands of construction and permanent jobs, millions of dollars in additional tax revenue and stable, reasonable rates that have, for residential customers, increased only about 1 percent since 2008 and remain well below the national and regional averages.
MEETING DEMAND AT VIRGINIA POWER
In 2013 at our Virginia Power electric utility, we converted three small coal-fired power stations to use biomass, principally tree tops and branches that remain unused from timbering operations, as fuel. These three stations had become less economical over the past decade, running only a quarter of the time just five years ago. For a relatively small conversion price tag of about
$157 million, the plants provide a steady, stable, reliable, renewable form of power.
And more is needed, as demonstrated
in January of this year, when the utility had record winter demand and needed to import electricity from elsewhere. To help compensate for a longtime shortfall, we are building two highly efficient, round-the-clock-operating gas-fired stations. The $1.1 billion, 1,329-megawatt plant in Warren County, Va.,
is more than half complete and has
an expected in-service date of late 2014.
A similar-sized, $1.3 billion facility in Brunswick County, Va., is projected to come online in 2016. A coal-to-gas conversion at our Bremo Station, expected to enter service in 2014, maintains 227 megawatts and costs $53 million. Since January 2011, we have added about 1,200 net new megawatts of generating capacity to Dominion Virginia Power’s service area, enough to serve 300,000 homes.
The Brunswick station and a 500-kilovolt transmission line into southeastern Virginia are expected to offset the generating capacity loss from the planned shutdown of Chesapeake and Yorktown units totaling about 1,000 megawatts, and help to meet future electric demand in the region.
Skiffes Creek is also part of an expected investment of about $600 million per year over the next five years to modernize Dominion’s electric transmission system. The company plans to systematically rebuild
  ENVIRONMENTAL PROGRESS
Dominion Transmission is a partner in the U.S. EPA Natural Gas STAR program. In 2013 the company documented a reduction in methane emissions through implementation of five Best Management Practices. This is part of a companywide effort to reduce emissions across our electric production and gas transportation businesses.
COMMUNITY INVESTMENT
Each year Dominion contributes to educational, environmental, and basic human needs endeavors in the communities we serve.
In 2013, the Dominion Foundation gave $15 million to more than 1,400 organizations, and Dominion’s EnergyShare program helped 16,000 households stay warm in the winter and cool in the summer. Part of our commitment to community includes an effort to employ military veterans, who represented 22 percent of our new hires in 2013.
      
15 DOMINION RESOURCES, INC.
   the 500-kilovolt loop that serves as the backbone of our service area and improve critical substation security.
For the distribution network that serves homes and businesses, we have targeted upgrading some of our more vulnerable infrastructure. We recently completed a $20 million program to inspect and replace about 3,000 at-risk transformers, which reduced the number of transformer failures by 200 per year in both 2012 and 2013. And we have developed a $175 million per- year undergrounding strategy for distribution system hardening that will help minimize the effects of severe weather on our customers.
RENEWABLE PORTFOLIO GROWS
Recognizing the need for fuel diversity and for more renewable resources at Virginia Power, in late summer 2013 we sought and won the right to lease more than 100,000 acres off the Virginia coast for a possible wind farm. Although we are in the early stages of development, and have not committed to constructing the project, we are excited to demonstrate this new technology and determine the commercial viability of offshore wind turbines.
In addition, we have ramped up other renewable energy efforts, placing into service solar arrays in Connecticut, Georgia and Indiana and a fuel-cell facility, also in Connecticut. Together, they represent an investment of approximately $200 million. Each of these renewable facilities has long-term, fixed-price power purchase agreements with electric cooperatives and utilities in its region.
Over the next two years, we anticipate growing our fleet of contracted solar projects by nearly 250 megawatts. Dominion is in ongoing discussions with multiple parties to achieve this goal.
NATURAL GAS BUSINESS EXPANSION
For Dominion to reap the benefits of heftier gas production in the shales of the Appalachian Basin, we must expand our current system, build additional facilities to gather and process that gas, and move it to market. In the Utica, in particular, the “wet” gas contains heavy hydrocarbons known as natural gas liquids (NGL) that must be extracted before transportation
across interstate pipelines. So processing and fractionation—separating the NGL into their component parts for commercial uses — are essential. As are long-haul pipelines for transportation, and storage for when supplies outstrip local demand.
As new players enter the region, Dominion’s geographic advantage is enhanced by having constructed and operated such facilities for 123 years. We have been a pioneer, building one of the nation’s first interstate gas pipelines, the nation’s first extraction and fractionation plant, and one of the Appalachian Basin’s first underground storage fields.
Indeed, ours has been a history of “innovation, ingenuity and accomplishment”— words spoken in 1979 by one of my predecessors, former CNG chief Jack Tankersley — words that continue to be true today.
PROJECTS OPEN UP NEW MARKETS
From 2014 to 2018, Dominion plans to spend about $2.1 billion on projects that open up new markets for gas producers by facilitating their products’ transportation. In 2013, we also spent $170 million to replace approximately 203 miles of aged bare steel pipe at Dominion East Ohio, a steady investment that will continue for more than a decade.
To support Marcellus production,
in 2013 we brought into service two projects that move gas to markets or storage in the Northeast. At a combined cost of $84 million, the new pipelines and compressor and metering stations can transport the equivalent of 362 million cubic feet per day of natural gas produced in the Marcellus Shale.
Overall, since mid-2012, new DTI pipeline projects have increased send-out capacities from Appalachian Basin gas fields by about 1.2 billion cubic feet per day.
In 2014, we intend to bring online new gas developments that will increase regional pipeline capacity to move an additional 600 million cubic feet of produced gas per day — and add 7.5 billion cubic feet of natural gas storage. Three projects — Allegheny Storage, Natrium to Market and Western Access—require approximately $250 million in capital spending.

 16 DOMINION RESOURCES, INC.
   DOMINION FINANCIAL CHARTS
TOTAL RETURN COMPARISON Percent / Through Dec. 31, 2013
TARGETED DIVIDEND INCREASE*
Dollars Per Share
2.11 2.25 2.40* 1.83 1.97
10 11 12 13 14
* All dividend declarations are subject to Board of
  Dominion
124.33
70.56 29.65
1 Year Total Return
Source: Bloomberg
S&P 500
128.04
56.70
GROWTH PLAN BENEFITS COMMUNITIES
Dow Jones Utility UTY
64.32
11.04 31.59
5 Year Total Return
53.16
             12.74 37.08
 3 Year Total Return
32.36
                     INFRASTRUCTURE INVESTMENT
Dollars in Billions
Cumulative Planned Growth Capital Expenditures*
Directors approval.
CLEANER AIR IN VIRGINIA
Percent / Projected emissions reduction*
 Growth:
Construction Jobs:
Local Property Tax Revenue:
$27.6 billion*
28,254
$519 million
SO2  NOx
 Hg (Mercury)
     12.2 9.5
6.8
13.8
0 −20 −40 −60 −80 −100
       3.8
14 15 16 17 18
* All planned expenditures are preliminary and may be subject to regulatory and/or Board of Directors approvals.
MARKET CAPITALIZATION
Electric & Gas Utilities (by NYSE ticker symbols) Billions of Dollars
50 40 30 20
10 0
Figures are estimated growth capital expenditures, construction jobs and local taxes from 2007–2018.
* All planned capital expenditures are based on the capital expenditure plan reviewed and endorsed by Dominion’s Board of Directors in late 2013. Dominion undertakes no obligation to update this information to reflect plan or project-specific developments, including regulatory developments, or other updates until the next annual update of the plan. Actual capital expenditures may be subject to the Board of Directors approval and/or regulatory approval and may vary from these estimates.
−85% NOx −94% SO2 −95% Hg
     00 02 04 06 08 10 12 13 15 20
 * 2013 Hg data is estimated. Actual data available July 2014.
   37.6
DOMINION RANKS SECOND
IN MARKET CAPITALIZATION RELATIVE TO TOP U.S. ELECTRIC & GAS UTILITIES
                            DUK D NEE SO EXC AEP SRE PPL PCG PEG ED EIX XEL FE NU DTE ETR AES CNP WEC NRG AEE CPN CMS SCG PNW LNT ITC POM
 Source: Bloomberg (as of Dec. 31, 2013).

17 DOMINION RESOURCES, INC.
    “DOMINION HAS EARNED TRUST AND BUILT A STURDY REPUTATION FOR INNOVATION
AND ACCOMPLISHMENT AMONG OUR CUSTOMERS, REGULATORS, FINANCIAL ANALYSTS AND PEERS.
”
Returns for such gas storage and transmission assets are regulated by state and federal commissions.
Dominion also has brought online the Natrium processing and fractionation facility in Marshall County, W.Va.
We have contributed the plant, which can process 200 million cubic feet of gas and fractionate 36,000 barrels of NGL daily,
to Blue Racer Midstream, LLC, a joint venture between Dominion and Caiman Energy II, LLC.
The Blue Racer joint venture, which focuses on Utica infrastructure, expects to put into service additional Utica natural gas processing facilities — Natrium II in West Virginia and Berne in Ohio—in 2014, capable of processing 400 million cubic feet of gas per day. Blue Racer has entered into agreements totaling more than 300,000 dedicated acres, which should be enough at full production to support both Natrium II and Berne.
COVE POINT PROJECT CONTINUES
For producers seeking new markets for their gas, LNG export facilities provide foreign markets for them.
The Cove Point liquefaction project in Lusby, Md., at an anticipated cost of $3.4 billion to $3.8 billion, would be Dominion’s largest in a generation.
For Dominion, the Cove Point project breathes new life into the facility. Long-term terminal service agreements with an affiliate of Sumitomo Corp., of Japan, and GAIL Global (USA), of India, give Cove Point additional opportunity and create a steady stream of income for Dominion and its shareholders whether or not the facility is in use. This project also would extend the life of the facility at least an additional 15 years.
Moreover, it would produce tangible benefits—a balance-of-trade reduction
in America’s favor; new jobs, economic activity and revenue for Maryland and Calvert County; international markets for gas producers; and a regular, clean supply of natural gas for Tokyo Gas, Kansai Electric Power Company and GAIL utility customers that will help to power the Japanese and Indian economies for years.
* All dividend declarations are subject to Board of Directors approval.
Before your company can begin construction, we continue to await permits from the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission and the Maryland Public Service Commission.
We aim to break ground in 2014 and place the liquefier into service in late 2017.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR INVESTMENT
Our corporate roots are anchored in Virginia and in the gas-producing Appalachian Basin, where we have served our customers reliably and well for generations.
Over those years, Dominion has earned trust and built a sturdy reputation for innovation and accomplishment among our customers, regulators, financial analysts and peers.
An investment in Dominion recognizes growth opportunities along several business lines — electric and gas. You can expect us to use our advantages and those opportunities to leverage earnings-per-share growth, solid shareholder returns and increasing dividend payouts.*
Every day, our employees acknowledge your commitment to the company.
We want to ensure that your decision
to invest in Dominion was wise, but we also want you to believe in what we do. We provide products — that no one can live without — safely, efficiently and cost- effectively, with minimal impact to the environment and with maximum benefit to the communities where our employees and customers live, work and raise their families.
Once again, thank you for your continued investment in Dominion.
Sincerely,
Thomas F. Farrell II
Chairman, President and CEO
   