A New Dean. A New Day.
Dear Fellow Shareholders:
On December 21 of last year, we announced the completion of our merger with Dean Foods Company. The announce- ment marked the end of a year of hard work and focused dedication for the employees of both companies who made the transaction a reality. It also marked the realization of our vision of creating a truly national dairy company with the scale and scope to deliver unprecedented value to our customers, consumers, shareholders and employees.
More importantly, it marked the beginning of a new era for our company. With this transaction, we transformed our company into not just the nation’s leading dairy company, but one of the leading food and beverage companies in the country. I believe that the value-creating opportunities generated by this merger make our future one of the most promising in the food and beverage industry today.
In addition to completing the transaction, we also had an impressive year operationally. Despite the weak economic environment, record high raw material prices and the unavoidable distraction caused by our merger preparations, our operating units met their goals. I am proud of our performance in 2001, and believe it once again demonstrates the extraordinary level of talent, discipline and commitment of our management teams.
We also continued throughout the year to deliver on our commitment to innovate. In May 2001, we announced an agreement with Procter and Gamble to launch and market Folgers® JakadaTM, a chilled coffee drink made from Folgers coffee and lowfat milk. We began the product rollout in January 2002, and initial reactions have been positive. We also completed several brand extension projects during the year, including the introduction of Hershey’s® single-serve milk-
shakes and new Coffee Latte flavored Sun Soy® soymilk.
Now we are intently focused on delivering on the promise that this merger holds, and are already well
underway with our integration efforts. Our progress to date has been better than expected and we look forward to continuing to report on our integration
progress throughout the year.
Net Sales
(in billions)
  $7.00
6.00
5.00
4.00
3.00
2.00
1.00
$6.23
    $5.76
   $4.48
         2
1999 2000 2001
  
  This year, and over the next several years, our strategy will be:
■ To Be Our Customers’ Supplier of Choice. We intend to maintain and extend our leadership position in the dairy case by continuing to provide our customers with excellent quality, service and value. We intend to leverage our unique capabilities, including our unparalleled refrigerated “direct store delivery” system, to grow with our customers and increase our revenues.
■ To Deliver on Our Synergy Targets. We have promised annual cost savings synergies as a result of the merger of at least $60 million in 2002, increasing to at least $120 million by the end of 2004. We intend to achieve these synergies by vigorously pursuing economies of scale in purchasing, product development and manufacturing, and by eliminating duplicative costs.
■ To Invest in and Build Upon our Growth Platforms. Innovation will be the key to growing our sales and our profitability over time. Therefore, we intend to invest in and build upon our largest growth platforms, including beverage enhancers, such as coffee creamers; food enhancers, such as refrigerated dips and salad dressings; single-serve dairy-based refrigerated beverages; and functional beverages, including soymilk and lactose-reduced milk.
■ To Rationalize Our Asset Base. We intend to carefully examine our portfolio of assets and businesses and to divest non-core businesses that do not fit into our long-term business strategy, and sell or close plants with overlapping markets or excess capacity.
■ To Wisely Invest Our Cash. In addition to investing in our growth platforms, we intend to continue to invest our capital where returns are greatest, including acquisitions in our core lines of business and reductions of debt.
Diluted Earnings Per Share
As always, I am very grateful to all of our 30,000 employees for their individual contributions toward making our company a success, and I thank you, our shareholders, for your continued investment in and support of the new Dean Foods.
I look forward to reporting another year of outstanding results. Sincerely,
Gregg L. Engles
Chairman of the Board
and Chief Executive Officer
(before non-recurring items)
 $3.98
    $4.00 3.50 3.00 2.50 2.00 1.50 1.00 0.50
$3.86
 $3.37
        2001
1999 2000
3
 