           Dear Shareholders,
Fiscal 2012 was an exciting year of record performance, as well as innovation and creativity, at The Walt Disney Company. For the second year in a row Disney achieved record net income, revenue, and earnings per share. In fiscal 2012, net income for our shareholders was a record $5.7 billion, an increase of 18% over last year, and revenue was a record $42.3 billion, up 3% from last year. Diluted earnings per share increased 24% to a record $3.13.
Our success was driven by improved results in each of our businesses and reflects the strength of our entire portfolio. It’s also the result of our long-term strategy and the significant investments we’ve made over the last several years to ensure that we continue to find new ways to capture the imagination of millions with entertainment experiences that exceed expectations and become cherished memories.
We have built an amazing collection of some of the world’s best media brands – Disney, ESPN, ABC, Pixar, Marvel, and now Lucasfilm – that provide enormous opportunities for us to continue to create high-quality content and unparalleled experiences. In a world cluttered with a growing number of entertainment choices, people look for the quality brands they know and love. And today, whether they’re looking for the best in sports, television, or family entertainment of any kind, hundreds of millions of people are looking to our company and its wonderful array of high- quality entertainment.
Our remarkably successful acquisitions of Pixar and Marvel, in particular, have proven our unique ability to nurture strong brands and expand fantastic creative content to its fullest potential and maximum value. Pixar also reinvigorated our animation, and we’re seeing a tremendous creative resurgence as a result. Building on the success
of Tangled, Disney’s Wreck-It Ralph has drawn great reviews as well as record audiences. Wreck-It Ralph delivered the highest grossing opening weekend in Disney Animation history and also became the 75th Disney film to cross the $100 million domestic box office threshold, with more than $175 million to date.
Each of our strategic acquisitions has generated tremendous new opportunities and creative potential across our entire company, and we are thrilled to add Lucasfilm and its beloved Star Wars franchise, with its universe of more than 17,000 characters, inhabiting several thousand planets, spanning 20,000 years. Star Wars offers infinite inspiration and opportunities, and we’re already moving forward on a new feature film to continue the epic saga. Star Wars Episode 7 will be in theaters in 2015, with more feature films planned – along with television programming, games and merchandise, and an expanded Star Wars presence in our parks around the world.
Over the last seven years we have focused on three key strategic priorities that have been critical to our success: creating exceptionally high-quality content for families, making that content more engaging and accessible through the innovative use of technology, and growing our brands and businesses in markets around the world. And this has been another year of great achievement for our businesses in these key areas.
On December 16th, Walt Disney Imagineering (WDI) celebrated 60 years of incomparable creativity. Originally founded to bring Disney’s great storytelling to life with immersive experiences in ways that had never even been imagined before, WDI was the genesis of our parks and resorts business around the world. And 2012 saw the opening of some of WDI’s finest work yet – including the phenomenal new Cars Land at Disney California Adventure, which completed the transformation of that park into a worthy neighbor to Disneyland and an extraordinary experience
in its own right. We also launched our fourth cruise ship, the incredible Disney Fantasy, and opened two new areas in Hong Kong Disneyland, along with the first phase of our historic expansion of Fantasyland in Walt Disney World to take storytelling in this iconic location to a whole new level. This year we made significant progress toward our goal of opening our first Disney destination in mainland China, and our Imagineers continue the development and construction of our Shanghai Disney Resort to bring our vision to life.
The Walt Disney Studios smashed global box office records with Marvel’s The Avengers, the year’s #1 hit as well as the third-highest grossing film of all time, with more than $1.5 billion􏵎 􏰭􏰾􏵐􏵑 􏵒􏵓􏵔􏰾􏵕 􏵍􏵓􏵖􏵑􏰾¢􏵗􏱀􏵓¡􏵐􏵘􏵙􏵖 Brave, Disney’s Frankenweenie, and Walt Disney Animation Studios’ Wreck-It Ralph demonstrated the creative excellence and rich
1
January 2013

diversity of our animation efforts. Each of these movies earned both a Golden Globe and an Oscar nomination for the year’s best animated feature, something we are obviously quite proud of. We are also incredibly proud to distribute Steven Spielberg’s Lincoln, which premiered in November to sold-out crowds and critical acclaim and also earned 12 Oscar nominations, including a nod for best picture of the year. Together these films contributed to a record year for our studio at the domestic box office.
In 2013 we’ll release Marvel’s Iron Man 3 in May and Thor: The Dark World in November. Disney’s fantastical
Oz The Great and Powerful will whirl into theaters in March, and in July superstar Johnny Depp will saddle up in
The Lone Ranger􏵎 􏰰􏰾􏵙􏵘􏰾 􏵐􏵔􏵖􏵚 􏵔􏵚􏵚􏵛􏵓􏵑􏰿 􏱁􏵚􏵘 􏵐􏵘􏵜 􏵝􏵚 􏵍􏵓􏵖􏵑􏰾¢􏵗􏱀􏵓¡􏵐􏵘􏵙􏵖 Monsters University in June, and Frozen, based on Hans Christian Andersen’s The Snow Queen and predicted to be the “coolest” comedy-adventure to ever hit the big screen, will be in theaters in November. We’ll end the year with Saving Mr. Banks, the story behind one of our most beloved classics, Mary Poppins, starring Tom Hanks as Walt Disney.
On the stage, Disney productions continue to wow audiences and critics alike. Disney’s new smash hit musical, Newsies, has played to packed houses since its March debut, breaking Broadway box office records to turn a profit faster than any previous Disney production and earning two Tony Awards in the process. Meanwhile, Peter and the Starcatcher earned another five Tony Awards, The Lion King celebrated its 15th anniversary by officially becoming the highest grossing show in Broadway history, and fans around the world got a chance to see new productions of Mary Poppins, including the first-ever performance in Spanish.
Technology remains one of our key priorities because it is transforming virtually every part of our business. As consumers change the way they use media and interact with the world around them, they create even more opportunities for us to connect and engage them in new ways.
In 2012, we re-imagined our online presence with the launch of the new Disney.com. It’s the digital gateway for all things Disney, designed with the next generation of Disney fans in mind, offering a rich experience for users that is consistent as they move from one platform to another. During 2012, Disney’s Where’s My Water? became the #1 mobile game in 96 countries, and the various versions of the game have been downloaded more than 100 million times. Fiscal 2012 was actually a rather transformative year for our interactive business. We launched five #1 mobile games and also had tremendous success with our first branded social game, Marvel: Avengers Alliance, which garnered critical acclaim and millions of players worldwide. And 2013 promises to be even more exciting as we reinvent the way video games tell stories with the highly anticipated launch of Disney Infinity, an extraordinary new gaming platform that lets people play with all of the Disney properties any time, any place, across devices to create their own unique gaming adventures.
We’re also incredibly proud of the continued success of our broadcast and cable networks. ESPN remains the world’s undisputed leader in sports programming, bringing more sports coverage to more people in more ways than ever before. Whether sports fans are watching NFL games, Wimbledon, the NBA, the Indy 500, Major League Baseball, college sports, or sports news – on television, online, or on a hand-held device – most of them watch ESPN. The revolutionary WatchESPN service now allows fans in more than 46 million U.S. homes to watch ESPN online, on-the-go from their tablets and mobile devices, and through Xbox.
ABC delivered three of the fall season’s top ten scripted series, including Modern Family, the #1 comedy on television; Grey’s Anatomy, television’s top-rated broadcast drama; and Once Upon a Time, a breakout hit in its second season. Good Morning America officially became the country’s top morning show, and ABC News and our ABC-owned stations did stellar work covering the year’s most important events. From the 2012 election to the devastation of natural disasters, these teams told the stories that mattered in ways that revealed the power, importance, and humanity behind them.
In 2012 Disney Channel took the top spot among kids 2-11 for the first time ever, and continued its winning streak as the #1 network among kids and tweens in the U.S. Disney Channel delivered the top three TV series among kids 2-11 for the year, as well as the top six shows among kids 6-11, and the top three shows among tweens (9-14). Building on the successful Disney Junior programming block on Disney Channel, in March we launched a 24-hour Disney Junior channel in the U.S. for preschoolers. Disney Junior content is a big hit with these viewers, who have made
Doc McStuffins cable’s top-rated show and Sofia the First: Once Upon a Princess cable’s highest rated telecast of all time among this young audience.
2

Disney Channel has been a touchstone for our brand in homes around the world, introducing Disney to new markets with each new channel we launch. On New Year’s Eve 2011 we launched our first free-to-air Disney Channel in Russia, reaching more than 40 million homes, or approximately 75% of Russian viewers. We followed that success in January 2012 with the launch of a free satellite Disney Channel in Turkey, expanding our reach from 1.5 million homes in that country to 11 million. We now have 108 Disney Channels in 34 languages reaching more than 426 million homes in 166 different markets around the world. When you add the extended reach of our partners around the world, Disney and Marvel branded kids television content is now available in almost one billion homes.
As the world’s largest licensor, Disney is able to extend our storytelling beyond the screen, taking our beloved characters into the daily lives of millions of people. A wide array of merchandise based on some of the world’s most iconic franchises such as Mickey Mouse, Disney Princesses, Cars, and Marvel’s The Avengers is available in innovative online and retail environments that continue the Disney experience, and take fans even deeper into the stories they love. Disney is also the world’s leading children’s publisher, using digital technology to create dynamic new reading experiences. In fiscal 2012, we launched a line of digital learning opportunities, based on our successful Disney English Learning Centers in China, to help parents everywhere use their children’s favorite characters to share their love of learning. We also expanded our growing Disney Baby brand across North America and are poised to grow it internationally in the coming year.
Our high-quality content translates into new businesses and new markets around the world, and we continue to see enormous growth potential in emerging countries. There is a rapidly growing middle class in these markets, with rising disposable income, and a desire for the kind of family entertainment Disney creates. In addition to continuing
to expand our presence in both China and Russia, this year we also made our largest investment in India to date, acquiring UTV to become India’s leading film studio and TV producer. The deal also added six of the country’s most popular entertainment, news, and film channels to our portfolio, so we’re now one of India’s premier broadcasters as well, reaching more than 100 million viewers every week. The UTV deal also positioned us as a significant player in the digital media space, thanks to Indiagames, the number one mobile gaming company in this market.
We believe that acting responsibly is an integral part of our brand, and are committed to being a good corporate citizen around the world. We published our first Corporate Citizenship report in 2008, and in 2012 we added specific, quantifiable targets to measure our progress in a variety of areas, from reducing our environmental impact and ensuring respectful workplaces to promoting the well-being of kids and families. In June we continued our partnership with parents to make healthier living easier and more fun for families, and became the first major media company to set standards for food advertising on programming targeted to kids. Disney took the first step in this direction in 2006, with our landmark nutrition guidelines, and we are proud to continue to lead the industry forward.
We are also proud of our legacy of supporting those who serve our country, and are committed to continuing
that effort. In March we launched Heroes Work Here, a company-wide effort to support U.S. veterans and military families. The initiative included assistance to veterans transitioning from active service to civilian life, public service announcements on our broadcast and cable networks, and a commitment to hire at least 1,000 military veterans – a goal I am very pleased to note we have already surpassed.
By all accounts and any measure, 2012 was an extraordinary year for The Walt Disney Company, and we are well positioned for continued growth and success in the new year. Our achievements are a testament to the commitment and tireless work of our incredibly talented employees around the world. The strength of our company truly does come from the character and integrity of our people, and I am grateful to have such amazing men and women at Disney.
On behalf of everyone at Disney, I thank you for your continued support and confidence. You can count on us to continue creating fantastic family entertainment and doing what it takes to deliver extraordinary experiences and create shareholder value.
 Robert A. Iger
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer The Walt Disney Company
3
