A Look Beneath the Surface Reveals Our Long-term Strategy
DEAR FELLOW SHAREHOLDERS: By many measures, 2003 was the best year in Devon’s history. We increased oil and gas production 21%, setting an all-time record. Higher production and stronger prices drove 2003 revenues up 70%, to a record $7.4 billion. Devon’s marketing and midstream operations also delivered their best results ever, contributing $286 million to operating margins. Net earnings climbed to $1.7 billion or $8.07 per diluted share—the
highest levels in Devon’s history. We finished the year with proved reserves of more than two billion equivalent barrels, yet another record.
We also had a very good year in 2003 from an operational perspective. We drilled 1,884 successful development wells and 232 exploratory discoveries. One of those discoveries, St. Malo in the deepwater Gulf of Mexico, confirmed a major new hydrocarbon trend. On the development front, we increased production from the Barnett Shale, already the largest natural gas field in Texas, by more than 20%. We launched a multi-year, heavy oil project in Canada with the potential to add 300 million barrels of new oil reserves. Outside North America, we added substantial production volumes in West Africa and China.
The record results of 2003 reflect one of our most important accomplishments of the year—our merger with Ocean Energy. Devon merged with Ocean on April 25, 2003, following overwhelming approval by the shareholders of both companies. Former Ocean shareholders received 74 million Devon common shares in exchange for their Ocean shares.
The Ocean merger enhanced our production profile. Ocean brought development projects at Nansen/Boomvang and Zia in the deepwater Gulf of Mexico and the Southern Expansion Area of Zafiro in Equatorial Guinea. Production from these projects supplemented Devon’s 2003 production growth from the Barnett Shale in north Texas and our Panyu project in the South China Sea. On a pro forma combined basis, Devon and Ocean increased 2003 production by 5.5% over 2002. We expect to deliver healthy production growth again in 2004—without the benefit of acquisitions. The deepwater Gulf of Mexico development projects at Red Hawk and Magnolia, described elsewhere in this annual report, are scheduled to commence production in the second half of
2004. Devon’s share of these projects is expected to bring approximately 20 thousand equivalent barrels per day of new production.
Beyond this immediate production growth, the Ocean merger also brightened Devon’s longer-term outlook. Ocean focused on offshore exploration. Through the merger, Devon acquired many talented oil and gas professionals and fortified our exploration inventory. The Ocean assets bolstered Devon’s already extensive deepwater Gulf of Mexico acreage position. We now hold more than a million net acres in the deepwater Gulf, the most of any independent. Previous Ocean
   Total Revenues
($ Billions)
Strong oil and gas prices and record production drove 2003 revenues ahead 70% to $7.4 billion...
Net Cash Provided by Operating Activities
($ Billions)
    ...and allowed Devon to more than double net cash provided by operating activities to $3.8 billion.
 2 Devon Energy 2003 Annual Report
1.1
2.6
0.5
1.6
2.9
4.3
1.9 1.8
7.4
3.8

 􏰀 LARRY NICHOLS Chairman and CEO
 Beneath the Surface 3
  deepwater discoveries at Merganser and Vortex await development and should add reserves and production in the future. Ocean also brought a large inventory of high- potential exploratory blocks offshore West Africa. During 2004 we will test several of these promising international prospects.
Building for the Long Run
Including the 550
million-plus equivalent
barrels acquired in the
Ocean merger, Devon replaced 321% of 2003 production. We closed the year with 2.1 billion equivalent barrels of proved oil and natural gas reserves. We incurred capital costs, including acquisitions, of $7.9 billion. This resulted in an all-sources cost of $10.82 for each added barrel of reserves. While these 2003 finding and development costs are above industry norms and Devon’s historical results, a look beneath the surface reveals our long-term strategy.
During the last three years we have completed three major mergers and acquisitions: Ocean Energy, Mitchell Energy and Anderson Exploration. Each of these companies had significant development projects that Devon assumed. In 2003, we invested $900 million in developing already proved reserves. Simultaneously, we have stepped up our investment in large, multi-year projects. These include a significant exploration effort in the deepwater Gulf and offshore West Africa as well as long-term investments in Canada. In total,
we invested about $500 million in 2003 on long cycle-time projects.
Most of these projects are designed to provide growth beyond 2004. While these development projects and long-term investments drive up our near-term finding costs, they position Devon to benefit in the future. Devon is now the largest U.S.-based independent oil and gas producer. Our arrival to this position coincides with one of the strongest periods for oil and gas prices in history.
This is driving our earnings and cash flow and allowing us to make these investments for the long run. And we are confident that as these longer-term investments begin to add new reserves and production, they will extend our track record of profitable growth.
Deepwater Exploration Gaining Momentum
Over the last five years we have enhanced our deepwater Gulf exploration capacity by integrating the deepwater leases, seismic libraries and technical capabilities of several companies. Our 2003 discoveries increase our excitement about the deepwater Gulf. St. Malo, in the Walker Ridge area of the central Gulf, logged more than 450 net feet of pay. This well, in which Devon has a 22.5% working interest, is Devon’s second discovery in the emerging lower Tertiary trend. Our first discovery in the trend was Cascade,
continued on next page
Strategy.
Beneath the Surface

also in the Walker Ridge area. We plan to drill follow-up wells to both St. Malo and Cascade in 2004. If these confirmation wells meet expectations, we will begin to plan for their development. While the discoveries at Cascade and St. Malo have the potential to be meaningful on a stand-alone basis, their significance to Devon is far greater. Through acreage acquired in acquisitions, joint ventures and lease sales, Devon has assembled a large inventory of lower Tertiary prospects. Our early commitment and involvement with this play has provided us an outstanding competitive position.
Financial Strength Deepens
In Devon’s 2002 Annual Report we pledged to apply the excess cash we were generating to strengthening our balance sheet. During 2003 we repaid $500 million in debt and increased cash on hand to $1.3 billion at year-end. We also refinanced $500 million of existing long-term debt at a very attractive 2.75% interest rate. Our cash on hand covers 100% of debt repayments planned for 2004 and 2005. Given the current oil and gas price environment, we are continuing to generate cash from operations well in excess of our capital demands. This will allow us to further reduce debt.
Depth of Leadership
John Richels was appointed president of Devon in January 2004. John is a member of Devon’s Executive Committee. Following the 1998 merger, he led our Canadian subsidiary, with $8 billion in assets. He is a skilled manager with a thorough understanding of Devon and our industry. Chris Seasons previously reported to John and replaces him as head of our Canadian subsidiary.
Also in 2004, Devon named Brian Jennings chief financial officer. Brian joined Devon in 2000 and serves as senior vice president, corporate finance and development, and is a member of the Executive Committee. As CFO, he assumes responsibility for all financial functions. John, Brian and Chris reflect the depth of leadership Devon has developed throughout the organization.
In conjunction with the Ocean merger, Devon increased the number of directors on its board to 13. Joining Devon’s board were former Ocean directors Milton Carroll, Peter Fluor, Robert Howard and Charles Mitchell. Robert Weaver, who had served since 1999, resigned from the board. I welcome our new directors and thank Bob Weaver for his dedicated service.
Also announced in early 2004 were the retirements of two senior executives after lengthy careers with Devon. Mike Lacey, senior vice president, exploration and production, joined the company in 1989. Bill Vaughn, senior vice president, finance, began his career with Devon in 1983. Each was an important contributor to Devon’s success, a valued associate and a good friend.
These retirements remind us that change is inevitable. However, it is the things about Devon that have not changed of which I am most proud. We continue to believe in dealing with everyone honestly and ethically. We continue to believe in the powers of creativity, resourcefulness and hard work to uncover hidden opportunities. We continue to believe that to find success, you must look beneath the surface. ■
J. LARRY NICHOLS
Chief Executive Officer and Chairman of the Board of Directors March 11, 2004
  4 Devon Energy 2003 Annual Report
