FLUOR CORPORATION 2002 ANNUAL REPORT
Letterto Shareholders
ALAN L. BOECKMANN
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
Dear Shareholder:
As I reflect on the achievements of this past year, it is clear that 2002 proved to be a pivotal point in achieving our vision of “A Passion to Build”. This vision simply put is to become by all measures the preeminent Engineering, Procurement, Construction and Maintenance (EPCM) services company in the world. This goal is shaped by the collective views and commitment of the employees of Fluor and is aimed at pro­ viding outstanding value for our clients, shareholders and the communities in which we serve.
In 2002, the company delivered solid earnings growth despite a chal­ lenging environment. In addition, we posted our best year ever in safety, con­ tinuing to demonstrate that this is a cornerstone of our rich heritage. Every facet and part of the organization con­ tributed in a meaningful way to this out­ standing effort as we delivered on the promises that we made to investors and clients. Just as importantly, with the restructuring and refocusing actions of the past few years now behind us, we were able to concentrate on executing
our strategy which will deliver consis­ tent, long-term earnings growth, solid returns on capital and the creation of shareholder value.
Our focus on the core competen­ cies of EPCM services resulted in an effective implementation of execution excellence, financial discipline, increased marketing selectivity, and
an intense focus on client needs. As always, safety remains a core value, pro­ viding tangible benefits to employees, clients and shareholders. We remain absolutely committed to these princi­ ples and believe that they will provide the foundation for future success.
Operational Performance
In 2002, our impressive operational results were built on an increasing track record of successful project comple­ tions whereby we reached a standard of performance second to none in the industry. This translated into earnings from continuing operations of $170 million, or $2.13 per share, an increase of 33 percent over 2001. In addition, our operating margin also improved to 4.2 percent, up from 3.9 percent a year ago and cash flow from operations was a strong $207 million. This perform­ ance was the result of our focus on selectivity, the application of our com­ prehensive risk mitigation and man­ agement system, and strict adherence to the operating policies that we have established. We have the right people who are backed by proven systems. This talented team competes across a broad marketplace and can win and execute projects that achieve the appropriate returns on our resources.
Consolidated backlog at year-end was $9.7 billion, with a gross margin of $583 million for a 6 percent margin ratio. This compares to backlog of $11.5 billion with 6.6 percent gross
margin at the end of 2001. New awards and backlog were impacted by an anticipated downturn in power and the delayed award of a major upstream oil and gas production project in Kazakhstan.
We are optimistic about our business prospects for 2003 despite the geopolitical and economic uncertainty that could impact investment spending in our markets. A key to achieving sus­ tainable earnings growth is our broad market and geographic diversity. We remain confident that the current level and profitability of our backlog, com­ bined with our expectations for new business, will allow us to deliver earn­ ings in this year that equal or exceed our 2002 performance.
Business Strategy and Outlook
In assessing our strategic position as we enter 2003, our significant global presence and experience is unmatched in our industry. In addition, our busi­ nesses are both well balanced and extremely well positioned in each of the diversified markets that we serve. Our customer focus is paying dividends, and our next generation of management now in place, is highly capable with a strong track record of success.
During the last two years, Fluor has refined its strategy to capitalize
on our industry and geographic diver­ sity to dampen the cyclical impact of individual markets and to achieve more consistent growth. Our portfolio man­ agement approach allows us to quickly move resources across markets in response to varying cycles to take advantage of market upturns and man­ age costs in market downturns. We believe this adds to our growth rate as well as to our earnings reliability.
  PAGE 6

FLUOR CORPORATION 2002 ANNUAL REPORT
A key strength in our ability to achieve sustainable earnings growth is our broad market and geographic diversity.
Another key strategy is to increase the proportion of revenue and operat­ ing earnings from less cyclical growth markets to approximately 40 per­ cent. Today, these markets, primarily government services and opera­
tions and maintenance, account for approximately 20 percent of revenues and earnings.
Fluor will also continue to be a leader in the large cycle oil and gas and power markets. Although power has recently ended a major upcycle, the substantially larger global oil and gas market is poised at the early stage of a capital investment cycle. Within the more economically sensitive Industrial & Infrastructure segment, Fluor will continue to build on its leadership posi­ tion and benefit as capital spending and the overall economy recovers.
Through effective management oversight and resource allocation, we believe we can capitalize on the organic growth potential across our mix of busi­ ness opportunities and achieve our long-term financial goals. During 2002, we worked to establish or extend our leadership position in our target mar­ kets. To further this objective, we have focused on three areas where niche acquisitions could assist our efforts. These are federal services, operations and maintenance, and transportation.
Providing services to the federal government represents a large growth opportunity for Fluor, particularly
as the nation moves to outsource
more federal activities. In January 2003, we completed the acquisition
of Del-Jen, a leading provider of services to the Departments of Defense and Labor. This transaction reflects
an important follow-through on our corporate strategy and will broaden our participation in this large relatively stable market.
In early March 2003, we completed a second niche acquisition to strength­ en and expand our Operations and Maintenance (O&M) business with added skill sets. Fluor is acquiring
five specialty O&M business groups from Philip Services Corporation. Collectively, they are a leading pro­ vider of O&M services to domestic industrial facilities, particularly in
the oil & gas, refining, chemicals, petrochemicals and power genera­
tion industries. We are continuing to review additional niche acquisition candidates, employing a highly disci­ plined screening process with rigorous financial parameters.
Across all of our markets, we will continually stay abreast of market developments and adjust our organiza­ tional structure and market focus to capitalize on our greatest near-term opportunities, while continuing to posi­ tion the company for long-term growth prospects as well.
Financial Condition
An essential element of our strategy
is maintaining our strong financial condition and our “A” investment­ grade credit rating. Our balance sheet today exemplifies our leadership posi­ tion in the industry. This financial strength provides a distinct competitive advantage, instilling client confidence in our company and ensuring access to letters of credit and bonding capability critical to executing our business. Our strong cash and securities position of $753 million, with minimal debt, provides ample financial resources to fund internal growth, make strategic acquisitions, pay dividends and respond to unanticipated events. It is our intent to maintain and continually improve our financial strength.
Corporate Governance
It is impossible to report on Fluor’s financial performance without com­ menting on recent events within the U.S. capital markets. We are proud of our long history of judiciously manag­ ing our business, ensuring the inde­ pendence of our auditors, the board of directors and its committees, as well as the timely disclosure of material information to investors, and holding management to the highest standards of ethical conduct.
To further strengthen the board’s contribution, we implemented the con­ cept of a lead independent director. Peter Fluor, our longest serving direc­ tor, was unanimously elected to this position for a three-year term. In this role, he will facilitate open and free communications among our independ­ ent directors and with the management team. I am very supportive of this move and particularly pleased to work with Peter whose communication and busi­ ness skills will be an asset in this new role. It is our mutual intent to ensure that Fluor is the model of excellence in corporate governance.
Director/Management Changes
In March 2003, we were pleased to welcome Paul M. Anderson and
Kent Kresa to Fluor's board of direc­ tors. These individuals are outstanding business leaders and bring to our board significant global and market perspective, as well as valuable expert­ ise, relationships and financial acumen in the energy, natural resources and federal government markets. Paul Anderson retired in July 2002 as chief executive officer and managing director of BHP Billiton, one of the world's pre­ mier suppliers of natural resources.
PAGE 7

FLUOR CORPORATION 2002 ANNUAL REPORT
Fluor’s next generation of management is in place with increasing maturity and experience in executing the company’s long-term strategy for achieving its business objectives.
 Kent Kresa will retire April 1, 2003 as chief executive officer of Northrop Grumman, a global defense company. Also announced at that time was the retirement from the board of Thomas L. Gossage, a director since 1997. We will miss Tom who made many significant contributions during his tenure on
the board.
Jim Rollans, a key member of
Fluor’s senior management team and a member of our board of directors, announced his retirement from both positions effective January 3, 2003. During his 20-year tenure, Jim served in a number of senior-level manage­ ment positions, including chief admin­ istrative officer, chief financial officer, and president and chief executive offi­ cer of Fluor Signature Services. As a board member, he helped set Fluor’s long-term direction. While Jim has agreed to consult with the company on investment community matters, his daily presence and positive attitude will truly be missed.
Acknowledgements
Fluor Corporation employees are celebrating 50 years of corporate and community involvement this year with a series of service projects around the world. These activities are part of a global commemoration of the creation of the Fluor Foundation in 1952. Beginning with an original budget of $19,000 targeted at communities that were home to the company’s major U.S. offices, the Fluor Foundation today contributes annually to education and community organizations throughout the world. Since its inception, Fluor’s total philanthropic contributions have exceeded $100 million.
Fluor employees are also to be congratulated on another year of out­ standing safety performance. We completed 2002 with an all-time record
Pictured from left to right: Back row - Ron Pitts, Fluor Constructors International; Ron Peterson, Government Services; Garry Flowers, Corporate Security and Industrial Relations; Mark Stevens, Global Services; Jim Rollans, Investor Relations and Corporate Communications; Mike Steuert, Chief Financial Officer; Larry Fisher, Law and Secretary. Front row -
Kirk Grimes, Energy & Chemicals; John Hopkins, Sales, Marketing and Strategic Planning; Ron Oakley, Government; Steve Gilbert, Human Resources and Administration; Bob McNamara, Industrial & Infrastructure; Alan Boeckmann, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer.
 PAGE 8
low of lost workday performance, beating last year’s record and achieving a level that was 80 times better than the national industry average. This precedent-setting record was honored by the Construction Users Roundtable with the 2002 Construction Industry Safety Excellence Award.
I would also like to thank our board of directors and employees for their outstanding contributions during the year. Their absolute commitment to our guiding values of safety, integrity, teamwork and excellence in everything we do will be key to achieving our vision to be the premier engineering and construction company in the world.
Finally, let me express my appreciation to our fellow shareholders for their support and confidence in Fluor and its future. Despite the uncer­ tainties in today’s global marketplace, we see robust opportunities across our diversified markets, with significant
potential for increased market share in all of our target industries. Importantly, we can concentrate fully our energies and scope of resources to deliver the growth to drive shareholder value. I
am confident that Fluor is better posi­ tioned today than ever before to achieve this goal.
It is with great pride that I serve this company, its shareholders and employees and I look forward to the exciting future that lies ahead.
Alan L. Boeckmann
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
March 14, 2003
 