To Our Share Owners, Customers and Employees
The final year of the century was our finest, as 340,000 GE people around the globe posted the strongest results in the Company’s 122-year history.
▪ Revenues rose 11% to $112 billion, a record.
▪ Earnings increased 15% to $10.7 billion, the first time GE has broken the $10 billion mark in earnings from operations.
▪ Earnings per share were up 15%.
▪ Free cash flow was a strong $11.8 billion, up 17%.
▪ Our ongoing operating margin rate grew to 17.8%, a gain of more than a full point from ’98 and
the third straight year of more than a full point improvement. Working capital turns hit an all- time high of 11.5—an improvement of 2.3 turns. The 80% improvement in this key performance measure over the past three years has added
$4 billion to our cash flow.
▪ GE made 134 acquisitions in 1999, worth almost $17 billion. This marks the Company’s third year in a row with over 100 acquisitions, totaling over $51 billion.
▪ GE was named, for the second consecutive year, Fortune magazine’s “Most Admired Company
in America.” Also for the second straight year, we were named “The World’s Most Respected Company” by the Financial Times. A Business Week survey named the GE Board of Directors “Best Board,” and Time magazine described
GE as “The Company of the Century.”
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer John F. Welch, Jr. (center) and Vice Chairmen and Executive Officers John D. Opie (left) and Dennis D. Dammerman (right) form GE’s Corporate Executive Office.
▪ We repurchased $1.9 billion in GE stock in 1999, raised the dividend 17% for the second consecu- tive year, and proposed a 3-for-1 stock split, the fifth split in 17 years, which will take effect after share owner approval in April 2000.
Our share owners—including our active and retired employees who have $24 billion of GE stock in their savings plans—were rewarded for this perfor- mance. The total return on a share of GE stock in 1999 was 54%. This followed returns of 41% in 1998, 51% in 1997, 40% in 1996 and 45% in 1995.
1
  
Understanding GE
In this report, for the first time, the CEOs of the top 20 GE businesses will describe the highlights and, in a few cases, the shortfalls of the year, and their plans for the future. Fourteen of these 20 businesses produced dou- ble-digit earnings increases in 1999: five grew more than 40%; four between 25-40%; five between 15-25%; three were about flat; three were down.
We never get it all “right” in any year, and probably never will, but it is the scale and leading market posi- tions of these businesses, and the quality of the teams that run them, that allow us to have one great year after another. 1999 was an outstanding year — our best ever — but the past five have been great as well, as have the past 20. For that matter, it’s been a great century. Edison would be pleased.
We believe annual reports are as much about where we can go as where we have been; and our message to you this year should enable you to look forward to the brightest of futures for GE in its third century of operation.
...it’s actually easy to understand this Company, and to feel confident about its future growth, if you look at its array of world-class businesses and grasp the two fundamental forces that drive GE—its social architecture and its operating system.
Much has been said of the difficulty of “under- standing” GE because of the enormous diversity of its products and services and the breadth of its global operations. But it’s actually easy to understand this Company, and to feel confident about its future growth, if you look at its array of world-class businesses and grasp the two fundamental forces that drive GE — its social architecture and its operating system.
The Social Architecture
GE’s current social architecture began to form in the early ’80s when we became convinced that the only way a company like ours could move quickly and suc- cessfully through times of radical change was to use every mind in the Company and to involve everyone in the game — to leave no one, and no good idea, out. To achieve this radical cultural transformation, we devel- oped something we called “Work-Out,” which is based on the simple premise that those closest to the work know it best. Over the years there have been literally hundreds of thousands of Work-Out “town meetings,” where the views and ideas of every employee, from every function, in every business, were solicited and turned into action — usually on
the spot. People saw the value we attached to their intellect and their ideas — and as a result, their ideas began to flow in torrents.
The second facet of the social architecture involved the cultivation of what we call “boundary- less” behavior by the removal of every organizational and functional obstacle to the free and unimpeded flow of ideas—inside the Company across every operation, and outside the Company from the best thinking in world business. We measured this bound- aryless behavior in our leadership—and rewarded or removed people based on it. We anonymously survey thousands of employees every year to measure our progress and see if our rhetoric matches their reality. When it does not, we take action.
The combination of involving everyone in the game and of responding to this flow of ideas and information turned GE into what we are today — a learning com- pany. By becoming a learning company, we have taken market and geographic diversity, the traditional handi- cap of multi-business companies, and turned them into a decisive advantage — unlimited access to the most enormous supply of best ideas, information and intellectual capital the business world has to offer.
  2

Our social architecture—our values—is the software that drives what we call the operating system of GE.
The GE Operating System
The operating system of GE was devised to channel and focus this torrent of ideas and information and put it to use through the medium of Company-wide “initiatives,” as well as to track, measure and expand these initiatives as they take hold and flourish.
By becoming a learning company, we have taken market and geographic diver- sity, the traditional handicap of multi- business companies, and turned them into a decisive advantage—unlimited access to the most enormous supply of best ideas, information and intellectual capital the business world has to offer.
This operating system is based on an informal but intense, regular schedule of reviews designed to create momentum for the initiative. It progresses with a drumbeat regularity throughout our business year—year after year.
A typical initiative — Product Services, say, or Six Sigma Quality — is launched with passionate intensity at the meeting of our 600 global leaders in January.
A commitment to the initiative is made. Every subse- quent event in the Company is developed around implementing and expanding the initiative: resources are allocated; high visibility jobs are created; intense communications start throughout the businesses; and work begins.
Each quarter throughout the year, the leaders of our businesses meet to share what each of them has done to drive the initiative. At these meetings, leaders rang- ing from the Reinsurance CEO, to the NBC executive, to the head of the Industrial Systems business describe
how they are implementing the particular initiative in their own operations. The incredible amount of learning that comes from this shared experience expands the initiative and energizes their efforts.
Every Company activity and every Company event during the year add energy and momentum to the ini- tiative. In these same quarterly meetings, for example, every Business Management Course class at our Management Development Institute— 50 to 60 of our highest potential leaders—reports back on its three- week experience in the field on the best practices they found from other companies around the world—and they are brutally honest on how we stack up vis-à-vis the best they saw. This candid feedback really picks up the pace.
The same is true for Human Resources reviews.
In April and May, the Corporate Executive Office and Human Resources leaders go into the field for full-day personnel reviews at each location, where the people leading and practicing the initiatives present their progress, and a clear assessment is made of the capa- bilities and the level of intensity of the people involved in the initiative. We want only the best, the brightest and the most committed to be in these leadership roles, and the focus on talent is relentless.
By October, role models—heroes—have emerged in all the businesses, and they are selected to present to the 150 Corporate Officers at their annual meeting. This meeting serves as a platform where each busi- ness can measure its progress against that of the best of its peers.
This takes us full circle to January, when the 600 global leaders of our Company meet and focus, once again, on the initiatives. The initiative from the prior January usually occupies the entire first day, and the role models present their stories and share their learn- ing. On Day 2, new ideas around other ongoing initia- tives—some several years old—are shared. This year, for example, the first full day was on e-Business. Day 2 covered new thinking in Globalization, Six Sigma and Product Services.
  3

This operating system propels what has become a “learning engine” and embeds these initiatives in the DNA of the Company.
Crucial to the success of this social architecture and operating system is their synchronization with
our reward and incentive system. How well people capitalize on these initiatives, how open they are to change, determines the level of their reward. Making the numbers at GE gets you into the game. Living
the values and leveraging the operating system is the road to promotions and greater personal rewards.
The remainder of this report will describe how this social architecture and operating system have driven and expanded the four key initiatives that will be the source of GE growth for decades.
Globalization
The oldest current initiative in GE, driven by the GE operating system for about 15 years, is, like Work-Out, becoming so pervasive and ingrained in the Company that it’s less an “initiative” now and more a reflex. Globalization began with a GE that derived more than 80% of revenues from the U.S. and has taken us to where we are today, with 41% of revenues from out- side the U.S. and moving toward a majority sometime in this decade.
Globalization evolved from a drive to export, to the establishment of global plants for local consumption, and then to global sourcing of products and services. Today, we are moving into its final stages—drawing upon intellectual capital from all over the world — from metallurgists in Prague, to software engineers in Asia, to product designers in Budapest, Monterrey, Tokyo, Paris and other places around the globe. Our insatiable appetite for more advanced technology
is being fed, not by a new wing on our world-class Corporate R&D Center in Schenectady, New York, but by a soon-to-open greenfield laboratory in the suburbs of Bangalore, India.
There has been an enormous amount of comment recently on the subject of globalization. Let us assure you that GE brings only world-class business and work practices and careful, compliant and proactive envi- ronmental processes to every one of our global opera- tions. We understand that to be a truly great global company, we must be a great local citizen.
Today, American GE business leaders located out- side the United States have become fewer and fewer as local leaders, trained in GE operating methods and steeped in our values but with their own unmatchable customer intimacy and market savvy, are replacing them. Our objective is to be the “global employer
of choice,” and we are striving to create the exciting career opportunities for local leaders all over the world that will make this objective a reality. This initia- tive has taken us to within reach of one of our biggest and longest-running dreams—a truly global GE.
Product Services
The precursor to our Product Services initiative was a GE where new product development was primarily “where the action was” for our huge corps of engi- neers and scientists. The best and brightest of these wanted to work on the highest-thrust jet engine, the fastest medical scan or the leading-edge electrical turbine design. Product services consisted of less- exciting maintenance of our high-value machines — turbines, engines, medical devices and the like.
Making the numbers at GE gets you into the game. Living the values and leveraging the operating system is the road to promotions and greater personal rewards.
As recently as 1995, when this initiative was launched, GE derived $8 billion a year in revenues from product ser- vices. In 2000, this number will be $17 billion.
  4

The premise for the Product Services initiative was the collective realization that while GE cannot win, and shouldn’t play, in the “wrench-turning” game, it could find enormous growth in the high-technology, cus- tomer-productivity game—where there are few, if any, who can do the things we can do for that customer.
The human resources focus in the operating system made services the new “place to be” for the best and brightest. Big, exciting, high-technology jobs in services were created. And the GE values system—increas- ingly tied to customer focus—reinforced the shift.
But the most important key to the long-range suc- cess of our services initiative is the understanding that leading-edge technology can only be derived from creating great products. By driving this leading-edge technology back into the installed base of older equip- ment, we can increase our customers’ productivity and, in turn, make them more competitive—with sig- nificantly lower investment on their part. We want being a product services customer of GE to be analo- gous to bringing your car in for a 50,000-mile check and driving out with 100 more horsepower, better gas mileage and lower emissions.
For example, the technology in the world’s most advanced, highest-thrust jet engine—the GE90—is now being migrated into yesterday’s installed base, refreshing 20-year-old customer engines, improving their thrust, fuel efficiency and time on-wing.
“H” gas turbine technology, the world’s most advanced, is now improving the efficiency and heat rate of customers’ 20- and 30-year-old power plants. Twenty-first century AC locomotive technology is making 1980s’ locomotives more reliable; and 1990s’ CT machines are producing better scans because
of infusions of technology from Six Sigma-designed twenty-first century platforms.
We understand that to be a great services com- pany, we must be a great leading-edge product technology company—they go hand in hand. Using tomorrow’s technology to upgrade yesterday’s hard- ware will make our customers more successful and
create for GE a rapidly expanding services business for decades to come.
Six Sigma Quality
The Six Sigma initiative is in its fifth year—its fifth trip through the operating system. From a standing start in 1996, with no financial benefit to the Company, it has flourished to the point where it produced more than $2 billion in benefits in 1999, with much more to come this decade.
We want being a product services customer of GE to be analogous to bringing your car in for a 50,000-mile check and driving out with 100 more horsepower, better gas mileage and lower emissions.
In the initial stages of Six Sigma, our effort con- sisted of training more than 100,000 people in its science and methodology and focusing thousands
of “projects” on improving efficiency and reducing variance in our internal operations—from industrial factories to financial services back rooms. From there, our operating system steered the initiative
into design engineering to prepare future generations of “Design for Six Sigma” products—and drove it rapidly across the customer-interactive processes
of the financial services businesses. Medical Systems used it to open up a commanding technology lead
in several diagnostic platforms and has achieved dramatic sales increases and customer satisfaction improvements. Every GE product business and financial service activity is using Six Sigma in its product design and fulfillment processes.
Today, Six Sigma is focused squarely where it must be—on helping our customers win. A growing propor- tion of Six Sigma projects now under way are done on customer processes, many on customer premises.
  5

The objective is not to deliver flawless products and services that we think the customer wants when we promise them — but rather what customers really want when they want them.
One thing that the truly great companies of the world have in common, regardless of the diversity of their industries, is a total business focus on servicing customers. With Six Sigma as the enabler, we intend to meet that standard.
E-Business
E-Business, which entered the operating system at
the January Managers Meeting little more than a year ago, is already so big and transformational that it has almost outgrown the bounds of the word “initiative.” While we are already generating billions in Web-based revenues, the contribution of e-Business to GE has been so much more. It is changing this Company to its core.
One thing that the truly great companies of the world have in common, regard- less of the diversity of their industries, is a total business focus on servicing cus- tomers. With Six Sigma as the enabler, we intend to meet that standard.
For 20 years, we’ve been driving to get the soul of
a small company into this sometimes muscle-bound, big-company body. We described the contribution of Work-Out, and there was more. We de-layered in the ’80s, eliminating many of the filters and gatekeepers. We got faster by reducing corporate staff. We launched venture units, in imitation of start-ups. We made close to 30,000 people stock optionees in a Com- pany that used to have under 500. And we ridiculed and removed bureaucrats until they became as rare around GE as whooping cranes.
Every year we got better, faster, hungrier and more customer-focused—until the day this elixir, this tonic, this e-Business came along and changed the DNA of
GE forever by energizing and revitalizing every corner of this Company.
The first effect of e-Business was to further energize and refresh our other three initiatives. For one, it enabled us to put to customer advantage the enormous databases we had compiled on customer processes as part of Six Sigma projects.
What we are rapidly moving toward is the day when “Dr. Jones,” in radiology, can go to her home page in the morning and find a comparison of the number, and clarity, of scans her CT machines performed in the last day, or week, to more than 10,000 other machines across the world. She will then be able to click and order software solutions that will bring her perfor- mance up to world-class levels. And the performance of her machines might have been improved, online,
the previous night, by a GE engineer in Milwaukee, Tokyo, Paris or Bangalore.
The day is almost here when the chief engineer at the local utility may check the heat rate and fuel burn of his turbines—before he has coffee in the morn- ing—to learn how he stacks up with 100 other utilities. Again, with a click to a home page, he can look at what GE services can provide to increase his competitive- ness. Here, a number of GE’s service packages are offered that will take him quickly to world-class levels.
The efficient harvesting of intellectual capital, which is the state-of-the-art of the globalization initia- tive, is impossible without the Internet, and GE prod- ucts are today being designed collaboratively online around the globe 24 hours a day—as our Industrial Systems business does with its “Web City.”
But the transformation e-Business is bringing about at GE is more pervasive than even this growing magic.
When you think about this e-Business revolution that is transforming the world, an obvious question comes to mind: Why wasn’t the e-revolution launched by big, highly resourced, high-technology companies rather than the small start-ups that led it? The answer may lie, as perhaps is true in GE’s case, in the mystery associated with the Internet—the perception that
  6

creating and operating Web sites was Nobel Prize work—therealmoftheyoungandwild-eyed.Inour case, we once again used a best practice from one
of our businesses to overcome this discomfort. We took the top 1,000 managers in the Company and asked them to become “mentees” of 1,000 “with it”, very bright e-Business mentors—many brand new to GE— and to work with them three to four hours a week, traveling the Web, evaluating competitor sites, and learning to organize their computers, and their minds, for work on the Internet. It was this mentor-mentee interaction—which in some cases resembled that of “Stuart” and his boss in the Ameritrade commercial — that helped overcome the only real hurdle some of us had—fear of the unknown. Having overcome that
fear, and experienced the transformational effects of e-Business, we find that digitizing a company and developing e-Business models is a lot easier — not harder—than we had ever imagined.
Start-ups have energized the business landscape, supported by a strong venture capital environment and healthy IPO market; however, much of their resources must go to establish brand, develop real content and achieve fulfillment capability. We already have that! We already have the hard stuff—over 100 years of a well-recognized brand, leading-edge technology in both product and financial services, and a Six Sigma- based fulfillment capability. The opportunities e-Busi- ness creates for large companies like GE are unlimited.
But digitizing a company does more than just cre- ate unlimited business opportunities; it puts a small company soul into that big company body and gives it the transparency, excitement and buzz of a start-up.
It is truly the elixir for GE and others who relish excite- ment and change.
E-Business is the final nail in the coffin for bureau- cracy at GE. The utter transparency it brings about is
a perfect fit for our boundaryless culture and means everyone in the organization has total access to every- thing worth knowing.
The speed that is the essence of “e” has acceler- atedthemetabolismoftheCompany,withpeople laughing out loud at presentations of business plans for “the third quarter of next year” and other tortoise- like projections of action. Time in GE today is mea- sured in days and weeks.
E-Business was made for GE, and the “E” in GE now has a whole new meaning. We get it—we all get it.
The accelerating pace of our success in this initia- tive is leading to a lot of spontaneous celebrating — something big companies, including GE, have always had trouble doing as well as small companies. It generates more fun across a business than anything we’ve ever seen. The informality, joy of work and endless celebration that comes with “e” life is some- thing on which we are thriving.
E-Business was made for GE, and the “E” in GE now has a whole new meaning. We get it — we all get it.
We begin this century with a GE totally focused on the customer, utterly energized and rejuvenated by e-Business, and driven by the relentless beat of a unique operating system and social architecture. This Company is poised to move forward to levels of perfor- mance, growth and excitement undreamed of in
the past.
We thank you all for your support in helping make this future so bright.
John D. Opie
Vice Chairman of the Board and Executive Officer
   John F. Welch, Jr. Chairman of the Board and Chief Executive Officer
Dennis D. Dammerman Vice Chairman of the Board and Executive Officer
February 11, 2000
  7
