 DEAR STOCKHOLDERS:
2005 was one of the most difficult years in General Motors’ 98-year history.
It was the year in which GM’s two fundamental weaknesses in the U.S. market were fully exposed: our huge legacy cost burden, and our inability to adjust structural costs in line with falling revenue.
The challenges we cited in this space a year ago – global over- capacity, falling prices, rising health-care costs, higher fuel prices, global competition – intensified and significantly weakened our business. The result was a loss of $3.4 billion, excluding special items, and a reported loss of $10.6 billion, on revenues of $192.6 billion.
Obviously, that is unsustainable. Though we are confident that GM has time and sufficient cash to see itself through a turnaround, I want you to know that we are working diligently to get things moving in the right direction – quickly.
Essentially, we are changing our business model to deal with
the larger phenomenon of globalization and the competition it has brought to the U.S. economy. We already have made some significant moves to improve our competitiveness in the long term. We need to do more – and we will.
FINANCIAL REPORTING
We also have a renewed commitment to excellence and transparency in our financial reporting. The recent discovery of prior-year account- ing errors has been extremely disappointing and embarrassing to
all of us.
Credibility is paramount, for GM as a company and for me per- sonally. While I will not offer excuses, I do apologize on behalf of our management team, and assure you that we will strive to deserve your trust. The fact is that errors were made, and we can’t change that. What we have done is disclose our mistakes and work as diligently as we can to fix them.
We are moving aggressively to strengthen our internal accounting resources. Going forward, we will do our best to re-establish the ground that we have lost, as we restore GM’s reputation for financial accuracy and transparency.
SECOND HIGHEST SALES IN GM’S HISTORY
Outside North America, it was a relatively good year.
Global industry vehicle sales set another record, and we’re fore-
casting a record again this year – almost 66 million units, which would be up about 1 million units from last year. GM had its second highest sales volume globally last year, with nearly 9.2 million vehicles sold.
GM scored three significant “firsts” last year: More than half of GM’s sales globally came outside the United States; in the Asia Pacific region, GM sold more than 1 million vehicles; and GM, along with our joint venture partner, became the No. 1 car manufacturer in China, the world’s fastest-growing market.
Our success in China is evidence that where the playing field is even, GM can compete aggressively with the best and win.
GM also experienced significant growth in our Latin America, Africa and the Middle East region, with sales up 20 percent on
the strength of our Chevrolet brand. GM set sales records in Chile, Ecuador, Venezuela, South Africa and the Middle East as we marked the eighth consecutive year of sales leadership in the region.
In the tough European market, our turnaround remained on track. GM Europe cut its losses significantly based on good consumer acceptance of our new vehicles and strong progress on our cost- restructuring initiatives. We expect continued improvement in 2006 as we launch an all-new Opel Corsa and continue to expand the Chevrolet brand.
But most of the news about GM last year was focused on our North American operations, as we dealt with a dramatically changing competitive environment.
We addressed softer demand and our growing inventory in the first half with production cuts and our successful campaign that offered consumers the same prices that GM employees pay. Fuel prices increased sharply through the year, reducing demand for some of our highest-profit trucks, and tilting our sales mix more toward lower-margin cars. The devastation of Hurricane Katrina also had an impact, both on fuel prices nationally and on vehicle sales.
With our inventories now at manageable levels and several high-volume cars and trucks being launched this year, we expect our
General Motors Corporation 3

 FINANCIAL HIGHLIGHTS
(Dollars in millions, except per share amounts) Years ended December 31,
Total net sales and revenues
Worldwide production (units in thousands)
Income (loss) from continuing operations (Loss) from discontinued operations Gain on sale of discontinued operations Cumulative effect of accounting change Net income (loss)
Net profit margin from continuing operations
Diluted earnings (loss) per share attributable to $1-2/3 par value common stock
Continuing operations Net income
Income adjusted to exclude Hughes Electronics and special items(1)
Income (loss)
Diluted earnings (loss) per share attributable to $1-2/3 par value common stock
Book value per share of $1-2/3 par value common stock
Number of $1-2/3 par value common stock shares outstanding as of December 31 (in millions)
2005
$192,604
9,051
$«(10,458)
–
–
(109)
$«(10,567)
(5.4)
$÷«(18.50)
$÷«(18.69)
$÷«(3,354)
$÷÷«(5.93)
$÷÷25.81
565
%
2004
$193,517
9,098
$÷÷2,804
–
–
–
$÷÷2,804
1.4%
$÷÷÷4.94
$÷÷÷4.94
$÷÷3,629
$÷÷÷6.40
$÷÷48.41
565
2003
$185,837
8,246
$÷÷2,899
$÷÷÷(219)
$÷÷1,179
–
$÷÷3,859
1.6%
$÷÷÷5.09
$÷÷÷7.20
$÷÷3,234
$÷÷÷5.69
$÷÷44.31
562
                  (1) A reconciliation of adjusted amounts to amounts determined in accordance with accounting principles generally accepted in the United States may be found at www.gm.com/company/investor_information/, Earnings Releases, Financial Highlights.
Net Sales and Revenues billions
$192.6 $193.5
$185.8
Income (Loss) from Continuing Operations billions
Net Profit Margin from Continuing Operations percent
Earnings (Loss) per Share from Continuing Operations dollars
$4.94 $5.09
   $2.8
$2.9
1.4%
1.6%
             4
General Motors Corporation
05 04 03
$(10.5)
05 04 03
(5.4)%
05 04 03
$(18.50)
05 04 03

results in GM North America to improve. But while significant progress has been made, we continue to focus on addressing the challenge of our long-term, structural issues in the United States.
GM’S LEGACY CHALLENGE
The weight of history on our results has been significant.
GM has been in business for nearly a century, and in the last four decades, our business has undergone tremendous structural change.
Vastly improved productivity, greater reliance on suppliers, and large growth in the number of competitors in our largest market have all had an impact. But while GM today is a far leaner, more productive automaker, we still carry a significant financial burden of the past.
Consider that in 1962, we employed 605,000 people around the world. Of those, 464,000 were in the United States, where we sold 4.2 million cars and trucks. With only two major competitors, GM reached a record U.S. market share of 51 percent.
Fast-forward to 2005: GM employed 335,000 employees world- wide. Of those, 141,000 were in the United States, where we sold 4.5 million cars and trucks. While last year we competed against
11 major automakers from around the world, GM still led the market with a 26 percent share.
Over those 43 years, new technologies and downsizing resulted in a much leaner GM, producing more vehicles with far fewer employees. But the growth of our retiree population exploded in those decades, leaving GM today with the financial weight of outsized “legacy costs” for health care and pensions.
in the world has that kind of health-care obligation. Today we compete mostly against foreign-owned companies whose govern- ments cover much of their employee and retiree health-care and pension costs.
OUR NORTH AMERICA TURNAROUND PLAN
In 2005, we laid out and began to aggressively implement a four-point turnaround plan aimed at strengthening our competitive position and achieving strong business results for years to come. The four elements of our plan are:
● Keep raising the bar in the execution of great cars and trucks. ● Revitalize our sales and marketing strategy.
● Significantly improve our cost competitiveness.
● Address our health-care and pension legacy cost burden.
The last two points of the plan led to some difficult and painful decisions that involved sacrifice from virtually everyone with a stake in GM’s future:
● We announced plans to cease production at 12 U.S. plants by 2008, and reduce our manufacturing workforce by 30,000 positions.
● By working together with the leadership of the United Auto Workers, we reached an historic agreement that is expected to reduce our retiree health-care obligations by about
$15 billion.
● GM and the UAW, along with our former parts-making subsidiary, Delphi Corp., reached an agreement to reduce significantly the number of hourly employees in the United States through an accelerated attrition program.
● We announced that GM will cap the company’s contribution to salaried retiree health-care costs at the end of this year, reducing that obligation by almost $5 billion.
● We announced plans to significantly modify pension benefits for our salaried and executive employees, to further reduce GM’s financial risk and cost.
● We voluntarily reduced salaries of our top executives – including 50 percent for me. Our Board of Directors also reduced their compensation by 50 percent.
● We reduced our dividend by 50 percent.
General Motors Corporation 5
The chart below illustrates the scope of this obligation.
  U.S. Employees
Hourly Pension Plan* Salaried Pension Plan*
Total Health Plan Recipients**
1962 464,000 31,351 8,885
1,360,000
2005 141,000 337,588 115,762
1,075,000
    Stated another way, for every active GM employee in the United States last year, GM supported 3.2 retirees and surviving spouses. Back in 1962, the employee/retiree ratio was reverse: GM had 11.5 active employees for every retiree or surviving spouse in our pension plans.
GM’s health-care bill in 2005 – for every U.S. employee, dependant, retiree and surviving spouse – totaled $5.3 billion. No other company
* Number of U.S. retirees and surviving spouses who received pension plan benefits
**Est. number of U.S. employees, dependents, retirees and surviving spouses covered by health benefits

Combined with our target to reduce net material costs by $1 billion, these actions are expected to result in annual cost reductions totaling $7 billion on a running rate basis by the end of this year, with $4 bil- lion of that reduction to be realized during this calendar year. That’s a huge move – and it’s needed.
It is important to note here that these cost reductions will not affect our aggressive product development plans. We continue to invest heavily in new cars and trucks, recognizing that only success- ful new products will put GM back on a path toward sustained profitability and growth.
The plant actions are designed to reduce GM North America’s assembly capacity by about 1 million units by the end of 2008, in addition to the previously implemented reduction of 1 million units between 2002 and 2005. This should bring GM to 100 percent or more capacity utilization by 2008.
In addition, GM’s U.S. salaried workforce (including contract staff) has been reduced 33 percent since 2000, or an average annual rate of about 7 percent. We expect to continue to reduce our salaried staff- ing levels at approximately this rate in 2006, bringing our cumulative reduction to 38 percent from 2000 levels.
There’s more work to be done to reduce costs in the months ahead – with our union partners, our employees and our suppliers. But, clearly, we are addressing the global cost-competitiveness challenge.
GROWING GLOBAL REVENUE
As important as our cost-reduction efforts are, we know that’s only half of the equation to return GM to profitability. We’re also gaining traction on the other half of the equation: growing revenue around the world.
Despite our financial challenges, we actually increased our capital expenditures by about $1 billion to a total of $8 billion last year. Nearly all of that was invested in new products. We plan to maintain a heavy commitment to spending on new products and technologies this year.
We also continue to make progress toward our goal of globally integrating our product development, engineering, manufacturing and planning organizations. In doing so, we are starting to realize the economies of scale that a company the size of GM should.
We are leveraging all the skills of our design and engineering staff to provide more and better products to support each of our brands, while basing them on significantly fewer global vehicle architectures. Our integrated product development approach also is designed to reduce product lifecycles, increase productivity and improve quality.
At the same time, we are absolutely committed to trend-setting design for all of our brands around the world.
The evidence of that commitment is already on the road: The Pontiac Solstice (on the cover), Opel Astra, HUMMER H3, Chevy HHR, Saturn SKY, Buick Lucerne and Cadillac Escalade are all great examples of our design talent. The Chevy Camaro and Saab Aero X concept cars have been among the hits of this year’s auto show circuit.
Even some of our toughest critics now acknowledge the excellent craftsmanship, features, innovations and design built into our newest cars and trucks. Our challenge is to get that word out to consumers who may not have considered a GM brand in the past.
We’re also continuing to make significant progress in quality.
In last year’s well-respected J.D. Power Initial Quality Study, the top three auto assembly plants in North America were GM plants. Buick and Cadillac both placed among the study’s top five brands, ahead of such well-known brands as Honda, Acura, Nissan, Infiniti, Mercedes-Benz and, yes, Toyota.
We won’t be satisfied until all our brands are high on that list. But there is no disputing that the quality of GM’s cars and trucks has improved significantly over the past decade.
GM TECHNOLOGY & FUEL EFFICIENCY
We continue to put significant resources into technology, particularly in improving fuel efficiency. This is an area where we have a good story to tell:
● GM offers more products in the United States with an EPA highway rating of 30 miles or more per gallon of fuel than any other automaker.
● GM is a leader in flexible-fuel vehicle production and sales,
with more than 1.5 million flex-fuel vehicles already on the road. We have nine models that are E85-capable, which allows these vehicles to run on ethanol fuel. And, we have plans to add more than 400,000 E85-capable vehicles to our fleet in 2006.
● In addition to our very successful GM Hybrid Bus, which improves fuel economy by as much as 60 percent, we introduced a light hybrid system on our full-size pickup trucks two years ago, which we’ll offer in all 50 states this year.
● We’ll introduce a highly efficient, low-cost hybrid system on the Saturn VUE Green Line – a hybrid SUV that will cost less than $23,000.
6 General Motors Corporation

● Next year, we’ll offer our next-generation, two-mode hybrid system on our large sport utilities, starting with the Chevy Tahoe and GMC Yukon. This is a sophisticated hybrid powertrain derived from the system we use in our transit buses. We are developing
it in partnership with DaimlerChrysler and BMW, and we’re con- vinced it will become the industry standard for hybrids. With our partners sharing development costs and spreading them over a larger volume of products, we expect significant savings.
While these are great solutions to help reduce emissions and improve fuel economy over the near-term, we continue to commit significant resources in the development of hydrogen fuel cells. We realize that there’s no shortage of skeptics of hydrogen propulsion. But we’ve been working hard at perfecting this technology for years, and we’re making significant progress toward our goal of manufactur- ing a commercially viable fuel-cell vehicle.
Another example of GM innovation is OnStar, the in-vehicle safety, security and information service that no other automaker has been able to match. OnStar continues to add to its long list of services that delight GM owners, such as OnStar Vehicle Diagnostics, which runs regular diagnostic checks on your car or truck and sends you
an e-mail with the results.
REVITALIZING SALES AND MARKETING
Another key element of our plan to grow revenue is revitalizing our sales and marketing strategy. We’re putting great emphasis on building and differentiating each of our automotive brands around the world, and accelerating our drive for consistent, world-class distribution networks.
In the U.S. market, we’re renewing our focus on major metropolitan markets, like Miami, Los Angeles and New York, where we have under- performed in recent years.
Earlier this year, we announced an unprecedented reduction in sticker prices in the United States – an average of $1,300 per vehicle, affecting most of our cars and trucks. It was the biggest step yet in our strategy of fewer incentives and lower prices every day.
The lower prices have given consumers a compelling reason to try our new vehicles, and it’s working.
PENDING ISSUES
As this report was going to print, GM was exploring the possible sale of a controlling interest in our financial services subsidiary, GMAC,
with the goal of strengthening its credit rating and renewing its access to low-cost financing. If this occurs, we would plan to retain GMAC’s strategic support of our automotive business by retaining a significant interest in GMAC, and implementing a long-term operating agreement to continue to provide these services to GM dealers and customers.
GM also was involved in important discussions with Delphi Corp. and the United Auto Workers on issues surrounding Delphi’s Chapter 11 restructuring. We are pursuing an agreement in the best interests of GM and its stockholders, and that enables Delphi to continue as an important supplier to GM.
THE CHALLENGES AHEAD
We recognize that our stockholders have shared the pain as GM has struggled over the past year. We appreciate your patience and advice, and we are committed to making your investment in General Motors a profitable one.
Transforming GM to compete in this new global economy is a daunting task. But it also provides us with an opportunity to lead this great company into a new era of growth and success in providing the world with innovation in transportation. Our leadership team and our employees around the world are energized by this challenge.
By taking the necessary measures today to reduce our cost structure and grow our revenue, we are doing exactly what is needed to position GM for success. Outside North America, we are well-posi- tioned to take advantage of our industry’s future growth opportunities.
I am confident that we’ll emerge from these challenging times stronger, smarter, and a better global competitor.
We will succeed.
Rick Wagoner
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Detroit, Michigan
 General Motors Corporation 7
