                  FELLOW SHAREHOLDERS:
Henry and Richard Bloch founded this company with a
belief that delivering exceptional client service would lead
to a successful, profitable company. Sixty years later, we
continue to adhere to these long-standing values and
once again this year, we were able to deliver strong
results for you, our shareholders. This was a challenging
tax season, with the implementation of the Affordable
Care Act (ACA) and the continued and growing issue of tax fraud impacting the industry as a whole. Despite the challenges, our tax professionals fully embraced our Purpose: We look at your life through tax...and find ways to help. As a result, we were able to grow revenues for the third consecutive year, gain share in the digital Do It Yourself (DIY) category, and maintain strong margins.
THE INDUSTRY
To understand our results, it is first important to understand the factors impacting the tax preparation industry overall. Taxes and healthcare intersected for the first time this tax season, causing confusion and affecting refunds for millions. Our significant investment in training, systems and marketing ensured that we were well positioned to assist our clients. Taxpayers will continue to feel the impact of the ACA through their tax returns for years to come and the work we have done positions us to be their trusted adviser going forward.
There is another issue impacting the tax industry and our country in a troubling and growing way... tax fraud. Specifically, there are two areas in which our industry has seen significant trends over the past several years; tax identity theft and Earned Income Tax Credit fraud. H&R Block has been advo- cating for actions to address tax fraud for several years. Now, meaningful attention within the tax preparation industry is finally being paid to these issues that continue to cost taxpayers billions of dollars. We have led the industry’s fight against fraud and we remain focused on advocating for change that benefits consumers by strengthening anti-fraud measures.
OUR PERFORMANCE
Despite the industry-wide challenges, we had a successful year:
■ Our tax professionals delivered expert ACA advice to our clients this year and are positioned to be trusted ACA advisors in the years ahead.
■ We continued to improve our digital DIY product, enhancing the client experience.
■ We successfully launched a timely new product, Tax Identity Shield, designed to protect
our clients from the growing threat of tax identity theft faced by all Americans.
■ Our people continued to “Do the Right Thing,” taking care of our clients and delivering for you, our shareholders.
In the U.S. Assisted category, we grew revenues by 2.3% to $2.1 billion despite a decline in
volume of 4.4%. We improved the overall mix of returns we completed and focused on our infra- structure to ensure we are well positioned for success going forward. We implemented a new tax preparation platform in our offices. This new tool allows our tax professionals to better use their tax knowledge while providing an improved client experience. Additionally, the majority of our offices have now been upgraded to achieve a more welcoming, professional look and feel. Finally, we pur- chased and integrated several hundred franchise offices into the company management structure, which we believe are best suited to be company-run locations.
 William C. Cobb
President & Chief Executive Officer

                 Our DIY products had a very strong year, which I believe demonstrates H&R Block’s outstanding user experience and the impact of effective marketing. While we achieved an 8% increase in accepted e-files, I’m especially pleased in our 12% revenue growth which outpaced the industry. Our strong advertising and promotional efforts increased product awareness by six points. And by enhancing our products, we were better able to monetize, improving our overall mix.
Our Tax Plus products continue to provide tremendous value to our clients. To combat the grow- ing risk of tax identity theft, we launched Tax Identity ShieldTM, the industry’s first product specifi- cally directed at helping protect against tax identity fraud. Bundled with Peace of Mind® (POM), the product has performed well and has also increased POM sales, as the two products complement each other nicely. In addition, we successfully increased H&R Block Emerald Prepaid MasterCard® usage and average deposits. This is the continuation of a multi-year effort, which has resulted in a 40% increase in revenue per card since 2012.
Internationally, we continue to grow, with revenues increasing 8% in local currency. We are focused on thinking more globally as a company to capitalize on synergies between our domestic and inter- national businesses.
OUR RESULTS
Overall, we achieved much of what we set out to accomplish. We served our customers well, invested wisely with an eye toward the future, advocated for improvements within the industry, and continued to deliver value to you, our shareholders. The results of these efforts include:
■ Serving 24.2 million clients worldwide,
■ Delivering top line revenue growth for the third consecutive year, as total revenues
increased $54 million, or 1.8%, to $3.1 billion,
■ Growing DIY revenues 12% and tax return volume 8%,
■ Maintaining strong EBITDA margins of approximately 31%, while still investing in the business, and
■ Paying our 211th consecutive quarterly dividend, continuing our strong history of allocating capital to our shareholders.
LOOKING AHEAD
As we prepare for H&R Block’s future, we will capitalize on our successes and continue our focus on profitable growth. “We Do the Right Thing” is more than just a value statement on a poster. It is how we conduct business. We believe in our people. We take care of our clients. We deliver for our shareholders. By keeping these values front and center in all we do, we are well positioned to deliver strong results for our clients and our shareholders next year and for years to come.
Thank you for the confidence and support you’ve shown in H&R Block. I look forward to sharing our continuing success with you in the years ahead.
Sincerely yours,
William C. Cobb
President and CEO, H&R Block, Inc.
 