  JOHN J. GREISCH
PRESIDENT AND CEO, HILL‐ROM
TO OUR FELLOW SHAREHOLDERS, EMPLOYEES AND CUSTOMERS
By nearly every measure, fiscal 2016 was a record-setting year for our company. Hill-Rom achieved record sales and profitability while strengthening our foundation for future growth.
We successfully integrated Welch Allyn, deepened our customer partnerships, continued to streamline our operations and solidified our three global businesses: Patient Support Systems, Surgical Solutions and Front Line Care.
Our global organization and leadership structure is firmly in place and I could not be more pleased with the team we have assembled around the world.
We have reorganized around our three global businesses, each one of which continues to deliver first‐to‐market technologies to patients and their caregivers, consistent with our Mission and Hill‐Rom’s rich heritage of innovation.
The performance highlighted in the pages that follow would not have been achievable without the hard work and dedication of the more than 10,000 Hill‐Rom colleagues who choose to make a difference for the more than 7 million patients and caregivers who touch our products every day. To all of our colleagues around the world, thank you.
WORLDWIDE REVENUE
34%
 DOMESTIC REVENUE
44%
 INTERNATIONAL REVENUE
  FINANCIAL HIGHLIGHTS
Worldwide revenue for fiscal 2016 was $2.7 billion, which represented growth of 34 percent compared to fiscal 2015. Domestic revenue of $1.8 billion increased 44 percent, and revenue outside the United States of $826 million increased 15 percent.
For fiscal 2016, Hill‐Rom reported earnings of $1.86 per diluted share compared to $0.82 per diluted share in the prior‐year period. On an adjusted
15%
 HILL-ROM 2016 LETTER TO SHAREHOLDERS
basis, we increased our earnings by
28 percent to $3.38 per diluted share, compared to $2.64 per diluted share in the prior‐year period.
We are focused on improving our profitability, and are pleased to
report that in fiscal 2016 gross margin expanded by 300 basis points to 47.3 percent, while operating margin improved to 8.7 percent. On an adjusted basis, gross margin expanded by
280 basis points to 48.1 percent and operating margin expanded by 350 basis points to 15.3 percent.
Fiscal 2016 operating cash flow increased $67 million, or 32 percent, to $281 million, a new record level for the company. As a result of strong cash flow generation the company was able to reduce its debt by $101 million during the year, while returning $44 million to shareholders through our dividend.
                               
   CLINICAL FOCUS AREAS AND GLOBAL BUSINESS UNITS
Welch Allyn® monitoring and diagnostic products and services have broadened and strengthened our clinical offerings, complementing many of our product lines, especially those of our Clinical Workflow Solutions business. As a result, we have updated our Clinical Focus Areas accordingly:
 ADVANCING MOBILITY: Reducing immobility‐ related complications, patient falls and caregiver injuries, while improving the practice of caregiving.
WOUND
CARE AND PREVENTION: Preventing and treating pressure injuries and promoting wound healing.
PATIENT MONITORING AND DIAGNOSTICS: Giving caregivers accurate, consistent information through connected devices.
SURGICAL SAFETY AND EFFICIENCY: Improving staff and patient safety and procedural efficiency in the surgical suite.
RESPIRATORY HEALTH: Reducing the
risk of respiratory complications.
All of our collective energies — from product development and manufacturing to delivery and service — are organized around these Clinical Focus Areas through the following three global business units:
PATIENT SUPPORT SYSTEMS,
which includes our bed frames, surfaces, Liko patient lifts and Clinical Workflow Solutions businesses.
SURGICAL SOLUTIONS,
which is comprised of Trumpf Medical, Allen Medical and Aspen Surgical.
FRONT LINE CARE,
which includes Welch Allyn as well as our Respiratory Care business.
HILL-ROM 2016 LETTER TO SHAREHOLDERS

  OPERATING HIGHLIGHTS
Complementing the company’s strong financial performance were a number of significant achievements, continuing our company’s long heritage of product and medical technology innovation. These achievements allowed us to successfully grow our company to better meet the needs of patients and their caregivers around the world. While fiscal 2016 was noteworthy for our strong financial performance, we strengthened the company in several important ways:
• Successfully integrated Welch Allyn, following the acquisition in September 2015, resulting in a combined organization with greater diversification, scale, resources and broader geographic reach to drive improved patient care, lower costs and efficiency gains for our customers.
• Invested in innovative products and service solutions, capitalizing on a number of product introductions to drive accelerated future growth, such as:
− Integrated Table Motion for the da Vinci® Xi® Surgical System in the United States in collaboration with Intuitive Surgical. The surgical robot and Trumpf MedicalTM TruSystemTM 7000dv operating table seamlessly integrate allowing surgeons and anesthesiologists — for the first time — to make a comprehensive range of table adjustments easily and efficiently during da Vinci Surgery.
− Welch Allyn® RetinaVueTM 100 Imager, a breakthrough handheld technology that makes diabetic retinopathy screening simple and affordable for primary care settings. Diabetic retinopathy is the leading cause of blindness among working‐age adults because
it often goes undetected. With early detection and treatment, as much as 95 percent of vision loss cases can be prevented.1
− Welch Allyn® Connex® Spot Monitor, an easy‐to‐use, full‐ color touchscreen monitor that provides comprehensive and accurate patient vital signs (blood pressure measurement, pulse oximetry for assessing respiratory conditions, and thermometry) documentation using a single device.
− The VisiVestTM Airway Clearance System, a connected therapeutic solution for patients with chronic lung disease that is designed to help inform decisions caregivers make for their patients, resulting in reduced risk of respiratory infections, hospitalizations and medical costs.
• Improved our cost competitiveness by further consolidating Hill‐Rom’s global manufacturing network. We initiated or completed several manufacturing facility closures. In addition, the company’s recent acquisition of Tridien Medical, a manufacturer and developer of support surfaces and patient positioning devices, allows for insourcing of a significant supply function that is expected to further streamline supply chain operations.
• Optimizing the company’s product portfolio with the divestiture of non‐core products, including WatchChild®, an integrated perinatal data management system. This divestiture, along with others contemplated for 2017, will allow the company to focus resources on core strategic growth platforms.
TRUMPF MEDICALTM TRUSYSTEMTM 7000DV OPERATING TABLE
   WELCH ALLYN® RETINAVUETM 100 IMAGER
 WELCH ALLYN® CONNEX® SPOT MONITOR
 1. Facts About Diabetic Eye Disease; The National Eye Institute (NEI); https://nei.nih.gov/health/diabetic/retinopathy.
THE VISIVESTTM AIRWAY CLEARANCE SYSTEM

  EVERY DAY, AROUND THE WORLD, WE ENHANCE OUTCOMES FOR PATIENTS AND THEIR CAREGIVERS.
   LOOKING AHEAD
Hill‐Rom’s focus on differentiated and connected solutions that improve patient care is an integral part of our strategy. Our R&D, Engineering, Manufacturing and Marketing colleagues are collaborating to develop new products
and services across our Patient Support Systems, Surgical Solutions and Front Line Care businesses that will further expand and enhance our customer partnerships, and help them solve the challenges they face.
Fiscal 2016 was an eventful and exciting year for Hill‐Rom and our more than 10,000 colleagues around the world.
I encourage you to visit ir.hill-rom.com to learn more about all we accomplished this past year. I speak for all of us at Hill‐Rom when I say that we are proud of what we’ve accomplished and are humbled, honored and energized by our company’s impact on the patients and caregivers who rely on our products.
We remain deeply committed to our mission: Every day, around the world, we enhance outcomes for patients and their caregivers. Thank you for supporting our work in fiscal 2016 and in the years to come.
JOHN J. GREISCH
PRESIDENT AND CEO, HILL‐ROM January 2017
                                 