  Dear Shareholders,
It is with great pride that I look back at the accomplishments of our more than 10,000 Associates who have contributed to Lennar’s record financial performance in 2003 with revenues of approximately $9 billion, net earnings of $751 million, earnings per share of $4.65(1), a return on net capital of 23% and a return on beginning equity of 34%.
Stuart Miller
President and Chief Executive Officer, Lennar Corporation
  Our results for fiscal year 2003 provide continued evidence of the underlying strength of our Company. Not merely because of our record financial performance in both our Homebuilding and Financial Services operations, but because at the same time, we have improved the overall quality of the homes that we delivered and increased the overall satisfaction of our Customers.
As fiscal 2004 commences, we will continue to build upon a strong foundation created by last year’s performance. With $1.2 billion of cash and a net debt to total capital ratio of 9.7% at year-end, we are well positioned to continue as a leader in the industry. Our balance sheet remains strong and our leverage is at a histori- cally low level which positions the Company both for possible adverse market conditions and
for capitalizing on market inefficiencies and opportunities as they arise.
Today, we find a homebuilding industry that is very different from the one of years past. It truly is an industry that has reinvented itself from the 1980s and early 1990s. What was once an industry populated by a group of local and regional builders pulled together by a corporate nucleus and defined by a market that was typically cyclical has evolved into a very sophisticated industry populated by large public builders that are now disciplined and efficiently run companies that are prepared to react to any given market condition.
These companies today are corporately governed and financially driven with excellent management
(1) AdjustedforJanuary2004two-for-onestocksplit.
LENNAR CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT

   How does Lennar consistently achieve uncommon results on a regular basis?
How does Lennar consistently achieve uncommon results on a regular basis?
Discipline
LENNAR CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
 • We are a process driven Company
• Our unique process has been in place for years
• Consistently applied across the Company
  The Way We Manage
☞
Strong Balance Sheet
Building
a Better Company
Purchase Assets Below Market and Pare Down
Seasoned Management
Focused Management
Review • Do • Review
☞
Everyone Focused on Returns
Disciplined Financial Management
Carefully Managed Asset Levels
Culture and Leadership Development
Simple and Consistent Controls
  Focus on Integration
Identify Market Inefficiencies
The Way We Grow
  The Way We Achieve Results
☞
Target Net Debt to Total Capital 35%-45%
EPS Growth Target 15% or Higher
 Disciplined adherence to our simple and consistent process has enabled Lennar to generate extraordinary results on a predictable basis. Our process has provided consistency as we have expanded across the country.
  
 Conor Patrick at Fallston Crossing Baltimore Market

 teams and systems in place that effectively control and monitor how they operate. The controls that are now in place for the large public builders that are delivering 10,000 to 35,000 homes per year are sophisticated enough to allow them to continue to grow and comfortably run their businesses even at the 50,000 to 100,000 homes per year levels.
The evolution of homebuilders to large public growth companies is significant. This growth facilitates leveraging market share to drive growth and control future land supply. Additionally, this well-managed growth uses market share gains to improve our building processes and drive down costs while improving quality.
As you look at the large public builders and consid- er what differentiates one from the other, we would like to encourage you to specifically “Ask about Lennar” and find out what we feel defines our unique personality. We feel it is a compelling story and a story that must begin by first asking about the following five key areas where we believe we stand apart from the rest of the industry:
1. Our Business Process - The way we at Lennar have run our business has been consistent for many years. It is a process that is defined by how we manage, how we grow and how we achieve results.
The way we manage is all about people. We are focused on simplicity and consistency with all of our Divisions measured against the same set of standards, all contributing to the bottom line of our Company. The way we manage begins with our seasoned management team, continues with our simple controls, is enhanced by our review-do-review process and is nurtured with our leadership development training.
The way we grow is opportunity driven and is dependent on the strength of our balance sheet. It is focused on our ability to define market inef- ficiencies, enhanced by our ability to purchase assets below market values and then pare them down, and our relentless focus on integration. Our due diligence process and bottom line expectations have consistently resulted in successful acquisitions and organic growth.
 LENNAR CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
SHAREHOLDERS LETTER

    What does it mean to be a "Balance Sheet First" Company?
What does it mean to be a "Balance Sheet First" Company?
Focus
• Liquidity drives long-term growth while we maintain earnings growth
• Diversified long-term debt provides long-term stability
• Due diligence yields conservatively stated asset base
LENNAR CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
 Average Net Debt to Total Capital
31%
1998 to 2003 Growth Rates
Annualized EPS Growth Rate
33%
     We run our Company as an investment grade credit. We believe the standards that define "investment grade" are also the standards that will define the long-term growth of our Company. Lennar focuses on a strong balance sheet as the foundation for all business activity. While we consistently improve earnings and earnings per share, and while we maintain high return on capital standards, we simultaneously fortify our balance sheet with well-purchased assets, a varied maturity of long- term debt and a focus on increasing equity and liquidity.
  ☞
Annualized Return on Net Capital 18%

 Coronado at Spanish Springs Las Vegas Market

 And, the results we achieve are driven by a “whole Company” focus on return on net assets. That focus, along with an EPS growth target of 15% or higher, our careful attention to managing asset levels and our target net debt to total capital ratio of 35% to 45%, all allow us to consistently achieve extraordinary results year-after-year.
2. Our Balance Sheet - Lennar has always been a balance sheet first Company. A Company with one foot on the accelerator and one foot on the brake - the accelerator being our EPS goal and the brake our conservative leverage and focus on liquidity. We know that the strong values embedded in our carefully purchased assets leave us well positioned to catapult forward, while the liquidity embedded in our balance sheet allows us to continue to grow when opportunities present themselves.
We ended 2003 with a strong, healthy balance sheet, with a net debt to total capital ratio of 9.7% and approximately $1.2 billion of cash. This position, combined with our diversified debt structure, allows us to be very nimble and flexible as we move forward.
3. Growth - Our Focus on Finding Market Inefficiencies - With a return on net capital that well exceeds our cost of capital, we are in a very healthy position to continue to take advantage of market inefficiencies and to create future oppor- tunities for our Company.
We are well diversified both geographically and product-wise. With homebuilding operations in 42 markets, with homes ranging in price from below $100,000 in Texas to over $1 million in California, and with communities ranging from Active Adult communities catering to the needs of retirees to urban infill communities targeted to those who enjoy the urban lifestyle, and with our Dual Marketing strategy, we are able to employ an extremely diversified approach to growth.
On the one hand, we have focused on strong organic growth with an outstanding due diligence focused land acquisition team. On the other hand, we have focused on strong acquisitive growth with numerous successful acquisitions that we combine quickly to create a better Company.
      LENNAR CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
SHAREHOLDERS LETTER

 What’s unique about Lennar’s growth strategy?
 LENNAR CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
What’s unique about Lennar’s growth strategy?
Diversity
• We have employed many different ways to invest capital and grow
• Opportunity and returns define how we grow at any time
• Vast experience in integrating new growth
Growth Strategy
MULTIPLE WAYS TO INVEST:
     Organic Growth
Acquire New Communities One by One
Growth Through Acquisitions
Acquire 2nd Half of Dual Marketing In Existing Markets
   Acquire New Communities via Acquisition
Industry Consolidation
Build a Better Company
A diverse growth strategy is a distinct advantage as the homebuilding industry continues to consolidate. Lennar has grown both organically and through acquisitions in order to expand in existing markets, expand geo- graphically or expand product mix and type. Because we have a vast array of experience and expertise, we can maximize opportunity by growing in the manner that affords the best yield, rather than being forced to find yield in only one way at all times.
Enter New Markets via Acquisition
    
 The Pesade
Colorado Springs Market

 Whether we complete acquisitions of larger companies like The Newhall Land and Farming Company or smaller companies like the many homebuilders we acquired in the past two years, our experience and product offering affords us the ability to continue to be opportunistic in the future. As new opportunities present themselves, whether they are acquiring land, acquiring other homebuilders or repurchasing our own stock, we will have the ability and the resources to react.
4. Our Dual Marketing Strategy - At Lennar, we find great strength and opportunity in our unique Dual Marketing strategy. Our Everything’s Included® program offers great value and a simple home buying process while our Design StudioSM program offers our Customers the opportunity to personalize their homes through a central Design StudioSM location. In our Dual Marketing communities, both programs operate in the same location, independently and efficiently, side-by-side while competing head-to-head.
Our Dual Marketing strategy allows us to leverage the cost of the land that we buy and absorb land faster than if we were marketing under just one
platform. In addition, our Dual Marketing strategy also allows us to leverage our marketing dollars from both platforms and achieve efficiencies through advertising and signage.
We currently have Dual Marketing communities in place in 19 of our 42 markets in the country, with plans to roll out the program in every market in which we operate. Our current positioning, broad array of product offerings and local management teams that are already in place will allow us to do so swiftly and efficiently.
5. Our Unique Lennar Culture - We know and fully understand that it is the strength of our Culture, the effectiveness of it as a communication tool and the importance that it brings to everything we do at Lennar, that produces the consistent results that we have achieved over many years.
Our record of success in bringing many new companies into the Lennar Family of Builders over the years is a testament to our Culture and has also made us an attractive partner on a go forward basis for other builders and developers. We are not only a source of capital for them but
   LENNAR CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
SHAREHOLDERS LETTER

 What is Dual Marketing?
 LENNAR CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
What is Dual Marketing?
Competition
• Competing Lennar products in the same community
• Enhanced absorption rates with market share gains
• Higher return on invested capital
Everything’s Included®
• Simplicity and value to the customer • Personalize, not customize home • Efficient production schedule
Design StudioSM
• Provide opportunity to buyers to choose
interior and exterior features
• Implement via custom design studios
Side-by-side competition promotes greater traffic and greater asset turnover. In fast food, auto sales and retailing, competitors operate across the street in order to bring the traffic to a particular location. By operating competing programs under the Lennar umbrella, we define the new home location and capture a greater percentage of that traffic. As we sell more homes, we absorb land more efficiently with greater value, and therefore improve return on invested capital while we expand market share.
         
 Everest and Rushmore in Trueberry Bend Houston Market

 we provide a way to give their Associates a viable path for future growth. Our unique Lennar Culture is a primary tool in this process, allowing us to integrate new builders into our family by communicating our values, and our beliefs of who we are and what we stand for. Our Culture allows us to act as one cohesive family while rewarding individual initiatives and achievements. Our Culture lets everyone know that at any given moment, they are both a leader and a member of a great team.
Our business process, our balance sheet, our growth and focus on finding market inefficiencies, our Dual Marketing strategy and our Culture differentiate us, define our unique personality, and position us well as we move ahead to a successful future. While the homebuilding industry is positioned to continue to thrive as a growth industry, Lennar is well positioned within the homebuilding industry to grow and continue to achieve excellent results in the future. Our growth is focused on building not just a bigger Company, but an even better Company.
We encourage you to continue to “Ask about Lennar” as we move forward and we look forward to the opportunity to continue to share our story.
In closing, I would like to thank all of our Shareholders, Associates and Business Partners for their contributions to another outstanding year for the Lennar Family of Builders and Financial Services. We look forward to building upon our success of this past year and upon our foundation created over the past 50 years.
Sincerely,
Stuart Miller
President and Chief Executive Officer, Lennar Corporation
 LENNAR CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
SHAREHOLDERS LETTER
