 2– 3
From left to right: Christopher E. Kubasik, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer; Maryanne R. Lavan, Vice President, Ethics and Business Conduct; Arthur E. Johnson, Senior
Vice President, Strategic Development.
From left to right: Linda R. Gooden, President, Lockheed Martin Information Technology; Michael F. Camardo, Executive Vice President, Information & Technology Services.
Dear Fellow Shareholders,
With pride, I am able to report to you the remarkable accomplishments of the 130,000 men and women of Lockheed Martin over the past year. In extending the fundamentally sound strategy of disciplined growth, this management team has aligned our core strengths with specifically targeted markets. This approach to managing our business has resulted in solid sales growth, improved profitability and consistent cash generation.
Lockheed Martin is an extraordinarily innovative enterprise with all the qualities of a premier advanced technology leader, and we will continue to drive this competitive distinction in the years ahead.
For 2004, we established and met ambitious goals; it was our fourth consecutive year of operating margin improvement. We increased sales to a record $35.5 billion, a 12 percent increase over 2003, and we can report a backlog of $74 billion. In 2004, Lockheed Martin also generated a record $2.9 billion in operating cash. Effective cash deployment remains a priority. Since January 2000, we have reduced our debt from $12 billion to $5 billion, adding to financial flexibility and strength.
In 2004, we repurchased 14.7 million shares of our common stock, and we have repurchased 26.4 million shares since late 2002. We also delivered on our commitment to shareholders in 2004 by increasing the dividend by 14 percent. We view dividends as an important component of shareholder value, and will review the dividend annually.
Although financial results for the year have well met our expectations, we are far from complacent. In fact, during 2004, we continued using Return on Invested Capital (ROIC) as one of our key metrics for measuring financial performance, showing an improvement to 11.9 percent. In 2005, the ROIC performance metric will be a significant part of the evaluation measures for executive incentive compensation.
Our industry and customers’ environments are constantly changing. We face challenges in 2005 and the years ahead as defense budgets are adjusted and spending priorities are reconsidered. We are determined to stay ahead of those changes by continued focus on the performance excellence and technology leadership our customers deserve and expect.
Over the past year, we have talked about our adherence to an operating principle we call Horizontal Integration — the practice of making Lockheed Martin truly one company and one team with a unified vision supported by coherent and aligned business processes. Horizontal Integration means reaching across the breadth of this Corporation to develop the very best forward-looking solutions for our customers’ needs. In 2004, we applied the experience and leadership we have resident throughout this Corporation to deliver truly transformational technologies.

 LOCKHEED MARTIN ANNUAL REPORT 2004
From left to right: Katherine Kerchner, Vice President, Finance & Business Operations, Integrated Systems & Solutions; Stan D. Sloane, Executive Vice President, Integrated Systems
& Solutions; Ron M. Nakamoto, Vice President & General Manager of Intelligence Systems, Integrated Systems & Solutions.
For example, we will satisfy a critical military requirement for persistent airborne surveillance and reconnais- sance with the Aerial Common Sensor. In addition, the Warfighter Information Network – Tactical (WIN-T) will provide forces with mobile, high-speed, highly secure communications. We extended our collaboration with industry on these programs.
These systems directly address the Department of Defense’s priority for network-enabled systems that can bring new capabilities to the battlespace. The progress we have made in network-enabled capabilities is burnishing our reputation as a large-scale systems integrator with strengths not only in the platform components of the network but in all aspects of its architecture.
In 2005, we will open the Lockheed Martin Center for Innovation in Suffolk, Virginia, which will be crucial to developing the advanced technology solutions of the future. Participants at the Center and at any point in our Global Vision Network will have simultaneous access to data, simulations and rich analytical tools and processes as they work together. The Lockheed Martin Center for Innovation is indicative of the passion for invention that runs through this Corporation at all levels, and our commitment to reinvest in our enterprise. We are a company of 50,000 dedicated engineers and scientists with systems and software engineering capabilities independently assessed as among the best in the world.
We are committed to the development of new technologies that can be directly applied to the customers’ requirements in any of our three core markets: Defense/Intelligence, Homeland Security and Federal Government agencies with a focus on Information Technology (IT). With about 25 percent of our sales in the IT field, Lockheed Martin is the largest provider of IT solutions and services to the U.S. government.
Lockheed Martin management will look for smart acquisitions, but we are setting the bar appropriately high for quality, strategic fit and return on invested capital. That means we are looking for congruence with core competen- cies, alignment with our businesses, ease of integration and superior cash returns.
In 2004, we acquired Sippican Holdings Inc., a supplier of naval electronics systems. Sippican’s expertise in surface ship countermeasures, anti-submarine warfare training and submarine communications systems will enhance our global capabilities in naval warfare, unmanned underwater vehicles and low-cost manufacturing. Turning to divestitures, in 2004 we sold our interest in New Skies and Comsat General, two satellite services companies, and early this year sold our interest in Intelsat. In 2004, we terminated our merger agreement with Titan Corporation, as Titan did not satisfy all the closing conditions.

 4– 5
The past year has been marked not only by financial performance but by strong operational performance
as well. In one program central to U.S. Air Force modernization, the Lockheed Martin-led F/A-22 industry team reached a new level of program maturity with reliable production, solid performance and expanding capabilities. The U.S. Air Force recently completed a successful Initial Operational Test and Evaluation, satisfying the service’s requirement for an advanced air dominance combat aircraft that will be mission-capable for decades to come.
A Lockheed Martin team also completed key milestones on the Space-Based Infrared System (SBIRS) High,
a next-generation missile warning system. In 2004, Singapore became the 11th nation to participate in the F-35 Joint Strike Fighter program. The program also began worldwide production to build the first Systems Development and Demonstration aircraft. The successful Patriot Advanced Capability (PAC-3) flight test program in 2004 validated the system’s capability to engage multiple missile threats.
We enjoyed some impressive competitive wins in 2004 including:
❚ A contract to design and build the first of the U.S. Navy’s new Littoral Combat Ships
❚ A contract to build the MUOS narrow-band tactical satellite communications system for the U.S. Navy
❚ A five-year Information Technology contract from the Environmental Protection Agency
❚ A seven-year contract to provide information technology support to the Social Security Administration,
continuing a long-term partnership to help the agency meet its challenges for the future
❚ Leadership of a team to provide managed network services — including video, data, voice and wireless —
across the entire U.S. Postal Service under its Universal Computing Connectivity program
❚ The majority of launch vehicle contracts awarded worldwide, including orders for six Atlas V and six
Proton missions
The year did have some disappointments. A U.S. District Court ruling upheld the termination for default of the Pit 9 environmental remediation contract. The court concluded that Lockheed Martin must repay progress payments with interest, as well as cover decontamination and decommissioning costs. This impact was reflected in our 2004 financial results.
From left to right: Ralph D. Heath, Executive Vice President, Aeronautics; Lee E. Rhyant, Executive Vice President and Site General Manager, Marietta; Tom Burbage, Executive Vice President and General Manager, F-35 Joint Strike Fighter Program Integration; June R. Shrewsbury, Vice President, F-16 Programs.

 LOCKHEED MARTIN ANNUAL REPORT 2004
From left to right: Tom Marsh, Executive Vice President, Space Systems; Joanne M. Maguire, Vice President & Deputy, Space Systems.
From left to right: Jim Thomas, Vice President, Operations & Supply Chain Management; Carol Hulgus, Vice President of Programs, Lockheed Martin Maritime Systems & Sensors; Robert B. Coutts, Executive Vice President, Electronic Systems.
In a successful company such as ours, every employee shares a vision of how best to serve our customers at their defining moments. We place a premium on people development and opportunity. Foremost, we are dedicated to assuring an environment of inclusion, because diversity adds strategic depth to our company and in doing so we all become stronger. In the coming year, we will continue to focus on talent development, including utilizing the training facilities of our Center for Leadership Excellence.
No company can address future opportunities successfully without a top-down dedication to ethical and sound business practices. Ethics is the foundation of our enterprise and is not negotiable. It is a responsibility that cannot be delegated and belongs to every employee. The world we live in will not accept anything less and neither should we. As a management team, we want to recognize both Norm Augustine’s and Vance Coffman’s longstanding and selfless dedication to this enterprise and its shareholders as they retire from the Board this year. We wish them the best and salute their years of service.
In a post 9/11 world, our customers are counting on us more than ever, not just in distant lands abroad, but here at home as well. What we do will make a difference to the future of America and the free world. Our men and women in uniform deserve the very best in product and commitment. We are honored to serve the United States armed forces and our allies, and I am particularly gratified to report that our company and its employees contributed more than $600,000 in 2004 to Operation USO Care Package.
In closing, 2004 was a critical year validating that our investments and strategy are aligned with our customers’ vision. Our operational and financial performance reached new levels last year, and we approach 2005 with signifi- cant opportunities for growth. We are well positioned to continue to improve earnings and shareholder value. Powered by innovation and guided by integrity, Lockheed Martin is meeting customer commitments, achieving schedules, and paying attention to cost and quality — all the basics of business success.
March 1, 2005
Robert J. Stevens
President and Chief Executive Officer
