     Dear Fellow Shareholder:
We began 2000 with firm commitments to serve customers better, improve financial performance, manage for cash, drive operational improvements, and improve planning quality.
Also, around the globe corporations continue to consolidate resulting in enterprises of unprecedentedly large scale and complexity, whose appetite for comprehensive solutions based on the application of advanced technology is also rapidly expanding. Here too our competencies can be applied. Our actions will be guided by a disciplined focus on customers and markets that value total systems solutions, enabling us to consistently generate returns above the cost of capital.
We are pleased to report that we have met these commitments and, in so doing, have achieved significantly higher levels of customer satisfaction and enhanced shareholder value. We exceeded all financial goals set
for 2000, including achieving record orders and backlog, record free cash flow generation, substantial debt reduction, and the receipt of full and fair value for our divestitures.
More than any other attribute, however, the degree to which we continue to build our value based performance culture will determine our future and the well being of the customers we are committed to serve. We assembled this Corporation to perform, and we are going to do so. As we leverage the fully integrated resources of “Team Lockheed Martin”, performance is our key discriminator and shareholder value our key measure. The heritage
of where we’ve been individually is much less important than the future we create together.
Of nearly 550 operational and developmental “Mission Success” events measured, 95% were successful.
Two other important measures of customer satisfaction and confidence—award fees for current programs and orders representing future business—each increased substantially during 2000. Average award fees increased from 85% in 1999 to 93% in 2000, while we received more than $37 billion in new orders during 2000, some 33% higher than 1999. As a result, backlog expanded from $45.9 billion at the end of 1999 to $56.4 billion at the end of 2000, an increase of 23%. We believe that the realignment of our businesses, and careful focus by sen- ior executive leadership and our dedicated employees directly contributed to this performance. This realignment was intended to increase accountability throughout our organization while, at the same time, intensify the focus
on our customers as we deliver consistency and quality. We are gratified that our customers continue to place such trust in us, and fulfilling their needs remains our number one priority.
As we create that future, we are first committed to achieving continuous operational improvements, including increased profit margins, with commensurate increases to free cash flow generation. Our goal of driving operating margins toward double-digit performance levels remains and we have challenged our entire leadership team to contribute to this very demanding objective. As we work additional pathways to profitability, we remain committed to our average annual recurring EPS expansion goal of 15% to 25%.
In 2000, we committed the Corporation to managing for cash and reducing debt. Free cash flow increased from approximately $875 million in 1999 to $1.8 billion in 2000, our best performance ever. This accomplishment was achieved mainly through the reduction of days working capital as we focused on the management of receiv- ables, customer advances, payables and inventory throughout all our business areas. By combining free cash flow with the $2 billion of cash proceeds from our divestitures, we reduced our debt by $2 billion and increased our cash invested by $1 billion. This brought our net-debt-to-capital ratio down from 64% to 54% and we are making rapid progress toward bringing this ratio within a preferred range of 40% to 50%. In 2000, we committed to drive operational improvements and improve planning quality. Our LM-21 Operating Excellence Program has been significantly expanded to all elements of our enterprise. Our annual savings targets are now $3.7 billion. We have expanded the use of shared services across all our business areas to drive savings and efficiencies from using com- mon practices, reengineered processes, and e-commerce-based management tools in our administrative functions. In September of 2000 the aerospace and defense business-to-business exchange named “Exostar􏺟”, of which we were a founding partner, was activated. Our streamlining initiatives in Aeronautics and Space are providing additional annual savings of approximately $200 million, and our business planning process is sound as we met or exceeded all projections in 2000. We provided our shareholders with a total return of 58% for 2000.
Second, we must sustain our disciplined deployment of cash. We have made good progress on restoring flexi- bility and accelerating a return to a targeted net debt to total capital range of 40% to 50%, and we will continue to rigorously prioritize investments to assure the adequacy of returns.
Looking forward, we see opportunities as well as risks and challenges. We have defined a set of leadership and management imperatives that will extend our vision, evolve our strategy, and further drive our culture of per- formance as we continue the transition from recovery to disciplined growth and sustained value creation.
In closing, we are proud of our leadership team and the 130,000 Lockheed Martin professionals for their performance in 2000. It was, by every measure, a very good start to this millennium. We have the energy and excitement of being affiliated with a truly wonderful, high performance enterprise and we are committed to building on the momentum we have created as we drive forward to apply increasingly sophisticated technologies through integrated systems solutions to meet our customers’ most demanding challenges. This is a great company...our company...Lockheed Martin. While year 2000 was a year of recovery, we are sure our best days remain
ahead of us.
We continue to pursue our goal of being the world’s best systems integrator. We believe our proven com- petencies and capabilities, which enable the seamless integration and exploitation of complex technologies, will be under increasing demand. Governments are increasingly likely to turn to private sector partners for solutions to national and global challenges. It is our objective to be the partner of choice that has driven us to aggressively realign customer interfaces, streamline operations, reduce costs, enhance responsiveness, expand support, focus on innovation, and deliver as promised. Through our systems and information technology skills, we intend to meet our commitment to be the preferred private sector partner and superior infrastructure supplier to the
U.S. Government.
March 1, 2001
45
Third, we must concentrate on achieving higher levels of profitable organic growth in our businesses that have demonstrated the ability to consistently achieve solid profit margins and returns.
And fourth, we must continue to examine an array of strategic actions to enhance shareholder value. We will follow through with our exploration of alternatives for our state and local services business, as well as examining the best ways to yield value from Global Telecommunications. Such businesses require strategic partners, outside capital and entrepreneurial management to achieve their full potential. We have reported to you on imbalances between capacity and market demand in selected businesses and markets, and will work to resolve those imbalances provided shareholder value considerations are preserved. And we remain firmly committed to generating additional value by increasing the return on our intellectual capital through the more aggressive management of “technology mining” activities. Working with venture capital firms, we completed several transactions in the year 2000 to create startup companies in which we hold significant equity stakes.
Vance D. Coffman
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
Robert J. Stevens
President and Chief Operating Officer
