04
DEAR ManpowerGroup Shareholder,
ManpowerGroup had a good year in 2016, and our foresight, strategic focus and purposeful actions delivered very good results in a challenging, slow-growth environment with rising geopolitical uncertainty.
OUR PERSPECTIVE
Now more than ever, organizations need to be able to adapt to rapidly changing circumstances and plan for unpredictability. People need to be able to upskill and reskill to stay relevant and employable as skills cycles change faster than ever. Political instability and populist shifts impacting the UK, parts of Europe and the U.S. have their roots in the forces that ManpowerGroup has been describing for the last decade as the Human Age—shifting demographics, greater individual choice, client sophistication and technological revolution. The results are playing out in front of our eyes, and 2016 has been a tipping point when these structural changes produced upheaval in many parts of the global economy. We are seeing the polarization of communities and the bifurcation of the workforce between the Haves and the Have Nots. Those that have in-demand skills can take advantage of these shifts, and those with low or outdated skills cannot see how their circumstances will improve.
Business Line Gross Profit
 TOTAL $3.3
($ in billions)
■ Manpower 2.1 ■ Experis 0.7 ■ ManpowerGroup Solutions 0.4 ■ Right Management 0.1

 Operating Profit 2016 Revenues
increased by* increased by* EPS improved by*
+11% +4% +19%
*All figures in constant currency
As we anticipate more geopolitical uncertainty and continued technological change in the Human Age, the need for our capabilities and our role in society is as clear as it was when our company was founded almost 70 years ago. Our role is clear, but it is different. Today, we are seeing the emergence of a Skills Revolution where helping organizations and people adapt to a fast-changing world of work will be the defining challenge of our time. We need new ways to develop a skilled workforce that ensures organizations have the people with the skills required for the future. In times of tightening labor markets and shrinking workforces in many developed markets, we also need to do more to draw in those not fully able to participate to better contribute to growth and prosperity.
In 2016, ManpowerGroup has demonstrated that we are well-placed to provide people with the experience and opportunities they need to be resilient and to chart career paths in a fast-changing world of work, while providing robust solutions that allow companies the strategic flexibility and skilled talent they need to be nimble and successful. Our deep understanding of the labor market together with our duality of purpose— creating value for our shareholders while providing meaningful employment for millions—has proven we know how to adapt and succeed in times of great disruptive change.
OUR PERFORMANCE
Revenues increased by 4% in constant currency over 2015. Operating profit reached $751 million, up 11% in constant currency and 9% excluding 2015 restructuring costs. Our operating profit margin was 3.8%, while earnings per share reached a record $6.27 per share for the year, improving 19% in constant currency.
We remained focused on organic growth with strong performances from our Solutions business, accom- plishing another year of double digit growth, and our permanent recruitment business, responsible for 14.7% of our gross profit in 2016.
We also demonstrated the global capabilities of our strong and connected brands, including an historic collaboration as Official Supplier for the Rio Summer Olympic Games, where we recruited and placed more than 15,000 talented workers.
ManpowerGroup / Annual Report 2016 / 05

 06
Manpower delivered solid performance in 2016, ending the year with gross profit growth of 2% in constant currency. We expanded our Centers of Recruiting Excellence (CORE) teams across the world as the need rises for expedited sourcing of high-quality candidates, leveraging social media and advanced technology. Manpower also upped its commitment to developing talent, enhancing skills and earning potential with the launch of MyPath, providing U.S. associates with career coaching, upskilling opportunities and even full college tuition coverage.
Experis continued its trajectory of growth, increasing gross profit by 7% in constant currency. We also saw 11% permanent recruitment growth in constant currency in 2016, as employers increasingly seek to retain in-demand professionals with critical IT and finance skills. Experis further broadened its offerings with the acquisition of IT consulting and outsourcing capabilities in Norway and
the Netherlands.
Right Management gross profit decreased 5% in constant currency. Our global career expert business continued to lead with technology, expanding RightEverywhere®, its proprietary, digital, career development offering, to 48 countries and 15 languages, as well as the launch of P3, a comprehensive leadership model for developing stronger, more effective leaders.
ManpowerGroup Solutions again proved to be a powerful engine for organic growth, ending 2016 with gross profit growth of 11%
in constant currency. Our Recruitment Process Outsourcing (RPO) and TAPFIN Managed Service Provider (MSP) offerings performed well, both earning top honors from external analysts and named as global leaders in their field. Proservia maintained its momentum, successfully expanding our Solutions business across France and the rest of Europe.
                                                                     
OUR OPPORTUNITY
In this challenging, uncertain environment, our increasingly sophisticated clients require more diverse offerings and scalable solutions. Globalization and technology continue to disrupt business models and affect how people see their future prospects. ManpowerGroup’s value proposition has never been more relevant: our industry-leading global footprint, our strong and connected brands and our extensive workforce solutions portfolio mean we are well-positioned for this changing environment. We are not standing still. As expectations shift and increase, we will continue investing in the value creation our candidates and clients need most.
We are cementing our thought leadership by providing exclusive labor market insights with practical solutions around managing millennials, accelerating women into leadership and overcoming talent shortages which are at their highest since 2007. We are turning conversation into action and strengthening our relationship with partners like the World Economic Forum providing strategic guidance to their Global Councils on Employment, Skills and Gender, as well as Digital Transformation.
We are focused on innovating and identifying digital partnerships and platforms that will help us achieve speed, scale and accelerate success. With new tools and collaborations, we are transforming our business and leveraging areas that allow us to be more efficient and help our candidates and clients succeed.
This is the future of work. No one can slow the rate of technological advance or globalization. But we can invest in employees’ skills to increase the resilience of people and organizations. ManpowerGroup is ready with forward-thinking workforce solutions that explore new talent sources, people practices and work models, benefitting clients, job seekers and society at large. Never has our company’s purpose been more relevant: Meaningful, sustainable employment has the power to change the world.
OUR PEOPLE
The power behind our purpose is, of course, our people, who have made Doing Well by Doing Good the hallmark of their daily work since our doors first opened. This is what sustains our performance, enables our collaborative organization and contributed to record-high employee engagement in 2016. It is why we reaffirmed our commitment to talent development, succession planning and diversity.
We bid farewell to our former Chief Financial Officer, Michael Van Handel, retiring after 28 years with our company. We have benefitted enormously from his exemplary financial acumen, strategic discipline and leadership, capped by a successful and well-executed transition to Jack McGinnis, who succeeded Mike as CFO during 2016.
We also proudly introduced our Sustainability Plan defining the three pillars that together help people nurture learnability. Whether it’s our $70 million investment in employability programs or providing career guidance to more than 10 million people, ManpowerGroup is committed to responsive and responsible leadership. Intent on creating talent, not just sourcing people, we are getting people ready for work, job ready, not just graduate ready, upskilling people for the roles of today and tomorrow, and creating an inclusive and integrated workforce so people can bring their best selves to work.
ManpowerGroup / Annual Report 2016 / 07

 08
“In these turbulent times when things around us are shifting, we are proud that as a business we can grow and
adapt, while the values that made us succ”
beginning remain strong and unwavering.
We are skilling up ourselves, too. Our digital learning platform, powerYou, now supports 59,000 active learners with more than 7,500 virtual and blended learning courses, and our powerUDigital platform is live across Europe supporting the European Commission in equipping young people with eight key competencies needed in today’s world of work. Our Emerging Leaders Experience continues to develop our leaders of tomorrow through coaching, stretch assignments and peer interaction, with 80% of participants moving into new roles in 2016 and more leaders lined up for the 2017 series.
ManpowerGroup again earned many accolades last year. Most notably, we are the only company in our industry to be named World’s Most Ethical by Ethisphere and Fortune’s Most Admired. These honors recognize our team’s dedication to the same values and ethical foundation upon which our company was built.
As the leading global workforce solutions company,
we are ready to deliver on our responsibility: to help organizations and people succeed. In these turbulent times when things around us are shifting, we are proud that as a business we can grow and adapt, while the values that made us successful from the beginning remain strong and unwavering. With our talented team—expert, agile and passionate about what they do—we are ready to put millions of people to work, and help them acquire the skills they need because we believe meaningful, sustainable employment has the power to change the world. That
is our purpose and that is how we intend to grow our business in 2017 and beyond.
Jonas Prising
Chairman & CEO
essful from the
   