  Richard A. Fennessy
President and Chief Executive Officer
 ▼ Continuing Growth
DEAR TEAMMATES, PARTNERS AND SHAREHOLDERS:
Insight had a successful 2007, with overall financial results that exceeded our expectations. I’d like to thank our 4,700-plus Insight teammates for their hard work and commitment to positioning Insight as a leader in our industry. I’d also like to recognize the ongoing support of our valued clients and partners.
I’m pleased to report that our consolidated net sales for the full year 2007 were $4.8 billion, a 34 percent increase over 2006, while gross margin on these sales increased to 13.8 percent from 13.1 percent reported in 2006. Earnings from operations increased 25 percent to $126.1 million from $100.5 million in the prior year and net earnings from continuing operations grew 13 percent to $72.0 million from $63.7 million in 2006.
We are pleased with the overall financial performance of our business in 2007. Year over year, our North America segment grew its net sales by 18 percent and its earnings from operations by 6 percent. Our EMEA segment grew its net sales by 87 percent and its earnings from operations an even stronger 93 percent, while our APAC segment more than tripled its earnings from operations on a 260 percent increase in net sales. Earnings from operations of our EMEA and APAC segments accounted for more than 30 percent of our full year consolidated results for 2007, up from 18 percent in 2006. We believe that this is a clear proof point that our strategy to diversify our profitability profile by capitalizing on global demand is working quite well.
REFLECTING ON THREE YEARS OF PROGRESS
I would like to briefly reflect on the progress we have made over the last three years to realize our global trusted advisor vision and the effect those steps have had on our financial performance.
The execution of our trusted advisor vision continues to focus on:
• Growing profitable market share,
• Expanding our global footprint, and
• Continuing to build VAR-like solutions capabilities by gaining deep expertise in the high-growth areas of
enterprise software, high performance systems and networking and communications.
Below are a few comments about our progress in each of these focus areas:
GROWING PROFITABLE MARKET SHARE
Through a combination of organic and acquisitive growth, our business has grown significantly over the past few years on both the top line and, most notably, on the bottom line. Net sales have increased from $2.8 billion in 2004 to $4.8 billion in 2007, while gross profit margins have increased from 12 percent to 14 percent over the same period. Earnings from operations have nearly doubled from $67.6 million in 2004 to $126.1 million in 2007. These results reflect our transformation from a pure product fulfillment business to a global technology solutions business that includes a more profitable mix of sales from both a product category and geographic perspective.
EXPANDING OUR GLOBAL FOOTPRINT
In 2007, net sales outside of North America were approximately 30 percent of our consolidated net sales, up from roughly 16 percent in 2004. With the acquisition of Software Spectrum in September 2006, we now operate in 22 countries around the globe and, as a result, we have a broader international footprint than most of our competitors. As we experienced in 2007, our global footprint enables us to gain profitable market share by meeting the needs of our global clients and benefiting from the higher growth regions across the world.
DEVELOPING VAR-LIKE CAPABILITIES IN KEY IT SOLUTIONS AREAS
In order to deepen our relevance to our clients and secure more of their annual IT spend, we have pursued a focused strategy to develop or acquire deep expertise in the high-growth areas of enterprise software, high performance systems and networking and communications. While we continue to sell a wide array of products to our clients—the basic core of our business—we have taken very specific steps to secure more expertise in these solutions areas. Over the last three years, we have created a services organization within Insight
   
of more than 600 trusted IT advisors. These Insight teammates are dedicated to providing technical expertise from the beginning of the client engagement all the way through to the deployment of the IT solution within our clients’ businesses. In 2007, our services business generated approximately $108 million in net sales, up from $54 million in 2005.
Clearly, Insight has undergone a significant transformation over the last three years and throughout this change has delivered very strong financial results.
LOOKING AHEAD TO 2008
Looking ahead, our strategic and operational goals for 2008 will remain consistent with those we have been pursuing over the past several years. Specifically, we will:
• Continue to build out our VAR-like capabilities both organically and through targeted acquisitions like the Calence acquisition we announced in early 2008. Calence is a leading provider of networking solutions in the U.S., including networking products, professional services and managed services. This strategic acquisition will significantly enhance our technical capabilities around networking and will enable us to capture a leading position in the fast growing networking category.
• Additionally, we will continue to leverage existing client relationships. Over the past few quarters, we have been building metrics and tracking the progress of our efforts to cross-sell into our existing client base across our solutions sets of hardware, software and services. Our research shows that when a client buys across multiple categories, the net sales and profitability from that client increase significantly. We have established cross-selling as the mantra for our sales organization.
• Next, we will develop and implement a strategy to extend our reach into a new client segment, specifically the small business market. Historically, our SMB client set was comprised primarily of clients with over 500 seats. We have created a special team of account executives focused solely on the 50- to 500-seat small business market with metrics, methodology and offers that will address the unique needs of this client set. This market provides incremental opportunity for Insight, specifically in the U.S.
• Also in 2008, we will expand our global capabilities by introducing new services in key countries in EMEA and APAC to leverage existing client relationships and enhance our profitability.
• And finally, we will drive operational efficiencies in our business and improve our return on invested capital by continuing our IT systems deployment, streamlining key business practices and improving our working capital processes. Additionally, we will continue to deploy capital in a disciplined way as we execute our 2008 goals.
As we head into 2008, we believe our business is healthy and well-positioned for continued success. We are confident in our trusted advisor vision, our proven business model and the momentum we built in 2007. We are committed to driving shareholder value as we ascend to a leadership position in our industry.
Rich Fennessy
President and Chief Executive Officer Insight Enterprises, Inc.
Note: 2007 consolidated results include expenses of approximately $15.6 million, or $9.4 million after tax, for professional fees and costs associated with our stock option review and severance and restructuring expenses while the 2006 consolidated results reflect $2.3 million, or $1.5 million after tax, for professional fees and costs associated with our stock option review and severance and restructuring expenses.
            