 2012 was a very good year for Oxford. We remained steadfastly focused on our fundamental objective of increasing long-term shareholder value by delivering sustained growth in the earning power of the enterprise. Our strategy for delivering this growth is simply stated: We develop and market compelling lifestyle brands that evoke a strong, emotional response from consumers. the emotional connections made by brands such as tommy Bahama® and lilly pulitzer® foster tremendous consumer loyalty and ultimately growth.
during fiscal 2012 we grew consolidated net sales to $855.5 million — up 13% from the prior year — on the strength of outstanding performance at tommy Bahama and lilly pulitzer. together these two brands comprise more than 75% of our business. On an adjusted basis, earnings per share increased to $2.61 for the 2012 fiscal year, up $0.20 over the previous year. On a Gaap basis, earnings per share increased to $1.89 from $1.77 in the prior year.
Here’s a key takeaway on fiscal 2012: We grew earnings nicely while making significant
Thomas C. Chubb III
Chief Executive Officer and President
to Our shareholders
investments at tommy Bahama and lilly pulitzer. these investments, which include capital expenditures, as well as targeted increases in operating expenses, have helped us create infrastructure needed for future growth. even with the substantial investments at tommy Bahama and lilly pulitzer and the worse-than-expected difficulties at Ben sherman, we increased our adjusted operating earnings to $79.3 million, up from $76.8 million in the prior year. cash flow from operations for fiscal 2012 increased impressively to $67.5 million, up 51% from fiscal 2011.
looking forward, we are well positioned to continue to execute on opportunities for long- term growth. We expect to open approximately 16 new tommy Bahama stores around the world during fiscal 2013. locations include two stores that opened in april in the key tokyo market, one on the Magnificent Mile in chicago that opened in early May and another in sydney, opening soon. We expect to open at least four new lilly pulitzer stores during fiscal 2013. In both brands, we are also investing to support the ongoing growth of e-commerce
and continuing efforts to develop a seamless omni-channel consumer experience. We believe investing in the growth of the tommy Bahama and lilly pulitzer businesses will help drive the expansion in earnings that will increase long-term shareholder value.
a solid balance sheet has long been an Oxford hallmark and that continues today. during 2012 we amended and restated our revolving credit facility and redeemed our remaining outstanding senior secured notes. these two actions resulted in significantly lower interest expense for 2012 than we incurred in 2011, and we are projecting further interest expense reductions for 2013. Our balance sheet is in excellent shape to support our growth objectives.
tommy Bahama: driving Growth While Building a Global Brand tommy Bahama, our largest operating group, delivered a strong performance in 2012. tommy Bahama sales crossed the $500 million mark for the first time, ending the year at $529 million — a 17% increase over the prior
  5

 ■Oxford-ownedBrands 88% ■licensedBrands 8% ■privatelabel 4% Branded vs. private label sales
year. tommy Bahama also achieved several other important financial and operational milestones during the year: operating more than 100 domestic stores, generating more than $100 million in women’s sales and rolling out company-owned retail stores in the asia pacific market.
Multiple opportunities exist to drive continued growth at tommy Bahama. the first is domestic store expansion. In 2012 we opened a restaurant and retail “island” on fifth avenue in new York city, one of 12 stores launched during the year, which brought our domestic total to 105 units by year-end. during fiscal 2013, we plan to open another 12 stores in the u.s., including a high-traffic location on chicago’s Michigan avenue. While we expect these high-profile locations to be commercially successful, they also serve an important marketing function. By presenting our brand in our own stores to customers who were not previously familiar with it, we are able to tell the brand story our way and begin to build connections with new consumers. We believe that many of these new initiates will become brand loyalists and help drive future expansion.
although tommy Bahama’s island-inspired appeal has traditionally been strongest in
areas that are sunny and warm, we also have had great success in markets such as chicago, denver, Kansas city and Minneapolis. We see few geographic limits on the brand, and our continued domestic store growth will be targeted to reach the right demographics wherever we identify those customers.
International expansion represents another major growth opportunity for tommy Bahama. during 2012, we opened four new stores our- selves internationally and acquired five existing stores with the acquisition of our australian distributor’s business. In May 2013, we acquired nine additional international stores with the acquisition of our canadian distributor’s business. although we are still early in the process of developing our global presence, we are learning about consumers in each distinct market through interactions in our new stores in exciting locations such as Hong Kong and the Ginza district of tokyo. We are synthesizing these learnings rapidly and will use them to shape our future international growth plans.
another big growth opportunity is tommy Bahama’s women’s merchandise, which now represents 28% of its total direct to consumer business. during fiscal 2012 our sportswear,
swimwear and accessories offerings resonated with our female guests, with women’s sales growing at an even faster pace than men’s. a key objective is to continue the momentum we have in the women’s portion of the tommy Bahama business.
e-commerce, which now represents more than 10% of total sales at tommy Bahama, continues to be an opportunity for growth. as we build out the capabilities to provide a seamless omni-channel consumer experience, we also are gleaning crucial insights into customer preferences — data that helps us better frame our merchandise offering and target our marketing efforts.
2012 was a year of incredible achievement for the tommy Bahama team. they worked tire- lessly to reach many important milestones. Most importantly, they set the stage for continued growth in 2013 and beyond.
lilly pulitzer: timeless appeal — now More than ever
With sales in fiscal 2012 growing to $123 million, lilly pulitzer posted its second consecutive year of 30% sales growth. this remarkable achievement underscores the strong appeal
of this lifestyle brand and the wide avenue
  6 OxfOrd IndustrIes, Inc. — 2012 annual repOrt

 for growth it enjoys. this strong topline performance was coupled with rapid expansion of the operating group’s adjusted operating margins that approached 22% during the year.
direct to consumer represents more than half of lilly pulitzer’s revenues, with e-commerce constituting more than 20% of sales. lilly has a database of more than 750,000 customer e-mail addresses, a lively and robust social media component and, clearly, more runway for growth in e-commerce. We are investing in the people, systems and infrastructure needed to support that growth as well as the development of a seamless omni-channel consumer experience.
along with “clicks,” “bricks” remain an important part of the strategy. In fiscal 2012, we opened four new lilly pulitzer stores — the first new units for this business since we acquired it in 2010. all of the new lilly stores are deliver- ing excellent financial results. In addition, as with tommy Bahama, these stores and the e-commerce website perform an important marketing function. By providing us a forum to tell our brand story on our own terms, they allow us to establish the emotional connections with consumers that build brand loyalty. We
sales by distribution
believe this loyalty is an important part of driving long-term growth. during 2013, we plan to open at least four more lilly stores.
future growth at lilly will also be achieved through a careful expansion of the product categories that the brand covers. lilly’s largest product category historically has been dresses. In 2012, the strength in dresses was augmented by good growth in sportswear, supported by a number of strong key items. Going forward, lilly pulitzer will continue to carefully select targeted items to expand the breadth of its product offering and support a stronger, wider assortment of product.
two years of strong growth makes it important that we continue to invest to support lilly’s growth opportunities. We are particularly focused on adding depth to our talent pool in key areas such as retail, e-commerce, market- ing, design, and information systems and technology. even as we make these investments to build for growth, we expect lilly to continue to deliver strong operating margins in 2013.
On a more personal note, it was with great sadness that we learned on april 7, 2013, of the death of lilly pulitzer rousseau. lilly’s bright and happy outlook on life is the essence
of the brand that bears her name. Oxford is proud to be part of her legacy through our ongoing stewardship of the lilly pulitzer brand.
the lilly pulitzer team has delivered exceptional results since we acquired the business in late 2010 and has been a large part of Oxford’s success over the last two years.
lanier clothes: targeting profitable Opportunities
In fiscal 2012, lanier clothes achieved a solid operating margin of just over 10% on sales of $107 million. lanier clothes designs and markets branded and private label tailored clothing under a variety of labels at a wide range of price points. lanier is fundamentally a wholesaler serving a customer base ranging from off-price retailers to iconic luxury stores such as saks fifth avenue. lanier’s objective is to create programs for its wholesale customers that generate high rates of sell-through on their retail selling floor. When lanier clothes achieves this objective, it generally flourishes.
although tailored clothing is not a high-growth category, we see select opportunities to profitably grow the business going forward. these include growth in our trouser business, expansion into new channels of distribution and more tailored
■directtoconsumer 54% ■Wholesale 46% (includes retail and e-commerce)
  7

financial Highlights OxfOrd IndustrIes, Inc.
(In thousands, except per share data)
net sales
Gross profit, as adjusted
Operating income, as adjusted
earnings from continuing operations, as adjusted
diluted earnings from continuing operations per share, as adjusted
fiscal 2012
fiscal 2011
  $ $ $ $ $
855,542 473,600 79,299 43,291 2.61
$ $ $ $ $
758,913 419,737 76,820 39,763 2.41
     For reference, tables reconciling certain GAAP to adjusted measures begin on page 145 of this Annual Report.
clothing offerings at higher price points. If lanier clothes can develop programs that achieve strong sell-through within these areas, growth opportunities are likely to follow.
Our investment in lanier clothes consists primarily of working capital. the capital expenditures required to support growth in this business are minimal. the cash return on cash invested in this business is excellent.
the team at lanier clothes continues to exemplify operating discipline and outstanding execution in all aspects of their business.
Ben sherman: prudent steps toward a More stable future fiscal 2012 was a very poor year for Ben sherman. sales fell 10% to $82 million, while operating losses increased to $10.9 million. the substandard results were largely due to poor execution of its strategy. With 69% of the busi- ness outside the u.s., primarily in the u.K. and europe, Ben sherman’s performance was also negatively impacted by difficult consumer market conditions. We are very focused on putting this business on firmer footing in fiscal 2013 and, to this end, are executing initiatives in
these key areas: expense reduction, distribution control via exiting unprofitable customer relationships, improving the performance of our e-commerce website and our retail stores, and strengthening our management team.
to advance the last objective, in april 2013 we appointed a new chief executive officer to lead Ben sherman — a proven performer with extensive product, sales and marketing experi- ence with the brand. In addition, we promoted the group’s former finance director to the role of chief operating officer. We were pleased to tap our internal resources and elevate two capable leaders to these important roles. taken together, we think these initiatives will position us to achieve meaningful improvements in Ben sherman’s operating results in fiscal 2013.
the right strategy and team to extend Our Growth story
this is an exciting time for Oxford. three quarters of our business is comprised of tommy Bahama and lilly pulitzer, two powerful brands that are winning in the marketplace. We are also effectively executing a strategy to invest in and build the platform for continued growth both domestically and in markets
around the world. capitalizing on those growth opportunities is the key to increasing shareholder value going forward.
In 2012, I was honored and humbled when your Board of directors chose me to serve as chief executive officer. In this role I follow in the footsteps of Hicks lanier, a remarkable leader whose strategic vision and contributions during his decades of service to this company are truly immeasurable. In my 24-year career at Oxford I have never been more excited by the energy and passion of our talented colleagues across every business and discipline. these teams are focused every day on initiatives that will continue to strengthen this great company and build even greater success in the years ahead. I am grateful to them for their contri- butions, to Hicks and the rest of the Board for their guidance and support, and to all our shareholders for your continued support.
sincerely,
thomas c. chubb III
chief executive Officer and president
   8 OxfOrd IndustrIes, Inc. — 2012 annual repOrt
