 LETTER TO PULTEGROUP OWNERS, CUSTOMERS, ASSOCIATES AND BUSINESS PARTNERS:
Long-term shareholders know that since 2011 we have been operating under a clearly defined plan of action that we have titled our Value Creation strategy. In explaining Value Creation, we have discussed supporting concepts and tactics ranging from product and purchasing zones to commonly managed plans and strategic pricing, all in support of delivering higher returns on invested capital. Each component has played an important part in driving dramatic improvement in PulteGroup’s overall operating and financial results over the past several years.
As part of this year’s shareholder letter, let me introduce another underpinning of the strategy which has helped to guide our actions: the C-curve. The concept, which is depicted in the accompanying graph, is that companies working to materially improve business performance are best served by initially curtailing incremental investment into the business while fixing core operations and raising returns on invested capital. It is only after needed operational gains have moved a company’s returns above its cost of capital that the organization should consider increasing investment into the business. In simpler language, fine tune your operations before making them bigger.
In the case of PulteGroup, substitute 2011, 2012 and 2013 for Years 1, 2 and 3 on the graph and you have a good representation of the path we followed. In operating against our Value Creation strategy, we limited investment into the business at the outset while we worked to enhance margins, leverage SG&A spend and accelerate inventory turns; key levers to driving higher returns on invested capital.
In 2010 we spent approximately $450 million on new land acquisition, followed by expenditures of $330 million in 2011 and $300 million in 2012. During these early years, we focused our efforts internally on improving our fundamental operating performance which resulted in PulteGroup delivering some of the highest margins, pretax earnings growth and returns in the industry. We fully appreciated that restricting capital would initially hinder the Company’s ability to maintain market share or realize material growth in unit volumes, but it was a tradeoff we were willing to make.
On the curve, it was in 2013 when PulteGroup’s returns rose above its cost of capital. It was at this time that we began the process of intelligently injecting more dollars into the business. In homebuilding, increasing investment primarily means acquiring additional land assets. In 2013, we invested $570 million in new land acquisition, which grew to $860 million in 2014 and $1.2 billion in 2015. We expect another step-up in land spend in 2016 as well, in part driven by our January 2016 acquisition of approximately 7,000 lots and a premier luxury brand from John Wieland Homes and Neighborhoods.
 C-curve profile of improving profits then reinves􏱄ng for growth
ROIC 15
Year 4
Year 1
0.8 0.9 1.0
    10
5
0
Year 3
Cost of capital
Year 2
0.6 0.7
Year 5
Start
 Invested capital (indexed to 1 at starting point) Source: Boston Consulting Group
1.1
2015 ANNUAL REPORT | PulteGroup, Inc. 1

 LETTER TO PULTEGROUP OWNERS, CUSTOMERS, ASSOCIATES AND BUSINESS PARTNERS:
 1,300 1,200 1,100 1,000
900 800 700 600 500 400 300 200 100
NEW HOME SALES (000)
In addition to making good business sense, raising our land acquisition spend is consistent both with our stated priorities for uses of capital and with our expectations that U.S. housing demand continues on a slow, but sustained path of recovery. Since bottoming in 2011, annual new home sales of approximately 500,000 in 2015 are up over 60%, but still remain well below the 50-year average of 650,000 new home sales per year.
I also believe that the investments we have made are moving the Company to an inflection point in its Value Creation journey; increased investments of the past few years are enabling accelerated volume and earnings growth in the future. Given the pipeline of high quality land parcels we have assembled, we are in position to realize more meaningful volume and revenue growth going forward, while maintaining or slightly expanding our share of the overall new home market.
             0
1963 1967 1971 1975 1979 1983 1987 1991 1995 1999 2003 2007 2011 2015
Source: U.S. Census
 It is important to highlight that while our unit volume and top line revenue growth have been modest over the past few years, improvements in fundamental operating performance have resulted in dramatic gains in the Company’s earnings. On comparable unit volumes, annual pretax earnings in 2015 grew 18% over the prior year to $816 million. Even more impressive, in just four years of Value Creation, we have achieved gains in core operating metrics to where we were able to leverage a 12% increase in unit deliveries in 2015 compared with 2011 into a $1.1 billion increase in pretax
income. This is the type of performance our Value Creation work was meant to deliver.
So where do we go from here? First and foremost, we continue to operate the business consistent with the core principles of Value Creation and its focus on delivering higher returns on invested capital over the housing cycle. This means we remain focused on the business fundamentals of gross margin, overhead leverage and inventory turns, while understanding that the business is evolving. Where gross margin has been the primary driver of our financial gains in recent years, going forward volume growth, overhead leverage and operating margins will be the key metrics supporting return on invested capital.
We will also continue to be disciplined with our land investment. We have an established 13-point risk- weighting scale for assessing every transaction we consider for acquisition. We are supporting our underwriting processes with a commitment to focusing on better-located land positions that are closer to city centers. Given that demand among the entry level buyer looking for an inexpensive home in the distant suburbs has been slow to materialize, our strategy remains to target better locations closer to the job core, even if it means paying more for the land, and using options where possible to help mitigate risk and/or enhance overall returns.
2 PulteGroup, Inc. | 2015 ANNUAL REPORT

 LETTER TO PULTEGROUP OWNERS, CUSTOMERS, ASSOCIATES AND BUSINESS PARTNERS:
And finally, we must continue to allocate capital consistent with our stated priorities: 1) invest in the business; 2) pay our dividend; 3) pursue opportunistic M&A; and, 4) use excess capital to fund routine and systemic share repurchases. Consistent with this hierarchy, in 2015 we invested $2.3 billion into the business for land acquisition and development, while returning $559 million to shareholders through dividends and share repurchases.
Consistent with our first priority to invest in the business, we will continue acquiring land provided we can identify high returning projects and overall demand conditions remain supportive. If suitable projects are not available or if market conditions change, however, we will not force investment into the system. We have demonstrated the discipline to underspend our land acquisition budgets when suitable high-returning projects could not be identified.
Looking Ahead
We ended 2015 with strong financial results and tremendous momentum and optimism heading into 2016, but it would be dangerous to ignore the volatility roiling the world today. From concerns about global economic conditions, to the collapse in oil prices and gyrations in the stock and bond markets, the day-to-day moves can be violent. Given the long-term nature of homebuilding, our job requires that we try to look through such short-term volatility as we navigate a course for our business.
As we look across the housing landscape, we see the drivers of the current housing recovery remaining solidly in place. The U.S. economy added well over 2 million jobs in 2015 and expected GDP growth in 2016 should allow employment expansion to continue. Our population is growing and the demographic dynamics are certainly supportive with boomers on one end of the spectrum and the even larger millennial generation on the other. New home construction is also benefitting from limited housing inventories in most markets, while mortgage rates continue to hover near historically low levels. Given this favorable backdrop, we believe new home sales should continue to grind higher for the next few years.
In summary, PulteGroup has an excellent position in a good housing market. We have a more efficient homebuilding operation, supported by a robust land pipeline and the financial flexibility to take advantage of market opportunities as they develop. Equally important, we have the passionate commitment of our employees, trade partners and suppliers who are focused on delivering the best home and homebuying experience to our customers. On behalf of the Board of Directors, I thank them for the efforts and thank you, our shareholders, for your ongoing support of this company.
Sincerely,
Richard J. Dugas, Jr.
Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer
 2015 ANNUAL REPORT | PulteGroup, Inc. 3
