         Mark J. O’Brien
Our International operations realized important gains in 2001, but it seems that progress is measured in two-steps forward and one-step back. Our Mexico and Puerto Rico operations con- tinued to grow as we implemented new strategies to better serve these markets. While entry into Argentina got off to an excellent start, with strong demand for our new communities, uncertainty over the Argentine economy weighed on the market and hurt our 2001 results. The overall mix of events had a negative impact as the Company’s International Operations reported a pre-tax loss of $2.4 million. We remain encouraged by gains made during the year as we drive toward realizing consistent earnings contributions.
President and
Chief Executive Officer
In the months following the merger’s completion, we moved deliberately, but swiftly, to integrate the Webb operations. Duplicate functions were eliminated, management and community reporting relationships were realigned to leverage available resources, and we initiated an exhaustive review of construction and purchasing practices to uncover additional sources of cost savings. Throughout it all, the sharing of best practices between two industry leaders is making the ongoing business even stronger. Through these and other actions, we expect to realize “synergy savings” of $50–$75 million in the first year, while strengthening Pulte Homes’ overall market position. The combination of Pulte Homes and Del Webb has created a homebuilding powerhouse with a size, geographic presence and product portfolio that is unrivaled in the homebuilding industry and, likely, cannot be duplicated.
Earnings Per Share
Record Financial Results in 2001
Last year, we introduced Pulte Homes’ new brand platform of Quality, Involvement, Integrity and Innovation, also known as the Three I’s on Quality. The order of these strategic pillars is intentional as quality is the foundation upon which the brand and the entire Company must stand. As Pulte Homes continues to grow, we believe that our ability to deliver homes of superior and consistent quality will become a critical, sustainable competitive advantage; a vital point of differentiation from the rest of the industry. Progress to seize this advantage in the field continued on many fronts last year.
Letter to Pulte Homes
Shareholders,
Customers, Employees and Business Partners,
With our success in 2001, Pulte Homes completed its sixth consecutive year of record-setting financial results and its 51st year of uninterrupted profitability. As Bill and I review these results, we do so from our new roles, Bill as Chairman (a position he last held in 1998) and I as President and CEO, following the retirement of Bob Burgess in December of last year. Between the two of us, we have over 70 years of history with this Company. This fact is noteworthy only in providing some context in our making the following observations: 2001 was one of the most rewarding years in this Company’s history, and Pulte Homes today is in its strongest competitive position ever.
for our homes, to improve the mix of homes delivered and to lower construction costs, gross margins increased 120 basis points to a record 20.0 percent (20.2 percent prior to the impact of acquisition accounting). The combination of higher revenues and lower costs resulted in a 35 percent increase in pre-tax income for the group of $523 million. With a year-end backlog of 8,678 homes, valued at $2.1 billion, the business enters 2002 with tremendous momentum.
Looking back at 2001, our $1.7 billion merger with Del Webb Corporation clearly stands out as a bold stroke that forever changed the face of Pulte Homes. Over the past few years, we’ve looked at countless companies as potential acquisitions, but none offered the strategic value, competitive strengths and business synergies that we saw in Del Webb. With its unmatched posi- tion among active adult homebuyers, strong brand names, excellent land pipeline and more than 7,000 closings annually, Del Webb has given us a dominant position within the country’s fastest growing demographic segment.
Benefiting from increased homebuilding volumes, a declining interest rate environment and enhanced operating efficiencies, Pulte Mortgage Corporation (PMC) also posted record financial results. In 2001, we advanced several initiatives designed to more fully integrate PMC into the home selling process in all our markets. As a result, PMC’s capture rate rose to 60 percent, as compared to 56 percent in 2000. A higher capture rate, combined with a downward trend in interest rates over the year, helped drive a 49 percent jump in pre-tax income of $28 million.
Just as with the merger, 2001 saw success throughout the Company. Growth in all our opera- tions, plus the benefit of five months of Del Webb’s operations, resulted in record revenues of $5.4 billion, up 27 percent over the prior year. Reflecting our initiatives to drive increased profitability, net income from continuing operations of $302 million, or $6.01 per share, was up 38 percent over 2000. These results are consistent with our previously stated five-year goals of generating revenue growth of 10–15 percent and earnings growth of 20–25 percent, annually.
4
As a result of the Company’s financial success in 2001, Pulte Homes ended the year with a book value of $38.43 per share, as return on average equity registered 18 percent.
First, our internal Customer Satisfaction Measurement Survey, through which we question all new customers about their level of satisfaction, increased another four percent to its highest level ever. Second, in the JD Power and Associates 2001 New Home Builder Customer Satisfaction StudySM, Pulte Homes ranked or tied for first in four of the 10 markets surveyed (Charlotte (tied), Denver, Las Vegas and Southern California (tied)), and ranked among the top three homebuilders in seven of the 10 markets covered. And finally, Professional Builder Magazine, citing a variety of
1
Pulte Homes’ domestic homebuilding operations, inclusive of five months of Del Webb, reported another record year. Revenues increased 27 percent to $5.3 billion, as total domestic settlements grew 16 percent to 22,915 homes. Through a combination of initiatives to increase market prices
’90 ’91 ’92 ’93 ’94 ’95 ’96 ’97 ’98 ’99 ’00 ’01
0
Overall, we were very pleased with Pulte Homes’ operating results in 2001, and we see opportu- nities for even greater success in the future.
6
Three I’s on Quality
(in dollars)
Over the past decade, Pulte Homes’ revenues and earnings per share have grown at a compounded annual rate of 20% and 26%, respectively.
Pulte Homes 2001 Annual Report 3
$7
5
3
2

             22%
Last year’s letter discussed the battle waging between a slowing US economy, lower employment and reduced consumer confidence versus an aggressive Federal Reserve policy of lower interest rates. As we enter 2002, we believe the experts who forecast the worst of the economic weakness is behind us and that a rebound in the second half of 2002 is possible, if not likely.
20
These principles help form the foundation of Pulte Homes’ success, and they were clearly embod- ied in the leadership of Bob Burgess who retired as Chairman and CEO following 19 years with the Company. Bob’s focus on improving the quality of people we employ and homes we deliver were instrumental in Pulte Homes’ growth from a $900 million, mid-sized homebuilder in 1983 to the nation’s largest builder with over $5 billion in revenues. Bob’s counsel will be missed, but the values he instilled will help guide this Company for years to come.
18
We’ll continue to monitor all the key economic metrics and trends, but we’re homebuilders not economists. The best thing we can do for our shareholders is to focus on the long term and take the steps necessary to prepare for success. This means keeping our cost structure in alignment with market conditions, reaching our historical 40 percent debt-to-capital level by the end of 2002 and maintaining a well-positioned and well-balanced land portfolio. This final point is crit- ical given that Pulte Homes must reinvest approximately $1.7 billion in 2002 just to remain even with the land that will be charged off through cost of goods sold. Put another way, that means investing an average of almost $5.0 million a day in land and related land development. We believe very strongly that our entire land management competency is a critical skill that will increasingly be viewed as an important competitive advantage.
16
To paraphrase the opening line from A Tale of Two Cities, 2001 was the best of times; it was the worst of times. For Pulte Homes, it was a year of unprecedented accomplishments and record-setting successes. It was a year in which revenues grew past the $5 billion mark, while we completed the largest merger in the history of homebuilding. Yet, it would be impossible to look back on 2001 without gazing through the smoke and tears evoked by the tragedy of September 11. We salute the thousands of heroes who stood up that day and in the many days that followed. In their spirit, we as a country and as a company must and will move forward.
14
12
10
We thank our customers, employees, business partners and shareholders for their continued sup- port during this past year...a year in which having such relationships took on an even deeper meaning. Within these changing times, we at Pulte Homes see tremendous opportunities to reach new milestones, to set the bar higher and to achieve even greater successes. Our time is now to seize these opportunities, and to take a good company and make it great.
Domestic Homebuilding Gross Margins
What began in Pulte Homes as a simple concept called customer delight has grown into a business culture focused on the delivery of quality homes and unsurpassed customer satisfaction. We must acknowledge that in the past we have not always achieved the standard we expect of ourselves. This has only served as a wake-up call that we must always deliver on our promise.
➣ Hire, train and retain the best employees;
➣ Acquisitions where they make strategic, operating and financial sense; and ➣ Challenge ourselves everyday to become better.
’91 ’92 ’93 ’94 ’95 ’96 ’97 ’98 ’99 ’00 ’01
Over the past 10 years, margins within Pulte Homes domestic homebuilding operations have increased better than 50% to 2001’s record of 20%.
Sincerely,
factors including the Company’s commitment to customer satisfaction and quality, named Pulte Homes its Builder of the Year.
As we continue transitioning to the new senior management team, you can expect that the fun- damentals that have been the cornerstone of this Company will not change:
It’s been demonstrated across countless industries that having happy, satisfied customers makes good business sense. For Pulte Homes, the potential benefits are significant as higher quality can support a premium pricing position in the market and can help increase repeat/referral business. Today, 36 percent of our buyers have either previously owned a Pulte home or were referred by another Pulte homeowner. In other words, more than one-third of our business has minimal customer acquisition costs. The potential to increase sales and lower customer acquisition and warranty-service costs can have a dramatic impact on Pulte Homes’ top- and bottom-line results.
➣ Growth through conservative business practices emphasizing returns in excess of our cost of capital;
Looking Ahead
➣ Maintenance of a strong balance sheet to take advantage of market opportunities when they appear;
➣ Industry leadership in construction efficiency, while delivering unmatched quality and customer satisfaction;
Mark J. O’Brien
William J. Pulte
President and Chief Executive Officer
Chairman of the Board
Vision
These fundamentals will not change, but we will continue to challenge ourselves to get better and continue developing unmatched capabilities in other key areas including human resources, infor- mation systems and marketing.
Chairman of the Board
William J. Pulte
Pulte Homes 2001 Annual Report 5
