   IN 2003 “WE PAID DOWN DEBT BY NEARLY $400 MILLION, REDUCING OUR DEBT-TO-TOTAL-CAPITAL RATIO TO 36 PERCENT, SURPASSING OUR YEAR-END GOAL OF 40 PERCENT.
IN ADDITION, WE INCREASED OUR CASH POSITION FOR THE YEAR BY ABOUT $375 MILLION AND EXPECT STRONG CASH FLOW AGAIN IN 2004.”
Letter from the Chairman
After a nearly three-year downturn, the North American industrial economy finally began to rebound in the second half of 2003. Combined with plentiful growth in Asia and a slight improvement in Europe, our volumes have increased for seven consecutive quarters. This slow but gradual global recovery — and our continued success in building a foundation for performance and growth — were reflected in our financial results.
We recorded 2003 net income of $494 million, or $2.89 a share, including aftertax charges of $23 million,
or 14 cents a share, to reflect the net increase in the current value of the company’s obligation under our asbestos settlement agreement; $6 million, or 3 cents a share, for
the cumulative effect of a required change in the accounting for asset retirement obligations; and $2 million, or 1 cent a share, for restructuring. Sales for 2003 were a record
$8.8 billion.
That compares with 2002, when we reported a net loss of $69 million, or 41 cents a share, including aftertax charges of $484 million, or $2.85 a share, for the asbestos settlement; $52 million, or 31 cents a share, for restructuring; and $9 million, or 5 cents a share, for the cumulative effect of a required accounting change. Sales for 2002 were $8.1 billion.
Net income was up $563 million in 2003, largely because the charges for asbestos, restructuring and accounting changes were $514 million less than in 2002. The remaining increase of $49 million was the result of a combination of factors. Earnings increased because of stronger pricing in commodity chemicals; increased volumes in all three segments, coatings, glass and chemicals; stronger currencies in Europe; and greater manufacturing
efficiencies and lower overhead costs in coatings and glass. Several factors, meanwhile, partially offset these gains, including pension and retiree medical costs, which were $146 million higher than the year before. In addition,
Raymond W. LeBoeuf, right, chairman and chief executive officer, and Charles E. Bunch,
<#> 2003 Annual Report and Form 10-K ■
PPG Industries, Inc.
president and chief operating officer.
    
  rising natural gas prices reduced operating income by about $100 million.
PPG delivered another year of strong cash flow in 2003, generating a record $1.1 billion in cash from operations. We paid down debt by nearly $400 million, reducing our debt-to-total-capital ratio to 36 percent, surpassing our year-end goal of 40 percent. In addition, we increased our cash position for the year by about
$375 million and expect strong cash flow again in 2004. This supports our goal of sustaining our dividend at about one-third of earnings per share over time. In 2003 we raised shareholder payments for the 32nd consecutive
year and continued our legacy of paying uninterrupted dividends since 1899.
Additional cash on hand also positions us to reduce debt further, buy back shares once again and invest for growth, possibly in the form of acquisitions. Although we do not believe there are any large acquisitions on the horizon, small acquisitions in our optical products and architectural and industrial coatings businesses are possible.
Acquisitions, as well as divestitures, have played an important role in our company’s three-point strategic direction, whose overriding goal is to increase earnings growth and consistency. The strategies are to:
• Build A Better Mix of Businesses • Create Breakthrough Products • Improve Our Customers’ Results
The progress we have made in pursuing these strategies since the late 1990s enabled us to weather the industrial downturn better than our peers and the overall market. Since 2000, PPG returned a total of 15 percent per year to its shareholders, compared with 10.5 percent for the S&P Materials Index and minus 4 percent for the S&P 500.
Build A Better Mix of Businesses
Our acquisition and divestiture activity in the late 1990s contributed to that success. We divested our European flat and automotive glass and Chinese glass businesses. At the same time, we invested nearly $2 billion in coatings acquisitions. As a result, we are positioned to grow as the global economy continues to gain strength.
 A Dell notebook computer part painted by Huan Hsin Holdings Ltd. is examined by Sung Ping, a quality inspector for the company, and PPG technical service manager Xie Yijun, in Shanghai, China.
Supplying liquid coatings that meet the rigid requirements of the world’s leading computer systems company is only half the challenge. Ensuring the paint arrives on time at multiple locations for a customer that has redefined the concept of “just-in-time” manufacturing is every bit as important.
PPG industrial coatings facilities in Asia supply liquid coatings to Dell for its Latitude and Inspiron notebook computers and three models of the company’s hand-held computers.
A PPG account manager works with members of Dell’s design, engineering, procurement and quality departments at its corporate headquarters in Austin, Texas, supporting the coordination and supply of coatings materials to manufacturing locations around the world.
Meanwhile, a PPG account manager in Asia coordinates the supply logistics and assures color harmony for the many applicators in China, Japan, Malaysia, Singapore, South Korea and Taiwan, which are selected and approved by Dell and its manufacturing partners.
As a result, PPG helps Dell achieve seamless management of its coatings supply chain while meeting the color, performance and time specifications the company and its customers demand.
2003 Annual Report and Form 10-K ■ PPG Industries, Inc.
3
      
   Take, for example, the coatings acquisitions we made in Asia. The facilities we acquired, in combination with a series of existing operations, have enabled us to participate in the tremendous growth in that region. We have grown our electrodeposition coatings business there tenfold over the past two years, supplying a wide range of end-use markets, such as automotive parts and accessories, appliances, aluminum extrusion and fasteners. In addition, the demand for powder coatings is growing rapidly, and we’re well-positioned to fill that need, beginning produc- tion in 2003 at plants in China and Malaysia. We also have aerospace application support centers in Australia, China and Singapore. As a result of our focus on Asia, coatings sales in the region have doubled since 1999, and sales margins — thanks to our continuing efforts to reduce costs, even in a high-growth region — are now on par with our coatings segment as a whole.
Another area where acquisitions have positioned us for growth is architectural coatings. In addition to the growth we’re enjoying in sales to home centers, we have built a network of company-owned stores that is the fourth-largest chain in North America. In the process of building this network, we have developed an expertise in store operations management. With less than a 10-percent share of the North American architectural coatings market, we have plenty of room to grow. We also have the ability to use this network, as well as our company’s glass and coil- and extrusion-coatings relationships, to increase our partici- pation in commercial building projects. Furthermore, we can leverage our company-owned stores to penetrate the light industrial coatings market, which includes manufac- turers employing fewer than 100 employees and purchasing up to $200,000 worth of paint a year.
Our growth strategies have also challenged us to move closer to the end customer. An example of this is in the automotive aftermarket. As insurance companies sought ways to increase their efficiency in dealing with automotive glass replacement installers and others, we created LYNX Services, our auto glass claims management business. As a result, insurers have outsourced their auto glass claims to our call centers, which have sophisticated information
 Olympic paints are sold exclusively at Lowe’s home improvement stores, where approximately 9 million customers shop each week.
Lowe’s rise to become the world’s second-largest home improvement retailer, with 950 locations in 45 states, has also fueled impressive growth in the sales of Olympic paints and stains.
Manufactured by PPG’s architectural coatings unit, Olympic paints have been sold exclusively at Lowe’s since 1997. In addition, PPG supplies Lowe’s with Olympic interior and exterior stains.
A dedicated force of more than 100 PPG employees ensures Lowe’s shelves are stocked with Olympic brand products and assists customers with their coatings needs. In 2004, PPG is investing further in its relationship with Lowe’s with new in-store paint color centers, highlighting the Olympic brand and its wide selection of colors.
From its original store 58 years ago in rural North Carolina, Lowe’s has grown to become a Fortune 100 company with home improvement superstores coast to coast, being named America’s Most Admired Specialty Retailer by Fortune magazine in 2003. Growing westward and northward, Lowe’s has extended its reach into the top 25 metro markets, containing one-half of
the nation’s do-it-yourself market. Lowe’s opened 130 new stores in 2003 and plans to open 140 more in 2004.
4 2003 Annual Report and Form 10-K ■ PPG Industries, Inc.
       
  technology. Today we are the leading auto glass claims processor in the nation, handling nearly one in two outsourced claims nationwide, bringing substantial efficiencies to insurance companies and their policyholders. We aren’t stopping there, however. We have developed a host of technology solutions enabling glass shops, insurance companies, suppliers and vendors to conduct business
more efficiently. Our approach for creating additional value in the automotive aftermarket reflects the changing nature of the marketplace.
Such changes are reflected in the updated PPG Industries Blueprint, which was refreshed in 2003. Though the document that outlines our vision, values, strategies and outcomes has remained largely unchanged since it was first introduced in 1985, we periodically review it to ensure its relevance within the competitive landscape.
Create Breakthrough Products
In today’s manufacturing environment, research and development are among the few proven avenues for sustainable growth. That’s why we increased our Blueprint goal for the sale of new products. Today we want to generate 35 percent of our sales from products 4 or fewer years old. Previously, we defined new products as 5 or fewer years old.
Let me give you an example of why we place such a high priority on technical innovation. In the 1990s, using our expertise to develop photochromic dyes, we discovered a way to make plastic ophthalmic lenses darken when exposed to ultraviolet light and then return to a clear state in its absence, or indoors. We formed Transitions Optical, a 51-percent-owned joint venture with lens maker Essilor International, and have consistently improved the performance of Transitions lenses during the past 10 years, becoming the undisputed world leader in photochromic plastic eyewear. Backed by a $25-million media campaign — the largest such advertising commitment ever made for a PPG product — the fourth generation of this product has generated sales that are growing at twice the rate of the previous generation. As a result, we have increased the
U.S. market for photochromic lenses by nearly 40 percent.
 Representatives of LYNX Services enable policyholders to file auto claims and schedule repairs with a single telephone call.
By the nature of its business, LYNX Services is virtually anonymous to consumers. But among insurance companies, LYNX Services is well-known, handling more than 3 million claims a year.
When policyholders contact their participating insurance companies to file auto glass claims, the calls are automatically routed to LYNX Services representatives at computerized call centers in Paducah, Ky., or Fort Myers, Fla.
LYNX Services manages all aspects of the auto glass claim, including taking the policyholder’s “first notice of loss,” verifying coverage, locating the policyholder’s preferred choice of a glass shop to do the work, reviewing the glass shop invoice and issuing payment to the glass shop. Leveraging this process expertise, LYNX Services entered the collision claims management business in 2003.
LYNX Services is the largest business within PPG’s insurance and services unit. The others are GTS Services, which develops and implements software systems and solutions for the auto replacement and flat glass industries; GLAXIS,
an electronic hub enabling participants in the auto glass replacement market to conduct business online; and CEI, a joint venture that manages collision claims for fleet vehicle and leasing companies. All are part of PPG’s effort to generate efficiencies for insurance companies and providers in the automotive aftermarket.
2003 Annual Report and Form 10-K ■ PPG Industries, Inc.
5
     
   Improve Our Customers’ Results
Of course, the purpose of improving our business mix and generating breakthrough technologies is to meet our customers’ requirements, as illustrated on these pages. Whether it’s supplying paint for computers, making the active ingredient for an HIV therapy, manufacturing and marketing Transitions photochromic lenses and Olympic paints and stains or processing auto glass claims for insur- ance companies, PPG’s performance is helping customers improve their performance. That’s the ultimate measure
of success.
One of the primary ways we help our customers improve their results is through our commitment to the Quality Process, which is dedicated to meeting customer
 Grady Lenski, senior director of trade sales, left, and Yvan Bertrand, far right, national account executive for Transitions Optical, review the benefits of Transitions lenses with Eduardo Ortiz, optical manager of the Costco warehouse in Clearwater, Fla.
Transitions photochromic ophthalmic lenses are no ordinary eyewear, and the commitment Transitions Optical and Costco make to educating optical staff is equally exceptional.
Professionally accredited coursework, some led by Transitions Optical professionals, and monthly training materials enable the opticians at Costco, a membership warehouse chain, to recommend products with confidence, including Transitions lenses, the most advanced lens technology ever developed. Transitions lenses are as clear as regular eyeglasses indoors, but outdoors darken as much as necessary, even getting as dark as sunglasses.
Costco’s commitment to education, as well
as high-quality products and member satisfaction, have helped the Seattle-based company win recognition as America’s top optical retailer.
With 20 million members, Costco operates 430 warehouses, including 318 in the United States and Puerto Rico, 62 in Canada and 23 in Mexico.
Sales of Transitions lenses at outlets such
as Costco have helped Transitions Optical, a 51-percent-owned joint venture with Essilor International, to be the world’s fastest-growing optical lens company the past five years, climbing to a top-five industry position in sales.
6 2003 Annual Report and Form 10-K ■ PPG Industries, Inc.
requirements. Not surprisingly, price is one of the most common requirements among our customers. To meet this expectation and maintain our margins, we must be relentless in reducing our costs. Thanks to Sigma Logic and Lean Manufacturing methodologies as well as other initiatives, we have developed a level of operational excellence that has helped generate $350 million in manu- facturing efficiencies the past five years. Furthermore, our continued focus on the Quality Process enables us to drive costs even lower as we strive for continuous improvement.
Environment, Health and Safety
Our quest for continuous improvement extends to all areas of our company, including environment, health and safety. Although the PPG Injury and Illness Rate fell
8 percent in 2003, included in that number, tragically,
are the three PPG employees killed when an explosion occurred at a supplier’s facility located at our Caivano, Italy, automotive coatings plant in April 2003. That accident claimed the life of a supplier employee as well. Our 2003 rate also includes a U.S. architectural coatings employee killed in an automobile crash. I ask that you keep all these workers and their families in your prayers. As long as one employee is hurt, our efforts to eliminate risk will never cease. Accordingly, in 2003 we instituted the EHS Award of Excellence, which recognizes employees around the
      
  world who demonstrate superior achievement in environ- ment, health, safety and product stewardship, helping to maintain our focus on protecting employees, neighbors, customers and the environment.
Haynes Elected to Board of Directors
I welcome to our board of directors Victoria F. Haynes, president and chief executive officer of Research Triangle Institute, a North Carolina-based organization that performs scientific research and development in advanced technologies, public policy, environmental protection, health and medicine. Her experience and knowledge add to the strength of our company’s leadership.
As 2004 unfolds, PPG is positioned to perform well, which is a direct result of the efforts of our people around the world. Throughout the economic downturn, they worked hard to reduce costs and generate cash while maintaining our commitment to technology and customer service. Our company is on solid footing, thanks in large part to our employees. As stated in our Blueprint, we respect the dignity, rights and contributions of our employees. In return, we understand that our shareholders and the community at large expect an unwavering commitment to high ethical standards and integrity.
This foundation we have built for performance and growth is positioned to benefit us throughout the economic cycle, but especially as the global economy rebounds. Our optimism about the global economy grew throughout 2003, and that continues today. We see a steady improvement in economic conditions. At the same time, we remain committed to making significant further reductions in costs, ensuring that we enhance our perform- ance in all economic conditions and generate lasting value for our shareholders.
Raymond W. LeBoeuf
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
  Walter Sakowicz, left, PPG pharmaceutical products business manager, consults with Ernest Prisbe, Gilead’s vice president of chemical development, at Gilead’s headquarters near
San Francisco.
There are very few, if any, overnight successes
in the pharmaceutical industry. Commercial products often require years of development, trials and regulatory review.
That’s why PPG’s fine chemicals unit has developed strong relationships with pharmaceutical companies whose scientific excellence, management strength and commercial agility enable them to discover and develop breakthrough therapies. In the early 1990s, PPG recognized Gilead Sciences as one of those companies and has worked closely with its chemical development and contract manufacturing groups on several products.
Today PPG’s fine chemicals unit manufactures the active ingredient for Viread, a Gilead drug that is one of the fastest-growing HIV treatments ever. Using its unique technology portfolio, PPG worked with Gilead in rapidly developing an economical process to produce the highly complex active ingredient for Viread on an industrial scale.
PPG has been manufacturing the active ingredient at its PPG-Sipsy plant in Avrillé, France, since the product was introduced in the United States in October 2001. One of the most widely prescribed drugs in its class, Viread is also available in the major countries of Europe as well as Australia.
2003 Annual Report and Form 10-K ■ PPG Industries, Inc.
7
      