Shareholder Letter
Dear Shareholder:
In 2013, our continued focus on being the best performing industrial gases company in the world enabled Praxair to post record full-year sales, earnings and operating cash 􏽋ow, in a global economy that has shown only a modest recovery.
Sales were up 6% over 2012 – 8% excluding currency impacts – driven by volume growth including new project start-ups, higher pricing and several core industrial gases acquisitions.
Operating margin was an industry-leading 22%, contributing to earnings per share growth of 6%. Operating cash 􏽋ow was a record 􏽌2.􏱈 billion, about 2􏱛% of sales, enabling us to fund investments in new growth opportunities, increase dividends and reduce outstanding share count.
We also continued our diligent focus on return on capital, achieving an industry-leading 13%.
We completed three world-class hydrogen plants during the year to meet growing demand from re􏽍neries, increasing our global hydrogen capacity by 40 percent. Our acquisitions of NuCO2, a leading U.S. beverage carbonation business, and Dominion Technology Gases, a supplier of gases and equipment to the offshore oil and gas industry, were successfully integrated into Praxair’s existing operations and outperformed expectations.
We started up 18 large on-site projects globally
under long-term take-or-pay contracts and signed 11 new projects to contribute to future high-quality sales growth.
Our project backlog serves customers across several key end markets including chemicals, energy, primary metals, manufacturing and electronics. The backlog is well-balanced with approximately one-third of our projects located in
North America, one-third in Asia and the remaining in South America and Europe.
I applaud the entire Praxair team on another successful year of delivering on our mission – Making our planet
more productive. We remain committed to improving our customers’ economic and environmental performance through applications that improve water quality, reduce emissions and lower overall energy consumption, just to name a few. In 2013, we opened our latest global technology center in Shanghai, which will enable us to work closely with our customers to develop and implement these valuable applications both in China and across the globe.
Our success has been a function of not only our strategies, but our people and culture, which is re􏽋ected in our core values. Ethics and integrity set the foundation for all we do. And, safety remains a hallmark for the company where we continue to outperform the industry in key benchmarks such as recordable injury and lost workday rates.
In the area of environmental sustainability, Praxair has been selected as a component of the prestigious Dow Jones Sustainability World Index for 11 consecutive years – the only
U.S. chemical company with this distinction. One highlight in this area is our Zero Waste program in which over 8,000 employees and more than 200 sites globally have prevented approximately 􏱈8 million pounds of waste from going to land􏽍lls.
Our commitment to community engagement continues to grow stronger. In 2013, our employees invested nearly 63,000 hours of volunteer time in projects that bene􏽍tted more than 326,000 people around the world.
And 􏽍nally, diversity and inclusion remains a strong priority as we seek to attract and retain the best talent possible to ensure we continue to be the best performing industrial gases company in the world. We funded nearly 􏽌2.􏱛 million in diversity and education related programs and organizations such as Society of Women Engineers and the 􏹸razil Scienti􏽍c 􏱝obility Program. These programs form the foundation to ensure we have a diverse set of employees and leaders that re􏽋ect the expansive set of communities where we live and work.
As we look forward to 2014, we expect the global economy to grow at a moderate pace. And, while I am certain there will be pockets of variability as we progress through the year, we remain in a very good position to capitalize on all opportunities in the regions where we operate. Our unique position as the largest and only fully-integrated operator in North America will continue to pay dividends as the economy steadily strengthens and bene􏽍ts from a low-cost energy environment. In South America, growth should be positive, although uneven, given macroeconomic challenges. For continental Europe, we have a business properly sized to bene􏽍t as volumes stabilize. And, we also continue to expand our operations in Russia and are optimistic about its long-term growth potential. Finally, Asia is expected to grow at a healthy rate and our focus will continue to be on participating in that growth
while making sound and disciplined investment decisions
in the region.
We remain focused on our proven strategy of building out integrated supply systems and market density in our core geographies. And most importantly, we will continue to foster an environment of high performance and operational excellence in every aspect of our business. This culture has been institutionalized at Praxair over decades. It has made us who we are today and will enable us to deliver world-class shareholder value well into the future.
STEVE ANGEL
Chairman, President 􏱗 Chief Executive Of􏽍cer February 2014
  Financial comparisons are non-GAAP measures.
 page i
