DEAR FELLOW SHAREHOLDERS:
In 2014 RR Donnelley proudly celebrated its 150th anniversary and again achieved solid financial performance.
Full-year 2014 revenue increased by $1.1 billion or 10.7% versus last year, largely driven by the acquisitions of Consolidated Graphics, Inc. and the North American operations of Esselte Corporation. On an organic basis, we continued to see modest revenue growth, reporting a 0.5% increase for the year. We delivered $499 million of free cash flow, which was at the top end of our guidance range. It was the 11th consecutive year of significant free cash flow levels, affording us the financial strength and flexibility to pursue unique opportunities to grow domestically and internationally.
We completed our first year with our resegmented financial reporting, providing new visibility into our four business segments:
✓ Publishing & Retail Services: magazines, catalogs, retail inserts, books, and directories
✓ Variable Print: commercial and digital print, direct mail, labels, statement printing, forms, and office
products
✓ Strategic Services: logistics, financial, digital and creative solutions, and domestic-based sourcing – all of which are value-added offerings that complement our core print business
✓ International: product and service offerings in Asia, Latin America, Europe and Canada, Business Process Outsourcing, and Global Turnkey Solutions – an international supply chain offering that delivers value-added solutions to the consumer electronics, life sciences and telecom sectors
A Changing Landscape
We’ve been embracing change in communication trends since we were founded, and we’ve continued to evolve our business with these changing consumer preferences. Consumers all have their own preferred way to connect with brands they like – a catalog, the web, mobile and more. While print remains the centerpiece of
RR Donnelley, by increasing both our digital and print offerings, we continue to fortify our position as a leading integrated communication services provider. In 2014 we continued to add numerous complementary capabilities in creative and design services, content management, digital and print production, data analytics, supply chain management, business process outsourcing and logistics.
With this expanded portfolio of offerings and capabilities, RR Donnelley can power its more than 60,000 customers to create connected experiences with their customers. We synchronize our customers’ communications across multiple channels – from the inbox to the mailbox – to help them strengthen bonds and create loyalty with their customers and drive consumer response.
We’re working daily with organizations worldwide to create, produce, manage, optimize and distribute content that helps our customers to communicate more effectively. While different organizations have differing procurement strategies, product and service requirements, and strategic priorities, by employing our go-to-market approaches, we can address virtually any of an organization’s singular or enterprise-level communications needs.
Acquisitions
We continued to make investments to expand our portfolio of products and services while remaining alert to future opportunities. In 2014, we successfully completed the acquisitions of Consolidated Graphics, Inc., the North American operations of Esselte, and MultiCorpora, each of which provide our customers with an even more comprehensive menu of products and services to support their communications objectives.
Innovation
At RR Donnelley, our suite of IT-driven creative services, data analytics, innovative manufacturing, and mobile solutions are designed to support our customers’ omnichannel communications needs.

In 2014 alone, we were granted 20 new U.S. utility patents, adding to a global portfolio of over 700 patents worldwide. Among the technologies we continued to pursue in 2014 are Radio Frequency Identification (RFID) and Near Field Communications (NFC). These exciting innovations are creating new mobile marketing and consumer engagement opportunities for our customers. Our printed RFID and NFC inlay electronics can be incorporated into a variety of media, creating exciting opportunities to help customers reduce costs while improving inventory management, quality control and compliance verification.
Corporate Responsibility & Our Environmental, Health, Safety and Quality Priorities
Our comprehensive commitment to corporate social responsibility includes our unwavering support of sustainable environmental practices, diversity among our employees, health and safety initiatives, and a belief that we all must give back to the communities around the world we call home.
I am proud of the numerous accolades earned for our performance in printing, supply chain management and employee engagement, among others. I am also proud that organizations around the globe have recognized our work with awards and certifications that attest to our commitment to quality. In today’s competitive environment, maintaining acceptable levels of quality is a significant accomplishment that means achieving compliance with many different customer, legal and organizational requirements.
With all of our achievements, we believe that there is nothing more important than the safety of all of our employees. On five continents around the world, we set and strive to achieve new milestones in our safety performance year after year. While many programs and policies are in place to support our important safety initiatives, it is our employees’ daily attention to working safely that produces these results we so proudly report.
Living Our Values
As we embark on our next 150 years, we stand today on the shoulders of so many that came before us. I believe we reached this exceptional milestone in part due to our commitment to our core values and best practices.
RR Donnelley has always stood for the highest standards of integrity, ethics, sustainability, innovation, and dedication to its customers. While so much has changed in the world of communication, our core values have remained the same.
We are grateful to our employees for their dedication to operational excellence on behalf of our customers, their commitment to the highest ethical conduct, and their ongoing achievement of superior safety standards. We are most thankful to our customers worldwide for giving us the opportunity to serve their print and broader communications needs. To our shareholders, we thank you for your continued confidence.
Sincerely,
Thomas J. Quinlan III
President & Chief Executive Officer April 2015
 