  David Simon
Chief Executive Officer
EAxpanding Our Reach
look back at our activities and accomplishments in 2004 reveals an overriding theme, one of “expanding our reach” – by asset type, in retailer relationships, and
geographically.
 We have always been a retail real estate company and not “just a regional mall company.” After the acquisition of Chelsea Property Group, we operate from four major platforms –regional malls, Premium Outlet® centers, community/ lifestyle centers and our international property investments. Within these platforms, nearly all retail distribution channels are represented – from neighborhood shopping centers to power centers to Premium Outlet centers to mega-town centers and super-regional malls. Our strategy is to have a significant presence in each of these elements of the retail real estate spectrum since all of these channels have appeal to our retailers and consumers. We will pursue opportunities within all of our business platforms that enhance our retail real estate franchise and generate profitable returns.
 Our retailer relationships continue to expand and include such top names in retailing as Neiman Marcus, Nordstrom, Saks, Dick’s Sporting Goods, Dillard’s, Macy’s, Bloomingdale’s, JCPenney, Sears, Target and virtually every U.S. specialty and big-box retailer. We are the largest landlord to many of the nation’s leading retailers, and both we and our retailers appreciate the value of such a relationship and the importance of our mutual success.
 Our geographic expansion included the acquisition of Plaza Carolina in San Juan, Puerto Rico; the opening of four shopping centers in Poland, Italy and France; the addition of four Premium Outlet centers in Japan; and the opening of a Premium Outlet center near Mexico City. Our portfolio now includes 51 European shopping centers in France, Italy, Poland and Portugal, five Premium Outlet centers in Japan (the fifth opened in March of 2005) and one Premium Outlet center in Mexico.
2004 was a very productive year for us in new project development, asset acquisitions, and capital market transactions. We were active on many fronts, but remained focused on day-to- day operations and the creation and enhancement of value for our stockholders. This strategy paid off – both financially and operationally.
Report to Stockholders
Financial Highlights
 Consolidated revenues increased 14.9% to $2.642 billion in 2004 from $2.300 billion in 2003. The increase was due largely to our 2004 acquisitions and increases in occupancy, average base rent and tenant sales.
 Diluted funds from operations (“FFO”) of the Simon portfolio increased 12.1% to $1.198 billion, or $4.39 per diluted share, from $1.069 billion or $4.04 per diluted share. Results for 2004 include the impact of a non-cash impairment charge that decreased diluted FFO per share by $0.07.
 Net income available to common stockholders was $300.6 million in 2004 as compared to $313.6 million in 2003. On a diluted per share basis, the decrease was 12.7% to $1.44 per share from $1.65 per share in 2003. The decline is primarily attributable to our share of 2003 net gains on the sale of real estate that exceeded similar gains in 2004 and the non-cash impairment charge in 2004.
This strong financial performance prompted our Board of Directors to increase our stockholders’ annual dividend in February of 2005 by 7.7%, to $2.80 per common share. Our common stock dividend has increased 27% since February of 2002.
Operational Highlights
Business operations continued to be strong in 2004 as evidenced by solid increases in operational statistics for our three domestic platforms – regional malls, Premium Outlet centers and community/lifestyle centers (“community centers”).
 Occupancy increased in all three domestic platforms in 2004 – the regional mall portfolio was 92.7% leased, as compared to 92.4% in 2003; the Premium Outlet portfolio was 99.3% leased, as compared to 99.0% in 2003, and the community center portfolio was 91.9% leased, as compared to 90.2% in 2003.
 Tenant sales productivity also increased in all platforms. Comparable sales per square foot increased 6.2% to $427 in our regional mall portfolio; 7.0% to $412 in our Premium Outlet portfolio; and 2.9% to $215 in our community center portfolio.
 Rental rates were also higher in 2004 with a 3.8% increase in the regional mall portfolio to $33.50 per square foot; a 7.3% increase in the Premium Outlet portfolio to $21.85 per square foot; and a 3.0% increase in the community center portfolio to $10.91 per square foot.
The Company’s international properties also performed well in 2004.
 Our European shopping centers were 96% leased at December 31, 2004, and they generated sales of $526 per square foot. Average base rent at year-end was $34.11.
 4 Simon Property Group, Inc.

 The Company’s Premium Outlet centers in Japan were 100% leased at year-end, and they generated comparable sales of $821 per square foot.
As a result of 2004 acquisition and development activities, the Company’s portfolio in the United States increased from 245 properties comprising 190 million square feet to 297 properties with 203 million square feet. The Company’s international portfolio grew from 48 properties comprising 9 million square feet to 57 properties with 12 million square feet.
2004 Acquisitions
Our most significant transaction in 2004 was the fourth quarter acquisition of Chelsea Property Group (“Chelsea”), the leading owner, developer and manager of Premium Outlet® centers in the U.S. and Asia. Chelsea’s Premium Outlet centers are strategically located, highly-productive retail real estate venues in desirable markets. The Chelsea portfolio includes 31 Premium Outlet centers in the U.S. located in major metropolitan markets such as New York, Los Angeles and Boston, and tourist destinations such as Orlando, Las Vegas and Palm Springs. The portfolio also includes five Premium Outlet centers in Japan (located near Tokyo, Osaka, Nagoya and Fukuoka) and another Premium Outlet center near Mexico City.
Chelsea operates as a division of our Company from its headquarters in Roseland, New Jersey with David Bloom (chief executive officer of Chelsea) and the well-respected management team continuing in their leadership roles.
This transaction, completed on October 14, 2004 for $5.2 billion, gave us a market-leading position in the Premium Outlet business that will serve as a new growth platform for our Company. We will continue to grow this business through new development at attractive yields, increasing existing center cash flow and expanding the geographic reach of this successful product type.
During 2004 we also acquired a 95% interest in Gateway Shopping Center, an open-air center in Austin, Texas; a 100% interest in Plaza Carolina, a highly-productive mall in San Juan Puerto Rico; and additional ownership interests in five of the Company’s existing joint ventures.
New Developments/Openings
Last May we opened Chicago Premium Outlets in Aurora, Illinois. It is an upscale manufacturers’ outlet shopping center located approximately 35 miles west of downtown Chicago on I-88. In October we opened our 50%-owned Clay Terrace, an open-air, mixed-use lifestyle center in Carmel, a suburb north of Indianapolis.
In addition, we had six U.S. developments under construction at the end of 2004 – St. Johns Town Center in Jacksonville, Florida; Seattle Premium Outlets located 35 miles north of Seattle, Washington; Wolf Ranch located north of Austin, Texas;
 Simon’s Four Retail Real Estate Platforms
 Regional Malls
 Premium Outlet Centers
 Community/Lifestyle Centers
 International
20042A0n0n4uAanl nRueaplorRteport 5
 
  Consolidated Revenues
($ in billions)
$2.6
2002 2003 2004
                         $2.3 $2.1
                                                                                                                           FFO per Share
(Diluted)
$3.76
2002 2003 2004
   Dividends Per Common Share
$2.60 $2.40
$2.18
2002 2003 2004
                                                                                                                                                    Total Market Capitalization
($ in billions)
6 Simon PropeerrtytyGGrorouup,p,InIcn.c.
$4.39
                         $4.04
                                                                                                                        $37.2
                         $25.8 $21.3
                                                                                                                          2002 2003 2004
Firewheel Town Center in Garland, Texas (northeast of Dallas); and Rockaway Plaza in Rockaway, New Jersey, all opening this year; and The Town Center at Coconut Point in Estero/Bonita Springs, Florida opening in 2006. These projects are all open- air concepts located in growing markets. They contain lifestyle tenants and an increased number of quality restaurants. We are integrating a wide variety of retail uses from traditional department stores to leading discounters to category killers and other specialty retailers. We expect these developments to have broad shopper appeal.
During 2004, the Company opened hypermarket-anchored shopping centers in Bari and Cuneo, Italy and a theater-anchored shopping center in a suburb of Paris, France. In October, we opened the largest shopping center in Eastern Europe, Arkadia, in Warsaw, Poland. It comprises approximately 1.1 million square feet and is a multi-level enclosed mall anchored by Carrefour and Leroy Merlin. Lastly, Premium Outlets Punta Norte, located 17 miles northwest of Mexico City, opened in December.
The Company had four international projects under construction at year-end – Toki Premium Outlets located outside Nagoya, the third largest city in Japan, which opened in March 2005; Napoli Nola and Napoli Guigliano in Naples, Italy; and Porta di Roma in Rome.
All of our development projects, in the U.S. and abroad, are on-track to yield stabilized double-digit, project-level unlevered returns on cost.
Department Store Consolidation
We frequently receive inquiries regarding the impact of department store consolidation on our business, and recently, regarding the potential impact of the proposed merger of Federated Department Stores, Inc. and The May Department Stores Company. We have 27 malls with at least one Federated and one May store. These are high-quality assets in strong markets with average sales per square foot approaching $500. At this time we do not know if or where there will be store consolidation arising from this merger.
Over the years we have demonstrated our ability to add quality anchors and big-box tenants to our portfolio. During 2004 we added 32 anchors and big-boxes, utilizing space formerly occupied by Lord & Taylor, Montgomery Ward and Service Merchandise. These anchor and big-box additions include Nordstrom, Dick’s Sporting Goods, Barnes & Noble, The Cheesecake Factory, Target and JCPenney. For 2005 we already have scheduled the addition of 22 anchors, big-boxes and major tenants, highlighted by Nordstrom opening at Phipps Plaza in Atlanta in March and Neiman Marcus opening at Town Center at Boca Raton in October.
Because of the high quality of our portfolio, the strength of our leasing and development personnel, and our experience in the retenanting of our malls, I believe that we are well-equipped to respond to the recent merger activity in the department store industry.
Stockholder Returns and Governance
The price of our common stock advanced 39.6% to close at $64.67 at 2004 year-end, as compared to $46.34 at 2003 year- end. With the inclusion of our $2.60 cash dividend, stockholders experienced a total return of 45.2% in 2004.
 
  Comparative Performance – Total Return
(December 31, 2001 to December 31, 2004)
                                      
Sim
N
on
Property
AREIT Equity Index
S&P 5
00Index–r
Gr
oup – ros
os
– rose 87
e 11.2%
e 145.0%
.3%
     

+150% +125% +100%
+75% +50% +25%
+0% –25% –50%
                2002 2003 2004
 At Simon Property Group, corporate governance means much more than accurate financial reporting and director independence. Since going public in 1993, we have sought to provide investors the opportunity to invest in a liquid, dividend paying, quality real estate portfolio that was actively managed for the benefit of all stockholders.
The past year marked the successful completion of our assessment of the effectiveness of our internal controls over financial reporting as required under Section 404 of the Sarbanes- Oxley Act of 2002. I am pleased with the result of our efforts in this area, which involved a multi-disciplinary approach and deployed extensive resources to comply with all facets of these regulations. Further, our Section 404 methodology provides us with a stable foundation for ongoing compliance because of our existing controls and the adaptability of our organization. We are well-positioned to meet our ongoing Section 404 requirements.
Our corporate governance rating quotient by Institutional Shareholder Services (“ISS”) is very strong, and ISS reported that as of November of 2004, Simon Property Group outperformed 84.6% of the companies comprising the S&P 500 Index and 89.1% of the companies in the real estate group. Our stockholders can rest assured that we will remain abreast of any new requirements and take the necessary steps to insure we develop policies and procedures, with the input and assistance of our Board, that will enable us to comply with all applicable rules and regulations.
Board of Directors
We were pleased to announce the addition of Karen Horn to our Board of Directors in 2004. She is the Senior Managing Di- rector of Brock Capital Group and previously served as President of Private Client Services and Managing Director of Marsh, Inc., a subsidiary of MMC. She also serves as a director for Eli Lilly and Company, Georgia-Pacific, T. Rowe Price Mutual Funds and The U.S. Russia Investment Fund, a presidential appointment.
G. William Miller will retire from our Board at the 2005 Annual Meeting. Bill has served the Company with uncommon dedication and distinction throughout his nine year tenure, and we will truly miss his wealth of experience, his leadership as Chairman of the Board’s Governance Committee and his financial expertise. I cannot thank him enough for the guidance he has provided our Company during the last several very active years.
Outlook
Looking back over our history as a public company, I believe it is evident that we have been innovative leaders in our industry. We began the industry consolidation with our acquisition of DeBartolo Realty Corporation in 1996 and have led it since to our current position as the nation’s largest REIT. We were also the first to present the value proposition that “size and scale matter” in the retail real estate business and to espouse the benefits of acquiring premier malls in major markets with our acquisition of Corporate Property Investors in 1998.
With our launch of Simon Brand Ventures in 1997, we were the first to address the importance of number of shopper visits and owning malls in major media markets, and we created and have since refined the concept of the mall as a marketing medium. Through our Simon Business Network initiative we were the first
retail real estate company to aggressively aggregate purchasing power in our portfolio to control operating costs.
We were also the first domestic “mall company” to invest internationally in 1998 and move beyond the mall product to other forms of successful retail real estate including Premium Outlet centers and community centers.
I am proud of our history, our accomplishments to date and our reputation as the industry leader.
We have been a public company for eleven years, and during that time we expanded from a real estate company with a $3 billion market capitalization to become the largest REIT in the United States with a total capitalization in excess of $37 billion. This was possible because we never wavered from our focus on owning the finest properties in the very best locations. Whether acquiring properties or building new ones, our growth never came at the expense of our balance sheet. These same principles continue to guide our activities as we enter 2005.
The new year appears promising as the economy continues to improve. We believe that our multi-faceted growth strategy combined with our business platforms and our portfolio of highly productive, well-located retail real estate and sector leading balance sheet, positions us well.
I would like to express my appreciation to the many who contributed to last year’s success, particularly my colleagues and our many retailers. I wish to also thank our Board of Directors for their guidance and our stockholders for their continued support.
David Simon
Chief Executive Officer
Indianapolis, IN March 14, 2005
 2004 Annual Report 7
