Letter to shareholders
“Our strategy is working. We are delivering operating profit growth, improved margins and strong cash flows. In addition, we have taken numerous significant actions that demonstrate our ongoing commitment to provide sustainable, long‐term value to our shareholders.”
  Paul Manning
President and Chief Executive Officer
Performance and Progress
Sensient’s 2014 earnings per share increased 11% over last year’s performance to $3.02 per share. Operating margin increased 120 basis points to 15.3%, as each of our operating groups delivered higher margins this year. Overall, we had a very positive year that exceeded our performance objectives.
Operating cash flow was also strong in 2014, increasing 23% to $189 million, and free cash flow more than doubled to $110 million. Return on invested capital also improved 50 basis points to 10.2%. We will continue to improve returns by delivering solid earnings growth, rationalizing our production assets, reducing our working capital levels and optimizing our capital allocation strategy.
Revenue was stable in local currency terms, as we deliberately rationalized non‐strategic and low‐margin business. We began these efforts in 2010 in the Color Group and effectively concluded them in the first half of 2014. Revenue rationalization was more significant in the Flavors & Fragrances Group during 2014, and these actions will continue to impact the Group’s revenue growth in 2015. Consolidated revenue grew by 2.5% in local currency, excluding the impact of the rationalized business.
Color Group – Another Strong Year
The Color Group had another strong year in 2014, producing local currency revenue growth of 4%, and profit growth of 7%. The Color Group’s operating margins improved to 22.6%, an increase of 80 basis points over 2013.
The Color Group’s 2014 performance was driven by its technical capabilities, innovation and market reach, and these strengths
will continue to drive new growth. Sensient continues to build on our leadership in colors for foods and beverages. We stand out from competitors because of our unique ability to provide a full spectrum of both synthetic and natural color solutions. In 2014, our proprietary natural blue and brown color systems increased sales as manufacturers increasingly seek to extend their clean‐label offerings.
The Color Group’s cosmetics business also performed well in 2014, and we expect sustain- able growth moving forward. In 2015, we will
1

 2014 NET INCOME 2014 CASH FLOW
  $147
MILLION
$189
MILLION
open a new Center of Excellence just outside Paris, where we can showcase our capabilities in cosmetics and work closely with manufac- turers from around the world. This new facility will enable us to strengthen ties with custom- ers, accelerate product development and increase sales.
In 2014, our industrial ink business performed especially well, and we see significant opportu- nities for growth in this segment. Our propri- etary line of aqueous colors for digital printing is environmentally friendly and provides tremen- dous advantages, including brighter colors and faster printing speeds, to manufacturers of clothing, textiles and other products.
The Color Group’s performance in the last
five years serves as a model for the entire Company. When I joined Sensient in 2009, the Color Group’s annual revenue was $375 million, operating income was just under $59 million and the operating margin was 15.7%. During the last five years, the Group’s businesses
have delivered strong growth and expanded operating margins by focusing on product development and sales coverage, improving the product mix to emphasize value‐added solutions and reducing costs. From 2009 to 2014, Color Group revenue increased 35%, while eliminating $50 million in low-margin business, operating profit has nearly doubled and our operating margin increased by 690 basis points to 22.6%.
Flavors & Fragrances Group – Change and Progress
In 2013, we began implementing a series of strategic initiatives in the Flavors & Fragrances Group to match the success of the Color Group. We instituted processes used by the Color Group to foster new product development and strengthened our sales and technical teams. We
also realigned our commercial and technical activities around industry segments that better serve our customers.
In 2014, we began to eliminate non‐strategic product lines and products that do not generate adequate margins. We will continue to evaluate our product offerings with the goal of utilizing our unique ingredients within higher‐margin, value‐added flavor and fragrance systems that are differentiated from the competition. We are also streamlining production to improve plant utilization and lower costs. These strategic changes and restructuring efforts will temper our revenue growth in 2015 for the Flavors & Fragrances Group. We do expect to see improvement in both gross margins and operating margins next year. The Group remains on track to achieve operating margins in the high‐teens and consistent operating profit growth.
Sensient’s new state‐of‐the‐art Flavors & Fragrances Group headquarters, located
just outside Chicago, underscores our commitment to product development and customer engagement. At the new headquar- ters, we can better showcase our broad product portfolio, develop new solutions
and collaborate with customers.
Overall, the Flavors & Fragrances Group is
on track. While the Group’s operating profit did not grow, we saw significant improvement in the gross profit margin, which increased by 130 basis points. Operating margins also improved, even with our investment in sales and technical personnel. Several of the Group’s businesses performed very well and achieved double‐digit profit growth in 2014. Highlights include new wins with yogurt products; a growing beverage flavors business; and improved profitability and margin growth for our natural ingredients business.
 2

 Building Shareholder Value
Early in 2014, the Company announced a four‐ part plan to enhance shareholder value that included a dividend increase, share repurchas- es, restructuring savings and governance improvements. Each of these elements aligns with our objective to provide sustainable, long-term value to shareholders.
In 2014, the Board of Directors increased the quarterly dividend 9% to 25 cents per share, or $1 per share on an annualized basis. Sensient has increased the quarterly dividend almost 40% over the last six years. The Board recog- nizes that dividends are an important mecha- nism for returning capital to shareholders.
In the second quarter of 2014, the Company repurchased two million shares. In July, our Board approved a new share repurchase authorization, allowing the Company to repurchase an additional five million shares.
Sensient made a number of enhancements to our governance and compensation policies in 2014. We adopted a majority voting standard for uncontested Board elections, appointed an independent lead director and added two new independent directors. We will continue to evaluate potential director candidates, consistent with our ongoing commitment to Board refresh- ment. We have also more closely aligned pay to performance over the past few years, including linking 100% of share-based compensation awards for officers to performance targets.
In total, these actions improved the Company’s cost structure, returned significant cash to shareholders and demonstrated our commitment to maintaining best‐in‐class governance and compensation practices. Investors responded favorably to these actions as our stock price hit an all‐time high near the end of last year. Total shareholder return for 2014, with reinvestment of dividends, was 27%, significantly in excess of the 15% earned by the S&P 400 Specialty Chemicals Index. We will continue to take actions focused on delivering sustainable, long‐term value to our shareholders.
A Promising Future
It was very gratifying to lead the Company in a positive direction during my first year as Chief Executive Officer. Sensient’s Color Group has consistently delivered strong results, and the Flavors & Fragrances Group is well positioned to make significant progress in 2015 and beyond. We have unmatched technologies, robust product development capabilities, deep market reach throughout our businesses and great people.
We are now strengthening our ability to leverage these advantages in a number of ways. Notably, the Company is sharpening our focus on customers. We aim to be an indispensable creative and strategic partner to our customers— not simply a supplier. Our investment in excep- tional scientific, technical and sales personnel plays a critical role in our ability to attract and retain customers. The pieces continue to fall into place across the Company.
I want to conclude by thanking Sensient’s shareholders, customers, employees and Board members for your ongoing support. I have high expectations for the Company and look forward to sharing news of our progress.
Sincerely,
Paul Manning
President and Chief Executive Officer
SENSIENT TECHNOLOGIES CORPORATION 2014
    Governance Improvements
ENHANCING
shareholder value
Share Repurchase Program
  Restructuring Program
Dividend Increase
The new authorization gives the Company the flexibility to repurchase shares over the next several years, and we purchased another 500,000 shares in the fourth quarter. Including dividend payments, Sensient returned $185 million to shareholders in 2014, and we will continue to repurchase shares on an opportunistic basis.
The 2014 restructuring program was imple- mented to eliminate underperforming busi- nesses and consolidate manufacturing operations. These actions are on track and we expect to complete most consolidation activities by the end of 2015. Our restructuring actions will provide ongoing operating efficiencies and reduced capital requirements.
 3
