  2004 Annual Report
 Dear Shareholders,
Fiscal 2004 was another year of record performance for our company. We launched 72 exciting new products, delivered four new service offerings, significantly enhanced our direct sales force, and continued to aggressively promote our brand. Our global sales team capped off this great year with strong, double-digit revenue growth in every region. Momentum was evident in many areas of the business, including record results in our core antivirus business and consumer segment, as well as a record number of large enterprise wins.
Throughout the year, the threat environment continued to affect many enterprises and individuals around the world and produced one of the most serious outbreak environments we have seen yet. Today’s cyberattacks demonstrate that companies as well as individual users need to employ comprehensive, integrated security solutions. The combination of shortened lead times between the discovery of new vulnerabilities and the release of an exploit, coupled with rapid propagation techniques, is beginning to drive a new paradigm for Internet threats. We believe we are the best-positioned company in the industry to protect companies and individuals from these threats given the breadth of our offerings, and the confidence and trust our customers place in us during these challenging times.
“SYMANTEC’S INTEGRATION OF SECURITY FUNCTIONALITY AND ENTERPRISE- LEVEL MANAGEMENT HELPS CUSTOMERS SECURE AND MANAGE THEIR IT INFRASTRUCTURES MORE EFFECTIVELY. OUR ABILITY TO PROVIDE ADDITIONAL CAPABILITIES TO SOLVE REAL BUSINESS PROBLEMS—SUCH AS MANAGING THE GROWING COST AND COMPLEXITY OF TECHNOLOGIES DEPLOYED THROUGHOUT NETWORKS—IS DRIVING OUR SUCCESS.”
􏽄 ANOTHER RECORD YEAR
We successfully executed the strategy we outlined last year, continuing the well-established pattern of revenue growth, solid profitability, and strong cash generation. With one of the strongest new product lineups in the company’s history, and a more stable global economic environment, we exceeded our internal expectations every quarter throughout fiscal 2004. We grew revenue to a record $1.870 billion, representing 33% year-over-year growth when compared with fiscal 2003, and our non-GAAP* diluted earnings per share increased from $0.86 to $1.18. Deferred revenue grew 65% to $971 million, giving us the best visibility in our history.
*Non-GAAP results are reconciled to GAAP results on page 12.
«8» SYMANTEC CORPORATION
Left to right: John G. Schwarz, President and Chief Operating Officer; John W. Thompson, Chairman of the Board and Chief Executive Officer; Gregory E. Myers, Senior Vice President of Finance and Chief Financial Officer.

 
 2004 Annual Report
 As a result of strong cash flow from operating activities and cash proceeds from employees exercising stock options, our cash position grew significantly to $2.4 billion. Our robust cash position provides the flexibility to invest in our future with key acquisitions to strengthen our product portfolio. Additionally, we continue to return value to our shareholders through our stock repurchase program. By investing nearly 13% of our revenue in research and development, we are able to stay at the forefront of the markets we serve by delivering innovative technologies and services for our customers around the world.
“SYMANTEC IS LEADING THE SECURITY INDUSTRY’S TRANSFORMATION WHILE GROWING CUSTOMER AND PARTNER RELATIONSHIPS THROUGH AN EXPANDING SET OF PRODUCTS AND SERVICES. THREE CORE CAPABILITIES SET SYMANTEC APART FROM THE COMPETITION—INTEGRATED SECURITY SOLUTIONS, SERVICES, AND MANAGEMENT SOLUTIONS.”
􏽄 MARKET TRENDS AND GROWTH OPPORTUNITIES
Integrated Security Solutions. Symantec is positioned to address the full range of information security needs faced by home and small business users as well as enterprise customers. Computer Reseller News recognized Symantec as the pioneer of the integrated security approach with the introduction of our first integrated gateway security appliance more than two years ago. The SymantecTM Gateway Security 300 Series brings integrated security protection to small business customers. The SymantecTM Client Security solution provides customers with more comprehensive threat protection through integrated security technologies for remote, mobile, and networked client systems. These products offer a tremendous benefit to our partners as they build an expanded set of services to serve our mutual customer needs more fully. Additionally, our award-winning Norton Internet SecurityTM suite provides home and small business users with essential online security protection from privacy threats, hackers, and viruses.
Services. We will continue to invest in our three services families—managed security services, consulting, and education and training—to provide industry best practices, proactive monitoring, as well as management and knowledge transfer. We believe services are important complementary capabilities to our software offerings and help strengthen our long-term customer relationships. Gartner, a leading market research firm, placed SymantecTM Managed Security Services in the “leaders quadrant” in their most recent Magic Quadrant report. We believe this recognition underscores our market strength and continued leadership in helping companies manage their security environments.
«10» SYMANTEC CORPORATION
 
 2004 Annual Report
 Management Solutions. The only truly secure infrastructure is a managed one. That’s why Symantec is developing effective solutions that allow systems administrators to automate routine tasks and solve problems efficiently and securely. Our strategy is to blend our knowledge of vulnerabilities and network threats with key innovations in the systems and storage management areas, which are converging with network management. Our goal is to improve information availability and drive real-time, operational decisions for customers. Symantec DeepSightTM Alert Services monitors vulnerabilities in nearly 20,000 technologies from 2,200 vendors enhancing Symantec’s extensive knowledge of the threat environment. This early warning security system enables customers to proactively manage their environments and reduce the risk of disruption. Being able to trigger an operational event from a security alert can drive better control over the environment. We believe we are the only company that can fully secure and manage the integrity of information.
􏽄 FUTURE GROWTH DRIVERS
With the acquisition of PowerQuest and ON Technology during the year, our market opportunity sits at more than $30 billion, with a forecasted compounded annual growth rate of nearly 20%. This position provides Symantec with the opportunity to deliver strong double-digit growth over time.
We enter fiscal year 2005 with an unprecedented leadership opportunity and a clear intent to capitalize on the product breadth and capabilities that set us apart. We plan to move forward in our key growth markets, using the power of our technology platforms to meet the needs of customers, effectively leverage an ecosystem of partners, and provide more value to our shareholders. Our relationships with customers and channel partners are clearly driving Symantec’s results. By responding to their requirements with a broad portfolio of technologies for securing and managing the complexity of today’s IT environments, we help customers reduce the cost of dealing with an increasingly complex infrastructure and help ensure the integrity of their most precious asset—information. In doing so, we expect to realize the true growth potential of our company.
We want to thank our customers, partners, and shareholders for their continued confidence in our company. Most important, I’d like to thank our employees around the world for their talent, dedication, and commitment to the success of our customers and Symantec.
Sincerely,
John W. Thompson
Chairman of the Board and Chief Executive Officer
 SYMANTEC CORPORATION «11»
 