OUR HIGHLIGHTS FOR THE YEAR:
We executed our acquisition strategy, acquiring Mayo Healthcare, and integrating and leveraging the Vidacare acquisition we completed in 2013.
We fueled our R&D engine, launching 16 new products and line extensions.
We expanded our reach, extending 23 existing agreements and forging 6 new relationships with healthcare purchasing groups worldwide.
We developed a multi-year facility restructuring plan to drive operational efficiency and lower costs.
We also delivered strong 2014 financial results, including constant currency growth of 8.8 percent. Collectively, our 2014 accomplishments fortified our business platform, positioning Teleflex to meet the near-term demands of our marketplace and achieve continued growth in the future. The credit for our progress belongs to our employees who are the front line in connecting with our customers around the world. I want to thank all of our team members for their hard work and commitment.
EXECUTING OUR ACqUISITION STRATEGY
Acquisitions have played an important role in our growth, enabling us to achieve scale, diversify our product portfolio, strengthen our R&D, and broaden our reach. We follow a strict acquisition protocol that targets select opportunities, including:
Late-stage technology companies with promising products on the cusp of regulatory approval;
Established companies with differentiated products that align with our existing business; and
Product distributors in key geographic regions that allow us to convert to a direct sales model.
Our 2014 acquisition of Mayo Healthcare
falls into the third category and represents an excellent margin growth opportunity for Teleflex. Mayo is a provider of products, services and customer support to healthcare institutions across Australia. Through this acquisition,
we have forged a direct link to our customers
in this region, enabling us to increase sales volume and improve pricing. This transaction was immediately accretive, and during 2014, Mayo contributed 160 basis points to Teleflex’s constant currency revenue growth. We are continuing to evaluate additional distributor-to- direct conversion opportunities, especially in Asia and Europe.
TO OUR SHAREHOLDERS
At Teleflex, we are dedicated to delivering improved patient care while managing the cost of healthcare around the world. We believe this commitment will steadily increase shareholder value. We measure our progress against our ability to meet three financial goals: To grow revenues faster than the markets we serve, to increase our adjusted gross and operating margins, and to invest in our future. In 2014, we met these goals, while expanding our global market share and creating efficiencies across our business.
        2

We also demonstrated our commitment to swift and careful execution during the year
by re-branding Vidacare’s products under the Arrow® brand, integrating these products into our business, and building a franchise in the area of intraosseous (IO), or inside the bone, access devices. Customer response to the Arrow® EZ-IO® Vascular Access System and the Arrow® OnControl® Powered Bone Marrow Biopsy System has been extremely positive, and these products contributed approximately $87 million in revenue and 4.7 percent of constant currency revenue growth to Teleflex during 2014. We believe our intraosseous business offers significant opportunity for gross margin and revenue growth, and we are dedicating additional resources to developing it in the future.
DRIVING MARGIN GROwTH
We are constantly seeking to capture margin expansion opportunities, and we have many to pursue. During 2014, we began to implement a multi-year restructuring plan, which will relocate our manufacturing facilities in relatively high- cost areas to our existing facilities in lower cost areas. We expect to complete this program by year-end 2017, enabling us to improve operating leverage, streamline logistics and expedite product delivery.
This restructuring offers clear financial and logistical advantages, but also requires us
to reduce our workforce at certain facilities. These are not decisions we make lightly. After a careful review of current and future healthcare dynamics, we are convinced that this relocation is a necessary step. Moreover, we are confident that our restructuring will enable us to manage growing competitive pressures and pave
the way for growth in an increasingly cost- sensitive market. We have also identified other opportunities for margin improvement, including consolidating raw materials purchases, exploring cost-effective packaging options and increasing automation. We expect these initiatives to enable us to meet our long-term financial objectives. Even more importantly, we see opportunities
for continued margin expansion over the next several years, and we are committed to realizing these improvements.
LEVERAGING MARkET DYNAMICS
The global healthcare market is continuously evolving. At any given time and place, healthcare utilization is influenced by regional shifts
in regulatory policy, economic strength and political status that can create significant short- term challenges in individual markets. Teleflex
is well equipped to meet these challenges.
Our product portfolio addresses the needs of multiple healthcare segments, and our customer base spans the world. This diversity helps us to offset temporary regional business declines and generate steady revenue growth, regardless of the market environment.
Moreover, the long-term growth prospects for healthcare remain excellent, largely due to global demographics. Specifically, an aging population in industrialized nations and the emergence of
a middle class in many developing nations are driving a greater need for medical care. Societies around the world are seeking ways to manage the costs of this care, and they are turning to leading medical device companies like Teleflex to help. Our products increase precision, reduce pain and minimize the risk of complications, helping to speed patient recovery times and decrease the overall costs associated with a range of surgical and critical care procedures.
As a result, our portfolio offers a compelling value proposition to healthcare providers even in today’s cost-conscious market.
FOCUSING ON THE FUTURE
Teleflex moves forward with confidence. During the past year, we continued to prove that we have a strong, stable business that is positioned to manage short-term market challenges and capitalize on long-term opportunities. In the months ahead, we will continue our momentum, executing our strategies to drive revenues, improve margins and strengthen our business platform. In the process, we will continue to reinforce our dedication to rewarding you
– our shareholders − with the attention and commitment to value you deserve.
BENSON F. SMITH
Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer
 3
