                                           To Our Shareholders:
Allmerica Financial achieved record net operating earnings and record earnings per share for the sixth consecutive year. Our focused business strategies, which were first articulated in 1995, as well as a deeply-engrained expense management discipline, enabled us to improve our operations significantly and achieve a record level of operat- ing revenue and return on equity. Our record results were achieved in spite of challenging industry conditions during the year, including volatility in stock market prices, property and casualty loss trends and product pricing. This financial performance validated our conviction that we have the correct strategies and the com- petitive strengths to grow the company over the long-term, even if our markets undergo some short-term cyclicality.
Allmerica is a multi-line financial services company, which provides our shareholders
John F. O’Brien
PRESIDENT AND CHIEF EXECUTIVE OFFICER
with the stability that comes with a diversified, balanced earnings base derived from two different segments of the insurance industry. Our consis- tent earnings growth over the past several years has benefited from the ability to target the fastest growing parts of our industry with new products and technology, combined with well-established regional market knowledge and distribution.
Our retirement business empha- sizes products that combine asset accumulation and the ability to manage risk. We help our customers accumulate assets to fund their retire- ment and we develop products designed to enable them to maintain their lifestyle throughout retirement. Our purpose is to provide our clients with security over the long-term, first with the correct advice on appropriate accumulation strategies and then with the right combination of advice and service when converting to an income program that supports their retirement needs and
the transfer of wealth to heirs.
  2
00

                                           $5.58 $5.06
 $3.52 $3.00
$2.41
   96 97 98 99 00
  Net Operating Income Per Share
In the property and casualty busi- ness, we provide risk management insurance solutions for individuals and businesses. As indi- viduals have shown greater interest in buying auto and home insurance through their employers and business associations in recent years, we have targeted these “sponsored” markets. We also have concentrated on small commercial accounts, cap- italizing upon our regional strength, knowledge of local markets, and strong relationships with agents. In addition, sponsored markets for individ- uals and the small commercial market for business
offer above industry-average growth potential.
Record Financial Results
Allmerica’s 2000 net operating earnings were $5.58 per share, compared to $5.06 per share in 1999. We have achieved a cumulative average annual earnings growth rate of 23 percent since becoming a public company in October, 1995.
Return on equity rose for the fourth consecutive year to 12.8 percent as a result of higher earnings and the continuation of effective capital management strategies. During 2000, an additional 1.9 million shares of Allmerica’s common stock were acquired pur- suant to the repurchase program which was
initially announced in late 1998.
Employee ownership of Allmerica’s
stock, both individually and through retirement programs, has increased steadily since 1995 and rose again in 2000 to include over 80 percent of all employees.We believe that employees who also are stockholders of the Company have a stronger incentive to perform over the longer-term.
Asset Accumulation
Our Asset Accumulation business markets invest- ment-oriented life insurance and retirement savings products and services and provides invest- ment management services to individual and
 3

                                           12.3% 12.8% 9.4%
96 97 98 99 00
  9.0%
8.0%
    Return On Equity
institutional clients.This business increased pre-tax operating earnings for the sixth year in a row. In spite of a significant decline in the equity markets in the latter part of the year, which depressed growth in separate account assets under manage- ment and fee income, pre-tax operating earnings increased by 7.1 percent to $245.3 million.
We introduced many new variable annuity and variable universal life insurance prod- ucts during the year and improved our entire portfolio of investment options through the addi- tion of new fund offerings and more investment manager selections.We now offer a large selection of investment options through 25 high quality, carefully selected investment managers. Variable annuity sales increased to $3.1 billion, an 11.6
percent gain over 1999.
New business premium in variable
universal life insurance products increased by nearly 17 percent to a record $114 million. In 2001, we are placing significantly more emphasis
on the sales of variable universal life insurance products. Allmerica’s variable life insurance products are designed to meet the emerging needs of the retirement savings market by provid- ing the right combination of asset accumulation and risk management for the customer while producing better margins for the company over the long-term.
Our significant investments in the retirement business over the last few years have created a superior technology platform, enabling us to develop and launch new products faster and more efficiently, while improving service quality. A key goal for 2001 is to further expand our variable product portfolio, which already is considered to be one of the strongest in the industry.We will do so with more new products targeting the still growing asset accumulation segment and the now rapidly growing distribu- tion and wealth transfer segments of the overall
retirement savings market.
  4
00

                                           $225 $165
$116
$351 $291
     96 97 98 99 00
 Variable Product Fee Income ($ IN MILLIONS)
We have built a strong and diversified distribution platform in Asset Accumulation. Further expansion of this base remains a top priority. We currently plan an increase of 100 financial advisors annually over the next three years to reach a total of approximately 1,000. By early 2001, we expect to double the number of wholesalers in our Allmerica Select channel, and add new selling agreements with broker/dealer and financial planning firms in this rapidly expanding part of the business. We also are expanding our new niche product distribution opportunities with
major financial institutions.
Analysis of the major demograph-
ic trends in the United States confirms that there is a long-term growth market for retirement products and services.The actions we have taken and plan to take throughout 2001, evidence our commitment to this market.
Our investment management division also made important contributions in several areas during 2000, which should lead to higher profits in 2001.We increased the amount of spread-based assets under management with sales of $1.1 billion of stable value products led by our new Euro Medium Term Note program. Additionally, through well-timed portfolio management actions, over $1.0 billion of fixed income securities were repositioned to take advantage of higher current income opportunities in the securities markets before interest rates
declined later in the year.
Risk Management
Our Risk Management business markets person- al lines and commercial lines insurance products. Pre-tax operating earnings in this business were $190.0 million, a 4.8 percent decline from 1999. While operating results were below the previous year, we have made significant improvements to
 5

                                                   96 97 98 99 00
Property & Casualty Combined Ratio ■ INDUSTRY ■ ALLMERICA FINANCIAL *ESTIMATE
our property and casualty operations over the last several years, which position us for profitable growth in the future. In 2001, we are placing increased emphasis on improving underwriting results in workers’ compensation and commercial automobile, two lines that have been difficult for the entire industry in recent years. Despite very challenging industry conditions, we are confident in our ability to achieve profitable growth in targeted markets through careful risk selection and firm pricing decisions.
Our property and casualty opera- tions’ combined ratio, a key measure of under- writing performance, was 102.0 percent—well below the 2000 estimated industry average of
110.3 percent.
In 2000, we successfully imple- mented a new business model which places primary emphasis on segments of the insurance market offering higher than industry-average premium growth potential. We exceeded our top
line growth target for 2000 with an 8.9 percent increase in net premiums written—significantly above the 5.0 percent average growth rate estimated for the industry.
Through our continuing vigilance on expense management, we achieved substantial progress on operating efficiency and created a more competitive expense structure.We reduced our property and casualty underwriting expense ratio to 26.5 percent, compared to 28.5 percent at the end of 1999. We also reduced our loss adjustment expense ratio to 8.1 percent from 8.4 percent in 1999. Our loss adjustment expense
ratio remains one of the lowest in the industry. Our property and casualty compa- nies operate in an increasingly competitive environment, where we cannot rely upon price increases to improve profitability. Expense man- agement will remain one of Risk Management’s key strategic initiatives and a critical component
of our goal to deliver an underwriting profit.
  6
00
101.2%
102.0%
105.8% 104.5%
101.6% 104.0%
105.6% 104.6%
107.5%
110.3%*

                                           $599.9 $407.8
$210.1
$1,068.7 $882.2
     96 97 98 99 00
 Project Ready!
We are confident that Allmerica has the strategies in place in each business to capitalize on excellent long-term opportunities in growth markets for retirement savings, financial planning, and the segments of the risk manage- ment business which have above industry average
growth and profit potential.
Allmerica has successfully com-
bined the long-established, traditional values of an old-economy company with new-economy thinking, products and technology.With enthusi- asm, we look to extend our success in 2001 and beyond to further increase shareholder value.
John F. O’Brien
President and Chief Executive Officer
Retained Earnings ($ IN MILLIONS)
In July, 2000 we completed the initial phase of Project Ready!, a highly disciplined, and very successful corporate-wide initiative to increase revenues and reduce expenses. Through this project, which was coordinated by a group of our key employees, we identified approximately 1,500 improvement ideas. This year’s operating results were enhanced by many of the ideas already implemented and we expect to see continued benefits in 2001 as a result of this project.
2001 Outlook
Allmerica has very successfully adapted to the fast-changing financial services industry. During the past several years, we have made meaningful changes to the operating structures in both of our businesses, which have produced substantial improvements and strengthened our diversified earnings base.
  7
