 Letter to Shareholders 1
   DON JAMES
Chairman and
Chief Executive Officer
TO OUR SHAREHOLDERS AND FRIENDS:
As we anticipated, 2013 was a year of two distinct halves: In the first half, we continued to position the business for success as the U.S. construction economy moved toward recovery. In the second half, the construction market recovery accelerated, and we delivered.
 
2 Vulcan Materials Company
  While pricing was solid throughout 2013, aggregates volumes increased by 8 percent in
the second half of the year, after declining by
1 percent in the first half. And our gross profit from aggregates increased by 27 percent in the second half, after increasing by 4 percent in the first half, demonstrating both the accelerating recovery of our markets and the powerful earnings leverage
in our business.
For the year, earnings per share from continuing operations were $0.16, an improvement of $0.58 from 2012; Adjusted EBITDA — an important measure of our cash generating capabilities— increased by $57 million, or 14 percent; and gross profit margin increased by 230 basis points. Importantly, the profitability of our aggregates business as measured by cash gross profit per ton was 30 percent higher than at the prior peak
level of shipments, setting the stage for stronger earnings leverage in this cycle.
U.S. HOUSING STARTS
1,000,000 800,000 600,000 400,000 200,000
0
Throughout our business, Vulcan is reaping the benefits of our operational excellence,
our unmatched geographical footprint and the spirited performance of our people.
We continue to focus on what matters—controlling costs and exceeding our customers’ expectations while operating safely and in a socially responsible manner. In fact, 2013 marked a record year for
us in both safety and environmental performance. Thanks to decisive actions taken over the past several years by our employees—the best in the industry — Vulcan is positioned for better perfor- mance in any phase of the economic cycle and especially in a recovering construction economy. The significant and sustainable reductions in our cost structure over the past few years have been designed to allow our operations to participate fully in this recovery as it happens, at higher margins— and to bring with it additional improvements in unit profitability and significant earnings growth.
NEW HOUSING STARTS ARE IN THE THIRD YEAR OF RECOVERY
U.S. new housing permits continue to be strong, growing 16% in 2013, with Vulcan-served markets gaining 21%.
Mortgage rates remain low when compared to historical levels. Housing continues to be more affordable than at any point in the last 40 years, prior to the housing crisis.
Rental vacancy rates have reached their lowest point since the first quarter of 2001.
          2010
 2011
  2012
 2013
 Sources: McGraw-Hill and National Association of Realtors Housing Affordability Index

 Letter to Shareholders 3
   And we are not standing still. Throughout the year, and into early 2014, we made significant progress on our long-term strategy to drive growth, profit- ability and shareholder value by being the leading aggregates producer in the faster-growing regions and urban markets of the United States.
IMPROVED MARKET CONDITIONS
Demand for our products continues to benefit from recovery in private construction activity, particularly residential construction, in most of our key markets. We realized strong volume growth across all of our segments in the second half of 2013. Growth in residential construction activity, and its traditional follow-on impact on private nonresidential con- struction, continues to underpin our expectations for future volume growth and earnings improve- ment. Pricing in our aggregates business also continues to benefit from an improving demand outlook. We are realizing price improvements across most of our markets.
As you can see by the accompanying charts, the outlook for our business continues to improve, and we have delivered on the commitments we made.
CORE AGGREGATES STRATEGY
We have continued to make strong progress on our core aggregates strategy. In February 2012, we made a commitment to enhance profitability, divest non-strategic assets and reduce debt. We launched a Profit Enhancement Plan to improve run-rate profitability by $100 million and a Planned Asset Sales program to generate at least $500 million from the sale of non-strategic assets.
I am proud to say that we have exceeded those targets. Since announcing the plan, we have increased Adjusted EBITDA by $116 million and have completed actions that have generated more than $1 billion from the sale of non-strategic assets and from future production sales agreements. We also have reduced debt by almost $800 million.
In our most recent strategic initiative, we sold our cement and concrete businesses in the Florida area to Cementos Argos for gross cash proceeds of $720 million. We retain all of our aggregates oper- ations in Florida, and through a long-term supply
FULL YEAR FINANCIAL RESULTS
As Expected, 2013 Results Were Second-Half Weighted
 Aggregates
AMOUNTS IN MILLIONS, EXCEPT PER TON
Volume (Tons)
Year-over-Year Change
Price per Ton
Year-over-Year Change
Cash Gross Profit/Ton
Year-over-Year Change
Gross Profit
Year-over-Year $ Change Year-over-Year % Change
2013
 FIRST HALF
67.4 -1%
$ 10.74 4.0%
$ 3.92 -1%
$ 6.0 4%
SECOND HALF
78.5 8%
$ 10.86 2.9%
$ 4.76 7%
$ 55.2 27%
   agreement continue providing aggregates at market prices to the divested concrete facilities.
Divesting these non-strategic cement and concrete assets at a full and fair valuation enhances our financial strength and advances our strategic focus as the leading aggregates producer in the fastest-growing regions of the United States.
The transaction closed in early March of this year.
Concurrent with this announcement, we initiated a tender offer to purchase $500 million of out- standing debt. This tender offer will reduce annual pretax interest expense by approximately $32 million and increase annual net earnings by approximately $0.15 per diluted share.
With the growing recovery, and backed by the measures we have taken throughout the prolonged downturn, we have embarked on a course of stra- tegic, measured growth that we believe will benefit our shareholders for many years to come.

4 Vulcan Materials Company
  PROFIT ENHANCEMENT PLAN AND PLANNED ASSET SALES
ANNOUNCED FEBRUARY 2012
 Profit Enhancement Plan + > $100 million incremental EBITDA run rate by mid-2013
Planned Asset Sales
> $500 million in cash
+ Capital Structure and Dividend Reiterating commitment
to long-standing practice
 ✔ Increased Adjusted EBITDA $116 million
✔ Raised $1 billion in proceeds and invested more than $240 million to add aggregates operations and reserves
✔ Repaid almost
$800 million of debt and improved credit profile
ACCOMPLISHED AS OF MARCH 2014
 INITIATIVES HAVE IMPROVED EARNINGS AND CREDIT METRICS
ADJUSTED EBITDA (in millions)
ADJUSTED EBITDA / NET SALES
14.6% 17.8%
2011 2013
        $352
$468
  2011 2013 NET DEBT(in millions)
$2,660
$1,680
2011 2013
NET DEBT / ADJUSTED EBITDA
7.6X
        3 .6X
  In 2012, we made commitments regarding our Profit Enhancement Plan and Planned Asset Sales program. We did what we said we would do.
2011 2013
 
   Letter to Shareholders 5
  AGGREGATES CASH GROSS PROFIT PER TON
Trailing 12 Months
$5.00
265.3
$4.00
$3.37
$3.00 $2.00 $1.00
Higher unit profitability sets the stage for stronger earnings leverage.
30%
Higher than prior peak in
$4.37 volumes
                                          45.9 $0.00 Q1Q2Q3Q4Q1Q2Q3Q4Q1Q2Q3Q4Q1Q2Q3Q4Q1Q2Q3Q4Q1Q2Q3Q4Q1Q2Q3Q4Q1Q2Q3Q4Q1Q2Q3Q4
2005 2006 2007 2008 2009 2010 2011 2012 2013 Cash Gross Profit Per Ton Sales Volume (in millions)
                 Housing is now in its third
year of recovery with particular
strength in Vulcan-served 3.2
3.37 3.55 3.78 4.05 4.22 4.46 4.58 4.67
We remain deeply committed to building share- 4.7 holder value through the execution of our core 4.72 aggregates strategy. We further strengthened our 4.7
4.68
4.7 4.68 4.7 4.62 4.4 4.28 4.24 4.12 4.09 4.03 3.92 4.01 4.06
attractive San Diego markets. This purchase elim-
markets as exhibited by double-digit growth for the last two years.
258754 265279
of reserves and quarries in growing markets in California, Georgia, Texas and Virginia.
For example, on the West Coast, we exercised an option in December to purchase land, previously operated under a quarry lease, containing
136 million tons of aggregates reserves serving
will be used to complete reclamation of a 90-acre
2.91 3.01 3.1
245845
inates a $7 million per year lease payment, while
252594
allowing us to defer a significant portion of the cash
254970
taxes from the Argos transaction.
We also began mine development at our Azusa Rock
263624
Quarry, east of Los Angeles, California — the culmi-
258774
nation of years of cooperative work with the City
254709
of Azusa, regulatory officials and local stakeholders.
246657
This strategically located source of reserves in the
239761
S a n 2 G3 4 a4 b7 4r i e l V a l l e y c o n t a i n s o v e r 1 0 0 m i l l i o n t o n s of q2u3a0l5i7t1y granite aggregates, allowing us to supply c r i t i 2 c 2 a 8 l 4 8 i n0 f r a s t r u c t u r e p r o j e c t s a n d c o m m e r c i a l deve2l2o43p9m4 ent in Greater Los Angeles for decades t o c o2 1 m7 4 e 1 . 1 T h e A z u s a R o c k Q u a r r y a l s o w i l l g e n e r -
 aggregates business in 2013 through the acquisition
ate millions of yards of overburden material that
204607
190808
172608
former sand and gravel mine we own in nearby
160737
Irwindale, for large-scale commercial development.
150870 146244
These initiatives are emblematic of our long-term
148588
strategy of expanding our aggregates operations
147441
and securing reserves in the fastest-growing regions
147597 146833 142995 142166 143034 145820
1
 
6 Vulcan Materials Company
   POSITIONED FOR STRONG MARGIN GROWTH
A GREAT FOUNDATION FOR GROWTH
We are capitalizing on the growing market recovery, and are fully prepared to meet growing demand. Our ability to convert incremental sales to cash flow and profits is exceptionally strong. We have reduced our debt and improved our credit metrics sub- stantially, giving us greater flexibility to invest for growth and return capital to shareholders. With this in mind, we are pleased to report that our div- idend increase announcement in February begins the process of restoring a meaningful dividend, based on our improving operating earnings and cash flows, strengthening balance sheet and the favorable outlook for our business. Throughout
this period, we have continued to demonstrate industry-leading operational expertise and unit profitability.
Vulcan’s fundamental strengths are intact. We benefit from an outstanding workforce, strong and loyal customers, the best production locations and reserves, and superior aggregates cash gross profit per ton.
Our employees have delivered superior results in our aggregates business despite external economic challenges. Vulcan people are the very best in the business. Their focus and efforts position Vulcan for superior performance and results.
Thank you for your continued interest and support. We see a great future ahead.
Donald M. James
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer March 14, 2014
  1993–2005
278%
  92%
2%
32%
2011–2013
      Increase in Volume
Increase in Aggregates Margin
In the last three years, we have made significant improvements in aggregates margin on relatively flat volume. With economic recovery, robust margin growth will accompany even modest increases in volume.
of the United States, while also building upon our significant and valuable land holdings in ways that benefit our shareholders, our employees and our host communities.
OUTLOOK FOR 2014
Our positive momentum should continue this year.
Aggregates demand is expected to grow in each of
our end markets in 2014, driven primarily by private
   construction activity and large infrastructure and
fastest-growing regions, we expect that aggregates
volume growth in Vulcan’s markets will exceed
national averages.
2 32
Volume Margin
private industrial projects. Due to our focus on the
Overall, we expect our aggregates volumes will increase 4 to 7 percent in 2014, compared to 2013, and that pricing will increase by 3 to 5 percent. This outlook — combined with expected growth and earnings improvement from our non-aggregates businesses; stable selling, administrative and general costs; and significantly reduced interest expense from our debt reduction efforts — positions us to deliver strong results in 2014.
92 278
 