Letter from the Executive Chairman and the CEO
In year 2009, despite the unprecedented global recession, Vishay generated “free cash”* of $246 million, which is one of the best results in the Company’s history. thanks to a very significant reduction in fixed costs, Vishay permanently reduced its break-even point by $400 to $500 million. By the end of 2009, with improving end market demand, Vishay approached pre-recession profit margins at considerably lower sales levels. As the Company is committed to keeping its fixed costs stable, with future sales growth it is very well positioned for further profit margin increases.
yeaR 2009
Vishay’s revenues for 2009 were $2.042 billion, a decrease of approximately 27.6% compared to 2008. Vishay reported a
loss from continuing operations for the year ended December 31, 2009 of $56.5 million, or $0.31 per share.
Adjusted net earnings** for 2009 were $3.3 million, or $0.02 per diluted share, excluding various items affecting comparability such as restructuring and severance costs and asset write-downs. During 2009, cash generated from continuing operations was $290.4 million, compared to $268.5 million during 2008. our capital expenditures were limited to $50.3 million during 2009 compared to $152.0 million during 2008.
the global economy’s deep recession that began in September 2008 continued in 2009. However, in the fourth quarter of 2009, buoyed by a dramatic increase in end demand for electronic components, Vishay’s business grew from very
low levels at a robust pace. the very significant reduction in fixed costs that Vishay started in the fourth quarter of 2008 and completed in 2009 helped
the Company to increase profit margins approaching pre-recession levels by the end of 2009.
Vishay’s semiconductor business, which was hit the hardest by the recession, recovered strongly by the end of 2009. the recovery for Vishay diodes and optoelectronic products started in July 2009, driven by increased demand in
the consumer market in Asia. Increased demand for diodes and optoelectronic products in the european automotive market also started in the third quarter of 2009. By the fourth quarter of 2009, this recovery had spread to virtually all market sectors, sales channels, and regions.
Vishay’s passive components business also recovered strongly by the end of 2009. Increased demand for Vishay resistors and inductors was driven by
an accelerated rebound in the industrial market, as well as an upturn in most other
markets. Increased demand for Vishay capacitors was driven by an upturn in some key markets, particularly automotive and consumer.
our focus in 2009 was to generate “free cash.” We generated $246 million in “free cash,” making year 2009 one of Vishay’s best in terms of cash. only years 2002 and 2000 were better for Vishay in this regard.
Vishay, during 2009, continued the major restructuring and right-sizing efforts that we defined and began implementing in the fourth quarter of 2008. During 2009 we reduced inventories by $103 million and limited our capital spending to $50 million, compared to $152 million in 2008. our cash costs for restructuring were
$48 million in 2009. We reduced all fixed costs by $176 million in 2009, with $80 million coming from manufacturing and $96 million coming from SG&A. Since
the downturn began in September 2008, we have reduced the total number of employees by 19% and reduced total fixed headcount by 16%.
the restructuring of our operations continued successfully in 2009.
We completed the consolidation of optoelectronics packaging in Asia.
We closed our film capacitor plant in Shanghai, China, moving the volume
to loni, India. We closed our multilayer ceramic chip (MLCC) capacitor plant in Monroe, Connecticut, moving the volume to Migdal Ha’Emek, Israel. In addition,
we completed the move of non-linear resistor manufacturing from Belgium to China, Israel, and Germany. these actions permanently reduced our fixed costs.
VIshay PRecIsIon gRouP
sPIn-off
In october 2009, Vishay announced its intention to spin off its Foil technology products (strain gages, ultra-precision
foil resistors, and current sensors) and Weighing Modules and Control Systems (transducers/load cells, instruments, weigh modules, and control systems) businesses into an independent, publicly traded
company to be named Vishay precision Group, Inc. (VpG). Because these two businesses are not core components of Vishay Intertechnology’s overall operations, in terms of products, technologies, manufacturing processes, markets, and customers, we expect that the spin-off will enable the management teams of both Vishay Intertechnology and VpG to better focus on the unique issues facing their respective businesses and will permit each company to pursue its own business plan, resource allocation program, and growth strategy. Sales of VpG in the last few
years were approximately 9% of Vishay Intertechnology’s total sales.
the spin-off is expected to take the form of a tax-free stock dividend to Vishay’s stockholders and it is anticipated that holders of Vishay common stock will receive common stock of VpG and holders of Vishay Class B common stock will receive Class B common stock of VpG. Following the spin-off, VpG will be an independent, publicly traded company, and Vishay Intertechnology will not retain any ownership interest in it.
InnoVatIons In technology
In 2009, Vishay continued to develop, manufacture, and market new components based on innovative and proprietary technologies. these technologies make possible new generations of end products that are smaller and richer in features
and functions. examples of new Vishay components released during 2009 include the following:
• MOSFETs built on industry-leading trenchFet® p-channel technology that packs one billion transistor cells into each square inch of silicon. these MOSFETs save power and extend battery life in handheld devices.
• Trench diodes built on Vishay’s successful family of trench-technology- based TMBS® diodes. Vishay is the sole source for these diodes, which reduce power losses and improve efficiency
in computing, consumer, and other applications.
  *“Free cash” refers to the amount of cash generated from operations in excess of our capital expenditures and net of proceeds from the sale of assets, a measure which we use to evaluate our operations and our ability to fund acquisitions and repay debt.
**See table on page 34 of Vishay’s Annual Report on Form 10-K for the calculation of adjusted net earnings and adjusted net earnings per share.
Vishay Intertechnology

  • Industry-first ultra-miniature infrared receivers for remote control and data transmission in notebooks and other computing, communications, and entertainment devices. they reduce or eliminate causes of interference, including optical noise from fluorescent lamps and emissions from plasma displays.
• A resistor with Power Metal Strip® technology that is the first of its kind
to operate over a temperature range of −65°C to +275°C. Its high-temperature capability and high power ratings (double the standard rating for this product type) allow it to be used in harsh environments such as automotive sub- systems and industrial oil and gas well drilling equipment without sacrificing electrical performance. Vishay is collecting royalties via Power Metal Strip technology licensing agreements.
• Additions to Vishay’s growing series
of IHlp® power inductors (one of Vishay’s highly successful new product platforms) for end products including mobile devices, servers, and automotive controls. Vishay is collecting royalties via IHlp technology licensing agreements.
• TANTAMOUNT® tantalum chip capacitors that feature the highest voltage rating available for this device type. they are optimized for use in airborne, sensor, and industrial control applications and in telecommunications base stations.
Vishay products received a number of awards in 2009 from leading industry media outlets, including Electronic Products, EDN China, Electronic Product China, and EN-Genius Network.
fInancIal conDItIon anD
lIQuIDIty
As noted above, Vishay generated $246 million of “free cash” during 2009, $92 million of which was generated in the fourth quarter. Vishay has generated “free cash” in each of the past 13 years, and “free cash” in excess of $80 million in each of the past 8 years.
Vishay had total debt of $336 million
and cash and cash equivalents of $579 million as of December 31, 2009. the debt consists predominantly of the following: $105 million of long-term notes due in 2102 or in 92 years, with an interest rate of lIBoR plus 0%, and an $87.5 million term loan maturing in July 2011 with payments spread over the next one and a half years, with an interest rate of lIBoR plus 2.5%. We also have a $250 million revolving credit facility maturing in April 2012 with an interest rate of lIBoR plus 1.52%, $125 million of which was unused as of December 31, 2009.
Dr. Felix Zandman
executive Chairman of the Board
Dr. Gerald Paul
Chief executive officer
In summary, our liquidity was $759 million (cash and cash equivalents of $579 million and credit lines of $178 million) and total debt was $336 million, of which $105 million are long-term notes due in 92 years.
looKIng aheaD
Vishay permanently reduced its break- even point by drastically reducing fixed costs in 2009. thus, even at sales levels that are lower than those we achieved prior to the 2008-2009 recession, we expect that our profit levels will be higher. As we don’t intend to undo our fixed cost reductions despite expected sales growth, Vishay is in a favorable position to reach new performance levels going forward.
preparations for the spin-off of VpG
are proceeding smoothly. Vishay Intertechnology has a broad line of discrete electronic components, while VpG is vertically integrated from sensors to weighing modules to instruments to control systems. the spin-off will make Vishay a pure play discrete electronic components company. It will show VpG’s performance on a stand-alone basis, rather than being diluted into Vishay. Also, it will sharpen management focus for both companies. Furthermore, it will enable each company to more effectively execute strategies and allocate resources.
our R&D activities are progressing
as planned and will accelerate as the economy improves. With our strong balance sheet, good liquidity, and the improved economic environment, we are again actively pursuing acquisitions. We are targeting small to mid-sized companies. For our passive components business,
we aim to strengthen and broaden our position as a specialty products supplier. For our discrete semiconductors business, the intent is to increase market share and exploit synergies.
In 2010, as in the past, we expect that Vishay will continue to be an excellent generator of “free cash,” based on improved profitability in combination with only slightly higher working capital
requirements despite the anticipated sales growth. Inventories are expected to stay approximately flat. our controlled capital expenditures for expansion are targeted mostly at new products for which demand is rapidly growing. We do not yet expect
a need to expand capacity for commodity product lines. our defined restructuring programs have been implemented. therefore, restructuring costs going forward are projected to be low.
We are very confident that 2010 will be a good year for us. Vishay is structured for flexibility; in the case of a new economic slowdown we are fully prepared to reestablish all measures needed to adjust Vishay to new realities. Whether the economic upturn continues during 2010 or is followed by a new downturn, Vishay will continue to roll out a steady stream of new and improved products, generate a significant amount of free cash, and maintain its strong position in the global electronics industry.
Vishay thanks its employees, customers, vendors, strategic business partners, and stockholders for their support during 2009, and looks forward to continued support during 2010 and beyond.
Dr. Felix Zandman
executive Chairman of the Board
Dr. Gerald paul
Chief executive officer
    Vishay Intertechnology
1
