Chairman’s Letter
   David R. Whitwam Chairman of the Board and Chief Executive Officer
To Our Shareholders — Last year, a record number of consumers turned to the brands of Whirlpool Corporation for unique products and solutions, and in doing so, strengthened the company’s position as the world’s leading manufacturer and marketer of major home appliances.
Whirlpool’s growing appeal with consumers worldwide is the result of our simple yet powerful path to growth—listen closely to customers, develop relevant innovation that meets their needs and apply every available resource to build relationships that last a lifetime.
Our achievements indicate that Whirlpool is on the right course:
■ Consumer demand for all of our brands worldwide helped drive net
revenues in 2003 to a record level of $12.2 billion, an increase of approximately 10.5 percent from 2002.
■ Strong consumer interest in the Whirlpool brand once again made it the world’s top-selling, major appliance brand.
■ Full-year earnings of $5.91 per diluted share were in line with expectations. To deliver these 2003 results, our operations also had to overcome factors contributing $1.86 per share in unfavorable comparisons to 2002, such as the negative effects of increased U.S. pension costs, currency and reduced tax credits in Brazil.
■ Our operations achieved strong levels of total cost productivity, record improvements in net working capital and return on capital, and a solid reduction in total debt from 2002 levels.
■ We delivered full-year operating free cash flow of $302 million, a strong performance for the company that included a voluntary after-tax cash contribution of $97 million to our U.S. pension fund last year. The contribution effectively lowers the company’s pension contribution levels for 2004 and beyond, and flattens pension expenses year to year.
■ Our board of directors declared a dividend increase of 26 percent for the first quarter in 2004. The increase reflects the board’s confidence in the company’s financial position, the ability of our global operations to generate ongoing free cash flow, and the positive momentum of Whirlpool’s brands and businesses worldwide.
Building unmatched levels of customer loyalty
In 1999, Whirlpool began implementing worldwide its strategies and plans in pursuit of our vision: Every Home ... Everywhere with Pride, Passion, and Performance. The quest centered on achieving unmatched levels of customer loyalty to Whirlpool’s global brands.
Today, customer loyalty creates a clear competitive advantage for the company. We know that our loyal customers are asking for Whirlpool’s brands by name on retail floors, continually repurchasing our products and services, and passionately recommending our brands to others. Loyalty such as this drives revenue growth, margin expansion and increased trade support for our brands. To achieve our customer loyalty goals, we are transforming our global enterprise to continually deliver innovative products, services and solutions within a brand experience valued by our customers.
  2003 Awards and Achievements
■ Global Finance magazine named Whirlpool to the publication’s list of "The World's Most Socially Responsible Companies," based on a survey of companies worldwide that exemplify the principles of corporate responsibility.
■ Whirlpool was ranked fifth among the most respected international consumer goods companies in the latest "World’s Most Respected Companies" survey, conducted annually by the Financial Times and PricewaterhouseCoopers.
10

 Operating profit
($ in millions)
$830
$692
2002 2003
Free cash flow
($ in millions)
Net working capital
(% of sales)
Total debt
($ in billions)
$1.5
$1.4
2002 2003
          $291
$302
11.2%
2002
10.8%
2003
                            2002 2003
                 Connecting with customers through brands
Despite the global scope and scale of our organization, most customers know Whirlpool through their unique and personal experiences with one or more of the company’s leading brands. Our major brands include Whirlpool, the world’s No. 1 selling appliance brand; KitchenAid in North America; Bauknecht in Europe; and Brastemp and Consul in the Latin American market. We remain the major supplier in many product categories for Sears, Roebuck and Co.’s Kenmore brand appliances.
Our brands are carefully and continually cultivating loyal customer relationships by first listening closely to their respective customers and then developing solutions that fit unique lifestyles. To this end, our brands apply the resources of our global operating platform to create differentiated experiences for customers and competitive advantages within each regional market.
Thinking outside the box, inside the home
Innovation is central to Whirlpool’s loyalty efforts because it delivers unique value to our customers that competitors cannot easily match. Our rapid development and continuous introduction of Whirlpool innovation differentiates the company in the marketplace, improves our top-line revenue growth and drives higher levels of customer loyalty to our brands.
Over the brief span of five years, we have built an innovation competency founded on the creativity and diversity of our employees across Whirlpool’s global enterprise. Today, Whirlpool is recognized as
a leading innovator in the global appliance industry. Increasingly, our unique application of innovation is gaining prominence within business management and professional design circles.
Transforming our approach
In 2003, our brands continued to transform and strengthen their relationships with customers by assessing and integrating findings from extensive customer loyalty research involving thousands of consumers. We also expanded the level of employee involvement in the customer loyalty transformation through special training and awareness programs. Thousands participated in programs to help employees better understand the customer and engage in new loyalty efforts.
The company also launched Whirlpool University, an on-line tool that provides critical customer loyalty information to employees. In 2004, we expect to reach and train over 15,000 employees through the use of this tool.
Transforming Whirlpool’s enterprise to achieve unmatched levels of customer loyalty to our brands requires informed and passionate leaders at all levels of the organization. In 2003, nearly 200 top officers and directors participated in workshops designed to align leadership behavior with our transformation effort. This year, the training continues to cascade throughout Whirlpool’s organizations. These efforts have not gone unnoticed. Whirlpool’s leadership development program was ranked 11th among the "Top 20 Companies for Leaders" recognized by Chief Executive Magazine in a survey of 300 U.S. companies.
 ■ DiversityBusiness.com recognized Whirlpool in the organization’s annual listing of the United States' top 50 organizations for multicultural business opportunities. Fifteen thousand women- and minority-owned businesses selected the winners.
■ Whirlpool received two "Alexander Hamilton Awards" for excellence in Financial Risk Management and Technology. Treasury & Risk Management magazine sponsors the annual awards, which recognize excellence in corporate management practices.
11

  Reaching Every Home ... Everywhere
Since the late 1980s, when Whirlpool Corporation was primarily U.S.- based, the company has steadily expanded its operating footprint and integrated substantial business capabilities across global markets. Unlike other regional competitors looking to find a toehold in other parts of the world, Whirlpool already has in place a network of strategically located manufacturing facilities worldwide.
Whirlpool’s global enterprise also holds other unique competitive advantages in distribution, technology, procurement and information technology. These capabilities form the backbone of Whirlpool’s enviable global operating platform that supports our operations as they carry out customer loyalty initiatives in all of our markets.
Operating responsibly worldwide
As a company, we hold ourselves accountable for running our businesses and facilities in a manner that is sensitive to the stakeholders we serve and to the communities in which we operate around the world.
Last year, for example, Whirlpool pledged that by 2008, the company will reduce its global greenhouse gas emissions by 3 percent from the company’s 1998 emissions level, while also increasing our appliance production by nearly 40 percent over the same 10-year period. Whirlpool is the first company in the global appliance industry to make such a commitment.
Whirlpool also is committing significant time and resources to help address important social issues worldwide. In addition to the company’s direct involvement in contributing to the communities in which we operate, our global operations are at the forefront of initiatives that provide critical support to women and their families. And as the leading corporate supporter of Habitat for Humanity International,
Whirlpool helps provide affordable housing to low income families throughout North America.
Within the company, we are acting on our belief that to fully understand the unique needs of our customers living in countries and cultures worldwide, Whirlpool must reflect the diversity of those customers we serve. The success of our customer loyalty and innovation efforts depends on our ability to create an inclusive environment within Whirlpool that embraces each individual's unique strengths and allows everyone to contribute to the fullest potential.
Outlook
Whirlpool Corporation enters 2004 with good business momentum and positive economic trends in our key markets worldwide.
For the full year, we expect continued improvement in earnings based on the competitive advantages of Whirlpool’s unique global platform, the continued positive response by consumers to our innovative products and services, and the relentless drive by our employees to build unmatched levels of customer loyalty for our brands.
David R. Whitwam Chairman of the Board and Chief Executive Officer
   ■ I.D. Magazine recognized Whirlpool in the international design publication’s "Annual Design Review" competition. The Whirlpool Duet washer and dryer pair, and Whirlpool Europe’s Project F conceptual fabric care products won top honors.
■ Whirlpool co-sponsored the 2003 Jimmy Carter Work Project in the U.S. Employee volunteers helped build 92 homes, and the company donated nearly 800 appliances. JCWP is a program of Habitat for Humanity International.
 12

 Financial Highlights
(Millions of dollars, except per share data) 2003
Net sales $12,176 Earnings from continuing operations $ 414 Per share on a diluted basis $ 5.91 Net earnings (loss) $ 414 Per share on a diluted basis $ 5.91 Stockholders' equity $ 1,301 Total assets $ 7,361
Return on equity * 42.9% Return on assets * 6.1% Book value per share $ 18.56 Dividends per share $ 1.36 Average dividend yield 2.2% Total return to stockholders 41.7%
Share price
High $ 73.35 Low $ 42.80 Close $ 72.65
Total return to stockholders (five-year annualized) 8.1% Shares outstanding (in 000's) 68,931 Number of registered stockholders 8,178 Number of employees 68,407
2002 % Change $ 11,016 10.5%
  $ $ $ $ $ $
$ $
$ $ $
262 58.0% 3.78 56.3% (394) NM1 (5.68) NM1
739 76.0% 6,631 11.0%
14.8% 3.4%
10.67 73.9% 1.36 –
2.2% (26.9)%
79.80
39.23
52.22 39.1%
1.4%
68,226 1.0 %
8,556 (4.4)% 68,272 0.2 %
 * Refer to Eleven-Year Consolidated Statistical Review (pages 32-33) for more information about return on equity and asset calculations. 1 Not a meaningful comparison.
13

President’s Message
   Jeff Fettig
President and Chief Operating Officer
Whirlpool’s global operations made significant progress deploying our brand-focused-value-creation strategy in each of our regions last year. By effectively leveraging and developing Whirlpool’s brands, trade relationships and unique global platform, our operations turned
in record revenues and a strong improvement in the company’s productivity performance.
In 2003, our brands continued to apply deep insights about our customers to the ongoing development and introduction of relevant consumer innovation. Popular products with unique features and solutions, like the Whirlpool Duet washer and dryer pair in the United States, helped improve the average sales price of our products, despite significant price pressures in each of our global markets. The growing consumer interest in Whirlpool’s brands and products also reflects the success of the company’s ongoing efforts to embed innovation as a core competency.
Today, more than 500 employee innovation mentors have trained more than 10,000 employees to create and commercialize new products and solutions for our customers. These employees have contributed more than 7,500 ideas, with 500 potentially viable concepts currently in the company’s innovation pipeline at various stages of evaluation and development. To date, Whirlpool has funded and conducted more than 360 consumer-based innovation experiments following a customer-focused, 90-day commercial evaluation process.
Our innovation process also is creating new and important business opportunities for Whirlpool. For example, the company’s Gladiator GarageWorks—a complete modular storage and appliance line that
transforms the garage into a functional space—is becoming a significant revenue opportunity. Whirlpool innovation will continue to be a vital, strategic source of value creation for the company, and an important element of building and strengthening the relationships between our brands and customers.
The company’s strategic trade partner relationships are another important source of growth and customer loyalty. In each region, Whirlpool has built strong relationships with winning value-added trade partners whose strategies complement our own. In the United States, Whirlpool has the leading position with the top three national retailers and appliance buying groups, which combined represent 84 percent of the appliance retail market share. Whirlpool also strengthened its position in the new home building industry last year, as shipments of Whirlpool and KitchenAid products surpassed previous records.
Whirlpool’s unique global operating platform of integrated manufacturing, product development and supply chain resources is the foundation for competitiveness that drives our brands and our distribution activities in every region of the world. The company continually applies these resources in ways that allow us to serve our regional customers around the world with innovative products, produced at the best cost for each market.
Whirlpool’s global platform also provides an excellent means to continually speed new innovations to our customers, while lowering our ongoing investment costs. Through our global product development and design resources, innovation and technology are shared and
  2003 Awards and Achievements
■ Whirlpool formed a global alliance with New Zealand-based Fisher & Paykel Appliances, which is widely known for its innovative technology. The alliance includes global sourcing of appliances and co-development of technology.
■ Whirlpool Europe was recognized as the Euronics "White Goods Supplier of the Year" for 2003. Euronics represents the continent’s largest group of major appliance retailers, with 6,500 stores in 21 countries.
14

 quickly integrated across our regional operations and functions. These capabilities allow us to simplify processes, shorten development cycles and better utilize assets.
We effectively manage Whirlpool’s global manufacturing resources to optimize the product mix of our brands in each market around the world. In North America, for example, we leverage the scale and efficiency of Whirlpool’s Clyde, Ohio, facility—the world’s largest clothes washer manufacturing operation—to help maintain the company’s laundry leadership in the North American market.
We also leverage the advantages of Whirlpool’s production capacity elsewhere in the world to strengthen our cost position in global markets. Brazil, for example, is one of our key export platforms for Whirlpool’s global sales and distribution network. Our Brazilian operation significantly increased the level of exports from the region last year, which included shipments of new Whirlpool refrigeration products to customers in North America, Europe and Asia.
Whirlpool Asia also serves as an export base for such products as microwave ovens and smaller appliances that extend the product portfolios of Whirlpool’s brands in Europe and North America. Increasingly, Whirlpool China is filling another important role as a strategic source for the company’s global procurement network.
Whirlpool’s tradition of driving continual improvements in quality and productivity remains a key focus of our operations and a vital competitive lever. In 2003, productivity improvements by our North American and European operations reached record levels. Operating Excellence, our Six-Sigma process, is the tool we use to improve and
sustain these cost savings. We also are expanding the company’s lean manufacturing initiative throughout our global operating platform to further reduce waste and costs. The combination of all these productivity measures will help improve our already competitive cost position and allow Whirlpool operations to generate further increases in cash flow.
In 2004, we expect economic conditions worldwide to gradually improve throughout the year. Globally, we will continue to build strong brands supported by relevant consumer innovation. We will continue to forge relationships with value-added retailers and builders. And we will continue to drive record productivity levels by leveraging our unique global operating platform. These are the drivers that will continue to fuel Whirlpool’s growth and provide our customers with a brand experience that is second to none.
Jeff Fettig
President and
Chief Operating Officer
  ■ In a listing of Brazil’s top exporters published by the Brazilian Ministry of Development, Industry and Trade, Whirlpool’s combined operations were ranked in the top 50 in overall export business.
■ European consumers in France, Slovakia and Hungary named Whirlpool the top and most trusted appliance brand in the Reader’s Digest "Trusted Brands Survey."
 15
