Dear fellow shareholders,
Today, Ameriprise stands tall as one of the strongest financial services firms in the business —
a Fortune 500 company with more than a decade of independence and a proud 120+ year legacy. We manage and administer more than $820 billion for individuals, institutions and small businesses in the United States and globally. Over the years, we have invested significantly to develop and deliver products, services and capabilities to enable highly satisfied clients and lasting relationships. We have built one of the leading advisor networks in the country and currently help more than 2 million households achieve their near- and long-term goals through economic cycles and market shifts.
2018 proved to be a more challenging year from geopolitical, economic and regulatory standpoints. Despite stronger economic growth in the U.S., investors’ early optimism eroded as concerns about rising short-term interest rates, slowing global growth, Brexit and trade tensions dominated the headlines. Each of these factors affect markets, consumers, the industry and our business.
As always, we maintain a long-term perspective and focus on serving clients’ needs comprehensively with personalized financial advice and quality investment, protection and annuities solutions. Last year, thanks to our dedicated teams, we attracted more clients and assets in our wealth management business and navigated significant industry change in asset management.
Our commitment to clients translates into excellent client satisfaction and a strong reputation in the marketplace. I’m proud to share that Ameriprise continues to be recognized with top industry credentials for the value we provide and the way our employees and financial advisors work with clients every day, which I highlight in this letter.
(continued on next page)
Annual Report 2018 | 1
  JAMES M. CRACCHIOLO
CHAIRMAN AND CHIEF EXECUTIVE OFFICER
“Today, Ameriprise stands tall as one of the strongest financial services firms in the business — a Fortune 500 company with more than a decade of independence and a proud 120+ year legacy.”

2 | Annual Report 2018
In addition to the value we provide clients, we also work diligently to deliver value to Ameriprise shareholders
Since our debut as a public company 13 years ago, Ameriprise common stock has been a top performer. After a strong 2017, however, our total return declined in 2018, reflecting significant equity market declines and pressure across the industry. Importantly, we were opportunistic and accelerated our share repurchase rate, given
we believe Ameriprise stock is undervalued. In fact, our stock has responded well early in 2019, reflecting the resiliency of our business and further reinforcing our consistent record of delivering long-term value, investing for growth and returning capital to shareholders at attractive levels.
At Ameriprise, we take pride in our management and fiscal discipline. We operate the business prudently. Our approach is similar to how our advisors work with clients to serve and manage clients’ financial needs — with a focused plan, for the long term — managing risk and positioning ourselves to capture opportunities.
Maintaining a strong financial foundation is central to our approach. It underpins our business and includes a large excess capital position, substantial liquidity and a high-quality invested asset portfolio. Our financial position and
credit ratings are strong, and we’ve never
been downgraded.
Strong financial performance
In 2018, Ameriprise delivered another good year even with considerable equity market headwinds in the fourth quarter. In terms of adjusted operating results excluding the one-time, largely non-cash $320 million negative impact of tax law changes
in 2017:
• Net revenues increased 5 percent to $12.7 billion
• Earnings grew 11 percent to $2.1 billion
• Earnings per diluted share increased 18 percent to $14.45
• Return on equity, excluding AOCI, remained among the highest in financial services at 36.6 percent, up from 32.3 percent a year ago
 Adjusted operating total net revenue $ in billions
Adjusted operating earnings per diluted share
Adjusted operating return on equity ex. AOCI1
1 Accumulated other comprehensive income
               *Excludes Tax Act impact.
2014 2015 2016 2017* 2018
$11.6 $11.7 $11.6
2014 2015 2016 2017* 2018
$8.52 $9.32
2014 2015 2016 2017* 2018
23.1% 24.3%
$8.48
$12.27
22.2%
32.3%
$12.0
$12.7
$14.45
36.6%

                     l R
#1 #1 #1 #1
most trusted consumer loyalty customer service customer forgiveness
Clients rate Ameriprise 4.9 out of 5 in overall satisfaction
See source information in appendix.
| 3 Ameriprise Financial — A top performer in the investment industry
A
A
A
A
n
n
n
nn
n
n
n
u
u
u
ua
a
a
a
l
l
l
l
R
R
ep
po
or
r
rt
t
t 2
2
20
01
1
1
18
8
8 |
                                 The benefits of our diversified business
and integrated approach
Ameriprise is well positioned to seize a large and gro􏳭ing opportunity in the mar􏳮etplace􏴡 􏴢ith more than $44 trillion in investable assets in the U.S. alone, investors are looking for personalized advice, strong solutions and a reputable firm to help them achieve their goals. This need is large, growing and global.
“Ameriprise is well positioned
to seize a large and growing opportunity in the marketplace.”
􏴢e approach this opportunity 􏳭ith our 􏳭ealth management business as the core of our
firm, complemented by 􏳭ell􏴠managed asset management and insurance and annuities businesses. The extensive capabilities of our integrated model ensure we can offer a broad product suite and excellent experience to meet clients’ evolving needs and market dynamics. Unli􏳮e other firms that only manufacture or distribute products, we do both. By serving
clients comprehensively, 􏳭e benefit from multiple revenue streams 􏴦 fee􏴠based, spread􏴠based, transactional and other. This allows us to leverage our intellect and resources more fully given how these businesses complement each other and help us retain client assets for the long term.
As we continue to grow Ameriprise overall, we are deepening client relationships, effectively managing risk and extending our distribution globally through Asset Management.
A po􏳭erful and gro􏳭ing 􏳭ealth manager
pursuing a large opportunity in the U.S.
Ameriprise is one of the strongest wealth managers in the industry, with a long track record of delivering high client satisfaction and steady advisor productivity gro􏳭th􏴡 􏴢e􏴧re a longstanding leader in financial planning and advice, and 􏳭e have a proud history of standing by our clients.
Ameriprise is built on personal, long-term relationships􏴡 􏴢e begin by listening to our
clients to gain a complete understanding of their individual goals. Then we design personalized financial plans and shape solutions to help clients benefit from our informed perspective and navigate the inevitable market changes to achieve their financial goals􏴡 As conditions change and life events occur, our advisors work closely with clients to assess their needs and adjust plans accordingly. It’s a winning formula and it’s never been more important.
Ameriprise continues to be recognized for how we work with clients and for the value we deliver. 􏴢e􏴧re a top performer for consumer trust, customer service and loyalty, as shown above. And we are a leader in the industry in terms of employee and advisor engagement 􏴦 integrity, respect and client focus consistently rank as our greatest strengths.

 4 | Annual Report 2018
 Of clients 􏳭ho have had the Confident Retirement®conversation:
94% feel the advice addressed their needs*
90% feel more confident about retirement*
See source information in appendix.
Leaving a legacy
Preparing for the unexpected
Ensuring lifestyle
Covering essentials
Essentials are the neces expenses that keep your these expenses with gua
    ® income sources. The Confident Retirement® approach.
sities — the monthly life running. Cover ranteed or stable
 The Ameriprise advice value proposition
is more relevant than ever
Today, we are well positioned to serve more clients in our gro􏳭ing target mar􏳮et 􏴦 investors 􏳭ith between $500,000 and $5 million in investable assets who value an advice relationship and have a responsible mindset.
During the year, 􏳭e continued to invest significantly to deliver outstanding service and support for our clients and to help advisors grow their practices.
Our investments included:
• Enhancing our digital and financial planning capabilities to make it even easier for clients and advisors to address their goals when, where and how they want
• Elevating our Customer Relationship Management platform to be delivered in 2019
• Further developing our fee-based investment advisory business in a more streamlined and customized way for clients and advisors to manage client investments
• Taking steps to expand our banking products and services and applying to convert our national trust bank to a federal savings bank, which is proceeding as planned for a 2019 launch
􏴢e􏴧re 􏳭or􏳮ing closely 􏳭ith our advisors and their staff to leverage these new capabilities, including providing robust training to help them seamlessly integrate these important capabilities into their practices.

Importantly, we’re continuing to raise awareness of Ameriprise in the marketplace, telling our story of how
we work with clients and the confidence we instill. The Ameriprise brand is strong and resonates with clients and consumers — brand awareness reached record levels
in 2018. And we continue to build upon and extend our successful Be Brilliant.®brand platform. As part of our campaign, we launched new television advertising in 2018 and we’re introducing additional ads in 2019 that highlight the personalized, differentiated experience we deliver
to clients.
We’re serving more clients in our target market than ever before, which is translating into strong retail client flows and solid growth in client activity
2018 was an excellent year for client net inflows and transactional activity:
• Clients added more than $21 billion into our investment advisory “wrap” platforms, bringing total wrap assets to $251 billion — one of the largest fee-based platforms in the industry
• With the spike in volatility in the fourth quarter, client cash balances grew to $28 billion, money that can be redirected to other investments
• Advisor productivity hit an all-time high of $624,000 per advisor on a trailing 12-month basis
• Our advisor count remained strong at more than 9,900
• 335 experienced advisors moved their practices to Ameriprise in 2018, given the breadth of our capabilities, strong reputation and the values that underpin our firm.
“2018 was an excellent year for client net inflows and transactional activity.”
Wealth Management delivers a record year
Our Advice & Wealth Management business had a record year in 2018. On an adjusted operating basis, revenues were up 10 percent, earnings increased 19 percent and we delivered a pretax margin of 22.4 percent — one of the top returns in the industry. Ultimately, our wealth management clients drove more than 70 percent of firm-wide revenue.
Annual Report 2018 | 5
 Wrap net inflows
$ in billions
     Client assets in fee- based wrap accounts
$ in billions
     Operating net revenue per advisor
$ in thousands
     2014 2015 2016 2017 2018
$496 2014 $514 2015 $528 2016 $575 2017 $624 2018
$175 2014 $180 2015 $201 2016 $248 2017 $251 2018
$14.2 $11.2
$10.2
$19.5
$21.1

6 | Annual Report 2018
RiverSource: our Insurance and Annuity businesses
serve clients’ comprehensive needs
The protection and retirement income solutions we
offer through RiverSource have long provided important capabilities and earnings contributions to Ameriprise. We have built these books of business over many decades, and they continue to perform well during an extended period of extremely low interest rates. Revenue and earnings results met our expectations in 2018, and we remain focused on managing these businesses prudently.
“RiverSource solutions help deepen relationships with clients and contribute to our high client satisfaction and long-term relationships.”
Our priority is to help clients understand the critical role RiverSource insurance and annuity products can play within a diversified plan — protecting what matters most and providing a reliable income stream in retirement.
As advisors continued to focus on addressing clients’ needs, variable annuity sales increased year-over-year. Life insurance sales remained stable, with life insurance in force remaining relatively flat at $195 billion.
These solutions are key to our Confident Retirement approach and excellent client experience. We’re further investing in our online capabilities, strengthening our underwriting and training our advisors to appropriately consider insurance and annuity solutions for their clients.
Columbia Threadneedle Investments:
key contributions as part of Ameriprise
Asset Management has been an important part of
our diversified firm for decades. Through Columbia Threadneedle Investments, we’re a global asset manager with more than $430 billion across equities, fixed income, asset allocation and multi-asset solutions, as well as U.S. real estate and UK property.
               Built on a heritage of more than 120 years of financial strength
Variable annuity account balances
$ in billions
     RiverSource variable annuity deposits up 6% in 2018
Life insurance in force
$ in billions
        Stable in-force business in line with our strategy
2014 $196
2015 $196
2016 $196
2017 $196
2018 $195
2014 $77 2015 $74 2016 $75 2017 $80 2018 $72

We offer individual and institutional investors access
to our capabilities through mutual funds, separate accounts, model portfolios, ETFs/strategic beta and alternative strategies. And through acquisitions, we’ve established important strategic relationships with leading wealth managers and insurers where we manage legacy assets, large insurance pools and model portfolios
that complement our established third-party retail and institutional businesses.
Ultimately, we are a large player operating in a rapidly evolving industry and managing quite a bit of change. 2018 was a challenging year in terms of outflows for active managers. The market downturn in the fourth quarter, high volatility and tax-related selling accelerated outflows across asset classes and overshadowed improvements in our gross sales.
While the year presented challenges, we’re focused on executing our strategic priorities to further strengthen
our products and distribution to drive profitable asset growth and improved flows across our key channels, both internationally and domestically. At the same time, we’ve managed our expense base well. We’ve kept expenses relatively flat for several years and have allocated investments to those initiatives that will help us transform the business and deliver value for investors and the firm.
“Columbia Threadneedle Investments — a global asset manager with competitive profitability.”
This includes advancing key strategic priorities, including:
• Delivering consistent, competitive investment performance to clients — our longer-term performance remains quite strong overall, but we did experience
a tougher year in 2018. Currently, we’re seeing an improvement in 2019 as we expected
• Enhancing and further developing our data capabilities both in terms of distribution and within Investments
• Strengthening our global operating platform
• Successfully navigating Brexit and preparing for various outcomes
• Building on our strength in the UK and expanding in Europe with a focus on Germany, Italy and Spain
• Growing Columbia Threadneedle brand awareness and consideration
Annual Report 2018 | 7
 Global Asset Management Assets Under Management
$ in billions
1% 1%
8%
 37% $431
AUM by asset type
Equity
Fixed income
Money market
28%
$431
72%
AUM by domestic/international
53%
Alternative
Hybrid and other
        U.S.
1%
9% 33% $431
AUM by client type
Retail Institutional
Data as of Dec. 31, 2018
International
57%
Alternative Owned Assets
     
8 | Annual Report 2018
                                         􏴎􏴍􏴎 􏴨-􏴩􏴜-star
Morningstar-rated funds globally*
90+ awards globally
2017 – 2018
Thomson Reuters
Lipper Awards – 2018 US/UK/Germany/Austria/France/ Netherlands/Nordics/Hong Kong
European Investment Awards – 2018
Innovation Award for the Threadneedle European Social Bond Fund
Professional Pensions Investment Awards – 2018 Multi-Asset Manager of the Year
*See appendix for additional information.
• Generating consistent, competitive investment performance
• Enhancing global operating platform
• Expanding in Europe
• Managing Brexit uncertainty
• Increasing brand awareness in key regions
􏴢e􏴧re focused on the right initiatives and earned greater market share at many of our top intermediary firms
􏴢e􏴧re further developing our product lines, including expanding our SMA capabilities in the U.S., and strengthening relationships with key gatekeepers and earning important model 􏳭ins􏴡 􏴢ithin EMEA, 􏳭e managed a significant change agenda that led to higher expenses in the year, including extending our fund range in Europe and the transfer of EU client assets from our OEIC funds into Luxembourg- domiciled SICAV products; evolving our research capability under MiFID II; and complying with the General Data Protection Regulation.
At the end of 2018, Columbia Threadneedle brand awareness reached record levels in the U.S. and remained strong in EMEA as our consistency advertising campaign continues to drive improved results􏴡 And, 􏳭e􏴧ve made significant progress
in enhancing our operating platform to capture efficiencies, improve the client experience and support the long-term growth of our solutions approach to help individual and institutional clients achieve specific outcomes􏴡
Given our breadth of capabilities, we see opportunity to capture market share in our core markets in strategies li􏳮e large value, fixed income, international, strategic beta, risk-parity strategies and other solutions, as well as in our real asset capability.
Overall, in Asset Management, we’re managing headwinds as part of Ameriprise and we’re competing for share in a very competitive marketplace.
   Imagery from our 2018 advertising campaign: 􏴢hen it comes to investing, consistency is beautiful􏴡

For our company overall, generating shareholder
value with effective capital and risk management
Through our diversified business, we generate substantial free cash flow that we reinvest for growth and return to shareholders. In 2018, we returned more than $2 billion to shareholders. We increased our regular quarterly dividend 8 percent — the eleventh increase in nine years — and we increased our share repurchase rate given the decline in our share price. This level of return represented 98 percent of our 2018 adjusted operating earnings, which was the eighth consecutive year returning capital to shareholders at this level or more while maintaining more than $1 billion of excess capital.
Our capital strength reflects the ongoing, strategic mix shift we are orchestrating to have more of our earnings driven by our less-capital demanding, higher P/E businesses: Advice & Wealth Management and Asset Management. In 2018, these businesses drove 75 percent of our pretax adjusted operating earnings, compared to
64 percent in 2014. And it is reinforced by our rigorous process to identify, quantify and mitigate risk to help in our decision-making process across our businesses. As we’ve grown, we’ve continued to reinforce our strategic, proactive, integrated risk management approach, which has
resulted in sustained strong balance sheet fundamentals throughout market cycles.
“Our diversified business generates substantial free cash flow that
we reinvest for growth and return to shareholders.”
Annual Report 2018 | 9
 Differentiated financial strength and capital return
Dividends/share repurchases
$ in millions
          Dividends paid
Common stock share repurchases
• Excesscapital
• Strongratingsandrisk management
• High-qualityinvestmentportfolio
• Ampleliquidity
     A strategic mix shift
Pretax adjusted operating earnings*
Advice & Wealth Management Asset Management Protection & Annuities
*Excludes Corporate & Other segment.
36%
32%
25%
26%
 $2.5B
32%
2014
$2.8B
2018
49%
   2014 2015 2016 2017 2018
$435 $474
$1,372
$1,674
$489 $502
$1,675 $1,344
$516
$1,576

                 10 | Annual Report 2018
Our people and culture — the strength of Ameriprise
Throughout the year, I speak to investors about Ameriprise, our strong position and the large opportunity before us. I reinforce the strength of our people and culture as key drivers of our success and essential in delivering shareholder value. I am extremely proud to lead such a talented group of employees and advisors who work diligently to help our clients achieve their goals. Our client-centric, values-based culture guides our actions and we consistently achieve some of the highest levels of employee and advisor engagement in the industry.
Core to that engagement is the role we play
in helping to advance the communities where
our people live and work. Giving back is part
of our culture and values, and our employees
and advisors consistently demonstrate their steadfast commitment to volunteerism and giving, supporting more than 7,500 nonprofit organizations across the U.S. and internationally. Our people give generously and their participation in our annual giving campaign far exceeds national averages.
 A values-based firm with leading engagement
Our values
Client focused Integrity always Excellence in all we do
Respect for individuals and for the communities in which we live and work
• An industry leader in employee engagement and leadership effectiveness
• Recognized as a “Best Place to Work” nine times and a Military- Friendly employer five consecutive years
Experienced and long-tenured senior management team and strong corporate governance
      Supporting community vitality – corporate giving, volunteerism and employee and advisor gift matching
Supporting nonprofits: Ameriprise totals in 2018:
• 235 grants awarded
• 78,909 volunteer hours
• 72% corporate employee participation in the company’s annual giving campaign — more than double the national average
                                                                                
Looking ahead — confident in our vision and our future
Ultimately, our vision for growth is to do more of what we do best — offering our clients comprehensive, personal advice; focused active asset management; and well-managed annuity and protection choices. Our wealth and asset management businesses are important long-term earnings drivers for the company. They complement the stability and asset-gathering capabilities of our insurance and annuity businesses, which help to deepen relationships, increase client satisfaction and support asset persistency.
Building upon and continuing to enhance the client and advisor experiences are central to our priorities. Financial services is a dynamic industry and consumers have multiple choices for their provider.
For those who value advice and a personal approach, we believe Ameriprise represents a compelling choice. And for investors looking for an attractive investment opportunity, we believe Ameriprise is undervalued and we are energized about the opportunity to consistently demonstrate why.
For perspective, 2018 marked the 10-year anniversary of the global financial crisis. We’re as proud today as we were then about our ability to successfully navigate the intense market pressure while delivering for all our stakeholders — clients, advisors, employees and you, our shareholders. I raise this because the perspective is important. It’s what we do for our clients every day.
Today, U.S. and global economies, as well as company balance sheets, are in stronger positions. The need for personal advice and informed perspective continues to expand. Ameriprise is well positioned and committed to grow as a diversified firm and serve even more clients and advisors for the long term.
Thank you
It’s important for me to express my gratitude to all the people associated with Ameriprise Financial.
To our clients, thank you for entrusting us with your goals and wealth. We greatly value your business and will continue to work diligently to deliver value to you and help you achieve your goals.
To our more than 20,000 employees and advisors, thank you for your commitment to our clients, and for your tremendous energy and enthusiasm.
To my fellow members of the Ameriprise Financial Board of Directors, thank you for your counsel, perspective and support.
And finally, to our shareholders, thank you for your trust and confidence in Ameriprise. We will continue to do all we can to reward it.
Kind regards,
James M. Cracchiolo
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
Annual Report 2018 | 11
                     