AMPHENOL CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
Dear Fellow Shareholders:
The results for 2003 were very good:
Sales - $1,240 million - up 17% from last year - the second highest year in Amphenol history
Earnings per share - $2.52 - up 36% from last year - matched the all-time high for the year 2000 (excluding the 2003 one-time expense for early extinguishment of debt)
All members of the Amphenol family should take pride in achieving these results as the economy emerges from what has been described as the most significant slowdown in the history of the electron- ics industry. The results are impressive and reflect the enormous dedication and contribution made by Amphenol personnel around the world, a commitment that is focused on a clear and consistent business strategy:
♦ Focus on customer needs
♦ Design and develop application-specific interconnect solutions
♦ Establish a strong global presence in resources and capabilities
♦ Preserve and foster a collaborative, entrepreneurial management structure
♦ Maintain a culture of controlling cost
We adhered to this strategy in 2003, and it served us well. The increase in sales was far greater than the industry - analysts estimate the interconnect industry increased by 6% in 2003. We continued to maintain a high level of profitability; again, far better than the industry. We also continued to enhance our relationships with the major original equipment manufacturers ("OEMs"), original design manufacturers, electronic manufacturing service companies and distributors in our target markets as well as developing new relationships with emerging technology companies in the growing markets of Asia. We are very appreciative of these enhanced relationships for they reflect the confidence of our customers in our abil- ity to develop application-specific solutions and meet their needs in an increasingly complex and global marketplace. We also maintained our fiscal discipline which allowed us to generate the highest level of free cash flow in the Company's history; a cash flow that is vital to insuring the flexibility to continue to reinvest in the many opportunities we see.
1

AMPHENOL CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
A Global Leader in Interconnect Systems for Communications
It's a digital world and Amphenol is a leading manufacturer of interconnect products and as- semblies for wireless and wired voice, data and video communication systems and networks.
           2

AMPHENOL CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
In the dynamics of the global marketplace, I would like to share with you what I view as current
industry trends and how Amphenol is positioned to
take advantage of such trends:
Amphenol Strengths
Company has a diversified presence in high growth segments of the market.
As one of the handful of companies in the interconnect industry with a global presence, we have been successful in establishing preferred supplier relationships with leading companies in our target markets.
Strong engineering resources for developing application-specific, value added solutions to customer needs.
Strong global presence with extensive operations in low cost areas (52% of our workforce is in low cost areas).
Strong culture of cost control that is embedded in our operating philosophy.
Pursuing complementary acquisitions on a global basis where we can add value and that are accretive to performance.
Industry Trends
􏱧 Large $30 billion + interconnect market with renewed growth
􏱧 Customers are reducing their vendor base
􏱧 Increased sophistication and proliferation of electronic equipment
􏱧 Customer migration to low cost areas and new markets
􏱧 Pricing pressure
􏱧 Fragmented industry continuing to
consolidate
— —
—
—
— —
  With respect to the major markets we serve with interconnect and cable products and assemblies, we made significant progress in 2003 in strengthening our relationship with the leading customers in such markets as well as broadening our geographical presence and product portfolio. The following is an overview of last year's activity:
􏱧 The military/aerospace market comprised 25% of sales in 2003 and was up 18% over year 2002 levels. The Company is the acknowledged leader in high performance interconnect com- ponents for aerospace/harsh environment applications. The U.S. and certain other countries are continuing in a long term trend to upgrade military defense systems and increase homeland security programs. Several military/aerospace programs in which the Company has significant participation are in the early phases of production, and other major programs in which we have achieved design wins are still in the prototype stage, but such programs should provide very significant future long term revenues. The commercial aerospace market has gone through
3

AMPHENOL CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
A Global Leader in Interconnect Systems for Communications
Amphenol is a leading world provider of interconnect products for wireless infra- structure communication networks and mobile communication applications.
            4

AMPHENOL CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
difficult times in the past few years but there are indications of an improving trend and the long term future of commercial aviation transportation is good. Space exploration is also an area that showcases our enormous engineering and technological resources - we are a significant participant in the International Space Station program and also participated in the recent Mars Exploration Rover program including the Spirit and Opportunity landings. We are proud of the outstanding engineering capabilities represented by our leadership position in the military/aerospace market.
􏱧 The wireless/telecom/datacom markets comprised 36% of sales last year and were up 17% from year 2002 levels. The increase in the wireless/telecom/datacom market was especially welcome as this area was significantly impacted by the post-2000 economic slowdown. We have an excellent portfolio of interconnect products for the mobile handset market, mobile network infrastructure market and the Internet equipment market. In the mobile handset market, we had components in more than half of the worldwide production of mobile phones last year, and we continue to strengthen our relationships with the leading mobile phone manufacturers as well as the new and emerging producers in Asia. As mobile handsets increase in complex- ity and functionality, the outlook for growth in this market is excellent. Demand for greater mobile communication and data services in developed countries and the continuing demand for communication services in developing countries is also driving mobile network upgrades and expansion. We continue to gain position with the leading infrastructure equipment manu- facturers and increasingly are developing relationships with network system operators with a broad portfolio of value added interconnect solutions. With respect to the Internet equipment market, we have an excellent penetration in the areas of servers, storage systems and datacom equipment. Ourvalueaddedinterconnectproductsandsystemsserveanimportantroleinthe continuing demand for increased bandwidth, speed and miniaturization in this market. Our product offering to the communications markets is broad and deep, and our global resources have further strengthened our excellent relations with the major OEM equipment providers.
􏱧 The industrial/automotive markets comprised 26% of our sales last year and were up 28% from year 2002 levels. Our automotive market product offering is comprised of interconnect systems for automotive safety devices, communication and entertainment systems, and the in- creasing presence of automotive electronic features. This market was up last year reflecting the increased utilization of sophisticated airbag and related safety devices as well as the increased use of electronic devices and component applications in automobiles. The industrial market which includes factory automation, medical, test and measurement instrumentation equipment, and mass transportation was also up last year reflecting the key role of factory automation in driving productivity improvements, the growing use of sophisticated electronic equipment and instrumentation for medical applications, and the increasing importance of sophisticated intercity and intracity mass transportation equipment. The industrial markets encompass a broad and diverse range of applications with significant opportunity for growth resulting from the increased use of sophisticated and complex electronic components. We have done an excellent job of increasing our presence with leading OEM industrial manufacturers.
5

AMPHENOL CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
A Global Leader in Interconnect Systems for Industrial Applications
Amphenol is a leader in devel- oping interconnect products and systems for industrial, instrumentation and mass transportation applications.
Amphenol is a leading supplier of interconnect systems for automotive safety systems and other electronic applications.
         6

AMPHENOL CORPORATION 2003 ANNUAL REPORT
􏱧 The broadband market comprised 13% of our sales last year and was down 2% from year 2002 levels. We serve the broadband market primarily with coaxial cable, and after a period of ex- cellent growth in 1999/2000, that market has slowed significantly in recent years. The growth in prior years was fueled by significant expansion of broadband cable television systems in international markets and by the upgrade by cable operators in the U.S. to full service digital systems offering a variety of video, voice and data services. The slowdown has reflected a generally slowing worldwide economy, the availability of credit to finance system upgrades and expansion, and economic dynamics specific to certain operators. However, we believe the long term outlook for this market is good as deployment of broadband systems in international markets is still in the early stages, and U.S. systems will continue to be upgraded to offer the full potential of digital technology.
I am pleased to report that this year we promoted four individuals to Senior Vice President and five to Vice President. The promotions further an organizational structure that will carry us to the next level of growth and profitability. And, I am also proud that the promotions were internal as they reflect the broad and diverse management strength within the Company. I would also like to acknowledge the enormous contribution and entrepreneurial spirit from all of the management teams at our operating units.
2003 began as a very challenging year for us and the electronics industry, with improving economic trends in the latter part of the year. We performed very well, and for this I am grateful for the outstand- ing efforts and contribution of our personnel worldwide for making Amphenol successful in good and difficult times. We also acquired three companies last year, and while each is relatively small in its own right, collectively they will play a strategic role in expanding our products and services to the worldwide infocom and industrial markets. We are well positioned with global resources and an excellent prod- uct portfolio to serve the worldwide needs of our customers. Predicting the future in today's business environment is difficult. However, we are very confident that we are in excellent markets with a great organization, and we are very excited about the future. The excitement and confidence in the future also stems from the loyalty and trust of our excellent base of customers and suppliers; we thank them for their invaluable support. Finally, I believe we have a passion for the business, and it is this passion that drives the organization to high levels of performance. I know such intangible can be transitory. But I believe we have it; we think about it; and, we work hard to retain it.
Martin H. Loeffler
Chairman, Chief Executive Officer and President
 7
