                “BUSINESS AS USUAL” AT AVISTA IS NOT USUAL FOR MOST BUSINESSES. GOING BEYOND THE EXPECTED IS THE MINDSET OF OUR WHOLE COMPANY, WHERE WE CHALLENGE OURSELVES AND EACH OTHER TO THINK BIGGER THAN WHAT WE THOUGHT POSSIBLE, EVERY DAY.
                                                                                                             TO OUR
                       SHAREHOLDERS
                                             Our industry is changing each year, and this year, change was front and center for us. We embraced this change, as we do at Avista. Through thoughtful and deliberate efforts, we shaped the framework for a future partnership with Hydro One that is a win for all stakeholders.
                     In July, we announced the proposed merger with Hydro One of Ontario, Canada. In a consolidating industry, this partnership makes sense for all of us — our shareholders, employees, customers and communities. The decision to team up with Hydro One, at a time of strength and growth for our company, is a unique opportunity to preserve our identity and strong
legacy while allowing us to significantly define and control our future operations. Hydro One provides additional scale, helping us build a stronger foundation for our future and augmenting available resources that allow us to continue investing in our energy infrastructure and technology.
  
VALUE FOR ALL STAKEHOLDERS THROUGH A PARTNERSHIP WITH HYDRO ONE
■ Our shareholders will receive solid value, with an attractive
price of $53 per share at the time of close. Demonstrating strong support, shareholders approved the acquisition on Nov. 21, 2017, with 77 percent of the outstanding shares entitled to vote on the proposal voting 98 percent in favor of the acquisition.
■ Our customers will continue to receive high quality, safe and reliable energy services at a reasonable cost. We’ll remain local, with local headquarters and local leadership.
■ Our communities will continue to benefit from the critical philanthropic and economic development support we provide. In fact, we’ll be able to do even more. Hydro One has committed to nearly doubling our current levels of community contributions by providing a $2 million annual contribution to the Avista Foundation.
■ Our employees will see a continuation of the company essentially as it is today.
In January 2018, FERC provided its approval of the merger. We’ve submitted applications for regulatory approval in five states, which are still pending. We’ve requested regulatory approval from state utility commissions by Aug. 14, 2018. Pending these approvals, as well as approval from the Federal Communications Commission, clearance by the Committee
on Foreign Investment in the United States, and compliance with applicable requirements under the U.S. Hart-Scott-Rodino
Antitrust Improvements Act, we expect that the transaction will close in the second half of 2018.
How we work, make decisions and engage with our customers and communities will not change as a result of this acquisition. We will remain focused on providing the same levels of high- quality service for customers, delivering on our core strategies and contributing to our communities in meaningful ways.
We won’t be complacent.
While the industry continues to transform, we continue to help shape the future. We are a company with a long history of innovation and service. With this foundation, we think bigger to meet the expectations of our customers, strengthen our communities and engage our employees.
  HEATHER ROSENTRATER, VP ENERGY DELIVERY, IS A KEY LEADER IN AVISTA’S INNOVATION EFFORTS LIKE URBANOVA AND GRID MODERNIZATION.
     AS PART OF URBANOVA’S SMART AND
CONNECTED STREETLIGHT PILOT, SENSOR
PACKAGES WERE INSTALLED ON 10 STREETLIGHTS
IN THE UNIVERSITY DISTRICT. THESE SENSORS MEASURE AIR QUALITY AND WILL HELP RESEARCHERS ASSESS ITS ROLE IN A HEALTHY CITY.
2
      
  BEYOND ENERGY
Customer satisfaction is key to our success. When customers are informed and engaged with their energy choices, the benefits extend through the entire community. Paramount to customer satisfaction is anticipating their needs and offering choices to ensure we are their trusted energy advisor.
Through programs such as our Electric Vehicle Supply Equipment (EVSE) program, the Solar Select program and the launch of our new, more user-friendly website, we are providing solutions that benefit both the customer and the company and are engaging with our customers in diverse ways.
As a testament to our outstanding customer care, in April we received Edison Electric Institute’s 2017 National Key Accounts Award for Customer Service, selected by customers as one of eight companies from 700 across the country, including Microsoft and Walmart. This award looked at innovative offerings, ease
of incentive programs, communications and customer support before, during and after outages. We’re honored to be one of the few utilities to receive this award.
BRIDGING COMMUNITIES. CONVENING IDEAS.
When our communities thrive, we all benefit. Bridging communities means leveraging intentional innovation and strategic partnerships to improve the lives of those we serve. Avista can be a catalyst for community and economic growth
by recognizing projects we can support and convening resources and community leadership.
Urbanova, the smart city living laboratory in Spokane’s University District, is a collaboration of strategic partnerships
to create healthier communities, stronger economies, smarter infrastructure and a more sustainable future. As a founding partner, we’re helping develop and test smart city applications and solutions that can shape the future. This year, as part of Urbanova’s Smart and Connected Streetlights pilot, we installed sensors on streetlights in the University District that monitor air quality and other conditions. Researchers may use the collected data to inform future health initiatives for the community. We’re excited about what’s to come as part of Urbanova, including a Shared Energy Economy pilot that will create a microgrid and facilitate energy sharing among buildings in the University District.
THINK BIG. CREATE. MOVE SWIFTLY. SUCCEED.
Avista employees are hard-working, creative and dedicated. Their commitment and excellence is evident in everything we do. We ask them to think big, create and move swiftly. We nurture an entrepreneurial spirit among employees and give them room to turn good ideas into viable business possibilities. In return, Avista provides opportunities for professional development and success in a culture that engages all employees. Because when they do well, Avista does well, too.
AN OVERVIEW OF 2017 FINANCIAL RESULTS
Our financial results this year were in line with expectations. Customer growth, lower resource costs and lower operating expenses were offset by the impact of federal income tax law changes and costs associated with the proposed acquisition by Hydro One.
Consolidated earnings were $1.79 per diluted share, with net income of $115.9 million for the year ended Dec. 31, 2017.
Acquisition costs reduced earnings by $0.19 per diluted share. The impact of federal income tax law changes on deferred income tax balances associated with subsidiaries and non-utility operations reduced earnings $0.16 per diluted share. Tax impacts paid for by customers will be returned to customers, through the rate-making process.
Our balance sheet and credit ratings remain healthy. At year- end, Avista Corp. had $260.6 million of available liquidity under our $400 million line of credit. We added cost-effective long-term debt through the private placement market by issuing $90 million of Avista Corp. first mortgage bonds, bearing an interest rate
of 3.91 percent (4.55 percent effective interest rate), which will mature in December 2047.
Long-term corporate earnings growth of 4 percent to 5 percent continues to be our target. We believe earnings growth will come through our focus on updating and replacing aging infrastructure, continued effective cost management, investment in essential digital technologies and other growth platforms. Our projection for customer and load growth remains near 1 percent.
And, I’m pleased to note, that in 2017 the board of directors raised the dividend on Avista Corp. common stock for the 15th consecutive year, for an annualized dividend of $1.43.
3
 MYAVISTA.COM LAUNCHED IN JULY WITH ADDITIONAL TOOLS, ENHANCED MOBILE CAPABILITIES AND IMPROVED SECURITY.
 
   REGULATED OPERATIONS
AVISTA UTILITIES
Avista Utilities contributed $1.77 per diluted share to earnings in 2017. Continuing our investment in replacing and updating aging infrastructure resulted in total capital costs of $405.9 million for the year. We plan to continue making capital investments near this level in 2018 and 2019 to maintain the reliability and strength of our electric and natural gas energy systems.
The timely recovery of these costs is essential to earning an adequate return on our shareholders’ investment.
In Washington, we filed electric and natural gas general rate requests on May 26. These requests included a three-year rate plan and are pending before the utility commission. We expect a decision no later than the end of April 2018.
In Idaho, we received approval of our electric and natural gas general rate requests, with rate changes effective Jan. 1, 2018
and Jan. 1, 2019. The utility commission approved a two-year rate plan, and Avista will not file new general rate cases for rates to be effective before Jan. 1, 2020.
In Oregon, we received approval of our natural gas general rate request, and new rates went into effect on Oct. 1 and Nov. 1, 2017.
ALASKA ELECTRIC LIGHT AND POWER COMPANY
Operations at our Juneau, Alaska subsidiary, Alaska Electric Light and Power Company (AEL&P), went smoothly this year. AEL&P operations contributed $0.14 per diluted share to Avista Corp.’s earnings and made $6.4 million in capital expenditures. They plan to invest $7.0 million in capital projects in 2018.
In November 2017, the Regulatory Commission of Alaska made the 2016 interim rate increase of 3.86 percent permanent.
NON-REGULATED OPERATIONS
Non-regulated operations focused on strategic investments to help position the company for future growth. We continue to explore pathways for growth that will strengthen the company and the economies of the communities we serve. Through our investment in Energy Impact Partners, we are one of 16 active participants gaining greater access and insight into industry trends and technology innovations that can create opportunities to deliver new value to our customers in an increasingly digital and distributed industry. This and other venture investments are more than monetary, as they facilitate greater connection among industry innovators, create opportunities for sharing expertise and drive the development of products or services that are mutually beneficial.
In the long term, we envision our investments will result in both strategic and financial benefits that provide value for the utility and our stakeholders.
THE BEGINNING OF EVEN BETTER
As this year comes to a close, I’m filled with excitement
and nostalgia. While the merger may appear to bring the end
of something special, it is also the beginning of something special. Avista is well-positioned for what’s to come, with a tenacious commitment to our customers. This, combined with our fundamental belief that every individual has an impact on our community, will carry us into the next evolution of Avista.
Scott L. Morris
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
            4
 