1
       SCOTT MORRIS
Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer
   Dear fellow shareholders:
Thank you for your interest in Avista Corp. We are a company that provides energy and energy-related services through our core utility business as well as our energy management and sustainability business. But, we’re more than that. Avista Corp. is strong, steady, reliable and innovative. It’s all about the people – our employees – who continuously improve the ways we serve our customers.
There’s Kelly Magalsky, manager of process improvement, who coordinated cross-discipline employee teams that so far have developed and implemented significant enhancements to more than 50 points at which we interact with
our customers.
There’s Toni Pessemier, American Indian relations advisor, who helps us navigate sensitive political, operational, cultural and natural resource issues through the relationships she’s built and nurtured with Native American Tribes throughout our service territory.
There’s Barry Pasicznyk, investment recovery coordinator, and Seth Feist, claims processer, who together created a wire tool kit to help local businesses and law enforcement in their efforts to recover copper wire stolen from our utility.
There’s IloAnn Edminster, senior project manager at Ecova, who manages complex client relations to assure contract accountabilities are met.
The list goes on and on throughout our corporation. This kind of enthusiasm, dedication and knowledge is inherent in our employees – it’s in our DNA. And together,
we are Avista!
In this report, you’ll get a sense of who we are and how we work. I think that’s important, because when you make a decision to invest your money in a company like ours, you want to make sure that it aligns with what is important to you and your goals for creating value.
KELLY MAGALSKY
TONI PESSEMIER
BARRY PASICZNYK
SETH FEIST
ILOANN EDMINSTER
                                   
2
An overview of our 2012 financial results:
       The year was challenging for Avista Corp. Our 2012 consolidated earnings were $1.32 per diluted share, a decrease from $1.72 in 2011. This decrease reflects under-performance in each of our business segments.
Avista Utilities
The earnings contribution from our core business – Avista Utilities – was below our expectations for the year. As is the case for most utilities, our financial performance is dependent upon, among other things, weather conditions. In 2012, our energy loads were lowered by warmer weather during the first and fourth quarters, periods in which our customers usually have their highest heating needs. This was somewhat offset by a warm summer and fall, resulting in an increase in cooling loads.
The timely recovery of the costs of our capital investments continues to be essential to gaining adequate return on our shareholders’ investment. In 2012, we successfully settled a rate case in Washington that provides retail rate increases for both 2013 and 2014 and includes provisions that represent meaningful, incremental improvement in addressing the regulatory lag we experience in that state. And in February 2013, we reached a settlement agreement in the general rate case that we filed in Idaho in October 2012. If approved by the Idaho Commission, the agreement will provide additional revenue increases April 1, 2013, and October 1, 2013. These revenue increases, together with planned cost-management, provide a solid foundation for improved returns going forward.
Ecova
Weaker than expected results from Ecova, our primary unregulated business, coupled with losses from our other non-utility businesses, dampened our consolidated results for the year. Operating expenses were up at Ecova due to the addition of employees and other fixed infrastructure costs that were incurred to support the higher revenue growth we anticipated, but which did not materialize due to slower adoption of some of our new services. In addition, we encountered some delays in onboarding some new customers. As a result, Ecova’s performance this year did not meet our expectations.
We are pleased, however, that Ecova’s total revenues grew by 13 percent in 2012, including acquisitions, and we expect continued revenue growth in 2013. With completion of the integration of the two most recently acquired companies and through process and efficiency improvements made throughout the organization, we expect Ecova’s performance to improve in 2013.
Credit and Liquidity
Our balance sheet and credit ratings remain healthy. At year-end, Avista had $312 million of available liquidity under our $400 million line of credit. In November, we issued $80 million of 4.23 percent First Mortgage Bonds due in 2047, and there are $50 million in First Mortgage Bonds maturing in 2013. We issued $29.1 million of common stock in 2012, including $23.4 million under sales agency agreements. Plans call for us to issue up to $50 million in equity and up to $100 million in First Mortgage Bonds in 2013 to maintain an appropriate capital structure.
Earnings growth
We are planning for long-term corporate earnings growth of
4 to 5 percent. This forward-looking view of our performance builds on the signs of recovery we see in our regional economy and our focus on cost management, increased efficiencies in business processes and continued growth at Ecova.
WE ARE IMPLEMENTING PROGRAMS TO SLOW THE PACE OF GROWTH IN OUR OPERATING COSTS AND TO
ACHIEVE SUSTAINABLE COST SAVINGS.
In addition to the weather, the utility’s performance in 2012 was lowered by increasing operating costs, a continued weak economy and operational challenges at certain industrial customers. We are implementing programs to slow the pace of growth
in our operating costs and to achieve sustainable cost savings. Such measures include evaluating all
  operating and maintenance activities, reprioritizing projects
and implementing a voluntary severance program which was completed in December. Total costs for the voluntary severance program were $7.3 million (pre-tax). We expect that the long-term operating and maintenance cost savings will exceed the severance costs of the program, which has an expected
payback period of approximately 1.4 years.
The economic recovery in our service territory still lags
behind the rest of the country. We’re seeing lower than expected growth in new customers, fewer housing starts and lower energy usage by some major industrial customers. However, the positive signs that we’re beginning to see in lower unemployment rates and foreclosure rates staying below the national average lead us to expect positive economic growth in our service area in 2013 and 2014.
Winter and spring weather patterns kept rain falling in the low lands and the snow pack growing in the mountains. Combined with one of the wettest falls on record, we had above normal hydroelectric generation for the year. This, coupled with continued low natural gas fuel prices, resulted in lower
power supply costs, benefiting both our shareholders and our customers.
        
3
     The winds in the Palouse bring renewable energy to our diversified portfolio
On a blustery first day of May 2012, I was pleased to join a group of elected officials, construction and utility executives, and local residents and business leaders who gathered on a hillside outside of Oakesdale, Wash., to kick-off the construction of the Palouse Wind Project. The wind farm, which started commercial operations in December, has 58 turbines capable of generating 105 megawatts, which is enough clean, renewable energy to power 30,000 of our customers’ homes. Avista signed a 30-year purchased power agreement with the project’s owner, First Wind, bringing into our resource mix additional clean, renewable energy.
The power we get from Palouse Wind will be part of our
diverse energy portfolio that includes renewable resources like hydroelectricity and biomass. Palouse Wind helps us achieve our goal of meeting customers’ energy needs reliably and responsibly, while continuing our legacy of generating renewable energy. It’s good for our customers and communities to have the project right in our backyard.
                .49 .515 .545 .57 .595
1.16 1.10
1.00
.81 .69
          YEAR PAID
 COMMON STOCK DIVIDENDS PAID BY AVISTA CORP.*
* Annualized Dividend
Avista Corp.’s board of directors raised the dividend in each of the last 10 years, reflecting their confidence in the financial strength of the company.
 DIVIDEND PAID IN DOLLARS
ʻ03 ʻ04 ʻ05 ʻ06 ʻ07 ʻ08 ʻ09 ʻ10 ʻ11 ʻ12

4
   Long-term planning includes investments to modernize
our infrastructure
Replacing natural gas pipelines
Diggers, trenchers and other heavy equipment mingled with
the residents in downtown Davenport, Wash., all summer as they went about their daily routines. The piles of dirt and deep trenches were part of our 20-year program to replace more than 700 miles of natural gas pipeline that was installed prior to 1987 throughout our service territory. This is just one of several replacement projects that have been completed so far. Additional natural gas pipeline replacement projects are
planned for communities in Washington, Idaho and Oregon in the years ahead.
The wholesale price for natural gas declined again this year, and supplies are more plentiful. Furthermore, our 2012 Integrated Resource Plan forecasts sufficient natural gas pipeline resources well into the future. In fact, we believe that acquisition of additional pipeline resources will not be necessary until 2029 or later.
Updating legacy hydroelectric plants
Our hydroelectric resources provide about 50 percent of our generation capacity, with six plants on the Spokane River in Idaho and Washington. In addition, we own and operate two plants on the Clark Fork River as it flows from Montana into Idaho. Together Noxon Rapids (completed in 1959) and Cabinet Gorge (which celebrated its 60th anniversary in 2012) can generate more than 817 megawatts. With the completion of work on Unit 4 at Noxon Rapids this year, our Clark Fork projects together have the capability of generating an additional 30 megawatts of clean, renewable power. These upgrades will extend the lives of these work-horse plants well into the future.
              
5
         Rebuilding aging infrastructure and implementing new technology enhances reliable energy service
  Meeting the challenges of the Northwest’s terrain
Excavating 10 to 12 foot holes in steep mountainous terrain to accommodate 85 to 90 foot steel poles.
Finding safe shelter to wait out thunderstorms as they sweep through the canyon.
Digging up and relocating boulders the size of Volkswagens, but that weigh much more.
These were some of the challenges faced by Avista employees during the reconstruction of the 115KV transmission lines up the Burke Canyon in North Idaho. It was a feat of modern engineering and well-honed lineman skills.
them the information they need to effectively manage their own energy use and make more informed decisions about choices that drive their energy bill.
Investing through the capital budget
We’ve been intentional about making the investments needed to maintain and upgrade our transmission and distribution network and putting in place the technology and hardware it takes
to enhance its reliability. We invested $271 million in capital projects in 2012 and plan to spend about $260 million in each of the next two years. This commitment is capital intensive, but we believe the value and reliability it brings to our customers is worth every penny.
     Originally completed in 1926, the transmission lines run through
some of the most rugged terrain in our service territory – from
Wallace, Idaho, to the Montana border. They also span some $100 of the most beautiful recreation areas in the Northwest, with snowmobilers and four-wheelers traveling the canyon for miles.
A combination of replacing 50-foot wooden structures with taller
steel poles and closer spacing of these new structures
decreases the likelihood of snow and tree-related outages and
enhances service reliability for our customers. All of this was accomplished without a single lost-time accident. I am proud
of our employees’ skills and their focus on safety.
Updating technology on both sides of the meter
Along with rebuilding aging infrastructure to enhance reliability, we’re modernizing the technology we use to monitor our system operations and help customers better manage their own
energy use.
2013 CAPITAL BUDGET
Total capital budget $266 million ($ in millions)
$53
$85
    $75 $50
$
  $
3
3
6
6
      $
8
$2
$
$2
2
8
     $17
23
    $
7
$
1
1
4
4
       $25 $
$0
$6
6
    $4
4
                  Avista’s smart grid demonstration project in Pullman, Wash., is now in its third year. We’ve completed installing new transformers, circuit and communication equipment on our side of the meter. The next phase of the program calls for piloting the technology in customers’ homes that will provide
      OTHER FLEET ENVIRONMENTAL
FACILITIES NATURAL GAS GROWTH
GENERATION
TECHNOLOGY
TRANSMISSION & DISTRIBUTION

6
           RICK CLOUGH
Director of Resource Analytics
Putting into action the ideas that bring value
Innovation from the inside – out
It could be something as simple as a broken sprinkler head, continuously leaking hundreds of gallons of water a month. Or it could be as complex as an HVAC system running inefficiently, using too much energy to heat or cool guest rooms. When G6 Hospitality, the management company that operates more than 1,100 Motel 6 and Studio 6 properties across North America needed a solution to managing the energy use at each of its locations, they came to Rick Clough, director of resource analytics at Ecova. Working together, Rick and G6 have seen savings, through cost avoidance, of approximately $1.1 million to date.
I believe the unique business model that Ecova successfully implements tells the story of Avista Corp. innovation in action. Employees’ expertise in energy management and sustainable business practices has transformed Ecova into a market-leading company and has garnered it contracts with nearly 25 percent
of the Fortune 500 companies and an impressive 97 percent customer retention rate. As the business community continues
to look for ways to address resource constraints and save money, Ecova’s products and services provide opportunities to help solve these challenging issues.
Our commitment is to enhance the value of Ecova and its contribution to our shareholders’ return. We will continue to assess the opportunities of monetizing this company in the future.
                                  ECOVA REVENUE
 $156 $138
$102
$77 $59
$ in millions
                                 ʻ08 ʻ09 ʻ10 ʻ11 ʻ12

7
       COLLINS SPRAGUE
  Innovation that is renewable
Collins Sprague, our director of government relations, was instrumental in advancing legislation, signed in early 2012 by Washington Governor Christine Gregoire, that qualified legacy biomass energy projects (built before 1999) as eligible renewable resources for purposes of meeting Washington state’s
Renewable Portfolio Standard (RPS). As a result of the bill’s passage, a major portion of the energy generated at our Kettle Falls biomass plant, completed in 1983, will now qualify to meet our renewable requirements in Washington beginning in 2016 and will result in a significant reduction in the future costs for Avista to comply with the Washington RPS.
Our Kettle Falls generating facility was the first plant built in the U.S. specifically to use biomass as a generating resource. It has been producing renewable, dependable energy for almost 30 years. The plant pioneered a technology that has been replicated around the world and represents Avista’s culture and leadership in advancing renewable energy.
Innovation that builds communities
One of the best strategies for pulling out of the longest
and deepest recession of our time is to enable broad-based innovation and entrepreneurship. Since 2007 we’ve partnered with Spokane Community College (SCC) on the Avista Center for Entrepreneurship, giving those with great business ideas a better chance to make them a reality – creating jobs and enhancing the economic vitality of our community.
The programming and mentoring that make the SCC program successful have been expanded through the Avista Business Entrepreneurship Network. In 2012 we added programs at community colleges in Coeur d’Alene, Idaho; Clarkston, Wash.; and Medford, Ore. One college administrator told us, “It’s one of the most creative opportunities that has landed on our doorstep in a long time.”
Through active engagement with legislators and others, Collins Sprague was successful in getting approval for a major portion of energy from Avista’s Kettle Falls plant to qualify as an eligible renewable resource.
STEVE TRABUN
        Regional Business Manager Steve Trabun partnered with faculty and administrators at Spokane Community College to extend the Avista Business Entrepreneurship Network to Coeur d’Alene, Idaho; Clarkston, Wash.; and Medford Ore., a strategy to create jobs and enhance economic vitality in our service territory.
     
8
People – Powered – Performance
      We’ve set our strategies and we’re performing on them.
At Avista Utilities we are
Increasing customer engagement to strengthen mutual understanding and continue to improve service delivery;
Delivering continuous improvement and innovation for customer value, operational efficiency and growth;
Investing in our infrastructure to replace aging equipment and enhance reliability and safety;
Controlling a portfolio of generating resources that responsibly meet our long-term energy needs; and
Driving effective regulatory outcomes.
At Ecova we are
Expanding utility programs, and commercial and industrial cross sales of services;
Maintaining customer retention rates; and
Evaluating opportunistic acquisitions to diversify service offerings.
We recognize that 2012 was a disappointing year for our overall financial performance, but I believe we have a solid foundation of strategies and actions in place that will provide for stronger performance in 2013 and beyond.
ELECTRICITY GENERATION RESOURCE MIX
As of Dec. 31, 2012
It is through our employees’ talents and dedication to service that Avista Corp. is well positioned to meet the job today and in the future. I am very proud of this wonderful group of individuals and the valuable and essential services they provide. They are Avista.
I want to thank you, our shareholders, for your continued support of our company. We will continue to work hard to be worthy of your trust.
Sincerely,
Scott L. Morris
Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer
              Ages are as of the proxy date – March 29, 2013.
  WIND 6% BIOMASS 2%
COAL 9%
   HYDRO
(40% Avista & 8% Contracts)
NATURAL GAS 35%
        $140 $119
$142
       TOTAL SHAREHOLDER RETURN
(assumes $100 was invested in AVA and each index on Dec. 31, 2007 and that all dividends were reinvested when paid)
Avista Corp. (AVA)
S&P 400 Electric Utilities Index S&P 500 Index
$150
$100
$50
$109 $93
                                                                                                             $0
        ʻ08 ʻ09 ʻ10 ʻ11 ʻ12
