 TO OUR STAKEHOLDERS
4
David C. Dauch
Chairman, President & Chief Executive Officer
2014 was another successful year for AAM, characterized by sales growth that continues to outpace the industry and financial performance that was highlighted by solid profitability and improved cash flow. We made great strides
in achieving global operational stability while delivering world-class quality products. We
are confident in AAM’s future as our focus on technology leadership and product innovation has resulted in a solid new business backlog that serves as the foundation for our strong profitable growth opportunities.
 
 In 2014, AAM’s net sales were nearly $3.7 billion, up approximately 15% on a year-over-year basis—almost triple the growth rate for the industry. From 2009-2014, AAM’s compound annual growth rate of sales (CAGR) has been nearly 20%. This is significantly faster than the industry growth rate observed for the past five years, whether measured as growth in the U.S. Seasonally Adjusted Annual Rate (SAAR) of sales at 9.6% or North America light vehicle builds at 14.7%.
For the full year of 2014, AAM delivered cash from operating activities of nearly $320 million. AAM’s strong financial performance and cash flow generation have allowed us to make great progress in improving our capital structure. We now have the financial flexibility to invest in our future and support the execution of AAM’s long-term strategic objectives.
 FINANCIAL PERFORMANCE
5

SALES
AAM’s strong position in the light truck market in 2014, as well as our increased presence in the all-wheel-drive (AWD) passenger car and crossover vehicle markets, are the key drivers of our sales growth.
GROWTH
Sales supporting AAM’s North American light truck business were up approximately 16% on a year-over-year basis, driven by higher production volumes for our North American light truck programs—mainly GM’s full-size pickup trucks and SUVs and Ram’s heavy-duty pickups.
Sales in our passenger car and crossover vehicle business were up an impressive 73% versus 2013. This increase was primarily due to higher sales of our EcoTrac® Disconnecting AWD system, which has now launched on the 2014 Jeep Cherokee and the 2015 Chrysler 200.
AAM’s non-GM sales grew nearly 30% on a year-over-year basis to approximately $1.2 billion. This is almost double the growth rate for our company in total this year.
 6
© General Motors

DIVERSIFICATION
In 2014, AAM made excellent progress diversifying our customer base, achieving new business wins and launching new programs with customers such as Fiat Chrysler Automobiles (FCA), Volkswagen, Mercedes-Benz, Ford, Nissan, Jaguar Land Rover, Honda and others. This fast-paced growth has allowed us to make significant gains in AAM’s business diversification, examples of which include:
• Non-GM sales have more than tripled since 2009 – tracking at $1.2 billion in 2014.
• Approximately 70% of AAM’s $825 million new and incremental business backlog for 2015 to 2017 is for customers other than GM.
• Approximately 75% of our new and incremental business backlog for 2015 to 2017 supports passenger car and CUV programs.
• Approximately 85% of AAM’s new and incremental business backlog for 2015 to 2017 is for programs sourced outside of the United States.
AAM’s new and incremental business backlog includes product programs that feature new and innovative product technologies including: AAM’s industry-first EcoTrac Disconnecting AWD System; AAM’s high-efficiency technologies; e-AAMTM
hybrid & electric driveline systems; and AAM’s SYLENT driveshaft technology.
With a continued focus on product innovation and product-line extensions, AAM successfully expanded and broadened our product portfolio and customer base in 2014, and has gained momentum for further diversification in the future.
 7

 Over the past five years, AAM has completed 100 major product and facility launches. In 2014 alone, AAM successfully executed 16 product launches. These programs have been key in supporting our sales growth and instrumental in helping us achieve our diversification and global growth objectives.
In 2014, AAM launched new and improved driveline systems for two of our largest North American light truck programs: GM’s next- generation full-size SUVs and heavy-duty series pickup trucks and Ram’s heavy-duty pickup trucks. Our Guanajuato Manufacturing Complex and our Three Rivers Manufacturing Facility were instrumental in the success of these program launches.
LAUNCH ACTIVITY
AND KEY PROGRAMS
 8
AAM’s innovative and fuel-efficient EcoTrac Disconnecting AWD System received both awards and accolades in 2014. EcoTrac was featured on the 2014 Jeep Cherokee, named by MotorWeek as the Best Small Utility Vehicle of the Year, and the Chrysler 200. AAM was also named a 2014 Automotive News PACE Award finalist for our first-to-market EcoTrac technology.

 Also in 2014, MSP Industries, an AAM subsidiary based in Oxford, Michigan, launched production of continuously variable transmission (CVT) pulleys for Honda. As a premier metal-formed product supplier, MSP is highly experienced in the CVT pulley forging process. The facility has been making CVT pulleys since 2006 and currently supplies in excess of 3 million parts per year
to the automotive industry. The facility’s experience in the market and its innovative processes were Honda’s incentive to award MSP this multimillion-dollar program.
AAM Europe made great progress with the launch of
two exciting new products for Jaguar Land Rover’s next generation of passenger car vehicles. The products include a rear-drive unit (RDU) that launched in the fourth quarter of 2014 at our Świdnica Manufacturing Facility, along with three front-drive units (FDUs) that will launch in 2015.
AAM’s market presence in China continued to grow and diversify in 2014. For Mercedes-Benz, we will soon be launching independent rear-drive axles for a crossover vehicle program based off both the C-class and E-class vehicles in China. And for FCA, we will be providing power transfer units (PTUs) and rear drive modules (RDMs) for a third EcoTrac derivative for the China market.
 QUALITYPERFORMANCE
Quality is one of AAM’s founding strategic principles. In 2014, AAM continued to operate at levels less than 10 discrepant parts per million. We continue to emphasize quality, warranty, reliability and durability performance in everything that we do. AAM’s stringent quality standards are demanded by our customers and the industry in general. We are very proud that we continue to meet and exceed these standards year after year.
In addition to our strong quality and warranty performance, three AAM facilities: our Colfor-Malvern facility in Ohio, our Changshu facility in China, and our DieTronik operations in Auburn Hills, Michigan, were all recognized with the GM Supplier Quality Excellence Award for their outstanding performance. AAM’s commitment to the highest level of quality performance in the industry is a critical differentiator in the marketplace and something that is valued by our customers.
9

 TECHNOLOGY LEADERSHIP
As the automotive industry continues to innovate
and evolve, AAM is working to develop new forward-
thinking technologies encompassing independent drive,
hybrid and electric vehicles. To meet these challenges, AAM
plans to substantially increase its investment in advanced product, process and systems technology. That’s why, in 2014, AAM invested approximately $104 million in research and development.
In 2014, we announced our continued commitment to technology leadership with
plans to open a new Advanced Technology Development Center (ATDC) in Detroit,
Michigan. AAM will invest $15 to $20 million in this facility, which is expected to open in 2015 and create up to 100 jobs in the City of Detroit.
The objective of the ATDC is to combine advanced product, process and systems development into a single consolidated “innovation” setting. The ATDC will enable us to expand our benchmarking capabilities and accelerate the development of critical competencies needed to successfully address the dominant industry trends affecting future driveline systems. These include:
• Improved Efficiency
• Mass Reduction
• Enhanced Vehicle Performance
10

 OUTLOOK
FOR 2015 AND BEYOND
Building on the solid success of 2014, we expect our $825 million new and incremental business backlog for 2015 to 2017 will continue to support our plan to sustain solid profitability and improved cash flow performance. We also expect to have measurable progress on business diversification, with non-GM sales expected to grow faster than our total sales growth.
In 2015, AAM will execute 18 product and facility launches, which include:
• Rear axles for a light vehicle application in the Thailand market for Ford
• Driveline system components for a passenger car program for Jaguar Land Rover
• Driveline system components for a global crossover vehicle program for GM
• Front and rear axles for a light-truck program for Nissan
We are excited for 2015 and beyond as AAM moves forward with a solid, cost-competitive global manufacturing footprint; a diversified customer base and product portfolio; and a new business backlog that will continue to support our top line growth.
AAM remains focused on our business strategy of quality performance, operational excellence and technology leadership. We believe our focus on these three critical strategic objectives positively differentiates AAM within the industry and will allow us to build value for all our stakeholders.
Thank you for your loyal and continued support of AAM. Sincerely,
  David C. Dauch
Chairman of the Board, President & Chief Executive Officer
11
