2
CHAIRMAN’S LETTER
 Richard E. Dauch
Co-Founder, Chairman of the Board & Chief Executive Officer
  
   The year 2004 was profitable and rewarding for American Axle & Manufacturing (AAM), our shareholders, associates and other stakeholders. It was a year in which we met new and ongoing challenges and saw the continuation of our international expansion.
Like other U.S. automotive companies, we experienced the harsh realities of structural changes affecting the industry: global competition, customer demand for global pricing and an escalating domestic production cost environment.
We celebrated a major AAM milestone—the completion of 10 successful and profitable years of existence—and entered the next phase in our evolution and continued profitable growth.
Major events have occurred—in the industry, the country, the world— during our young life as a public company. But our rock solid foundation and excellent balance sheet upon which we have built AAM continue to serve us well in converting what some may see as difficulties into opportunities. In 2004, IndustryWeek recognized AAM as one of its “50 Best Manufacturing Companies,” based on our ability to “more than survive during difficult times” and to “operate more intelligently and efficiently” than our competitors.
I believe that we have every reason to be confident and optimistic about AAM’s future as a leader in sophisticated, high technology and world-class quality manufacturing.
OUR STRONG FINANCIAL AND OPERATING PERFORMANCE CONTINUES
AAM is the 26th largest automotive supplier in the world. We continue to be a leader with respect to profitability, cash flow and after-tax return on invested capital (ROIC). Our performance in 2004 was no exception:
■ We delivered diluted earnings per share of $2.98.
■ We achieved net operating cash flow of $213.0 million.
■ We realized a 12.7% ROIC that continues to be in the upper range of our peer group.
■ We established a dividend policy and paid our first ever quarterly cash dividends as a public company.
■ We initiated a stock repurchase program, authorizing 2.5 million shares in February and adding 3.0 million shares in August.
■ We refinanced our debt at attractive investment-grade levels.
■ We improved our net debt to capital to 31.2%.
■ We are in compliance with Section 404 of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 relating to AAM's internal controls as of December 31, 2004. We also received an attestation report regarding our compliance from our Independent Registered Public Accounting firm.
These achievements further demonstrate our commitment to financial discipline and the integrity of our financial reports, which were certified by management.
AAM ANNUAL REPORT 2004 3

2004 WAS A BREAKOUT YEAR FOR SECURING OUR FUTURE
AAM won incremental and successor business that secured approximately 80 percent of our current book of business for the next 10 years — a claim few Tier One automotive suppliers can make.
Our significant and growing research and development (R&D) efforts are yielding advanced product technology that is paving the way into new markets, enabling us to grow domestically as well as internationally. For example, AAM's new rear drive modules (RDMs) and independent front drive axles (IFDAs) are creating opportunities for us in the growing all-wheel-drive (AWD) passenger car and crossover vehicle market, including a major AWD program that was sourced to AAM and is scheduled to launch in 2007 for a global OEM.
We also secured new business with two Asian OEMs. One award represents AAM's first opportunity to provide a foreign customer with front and rear axle modules for a major North American product platform. The second award marks our entry into the Asian market. Under this lifetime program contract with South Korean automaker Ssangyong Motor Company, AAM will produce RDMs and IFDAs for multiple new vehicle programs beginning in late 2005.
WE ARE EXPANDING ENGINEERING AND APPLIED TECHNOLOGY
AAM’s applied technology capability became a catalyst for attracting new business this past year. AAM engineers at our World Headquarters in Detroit, Michigan, our Technical Center in Rochester Hills, Michigan and our new technical/business office in Puné, India keep design and development going around the clock. We have also been proactive in applying AAM technology in innovative ways that are drawing interest from OEMs such as The Chrysler Group, whose all-new Dodge Ram Power Wagon includes AAM’s first electronically controlled SmartBarTM vehicle stabilizer system and TracRite® electronic locking differentials.
WE CONTINUE TO GROW AND ENHANCE OUR OPERATIONS
AAM is in the process of evolving our Metal Formed Products Division from basic steel procurement and forging of raw steel to the use of advanced processes and the production of precision-finish machined and heat treated components.
We have completed the initial phase of construction of our AAM facility in Araucária, Brazil. In addition, we have initiated the third major expansion of our Guanajuato manufacturing facilities in Silao, Mexico.
At our South Campus in Detroit, continued renovations and expansion enabled us to centralize three important AAM disciplines in the newly created Process Development Center, Quality Engineering Technical Center (QETC) and AAM Training Center.
AAM QUALITY CONTINUES
TO BE A DIFFERENTIATOR
We achieved Six Sigma quality performance (3.4 or less discrepant parts per million), as measured by our largest customer, in April, June and November of 2004. The introduction of new programs, such as Robust Engineering with its focus on variation reduction, will help us continue to meet and exceed our customers’ quality and warranty expectations.
WE ARE MANAGING FACTORS THAT AFFECT OUR BUSINESS
Major challenges for the year included an uncertain and softening market for domestic OEM vehicle production volumes and increased costs associated with the highest steel and metal prices in decades.
Countering rising commodity prices — While we cannot control global economic supply and demand, we are leveraging our strong position in the marketplace to protect continuity of supply and secure the lowest possible prices for our metal market commodities.
THIS I
                The first 10 years.
1994
• March 1 — AAM opens for business with five U.S.
       A decade of progress and manufacturing facilities purchased from GM
profitable growth
AAMilestones
• With new leadership, a new corporate culture is developed focusing on manufacturing excellence and productivity
• AAM begins to diversify its customer base with a contract to supply ZF with net-shaped gears for Mercedes-Benz SUVs
 4
  
Over the past five years, we have identified alternative sources of supply and validated new steel sources in countries such as Brazil, Italy, Mexico and South Korea.
Constructive labor negotiations — AAM reached new, four- year national agreements with the United Auto Workers (UAW) and the International Association of Machinists (IAM), which became effective on March 8, 2004 and May 17, 2004, respectively. The UAW and IAM contracts, covering approximately 6,700 AAM associates in North America, represent a mutual effort to address structural changes in the industry with solutions that improve AAM’s competitiveness and flexibility.
OUR FOCUS IS ON THE FUTURE
The pages of this annual report illustrate the qualities that helped create and continue to define American Axle & Manufacturing. Today and moving forward, AAM is:
■ A company that knows who it is: Strong, disciplined, sustainable and Detroit-based with high-technology products, world-class quality, delivery and value as our differentiators.
■ A company that knows where it is going: Where our customers are, where there is profitable growth and where new markets exist for our advanced and innovative technology products.
■ A company that has the right strategy for getting there: Diversify, profitably grow and expand our efforts to continue our
global growth.
■ A company that performs at the highest level of financial discipline and integrity, in full compliance with the Sarbanes-Oxley Act
of 2002.
In 2005 and beyond, we will continue to seek creative solutions to global business challenges. We will lead the way with solutions that add value for our customer base. Our strategy for ongoing profitable
growth includes expanding our market share in North America and South America through new opportunities with domestic and transplant OEMs. We will strengthen commercial and technical relationships with European and Asian OEMs and continue to investigate opportunities for further global growth.
THIS IS AAM!
As a company, AAM is only as strong as the people whose spirit, energy and teamwork drive it. We are proud to participate in the communities in which our facilities are located.
I would like to thank all of the dedicated men and women who led our company through its first decade so successfully. Your knowledge, integrity, work ethic, productivity and creativity provide AAM with the basis to compete in this globally competitive environment.
I would also like to thank our stockholders for your ongoing trust, support and investment. We will continue working to enhance stockholder value as we pursue our strategic objectives.
It is most fulfilling and satisfying to have AAM’s strength, commitment and values showing through daily at our new World Headquarters, which we dedicated on July 23, 2004. AAM is proud to be part of the city that is the epicenter of the global automotive industry.
Strong, dedicated and here to stay. We continue to press forward with our vision and strategy to ensure a sustainable, profitable future for AAM.
This is who we are. This is what we do. This is AAM!
Richard E. Dauch
Co-Founder, Chairman of the Board & Chief Executive Officer
 S AAM
  1995
• The AAM
Technical Center opens in Rochester Hills, Michigan
• A $20 million paint facility opens at Buffalo Gear & Axle
• AAM expands its product portfolio with aluminum and metal matrix composites as alternatives for driveshaft manufacturing
1996
• AAM earns the driveline system program for
GM’s new full-size trucks and SUVs
• TracRite® traction-enhancing differentials are
added to the AAM product portfolio
• The ongoing $2 billion facility and machinery
upgrade process brings AAM operations to
world-class levels
• AAM's R&D efforts lead to a new generation of
I-RideTM rear suspension modules (RSMs)
1997
• Recapitalization
paves the way for AAM to expand its global footprint
• AAM establishes its Asia Pacific Business Office in Tokyo, Japan
• AAM is awarded the driveline system program for GM’s all-new mid-size SUVs
  AAM ANNUAL REPORT 2004 5
!
    