 Kenneth I. Chenault
Chairman and
Chief Executive Officer
To our shareholders:
In many ways, 2001 was one of the most challenging years American Express has seen in its 151-year history. During the first half of the year, we were confronted with a weakening economy, depressed equity markets, historically high default rates for high-yield securities and a sharp slowdown in spending by Corporate Cardmembers. This was followed by the ter- rorist attacks of September 11, which led to even sharper slowdowns in corporate and consumer spending, business
travel and investment activity.

 axp_5
Together, these issues had a profound negative impact on nearly every aspect of our card, travel and financial services businesses. The impact was evident in many of the business indicators I will discuss later in this report. It was also evident in three significant items:
❚ A first-half charge of $1.01 billion pretax ($669 million after-tax), reflecting write downs in the investment portfolio held by American Express Financial Advisors (AEFA) and losses associated with rebalancing the portfolio toward lower-risk securities;
❚ Restructuring charges in the third and fourth quarters, totaling $631 mil- lion pretax ($411 million after-tax), primarily to cover the cost of reducing our workforce. In combination with reductions identified earlier in the year, we are reducing our staffing levels by approximately 16 percent or 14,500 jobs; and
❚ The one-time costs and business interruption losses of $98 million pretax ($65 million after-tax) resulting from the September 11 attacks.
As a result, our financial performance in 2001 fell far short of our long-term targets of 12 to 15 percent growth in earnings per share, return on equity of 18 to 20 percent and revenue growth of 8 percent, on average and over time:
❚ Net income was $1.31 billion, down 53 percent from $2.81 billion in 2000. Diluted earnings per share declined 53 percent to $0.98 from $2.07.
❚ Net revenues on a managed basis totaled $21.4 billion, down 3 percent from $22.1 billion in 2000.
❚ Return on equity was 10.9 percent, compared with 25.3 percent in 2000.
The factors cited above also contributed to a decline in our share price. Total shareholder return for 2001 declined 34 percent relative to 2000, exceeding the percentage declines of both the S&P 500 (down 12 percent) and the S&P Financials (down 9 percent).
Following the losses in our high-yield portfolio and the decision to take the third quarter restructuring charge, we suspended our share repurchase program. This action helped us maintain our capital position. No share repurchases are antic- ipated for approximately the first half of 2002.
TOTAL RETURN TO SHAREHOLDERS
Cumulative Value of $100 invested on December 31, 1996
❚ American Express
❚ S&P financial index ❚ S&P 500 index
$350
$300
$250
$200
$150
$100
$197.14 $197.10
$166.24
  96 97 98 99 00 01
In 2001, total shareholder return declined 34 percent, exceeding the percentage declines of both the S&P Financial Index and the S&P 500 Index. For the past five years, American Express’ cumulative return to shareholders outper- formed the S&P Financials and the S&P 500.
 
axp_6
On an absolute basis, we are disappointed with our 2001 results. Our relative performance, however, was generally in line with that of our competitors, par- ticularly diversified financial companies and financial services firms. Several key business indicators – notably lending balances, consumer billings and earn- ings from our financial services business (excluding high-yield losses and related charges) – compared well with those of relevant industry peers, demon- strating our solid competitive position.
 We are re:engineeringour business, becoming less dependent on a robust economy to deliver our targeted earnings.
 While the disappointment in our financial results cannot be minimized, 2001 was also a year of significant accomplishments for the company. We did not merely weather the storm. We took decisive action in making a series of fun- damental changes that strengthened our position for the long term. In fact, as a result of these measures, I believe we are now in a stronger position than we have been over the last several years.
Transforming Our Business
To understand the transformation at American Express, it is helpful to look back at how we generated our financial results over the past decade. During the early to mid 1990s, our earnings growth was heavily dependent upon expense reduc- tion, with low revenue growth. By the late 1990s, we had changed that dynamic. By focusing on expanding our core businesses, we delivered revenue growth rates ranging from 10 to 13 percent, and our earnings were at the high end of our target range. During that period, however, we also benefited from strong and consistent economic growth. We recognized that we could not rely on such a favorable environment for the long term, so we began to strengthen our busi-
   
 axp_7
 ness models and reduce expense levels to lessen our dependence on strong market conditions. In 2001, we accelerated these efforts to build even more flexibility into our business.
As a result of these actions, we are now less dependent on revenue growth to deliver our targeted earnings. This is critical, given that we face a tougher environment in the near term, and our businesses are not immune or counter- cyclical to weaker economic conditions.
That said, with the measures we have taken, we are well positioned to take full advantage of an upturn in the economy when it does occur. In short, we are confident that American Express is positioned to grow, even in a more uncer- tain economic environment. Therefore, we believe our long-term financial targets remain appropriate.
In addition to reengineering our business and reducing expenses, we took two additional steps during 2001 to position American Express for success in the future:
❚ We substantially lowered the company’s overall risk profile. We did this by rebalancing and decreasing the exposure in AEFA’s high-yield investment portfolio, ensuring strong reserve ratios for our card businesses, adding to the reserves related to credit exposures for merchants in the travel industry, and significantly shifting American Express Bank’s (AEB) loan exposure away from corporate lending to consumer activities; and
❚ We targeted resources on growth opportunities in the global payments and retail financial services markets and made a series of strategic investments to take advantage of these opportunities.
I’ll describe these actions in greater detail later, but first let’s review our business unit results for the year.
Business Unit Results
TRAVEL RELATED SERVICES
Travel Related Services (TRS) – which includes our card, travel, merchant and network businesses, as well as our Travelers Cheque Group – reported net income for 2001 of $1.46 billion, down 24 percent from $1.93 billion in the prior year. Excluding TRS’ portion of the restructuring charges and September 11-
4%
REBALANCING RISK
  12%
In light of deteriorating market conditions, American Express substantially lowered its risk profile by rebalancing the invest- ment portfolio at American Express Financial Advisors — reducing the percentage of high- yield securities to approximately 4 percent, from 12 percent. Going forward, the company plans to work toward a level that is more in line with the industry average of approximately 7 percent.
 
 axp_8
related charges, the unit’s net income for the full year would have been $1.78 billion, down 8 percent from last year.
TRS’ net revenues rose 4 percent in 2001, as growth in loans and fee revenues were partly offset by a 16 percent decline in travel commissions and fees. Billed business, or the total amount spent on American Express® Cards, was up slightly in 2001 as higher consumer card spending in the retail and “everyday” cate- gories was largely offset by lower Corporate Card spending in the travel and entertainment sector, particularly after September 11. Net finance charge rev- enues rose 32 percent, due to growth in loan balances and wider net interest yields. This increase reflected a smaller percentage of loan balances on intro- ductory rates and the benefit of declining interest rates during the year. Travel sales declined 24 percent due to the effects of the September 11 terrorist attacks and the weaker corporate travel environment.
TRS’ provision for losses grew faster than its receivables largely as a result of an increase in U.S. lending write-off rates and delinquencies, reflecting higher unemployment and the overall economic environment.
AMERICAN EXPRESS FINANCIAL ADVISORS
AEFA reported net income for 2001 of $52 million, down from $1.03 billion a year ago. Excluding its portion of the restructuring charges and the one-time September 11 charges, AEFA’s net income would have been $130 million, down 87 percent from last year. Reflected in these results were the previously men- tioned charges to write down high-yield securities and rebalance the risk profile of AEFA’s investment portfolio.
AEFA’s net revenues for 2001 decreased 33 percent to $2.8 billion, reflecting weakness in equity markets and narrower spreads in the investment portfolio. The weakened equity markets led to lower asset levels and lower sales of investment products. As a result, assets owned, managed and administered declined 8 percent to $253.3 billion. Management and distribution fees fell 13 percent. Mutual fund sales, including proprietary and non-proprietary funds,
$300
$275
$250
$225
$200
$253.3
AMERICAN EXPRESS FINANCIAL ADVISORS ASSETS OWNED, MANAGED OR ADMINISTERED (in billions)
  98 99 00 01
Throughout 2001, weak equity markets led to lower asset levels and lower sales of investment products. As a result, assets owned, managed or administered by American Express Financial Advisors declined 8 percent.
 
axp_9
decreased 24 percent and sales of our annuity products decreased 4 percent. Net new money flowing into managed accounts continued to remain positive, however, despite the difficult economic environment.
AMERICAN EXPRESS BANK
AEB reported a 2001 net loss of $13 million in 2001, compared with net income of $29 million a year ago. Excluding its portion of the restructuring charges, AEB’s net income would have been $52 million, up 82 percent from the prior year.
The Bank’s results for 2001 reflect a 10 percent growth in revenues, which were driven by higher net interest income, as well as higher foreign exchange and other revenue. These improvements were partially offset by lower commissions and fees. AEB’s results benefited from lower funding costs and lower operat- ing expenses that resulted from ongoing reengineering efforts. However, these benefits were offset in part by higher provisions for losses, primarily due to higher personal loan volumes.
The Bank’s overall results were driven by strong performance in both the Personal Financial Services (PFS) and Private Banking groups, which together accounted for 46 percent of AEB’s total 2001 net revenue, compared with 37 percent in 2000. Private Banking client holdings rose 19 percent and client volumes in PFS increased 9 percent. The Private Bank’s client holdings stood at $12.4 billion at year-end.
Improving the Company’s Competitive Position
Earlier, I referred to three major initiatives: strengthening our business models, lowering our risk profile, and investing in key growth opportunities. Let me now explain how these initiatives are improving our competitive position for the future.
STRENGTHENING BUSINESS MODELS
Our efforts to improve margins are not focused on fixing weakness. Instead, they are focused on strengthening the performance of our businesses and pro- viding greater flexibility so that we are less dependent on a robust economic
   
axp_10
environment to deliver earnings growth. To this end, we have made significant progress in a number of key areas:
WE HAVE EXPANDED THE DIVERSITY OF OUR CARD-SPENDING BASE. While the traditional travel and entertainment category remains an important driver of revenue, we have significantly increased the use of our cards for everyday spending at such places as gas stations, supermarkets, retailers, as well as for telecommunications. During periods of economic weakness, consumers tend to maintain their level of spending in these industries, even while cutting back on travel and entertainment. Our increased presence in these sectors enables us to produce more stable charge volume.
Over the past ten years, we also have significantly expanded the roster of mer- chants who accept our card products. In 1990, 65 percent of our billings came from the travel and entertainment sectors and 35 percent from retail and other sectors. Today that proportion is essentially reversed; everyday spending now accounts for about 60 percent of the business billed on American Express Cards.
US CARD SPENDING
Charge Volume by Industry
❚ Retail and Other ❚ T&E Related
35%
65%
40%
  1990
2001
The use of American Express Cards for “everyday” spending at places such as gas stations, supermarkets, retailers and
for telecommunications has increased to 60 percent of total U.S. billings, up from only 35 percent a decade ago.
60%
 We are re:positioning American Express for long-term, sustainable growth.
 Our progress in this area continued during 2001 with the signings of several key merchants outside the travel and entertainment industries, including Pathmark Supermarkets, REI (sporting goods), PayPal (online payment service) and Qwest Communications International Inc. in the United States. Internationally, our signings included Singapore Telecom and Arrow Pharmaceuticals in France.
In our commercial card business, we are also making a shift to reduce our reliance on travel and entertainment spending with the expansion of our Corporate Purchasing Card program for large and middle market companies.
   
 axp_11
As is the case with consumer spending, companies tend to continue purchasing everyday goods and services (such as office and industrial supplies, computer equipment and software) during tough economic times, while tightening their belts on discretionary business travel and entertainment expenses.
WE HAVE DIVERSIFIED OUR PRODUCT PORTFOLIO AND GROWN OUR CARD LENDING BUSINESS. Sincelate1994,whenwesetoursightsonaggres- sively expanding our credit card business, our lending balance growth has been among the top tier of issuers. Today, about 19 percent of our U.S. card billings come from our lending products, as compared with just 4 percent in 1995. This change in product mix has shifted our overall card revenue base and helped to make it less volatile. Revenues from our charge card products are derived from current spending and are more sensitive to short-term economic swings. Lending products, on the other hand, produce revenues as customers build up loan balances and pay them down over time. When credit exposure is managed prudently, the interest revenue from these products tends to be a less volatile source of earnings.
At year-end 2001, our worldwide lending balances on a managed basis were more than $36 billion, up 14 percent from 2000. With $32 billion of receivables in the United States, our growth rate continued to exceed that of most of our competitors.
Much of this growth has been due to the breadth of our lending products – such as our popular Blue from American ExpressSM – and to the value we provide our cardmembers. We have also increased the number of charge cardmembers who are taking advantage of our “lending on charge” options such as Sign & Travel®, when they occasionally choose to revolve.
WE HAVE ACCELERATED OUR REENGINEERING INITIATIVES THROUGH- OUT THE COMPANY. Thereengineeringactionswetookduring2001enabled us to deliver more than $1 billion in gross realized benefits during the year.
The benefits generated by these initiatives serve not only to support earnings but also to establish the foundation for sustainable, long-term growth. Thus, while a portion of the savings from reengineering has gone into improving our
in 2001 19%
U.S. BILLINGS ON
  4%
in 1995
About 19 percent of total U.S. spending on American Express Cards last year was on one of the company’s revolving credit card products. Attractive terms and cobrand relationships have helped to raise this amount from only 4 percent in 1995.
REVOLVING CREDIT CARDS
 
 axp_12
operating margins, we are also investing some of these savings in growth oppor- tunities. These include investments in new products, customer acquisition and more efficient technology platforms that will help employees do their jobs and service our customers more effectively.
Reengineering has been an integral part of the way we conduct business for many years now. Our experience has shown that – to achieve sustainable improvements – reengineering must extend beyond cost cutting. It must also include initiatives that increase revenues, improve infrastructure and enhance processes. Over the past several years, we have implemented hun- dreds of such initiatives.
For instance, on the revenue side, our U.S. customer service representatives have, for some time, had success in cross-selling appropriate products and serv- ices to cardmembers who call into our service centers. During 2001, we reengineered this process to increase the productivity of our representatives, resulting in an overall sales increase of 60 percent.
We continue to harness the power of the Internet to reduce costs, improve processes and enhance customer service across our businesses. Internally, processes such as employee benefits enrollment, expense
management and business travel reservations are now being
handled online. Externally, we continue to support and deliver
a vast array of online tools to help all of our customers effec- tively manage their relationships with American Express. In fact, we now handle more U.S. card customer service transactions on the Internet than we do by phone, mail or in person.
An example of this is American Express @ Work®, our desktop
portal that helps our business customers manage their Corporate
Card and Corporate Purchasing Card programs online. Just two years
after its launch in the United States, American Express @ Work now
handles more than half of all our commercial card maintenance transac- tions. About 85 percent of all management reports are now delivered electronically. In 2001, we expanded American Express @ Work internation- ally, and it is now offered to companies in 20 countries. With Internet usage
American Express @ Work has transformed the way companies manage their Corporate Card and Purchasing Card programs. By moving daily administrative tasks online, this tool significantly reduces time and costs for cus-
tomers and for American Express.
  
axp_13
more than tripling among our clients, this transformation has improved cus- tomer satisfaction while simultaneously reducing expenses.
Elsewhere, we are using the Internet to enhance merchant transactions with American Express. New online services introduced in 2001 have streamlined billings and provided merchants with a greater
ability to access and update their accounts over the Internet.
Our online services are faster and less expensive – both for mer- chants and for American Express.
The Internet also is a powerful and cost-effective tool for acquiring new customers. During 2001, 16 percent of all new cardmembers in the United States were acquired online.
WE HAVE ENHANCED OUR REWARDS PROGRAMS AND FORMED NEW PARTNERSHIPS WITH LEADING-EDGE COMPANIES. Our industry-leading Membership Rewards® loyalty program continues to be a strong driver of card- member retention and profitability. While it is already the largest program of its kind, with more than 9 million participants worldwide, we still have a sig- nificant opportunity to grow our base.
While focusing on increasing the number of cardmembers enrolled in Membership Rewards, we have also worked to reduce the costs associated with the program. For example, we have enabled cardmembers to handle many pro- gram-related activities, such as point redemption, online. We have also expanded rewards opportunities beyond travel to the retail and online sectors. More than 700 partners now participate in our program worldwide. The broader range of redemption choices has improved customer satisfaction and lowered our overall rewards costs.
Our rewards program is just one example of how we partner with other com- panies to improve the value that we offer to our customers. Other examples include our partnerships with Delta Air Lines and Costco. The cobrand cards we offer with these partners have added millions of highly profitable cardmembers to our base over the past several years. We are also seeing strong results from our partnership with British Airways, which led to the 2001 launch of three new cobrand credit cards for British Airways UK Executive Club members.
  Membership Rewards, American Express’ industry-leading loyalty program, has more than 9 million participants worldwide and is a strong driver of cardmember retention and profitability. Reward points can now be redeemed at more than 700 participating partners worldwide.
  
 axp_14
Partnerships also play a role in our efforts to expand the network of merchants who accept the Card. Working with JCB Co., Ltd., the largest card issuer and merchant acquirer in Japan, allowed us to expand significantly American Express’ merchant coverage in that country. Our relationship with JCB
also provides for reciprocal card acceptance, merchant acquisition and merchant processing in Japan, as well as in Australia, Canada, India, Mexico and New Zealand.
The importance of partnerships to American Express extends to Corporate Travel as well. Early in 2002, we partnered with China International Travel Services in announcing the first Sino-U.S. corporate travel joint venture in the People’s Republic of China. We also announced a Corporate Travel joint ven- ture in Italy – UVET American Express Corporate Travel. At its launch in January 2002, the company was the largest corporate travel agency in Italy.
In our retail financial services business, a new partnership with Costco offers our auto and homeowners insurance to Costco members in 22 U.S. states.
For many years, partnerships have been at the heart of our oldest business, the Travelers Cheque Group. In 2001, as a result of our agreement with Citicorp Services, Inc. to convert their distributors to American Express, we achieved the largest new seller signing in the history of our Travelers Cheque business. Further expanding our potential sales volume are our agreements with HSBC, which began selling our products globally in early 2002, U.S. Bancorp, Australia Post and Rabobank in the Netherlands. And, with the recent addition of JTB and Nippon Travel Agency, Japan’s top five travel agents now sell American Express® Travelers Cheques.
WE HAVE TRANSFORMED AND STRENGTHENED OUR CORPORATE TRAVEL B U S I N E S S . We have substantially improved the economics of our Corporate Travel business. As in other areas of the company, we moved many of our business processes and customer servicing online. The percentage of Corporate Travel reservations processed online in 2001 increased fivefold. This shift lowered our costs while providing clients faster, better service.
A new partnership with British
Airways led to the introduction of three new cobrand cards — each with its own level of rewards and benefits — to British Airways UK Executive Club members.
  
 axp_15
We also transformed the economics of this business by making a fundamental change in the source of our revenue. Traditionally, we earned our fees from com- missions paid by suppliers such as airlines or hotels. Starting in the mid 1990s, however, the airlines sharply reduced their commission rates. In response, we redesigned the business and now rely on customers to pay transaction fees for our travel services, rather than having our revenue based on commissions from sup- pliers. In 2001, 70 percent of our travel revenues came from customer fees and only 30 percent from suppliers. A few years ago the mix was just the opposite.
These changes enabled us to manage successfully through one of the toughest years in recent history for travel, while operating the business profitably. We also took advantage of the downturn in travel to step up our sales efforts. We finished the year with an impressive list of new travel clients, including Aventis in the United States, Jaguar Cars Limited and Land Rover UK in the United Kingdom, Ford in Latin America, Philips in Taiwan and PepsiCo Europe and Xerox in Europe. Worldwide, we now handle corporate travel for more than 50,000 companies.
 We are re:balancingthe company’s overall risk-reward profile.
 LOWERING RISK PROFILE
As I stated earlier, the second major step we took to improve the company’s long-term position was to decrease our overall risk profile:
AT AMERICAN EXPRESS FINANCIAL ADVISORS, WE HAVE SUBSTANTIALLY REDUCED OUR EXPOSURE TO HIGH-YIELD INVESTMENTS AND UPGRADED THE QUALITY OF OUR HIGH-YIELD BONDS. Over the past several years, we had a larger percentage of high-yield investments in our portfolio than was the insurance industry norm. While these investments had provided excellent
   
 axp_16
returns for many years, we did not anticipate the full effect that the economic downturn, coupled with the worst high-yield default rate in many years, would have on our portfolio. Given our loss experience, as well as our view that the default rates would continue to be high for some time, we took decisive action to rebalance the portfolio’s risk-reward profile.
We sold or wrote down specific investments and repositioned our portfolio toward lower-risk securities. We continued our risk reduction efforts through- out 2001, thereby decreasing our level of high-yield securities to approximately 4 percent of AEFA’s $34 billion investment portfolio. This is down from 12 per- cent at the end of 2000. Going forward, we plan to work toward a level that is more in line with the industry average of approximately 7 percent.
AT AMERICAN EXPRESS BANK, WE HAVE SIGNIFICANTLY SHIFTED OUR LOAN EXPOSURE.Inrecentyearswehaveincreasinglymovedawayfrom the corporate banking business toward more broad-based consumer activities. As a result, we had less than $1 billion in corporate loans at year-end 2001, down from $3.1 billion in 1997. During the same period, our Personal Financial Services and Private Banking loans grew to $3.2 billion from $1.4 billion, or 60 percent of total loans, up from 22 percent. Despite the deterioration in many economies around the world, non-performing loans at AEB have been well controlled.
IN TRAVEL RELATED SERVICES, WE ADDRESSED BOTH INDUSTRY- WIDE DETERIORATION IN CREDIT QUALITY AND THE GROWING RISK RELATED TO MERCHANT BANKRUPTCIES. Within our U.S. charge card and lending portfolios, we have maintained our coverage ratios at the higher end of our reserve range. We also increased our reserve coverage of total receivables and loans and coverage of past due balances in excess of 100 percent. To reduce the risk associated with merchant bankruptcies in a difficult economy – par- ticularly in the travel industry where merchants may be paid by American Express prior to rendering the actual services to cardmembers – we hold reserves to cover this exposure where appropriate. In some cases, we have insti- tuted annual fees or lengthened the time between when the card charges are submitted to us and when we pay the merchant.
AMERICAN EXPRESS BANK LOANS
(in billions)
$7
$6.2
$6
$5
$4
$3
$2
$1
$5.3 $5.3
     97 00 01
50% 34% 18% 28% 25% 22% 22% 41% 60%
❚ Corporate and Other
❚ Financial Institutions
❚ PFS and Private Banking
American Express Bank continued to grow its lending to individuals while decreasing its corporate loan portfolio.
 
axp_17
INVESTING IN KEY GROWTH OPPORTUNITIES
The events of 2001 forced us to take a more critical look at our future growth opportunities. Like many other companies, we had to reprioritize our invest- ment spending and make difficult trade-offs. As a result, we have identified opportunities in our core businesses that offer the potential for the highest lev- els of return and the greatest chances of success. In particular, there are three areas that we think can provide sustainable growth for American Express over the short, moderate and long terms.
EXPANDING OUR CARD BUSINESS IN INTERNATIONAL MARKETS
In the consumer, small business and commercial card areas, we are investing significant resources in a number of key international markets. Many countries have much lower charge and credit card usage rates than those in the United States, and we believe the opportunities for growth in those countries will be substantial for the foreseeable future.
Over the past couple of years – despite economic downturns in some regions – we have significantly grown our business in many international markets. This is due largely to the introduction of new products and the creation of new alliances. While we have made good progress, our presence in many markets is still relatively small, providing us with significant additional potential for expanding our business.
Our total number of cards in force outside the United States rose to 20.6 mil- lion, up from 18.4 million a year earlier. This is a 12 percent increase for the year. International loan receivables grew by 32 percent during the year. Importantly, our credit quality has remained strong, despite economic pressures in many countries.
We launched a number of new consumer card products in international markets during 2001, including Blue from American Express in Australia, Austria, France and Germany. In addition to the British Airways products cited earlier, we launched cobrand cards with Indian Airlines, Accor in Germany and a small busi- ness card with Australia’s Westpac Bank. In total, we launched proprietary charge and credit products in 14 countries, as well as 41 affinity card products and 30 dis- tribution agreements.
  
axp_18
In the commercial card area, we continue to be the recognized leader around the world for helping companies manage their travel, entertainment and purchas- ing expenses. Worldwide, we have card relationships with more than 100,000 firms, and the total keeps growing. For example, we introduced our Corporate Purchasing Card in a number of key international markets, signing on as clients Pfizer in the United Kingdom, Nortel Networks in Latin America, and Dupont in Singapore and Hong Kong.
Since 1997, when we launched our Global Network Services (GNS) business, scores of banks and other institutions outside the United States have partnered with us to issue cards on the American Express network. We have expanded this business from a handful of independent operators to a robust business of 74 partners in nearly 80 countries. Network cards in force have grown at an annual rate of nearly 40 percent since 1997, while spending growth on
these cards has risen more than fourfold during that period. The growth
of GNS also has helped us dramatically accelerate merchant coverage, with almost 1.9 million new service establishments added to our network as a result of the partnerships that we have established. Among the new network partners signed during 2001 were Union Bank Limited in Pakistan, HSBC and Scotiabank Quilmes in Argentina, and Unibanca in Venezuela.
Early in 2002, we announced an agreement with Canada’s leading credit card issuer, Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce (CIBC), which became the first Canadian bank to offer both American Express and Visa credit cards to its cus- tomers. CIBC is issuing a suite of American Express-branded credit cards, including Canada’s first smart chip credit card available nationally. This agree- ment represents our first card-issuing partnership in Canada and is an important step toward expanding our brand presence in that country. It also reconfirms our experience around the world by demonstrating that major banks, including Visa and MasterCard issuers, will choose to partner with American Express when they are free to do so.
GROWING OUR CARD BUSINESS IN THE UNITED STATES
The use of charge and credit cards in the United States is significantly higher than it is in international markets. Nevertheless, there is a large opportunity for growth by continuing to expand the number and variety of places where cards
 American Express continued to expand its international presence by forming partnerships with banks and other financial institutions that issue cards on its network. We now have 74 partners in 77 countries. Among the new cards launched recently was a suite of American Express-branded credit cards issued by the Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce (CIBC).
  
axp_19
can be used. American Express stands prepared to capture a significant share of that new spending.
Over the past several years, we have made steady progress in our U.S. con- sumer card business, particularly in two areas cited earlier – growing our lending business and introducing new products.
We are also focusing on expanding our relationships with existing cardmem- bers by cross-selling other products and services. One example is in the Consumer Travel area where we are testing a variety of new programs, such as rebates to cardmembers for certain vacations purchased at participating American Express Travel Service locations. In addition, we are strengthening the appeal of our premium products – the Centurion Card® and Platinum Card® – through partnerships with upscale merchants such as Neiman Marcus, Sony and Equinox Fitness Clubs.
 OPEN: The Small Business NetworkSM signals our broadened commitment to helping small business owners succeed. We are introducing new products and services and expanding
our Internet offerings to meet the servicing needs of U.S. small business owners.
 We are re:investingsavings
from our reengineering initiatives into growth opportunities.
 Serving small businesses is another key growth area opportunity. Small businesses create three out of every four new jobs in the United States and are an important engine of the U.S. economy. Serving this sector has been a very successful, high-growth business for American Express. In 1987, American Express launched the first charge card specifically designed for small busi- nesses. Since then, we have become the leading card issuer to this segment, and over the past five years have grown to be one of the top lenders as well. Today, we serve nearly 3 million small business customers.
     
 axp_20
In early 2002, we took steps to strengthen our competitive position by intro- ducing a new set of products, services, customer communications and partnerships. We also are increasing our focus on the Internet to meet the serv- icing needs of small business owners. As part of this transformation, we adopted a new name – OPEN: The Small Business NetworkSM – and introduced a national advertising campaign to signal our broadened commitment to helping small business owners succeed. The campaign underscored the greater control over payment and financing that we provide customers.
In the commercial card area, we serve about 70 percent of the Fortune 500 U.S. companies. We have a strong presence among middle-market companies (those with revenues of $10 million to $1 billion), where the potential for expan- sion remains quite high. In an environment in which companies are increasingly tightening expenses, we have increased signings of new commer- cial card customers who recognize more than ever the value of expense management solutions. These accounts represent significant potential for us once the economy stabilizes and corporate spending increases.
During 2001, we added or expanded a number of Corporate Card relationships with companies in the United States, including Prudential, Invensys, Apple Computer, Inc., Delta Air Lines and EDS/AT Kearney, as well as about 7,000 mid- sized companies. We signed ADP, Delta and BP, among others, as Corporate Purchasing Card clients. We also announced a collaborative effort with Oracle to ensure interoperability between our Corporate Purchasing Card and Oracle’s iProcurement solution.
It is particularly noteworthy that, in October, a federal court ruled in favor of the U.S. Department of Justice and found that Visa and MasterCard had violated the country’s antitrust laws. The judge’s opinion found that the associations’ rules prohibiting banks from issuing American Express-branded cards in the United States were illegal, harmed consumers and American Express, and sti- fled innovation and competition. We are very pleased with the judge’s decision.
However, we were disappointed, but not surprised, by the stay of judgment granted to Visa and MasterCard pending appeal. The U.S. District Court judge reiterated that she is “fully confident” in her initial ruling, stating that the asso- ciations’ bylaws “have had a significant adverse effect on competition and
The use of purchasing cards by corporations to buy office supplies and equipment is growing. With the introduction of American Express’ Corporate Purchasing Card in Spain and Switzerland during 2001, the product is now used by corporations in 25 countries around the world.
   
 axp_21
consumer welfare.” We agree, and are confident that the decision will be upheld on appeal, although that process will take some time. We look forward to con- ducting our GNS business in the United States as we do in the rest of the world. That said, our ability to achieve our long-term financial targets is not predicated on U.S. banks being able to issue cards on our network.
GROWING RETAIL FINANCIAL SERVICES
As part of our long-term vision, we aim to make American Express as well known and successful in financial services as we are in the card and travel busi- nesses. Toward this goal, we are leveraging the strengths of our various financial services businesses in order to expand our customer base and increase our share of the market for global consumer financial services.
AEFA continues to be one of the premier financial planning companies in the United States, providing an excellent foundation upon which to build our finan- cial services business. Unlike many of our competitors, whose field forces typically comprise brokers who focus on completing transactions, many of our advisors are Certified Financial Planners who work closely with clients to develop long-term financial strategies. As a result, AEFA has an outstanding client retention rate of 94 percent. In fact, our redemption rates continue to compare favorably with industry levels, even in the difficult environment of 2001. Not only do our clients stay with us, but they tend to take a long-term view of investing.
Moving forward, AEFA’s strategy for growth is focused on two overriding strate- gic initiatives: to strengthen our premier retail distribution network and to develop world-class asset management capabilities. Within these strategic ini- tiatives, we are focusing on a number of key areas:
❚ CONTINUING TO ENHANCE THE PRODUCTIVITY OF ADVISORS: Advisors can select from three ways of affiliating with American Express – as AEFA employees, as American Express-branded independent contractors, or as non-branded independent contractors affiliated with our Securities America subsidiary. During 2001, we refined the “multiple platform” system in several ways. As part of our platform restructuring and in light of market conditions, we reduced our employee advisor population by 20 percent and we tightened our hiring criteria so that we more effectively select those applicants with the
  
axp_22
highest chance of success. At the same time, we strengthened our relationship with our branded independent contractor advisors. In fact, the retention rate for veteran advisors reached an all-time high in 2001, and we currently have more than 700 candidates in our pre-appointment pipeline.
We continue to invest considerably in developing tools and training for
our advisors to bolster their ability to offer solid advice and state-of-the-
art financial plans. The payoff for us is significant. During 2001, nearly
44 percent of new clients had a financial plan that we developed with them. As has been the case historically, our clients with plans tend to buy more products. In 2001, product sales generated through financial planning and advice services were 73 percent of total sales, compared with 68 percent dur- ing the prior year.
❚ GROWING OUR CLIENT BASE: To gain a larger percentage of affluent con- sumers as clients, we developed American Express Platinum Financial ServicesSM. Through this program, clients receive a variety of premier serv- ices, including a Platinum Card, concierge services, financial planning and advice, banking, investment, insurance and trust services — with one of our advisors acting as an overall relationship manager. We saw strong results from initial tests of the service in 2001, with clients who enrolled investing an aver- age of $250,000 in new money with AEFA. Based on this success, we will begin a national rollout this year.
American Express Platinum Financial Services — a new offer-
We are re:focusingour efforts
to deliver world-class asset management
services.
In addition, we will continue to focus on cross-selling AEFA’s products and services to our cardmember base. In recent years, more than 30 percent of new advisor clients have come from our base of U.S. cardmembers. We can and will do more to significantly increase the number of cardmembers who have a relationship with AEFA. With appropriate segmentation and targeted
     ing targeted to affluent clients — provides a variety of personalized, premium products and services, such as advice on tax-advantaged investing, estate planning, trusts and charitable giving, as well a fee-waived Platinum Card.
  
axp_23
offers, we could substantially add to AEFA’s bottom line even if only 5 to 10 percent of our U.S. cardmembers became AEFA clients.
❚ EXPANDING THE BREADTH OF OUR PRODUCTS AND IMPROVING INVESTMENT PERFORMANCE: We are working diligently in both of these areas, since they have a major impact on our ability to attract and retain clients. During 2001, we introduced 15 new products across our business lines, including six new funds that are sub-advised by leading mutual fund man- agers. In addition, we have been developing an integrated relationship account to enable us to gather a larger share of our clients’ assets, particularly short-term or cash-equivalent investments. We built the initial infrastructure needed to offer FDIC-insured cash accounts with competitive payment capa- bilities and consolidated account reporting. We plan to launch this product early in 2002.
We also took steps to improve the performance of our proprietary products by strengthening our investment talent, including the hiring of a new chief investment officer, research director, head of risk and, early in 2002, adding several new investment managers to our team.
American Express Bank is another key element in our strategy to grow
our retail financial services business. As cited earlier, we have made strong progress in realigning the business of the Bank. We have reduced our cor- porate banking business, while simultaneously growing businesses that serve consumers – Personal Financial Services (PFS) and Private Banking. With the bulk of this reorientation behind us, we are now focused on leveraging the opportunities for cross-selling between AEB and our international payments business to grow international financial services. In 2001, PFS client volumes were up by 9 percent for the year, and more than 55 percent of PFS customers are American Express Cardmembers.
We are also expanding AEB’s reach by partnering with other institutions to sell our mutual funds to their customers. During 2001, AEB signed more than 50 third-party distribution agreements in Europe. We also added our first part- nership of this kind in Hong Kong.
In all, we made many fundamental changes throughout American Express last year. The progress we made in each of our businesses gives us confidence that we are poised to take full advantage of an upturn in the economy.
  American Express Bank offers
a wide array of mutual funds to individual clients outside the United States both directly and, in the case of its Epic Class of American Express Funds, through other financial institutions.
   
axp_24
Remembering September 11
As all of you know, the terrorist attacks stunned the world and left behind a terrible amount of destruction and loss of life. For American Express, the crisis hit close to home. Sadly, 11 of our employees who worked at the World Trade Center died. Many other employees lost family members, friends and neighbors. And thousands of our colleagues who worked
in lower Manhattan had to flee the smoke, debris and ashes that engulfed the area.
As overwhelming as the attacks were, our people went the extra mile to help each other, our clients and our business partners under extremely difficult cir- cumstances. Our colleagues at the Servicing Centers outside of New York City were able to ensure that business operations continued without interruption immediately after the attack. Employees in the New York area who were dis- placed from their offices showed particular resilience as they resumed work despite the difficult conditions. In American Express tradition, our employees demonstrated an unparalleled commitment to customer service.
 American Express reached out to support New York City merchants after the September 11 terrorist attacks. The company’s efforts included launching a series of print and television advertisements promoting downtown establish- ments – reminding consumers that these merchants were “open” for business.
 We are re:affirmingour commitment
to New York City and to lower Manhattan by returning to our headquarters building.
 Our headquarters building, which is located across the street from the World Trade Center, sustained significant damage, and we had to relocate our New York staff to a number of interim facilities. We decided, however, to return to New York. American Express Tower has been our company’s home for 15 years, and our corporate headquarters has been located in lower Manhattan for most of our history. This April, we plan to reestablish our headquarters in the Tower. Doing so reaffirms our commitment to New York City and will help revitalize an important part of the city.
     
axp_25
Employees
Time and time again, our people have proven that they can overcome whatever challenges they are presented. This was clearly the case during 2001 – a year of unprecedented events and difficult business conditions. The creativity and ded- ication that I have seen throughout the year are a key part of our success and will help keep American Express strong, growing and focused on supporting our customers.
On a personal note, I want you to know how proud I am of the people of American Express. As I have often said, our people are our greatest asset. We remain committed to strengthening a workforce that provides strong compet- itive advantage. We measure our progress in this area each year through an employee survey. In 2001, nearly 70,000 employees and financial advisors par- ticipated in the survey, rating the company even higher overall than in past years. We achieved or exceeded our long-term targets in 7 of the 12 dimensions measured, including “employee satisfaction,” which attained an 82 percent favorable rating. To improve our results to the degree we have, in light of the many challenges we faced during the year, as well as the fact that the survey was administered during the weeks surrounding the September 11 disaster, is a significant accomplishment.
The company also continues to be recognized by leading publications as one of the top corporate employers. That public recognition contributes to our efforts to attract employees. Among the publications citing us were Fortune, which ranked American Express among the “100 Best Companies to Work for in America,” “50 Best Companies for Minorities” and the “Top 50 Best Companies for MBAs.” We also appeared on Working Mother’s list of “100 Best Companies for Working Mothers,” Globe & Mail’s “The 35 Best Companies to Work for in Canada,” and The Sunday Times’ “50 Best Companies to Work for in 2001” in the United Kingdom.
Board of Directors
We continue to benefit from the wise counsel and guidance of our Board of Directors. In 2001, we were pleased to welcome to the Board: Ambassador Charlene Barshefsky, Senior International Partner at the law firm of Wilmer, Cutler & Pickering, and former United States Trade Representative, and Peter R. Dolan, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer of Bristol-Myers Squibb Company.
  
axp_26
Summary
We took many fundamental steps to strengthen our business in 2001. While we expect the economy to remain weak this year, we are confident that American Express is in a strong position to grow over the moderate and long term. We have a number of exceptional assets – including our brand, our cus- tomer base, our global presence and creative, dedicated employees – that we can leverage to capitalize on the substantial growth opportunities in global pay- ments and retail financial services. Moreover, we improved the flexibility of our business models, an effort we began a few years ago and dramatically acceler- ated in 2001. This should better position the company to deliver more stable earnings growth, as well as free up funds to invest in growing our core busi- nesses and better prepare us for uncertain times.
American Express has been through difficult periods before. At various times in our history, wars, depressions and natural disasters have dealt severe blows to travel and consumer spending. In every instance, though, we learned to adjust. We strengthened our business. We emerged a better and stronger company. The past year is no exception.
Our brand is strong. Our commitment to customer service is strong. The actions we took in 2001 are helping to ensure that our premium competitive position remains strong. These strengths are as critical today as they have been through- out our 151-year history.
Sincerely,
Kenneth I. Chenault
Chairman and
Chief Executive Officer February 22, 2002
   