   to ouR
ShareholderS
As we begin Fiscal 2013, we are encouraged by both the operational progress we have made and by early signs of a recovery in the u.S. housing market. In fact, both home prices and new home sales have improved markedly in the last 12 months, with Case-Shiller’s 20-city composite index reflecting a 3% increase in home prices in the 12 months ended September 30, 2012, and single-family new home sales up 27% in the same time period.
But, rather than simply waiting for a housing recovery to take hold, we remain intently focused on returning to sustainable profitability by generating operational improvements from our four primary path-to-profitability strategies, including: driving sales per community, leveraging our fixed costs, gradually expanding community count and improving gross margins.
  FISCAl YeAR
2012 results
We delivered significantly improved operational results during Fiscal 2012. new home orders, closings and revenues all grew by double-digit percentages. We also generated positive adjusted eBItDA and demonstrated our ability to meaningfully leverage our fixed costs. these results reflect the tremendous progress we made to improve our internal operations, as well as
a much-welcomed improvement in the overall housing environment. While both the u.S. economy and the housing market continue to face challenges, including the overhang of yet-to-be-determined housing policies, we believe that the worst is behind us, and we are working tirelessly to accelerate our return to profitability.
For Fiscal 2012:
• Adjusted EBITDA increased $46.7 million to $21.8 million;
• New home orders were up 25%;
• Homebuilding revenues grew 40%;
• Home closings increased 36%;
• Homebuilding gross margins, excluding impairments and interest, improved 50 basis points;
• Year-end unrestricted cash increased to $488 million; and
• Total general and administrative expenses as a percentage of revenue
improved more than 700 basis points, to just 10.9% of revenue.
While we are still operating at a loss, primarily due to our interest expense obligations, our net loss from continuing operations per share improved to $7.34 from a loss of $13.53 during Fiscal 2011.
Beazer Homes 2012 AnnuAl RepoRt 1

                          FINANCIAL
HIGHLIGHTS
Financial Summary
Beazer Homes USA, Inc.
(dollars in millions, except for EPS) Year Ended September 30,
Continuing Operations Data Home Orders
Home Closings
Units in Backlog
Total Revenues Net Loss Per Share
2010
Total Controlled Lots as of June 30 , 2012
 4,045 4,421 772 991
2011
3,927 3,249 1,450
$ 742 $(13.53)
2012
4,901 4,428 1,923
$1,006 $ (7.34)
$
$ (2.47)
  OLradsteTrswaenlvdeMClonstihnsgs(LTM)Orders&Closings TotalControlledLotsasofSeptember30,2012
5,500
5,000
4,500
4,000
3,500
3,000
2,500
Immediate Availability
■ Homes Under Construction ■ Finished Lots
Near-Term Availability
■ Lots Under Option
■ Land Under Development
Long-Term and Non-Strategic Assets
■ Land Held for Future Development ■ Property Held for Sale
24,147 total controlled lots as of September 30, 2012
Of our total land inventory, more than 70%, or 17,000 lots, are available for development in the near term. This is an ample supply to meet our Fiscal 2013 objectives. In addition, we are making land investments to fuel growth in Fiscal 2014 and beyond.
                                    Q1F10 Q2F10 Q3F10 Q4F10 Q1F11 Q2F11 Q3F11 Q4F11 Q1F12 Q2F12 Q3F12 Q4F12
Orders Closings Trailing 12 Months
  We achieved positive trends in order and closing growth during Fiscal 2012. This improved performance is evidence of stabilization in the market and reflects our success in driving additional sales per community as we implement our path-to-profitability plan.
  SalesPerrCCoommmunuintyity CLeovsetraLgeeveFrixaegdeCosts
2.75 2.50 2.25 2.00 1.75 1.50
90% 85% 80%
20% 18.5%
16.2%
15% 13.9% 10%
              2.3
2.0 75%
5% 65% 0
11.6%
 2.2
10.9%
     1.9 1.8
70%
   Q4 Q1 Q2 Q3 Q4
FY2011 FY2012
􏲔 Sales per Active Community per Month, Rolling 4 Quarters
— % of Performing Communities (more than 3 sales per quarter), Rolling 4 Quarters
Q4 Q1 Q2 Q3 Q4
FY2011 FY2012
􏲔 Total G&A as % of Total Revenue (LTM)
In Fiscal 2012 we restrained fixed costs even as we closed more homes. This produced significant cost leverage, with total general and administrative costs totaling only 10.9% of revenues for Fiscal 2012.
 Sales per community per month improved 28% in Fiscal 2012. Increasing sales per community, and the percentage of communities that are performing, provide the foundation of our operational improvement efforts.
2 Beazer Homes 2012 ANNUAL REPORT

   CApItAl MARketS
activity
During Fiscal 2012, we took advantage of favorable market conditions to complete a series of capital markets transactions. Collectively, the transactions were intended to improve our capital structure and accelerate our return to profitability by reducing our interest burden and providing additional liquidity to increase our community count. In particular, we accomplished:
• A successful exchange offer of common stock for the substantial majority of our convertible notes and Tangible Equity Units outstanding when this offer was completed in March;
• A growth capital raise of over $170 million through the issuance of common stock and new Tangible Equity Units, which will enable us to grow the size of our business in the coming years;
• The refinancing of our 12% Senior Secured Notes, which were due in 2017. We replaced these with less expensive, 6 5/8% Senior Secured Notes that are due in 2018; and finally,
• The addition of a $150 million revolver, providing additional liquidity, which is available to be used for short-term working capital as we grow our business.
These transactions are expected to reduce our annual interest payments by $15 million
and will enable us to more confidently make investments to grow the size of our business Profitability in future years as we continue to implement our path-to-profitability strategies.
In addition, soon after the end of our fiscal year, we completed a 1-for-5 reverse stock split. This reverse split had no direct impact on the equity market capitalization of the Company, but was primarily intended to make shares of the common stock more attractive to certain prospective shareholders, to reduce transaction costs for investors and to reduce price volatility.
The 4 major strategies within our path-to-profitability plan, which we introduced a year ago, have not changed. These 4 strategies are:
Drive Sales per Community: Improving sales per community per month, as well as the portion of our communities that are performing at an acceptable level, has been the foundation of our operational improvement efforts. During the final quarter of Fiscal 2011, we shifted our sales focus to the community level and implemented an intense push to better apply the so-called 4-Ps of retailing – Product, People, Promotion and Price. We are very pleased that these moves have resulted in significantly improved sales per community driven by the contribu- tions of a higher percentage of our communities than in recent years. For Fiscal 2012, we achieved an average of 2.3 sales per community per month as compared with 1.8 sales per community per month during Fiscal 2011, representing a 28% improvement. In addition, looking at the average of the last four quarters, the ratio of our communities we calculate to be “performing” was up to 81% from 69% a year ago.
our desire to drive sales per community is an ongoing effort, but we are extremely pleased with the progress we have made to date on this strategy within our path-to-profitability plan.
leverage Fixed Costs: Despite appreciably higher closing volumes during Fiscal 2012, we reduced our total general and administrative costs for the year and achieved significant cost leverage. our total general and administrative costs for Fiscal 2012 totaled 10.9% of revenues, improved from 18.5% of revenues for Fiscal 2011. In addition, we continue to opportunistically look for ways to lower our interest expense as demon- strated by the $15 million reduction in annualized interest obligations we achieved during Fiscal 2012.
  pAtH to
Beazer Homes 2012 AnnuAl RepoRt 3

 Gradually expand Community Count: In order to return to profitability, we will need to grow the size of our business. For Fiscal 2012, however, our average active community count declined year-over-year as we focused on improving our sales per community and maintaining liquidity in a still uncertain marketplace. We believed that until we had enhanced the performance of our existing assets, it was not in our shareholders’ best interest to increase our land investment. now that we have substantially improved our sales per community results, demonstrated our ability to leverage our fixed costs and possess an increased level of confidence about the direction of the housing market, we intend to intensify our efforts to acquire land, which will enable us to expand our community count in future years. We have ample lots available to meet our operational objectives during Fiscal 2013, but expect to grow the size of our business to meet our growth projections for Fiscal 2014 and beyond. Our $170 million capital raise last July was completed with this intention.
Improve Margins as Sales per Community Metrics Improve: now that we’ve improved our sales pace, we need to expand gross margin percentage as well as our gross margin dollars per closing in order to accelerate our return to profitability. For Fiscal 2012, we began to see some improvement with homebuilding gross margins, excluding interest and impairments, up 50 basis points and higher gross margin dollars per closing than in the prior year. Heading into Fiscal 2013, we are laser-focused on finding additional ways to increase our home- building gross margins on each home that we sell, making adjustments to our products and features to fit the needs of our customers while increasing our margin potential. In addition, we anticipate the substantial increase in the average sales price embedded in our year-end sales backlog, which is up over $18,000 per home from last year, will enable us to increase gross margin dollars per closing.
overall, Fiscal 2012 was highlighted by the tremendous progress we made on the strategies Conclusion included in our path-to-profitability plan, while providing almost 4,500 customers with
new, high-quality Beazer homes. the solid sales results during Fiscal 2012 provided us with a backlog of homes under contract at the end of the fiscal year that was 33% higher in units and 43% higher in value than at the same time last year. There is still work to do,
but we are encouraged by the improving trends in many of our operational and financial metrics. And, with the completion of our recent capital markets activity, we believe that we have the capital necessary to fund our growth objectives so that we may fully participate in the emerging housing recovery.
All of us at Beazer Homes take our responsibility to return to profitability seriously. We’re appreciative of the opportunity we have and intend to continue our relentless and disciplined focus on our path-to-profitability plan. We look forward to continuing our drive to return to profitability in order to provide the returns your investment merits.
Sincerely,
Brian C. Beazer Allan p. Merrill
non-executive Chairman of the Board president and Chief executive officer
    4 Beazer Homes 2012 AnnuAl RepoRt
