Toour Shareholders
  our Fiscal 2011 coincided with another year of sharp declines in the volume of new home sales and further reductions in the level of new home prices in the United States. These broader market conditions have dramatically reduced the size of the homebuilding industry and challenged the ability of the Company to deliver acceptable financial and operational results. That’s the obvious and well-documented bad news. The less obvious, and perhaps underappreciated good news is two-fold: First, new home construction will inevitably recover in the years ahead as extraordinary new home affordability and the powerful demographics of household formation exert themselves in an environment of very low new home inventories. And second, despite the many challenges presented by this historic downturn, Beazer Homes remains a viable and geographically well-positioned, if somewhat over-leveraged, participant in this crucial sector of the economy. looking to Fiscal 2012 and beyond, we remain confident in the eventual recovery of the sector, but we are intent on improving our performance regardless of the ultimate trajectory of that recovery.
During the year, our Board of Directors made an important decision related to the leadership of the Company. After considerable deliberation of the Company’s strategy and operational performance, the Board decided to appoint a new Chief Executive officer and a new Chief Financial officer. This decision was not an easy one to make. The prior CEo, Ian McCarthy, had held the role since 1991 and, in that time, led the successful transformation of the Company from a small, regional builder into a top-10 national homebuilder with widespread U.S. operations. The Board is grateful to Mr. McCarthy for his many years of service, but determined that a change in leadership was in the best interest of both the Company and its shareholders. In June, the Board appointed Allan Merrill as President and Chief Executive officer and Bob Salomon as Chief Financial officer with an explicit mandate to drive a fundamental change in the business in order to accelerate
a resumption in profitability for the Company.
BEAZERHoMES 2011ANNUAlREPoRT 1

New Home orders
4,045 3,927
FY FY 2010 2011
New home orders for the year totaled 3,927, with a 33% increase in the fourth quarter of Fiscal 2011.
Full Year Financial & operational Results
Before addressing the prospects for 2012 and the Company’s strategies to return to profitability, let’s focus on our results for Fiscal 2011. In short, although 2011 was a challenging and somewhat disappointing year, we did see a marked improve- ment in our sales performance in the second half of the year. For the full year, our results from continuing operations were as follows:
• New home orders were down 3%
• Closings were down 27%
• General & Administrative expenses as a
percentage of revenue were 18.5%
• Our net loss was $2.71 per share, or $2.27,
excluding impairments
These full year results reflected a difficult year-over-year
comparison, primarily due to the absence of last year’s first- time homebuyer tax credit. Following the anniversary of the expiration of this credit, however, our year-over-year results were substantially better. The solid operational performance that we reported for the fourth quarter highlighted this improvement. our results from continuing operations for the fourth quarter were as follows:
• New home orders were up 33%
• Closings were up 23%
• General & Administrative expenses were
9.0% of revenue
• Our net loss was $0.57 per share, or $0.48,
excluding impairments
2 BEAZERHoMES 2011ANNUAlREPoRT
New Home Closings
+33% 1,006 757
Q4 Q4 FY10 FY11
4,421 +23% 3,249
Q4 Q4
FY10 FY11
1,376
1,119
                          FY FY 2010 2011
New home closings for the year totaled 3,249, with a 23% increase in the fourth quarter of Fiscal 2011.
  This improvement in fourth quarter sales resulted in a nearly
90% increase in our backlog of sold homes compared with last year. At September 30, 2011, we had 1,450 homes in backlog representing a sales value of $335 million.
While this improvement in sales during the fourth quarter was encouraging, our full year results were below our expectations. In fact, by March of this year, we realized that our hopes for a rebound in the housing market in Fiscal 2011 were not going to materialize. As a result, we undertook a dramatic reduction in overheads. By further streamlining every functional area in the Company, we were able to eliminate nearly 130 positions, down- size our office space needs and reduce many other operational costs. This allowed us to create a cost structure that more closely matches today’s market realities. As a result, we expect to realize a savings in our annual overhead costs of approximately $20 million.
In addition to ensuring that our cost structure is appropriate given today’s economic environment, we have considered other opportunities that profitably leverage our homebuilding skill sets. In May, we unveiled our Pre-owned Homes Division, which is charged with acquiring, improving and renting recently built, previously owned homes within select communities and markets. By September 30, 2011, this division had purchased 120 homes in the Phoenix and las Vegas markets, with approx- imately half already improved and rented to families. We are optimistic about the opportunity in single-family rental homes and believe we can create shareholder value from our initiative. We are mindful, however, of the many opportunities and

(revenues in millions)
Year Ended September 30,
Continuing operations Data Home orders
Home closings
Units in backlog
Total revenues
loss per share from continuing operations
obligations with a claim on our resources. Therefore, we intend to use third-party capital to scale the business and will limit our investment to no more than $20 million.
In our core homebuilding operations, we have a substantial
supply of land, with nearly 7,000 finished lots and approximately
8,000 additional lots in various stages of development. This land position will allow us to benefit from any improvement in demand for new homes within our existing communities and enables us to exercise considerable discretion in our land and land develop- ment spending related to new communities.
We ended the year with a substantial cash position, totaling
$647 million in cash and cash equivalents, approximately $370
million of which was unrestricted. This liquidity was bolstered in
the first half of October as we generated approximately $23 million
in proceeds from home closings that unexpectedly carried over into our first quarter. Although our total debt remains substantial at $1.5 billion, we have no significant debt maturities until mid-2015. This affords us the time to enhance our operational performance and grow back into, or otherwise take actions to improve, our capital structure.
2012 Perspectives & The Path-To-Profitability Plan
Across our organization, we have one primary corporate objective, which is to return Beazer Homes to sustainable profitability. We must do this in an environment that is still extremely volatile as high unemployment persists, tight lending practices continue and consumer confidence remains low. Nonetheless, we are taking an aggressive stance with a renewed focus and
$ $
$ $
2009
4,016 4,152 1,148
962 (4.48)
Financial Summary Beazer Homes USA, Inc.
2011 2010 3,927 4,045
3,249 4,421 1,450 772 742 $ 991
(2.71) $ (0.49)
    intensity to create our own recovery and improve the value of Beazer Homes for our shareholders. By holding each team member accountable for contributing to this objective, we believe that we can build on our improved backlog and make progress in Fiscal 2012 on our objective to return to profitability as soon as possible.
The new management team’s path-to-profitability strategy has four primary components:
Drive Sales Per Community: To accelerate our return to profitability, we must increase the rate of sales in every one of our existing new home communities. To accomplish this goal we have adopted a 4-P framework to evaluate underperforming communities. This framework analyzes: the product we offer, the people selling for us, our promotion efforts and the price and concessions we will accept. We have also delegated more autonomy back to the divisions to allow them to compete more quickly and effectively in their respective local markets. This included moving purchasing professionals and the responsibility for designing elevations and floor plans back into our largest divisions.
Gradually Increase Community Count: over the next several years, we need to gradually increase our number of new home communities. We do not have a specific number in mind, nor can we predict the regional allocation of these new assets. Rather, we are targeting opportunities that offer appropriate returns, manageable capital requirements and the ability to leverage our capabilities within our existing geographic footprint. our goal is to be smart about our
BEAZERHoMES 2011ANNUAlREPoRT 3

Pro Forma Cash and Maturity Schedule (in millions)
$647.5(1)
 􏲔 Senior Secured Notes
􏲔 Senior Unsecured Notes
$172.5
2014 2015
􏲔 Subordinated Notes
      $1.2(2)
$4.9(2) $4.0(2)(3)
$100.8 //
2036
$172.9
$300.0
$250.0
2018 2019
$497.4(1)
    Cash Balance
2011 2012 2013
2016 2017
Note: Based on calendar years.
(1) Includes $247.4mm related to our cash secured loan with a 7-year maturity, but putable by the lenders as early as November 2012.
(2) Includes the amortizing principal amount associated with the Tangible Equity Units.
(3) Excludes $57.5mm mandatory subordinate convertible notes due 2013 as such debt will be converted to common stock upon maturity.
  growth and to only add communities that represent profitable incremental investments.
Improve Margins as Sales Per Community Metrics Improve:
Increasing sales per community metrics naturally leads to higher gross margins as we are better able to leverage the components of cost of sales that are fixed at the community level. In addition, new communities typically offer opportunities for better margins. Finally, as we improve our local competitiveness, we should be able to make smarter and more profitable decisions about both standard home features and option packages.
Leverage and Control Fixed Costs: As we work to drive increased home sales and improve margins from those sales, we have to be particularly diligent about not allowing fixed costs to increase. This will enable improvements in revenue and margin to translate directly into enhanced profitability.
Conclusion
over the past several years, we have had to work hard to survive the sharp decline in new home sales and the impact of falling home prices as well as to successfully manage through some well- publicized legal, regulatory and capitalization issues particular to the Company. While we are proud of our team’s efforts to work through these issues, we are acutely aware that we have an enormous amount of work to do to return to profitability. With our increased focus, intensity and accountability, we are confident our management team and our Ambassadors can
continue to provide our homebuyers with well-built and energy-efficient homes, while generating improving financial results for our shareholders.
The relationships we have with our fellow Beazer Ambassadors, shareholders, suppliers and the financial community remain valued assets for us. The support they have given the new leadership team is greatly appreciated and will allow us to remain focused on returning Beazer Homes to its proud history of sustainable profitability.
Thank you.
Brian C. Beazer
Non-Executive Chairman of the Board
Allan P. Merrill
President and Chief Executive officer
December 1, 2011
  4 BEAZERHoMES 2011ANNUAlREPoRT
