CENTURYTEL 2005 ANNUAL REPORT
     Our high-quality broadband network, our committed employee base, our excellent customer service and our financial strength make us a strong competitor now and in the future.
Dear Shareholders
The telecommunications industry continued its rapid evolution during 2005 and will experience further innovation in 2006 and beyond. While this rapid change brings new challenges, we at CenturyTel believe these challenges are outpaced by the opportunities we will have to offer a broad array of advanced services – both to our existing customers and to new customers in new markets.
Driving change in our industry is the rapid advancement in Internet Protocol (IP) based technologies
that allow telecommunications, video, wireless and other service providers to offer services they have not traditionally been able to support. These new technologies mean that CenturyTel may face greater competition – particularly in the more densely populated areas
we serve. However, the advancement of IP technologies also provides us unprecedented opportunities to sell new products and services over our broadband network and to expand the geographic scope of the markets we serve.
We believe we are well positioned to take advantage of these opportunities.
3,479 3,410 3,617 3,088
2,337
We take our relationships with our customers personally, and we work hard to retain and grow our customer base by providing the best value, solutions and customer experience in our markets. Our high-quality broadband network, our committed employee base, our excellent customer service and our financial strength make us a strong competitor now and in the future.
Our Financial Strength
Enables Our Operational Success CenturyTel has the financial strength that we believe will be a key requirement
for companies to succeed in our rapidly changing environment. Once again, in 2005 CenturyTel delivered solid operating
1,068
956 965
793 573
   Net Cash Provided by Operating Activities
(in millions)
 Stockholders’ Equity
(in millions)
            01 02 03 04 05
01 02 03 04 05
  2
 
   results and further strengthened our financial position.
During the year we:
■ Generated nearly $965 million in net
cash from operations;
■ Returned over $580 million of cash to
shareholders through share repurchases
and cash dividends;
■ Invested $384 million in network
enhancements;
■ Improved our financial strength and
liquidity through the repayment of $349 million in debt, decreasing debt as a percentage of total capitalization to 42.3 percent;
■ Increased operating revenues 3.0 percent and diluted earnings per share 3.3 percent;
■ Grew high-speed Internet connections by more than 106,000, ending 2005 with over 248,700 broadband subscribers, an increase of 74.4 percent over 2004; and
■ Further secured our customer base by increasing bundle penetration from 12.2 percent to 15.5 percent of total access lines, driving further penetration of our enhanced calling features and long distance services.
CenturyTel’s strong cash flows and solid capital structure provide us the financial strength and flexibility to invest in growth initiatives, to meet the challenges that
lay ahead and to return capital to shareholders through share repurchases and dividends. I am pleased with our 2005 financial results, and we are committed to leveraging our financial position to continue driving shareholder value in 2006 and beyond.
We Continue to Position Our Business to Succeed in a Changing Environment As our environment grows more competitive, we know we must improve the way we serve our customers to ensure that our customer experience is unparalleled and that the costs we incur to deliver services are competitive. We believe that excellent customer care will be a key differentiator in markets where multiple competitors sell the same product sets at similar prices. We must challenge ourselves to provide this high level of service while being the low-cost provider in our markets. We expect
this effort to deliver improved market penetration and provide additional pricing flexibility.
In late 2005 we introduced a new branding initiative that emphasizes the qualities that distinguish us from other service providers. Our new tagline, “personal touch --- advanced communi- cations” is more than a marketing campaign. It is a statement of who we are, of the way we do business, and of how we treat one another and our customers. Together with our Unifying Principles, our brand is a critical tool in helping our customers understand who we are and in helping our employees understand what is expected of them.
Our Broadband Network Is
the Foundation for Our Future CenturyTel’s network is positioned to support the continued evolution that IP technology brings. Over the last five years, we have invested more than
$1.5 billion to enable broadband, extend fiber deeper into our network, start
an “on-net” competitive local exchange business and create a regional fiber
Our new tagline, “personal touch --- advanced communica- tions” is more than a marketing campaign. It is a statement of who we are, of the way we do business, and of how we treat one another and our customers.
CenturyTel’s Unifying Principles: Fairness -
The Golden Rule Honesty and Integrity Commitment
to Excellence Positive Attitude Respect
Faith Perseverance
  3
   
CENTURYTEL 2005 ANNUAL REPORT
   The broadband capaci- ty we have built into our network is our principal strategic advantage in an envi- ronment where multi- ple service providers compete to meet a customer’s complete communications needs.
network. Through these investments we have begun migrating our fiber network from a “voice-centric” TDM configuration to an IP-based system that supports a wider range of advanced services.
At year-end 2005, nearly 75 percent of our local exchange access lines were broadband capable. As technologies continue to emerge, we expect to be able to deliver IP-video over our existing facilities to a large number of customers with relatively modest amounts of additional capital investment. The broadband capacity we have built into our network is our principal strategic advantage in an environment where multiple service providers compete to meet a customer’s complete communications needs.
In addition to our broadband local exchange network, we also have nearly 10,500 miles of regional fiber, more than 630 carrier points of presence and metro fiber networks in 18 markets. These fiber assets carry much of CenturyTel’s internal traffic and deliver voice and data services to business and wholesale customers in 18 states. While we believe there are significant opportunities to profitably expand these businesses – our fiber
and CLEC revenues increased more
than 19 percent in 2005, excluding acquisitions – we also believe new technologies will allow us to leverage these networks to support broadband
services in existing markets and to serve new customers in new markets.
Additionally, more than two-thirds of our existing access lines are within easy reach of our fiber network. This positions CenturyTel to drive cost efficiencies in the IP environment as our different markets will be able to cost-effectively share switches, video head-ends and other centrally located network elements. At the same time, more than 155 million people live within 50 miles of either a CenturyTel service territory or a fiber network. We believe there will be significant opportunities to grow and diversify our revenues by leveraging our existing network to offer service to
some portion of these new markets.
We Are Capitalizing
on Today’s Opportunities
As we plan for the future of our business, we are also focused on taking advantage of the opportunities that are available to us today. We have established partnerships with wireless companies and a Direct Broadcast Satellite service provider to enable us to offer wireless and video services in our product bundles. We have also introduced switched digital television service to portions of La Crosse, Wisconsin, and the surrounding area.
We continue to utilize our flexible product bundles to drive penetration of
   Broadband Deployment (% of total access lines)
  71 75
249 436
415
DSL Customers
(in thousands)
Capital Expenditures
(in millions)
     61 59 63
386 378 385
      83 53
25
143
       01 02 03 04 05
01 02 03 04 05
01 02 03 04 05
  4
 
   broadband and other services. We believe providing bundled services with a single bill at a discounted price is a key element in customer retention. As of the end
of 2005, 19.6 percent of our residential customers had purchased a Simple ChoiceTM product bundle from us.
Additionally, we have increased our efforts to provide our business customers with the latest in communications services to help ensure the success of their operations. For example, we recently partnered with a large university to deploy a next generation IP communication solution. This partnership allowed the university to make a smooth transition to an IP-based platform, while reducing its capital commitment.
We Are a Strong Advocate for Sensible Regulatory Policies That Promote Universal Service and Broadband Deployment
The future of telecommunications undoubtedly lies in broadband deployment and the convergence of services among various types of service providers. Unfortunately, it is just as clear that the regulatory environment has simply not kept pace with technological advancements and changes in the competitive landscape.
Our positions on the principal regulatory issues facing our industry are straightforward. We are a strong advocate for regulatory policies that:
1) encourage network investment and broadband deployment, 2) ensure the universal availability of affordable communications services to customers in rural areas and 3) create regulatory parity among all service providers. We will continue our advocacy in these areas, and
we are encouraged that rational policies will result from these efforts.
We Enthusiastically
Look Toward Our Future
As we review the results of our efforts in 2005 and look ahead to 2006 and beyond, there is much of which we can be proud and even more to which we can look forward. We are excited about the potential of our broadband future and the growth opportunities that technological advancements will bring. We believe we have the network, the employees, the opportunities and the commitment to grow our business in the years ahead.
Glen F. Post, III Chairman and CEO
We are a strong advocate for regulatory policies that:
1) encourage network investment and broadband deployment, 2) ensure the universal availability of affordable communications services to customers in rural areas and
3) create regulatory parity among all
service providers.
     5
   