To Our Shareholders, Employees, and
  Customers: Page 1 of 4
Chairman’s Letter
Financial Highlights Form 10-K
  2010 was a challenging year for our company, as Americans reduced their utilization of healthcare services. Against a backdrop of a 4% decline in physician office visits in the
U.S., our revenue decline of 1.2% to $7.4 billion was not surprising.
 Despite the downward pressure caused by fewer physician office visits, we were able to increase earnings per share for the year and generate significant cash flow. In addition,
we made progress on a number of key growth initiatives.
 As the world leader in diagnostic testing, information and services, Quest Diagnostics is well positioned to capitalize on fundamental trends, which remain positive for our company. Diagnostic testing is becoming even more essential to quality healthcare, and we play a central role in improving health outcomes and reducing overall healthcare costs. We expect increased demand for higher value and more complex tests that help physicians identify predisposition to disease, diagnose disease, select treatment based
on a patient’s individual genetic profile, and monitor therapy and recurrence.
 The pace of technological change is accelerating. In order to remain competitive, we must therefore continually develop new tests to anticipate the evolving needs of the
healthcare community.
 As this letter is written, we finalized the acquisition of Athena Diagnostics and are preparing to complete the acquisition of Celera Corporation in separate transactions
that are expected to add 2% to our 2011 revenue growth and drive sustainable growth.
 Athena will establish Quest Diagnostics as the clear leader in the rapidly emerging neurology testing market. This represents one of the next significant growth areas in diagnostic testing, with significant interest and potential in the emerging area of
diagnostics and therapy for Alzheimer’s disease. We expect to operate Athena as an

   Strategy Starts with Patients
Our business strategy remains firmly focused on patients, growth and people. We differentiate ourselves from our competitors in several important ways, by:
• Improving quality by applying Lean Six Sigma principles; and
• Providing superior service. Our long term goals are to:
• Grow faster than the industry rate;
• Expand operating income to 20% of revenues; and
• Increase international operations to 10% of revenues.
2010 Financial Performance
For the full year:
• Revenues decreased 1.2% to $7.4 billion;
• We grew earnings per share 5% to $4.06; and
• We generated $1.1 billion in cash from operations.
Accelerating growth
1 Enhance sales effectiveness;
2 Promote innovative tests and technologies;
3 Assist Health Plans to reduce high cost out-of-network utilization;
4 Increase operating efficiency; and
5 Deploy our cash to drive growth and shareholder value.
I’d like to update you briefly on each element.
Enhance sales effectiveness
Over the course of much of the last year and a half, we invested in our sales
 • Developing and promoting new tests and technologies by building on our
leadership position in science and innovation;
 We have assembled an unmatched network of laboratories, patient service centers for
specimen collection and ground and air logistics, which position us well for growth.
 We continue to see strong demand for esoteric and gene-based testing. These tests, together with anatomic pathology, continue to account for 36% of consolidated
revenues, up from 19% in 2000.
Our anatomic pathology revenues continued to be negatively impacted by the trend toward in-sourcing of testing by certain physician practice specialties. We have taken steps to strengthen our offering as well as educate legislators and regulators about the real risk of overutilization when physicians refer testing to labs in which they have a
financial interest.
  We are focused on a five-point plan to drive improvement in our performance and take
advantage of growth opportunities. The elements of the plan are to:
independent business within Quest Diagnostics.
Celera, one of the world’s pioneers in genetic diagnostics discovery and development, will further strengthen our leadership position in molecular diagnostics. We will gain immediate access to an impressive range of proprietary tests and products, and a strong pipeline of biomarkers for the future. Berkeley HeartLab’s unique test offering and specialized sales force enhances our leading position in gene-based and esoteric cardiovascular testing. Celera’s products business significantly expands our in-vitro
diagnostics products and development capability.

 organization to respond to a changing marketplace. We added sales positions and substantially completed our sales force expansion by the end of 2010. In addition, we have expanded our specialty sales capability. With these enhancements, we entered
 2011 well positioned to capitalize on market opportunities in various subspecialties.
Promote innovative tests and technologies
 We are focused on developing and promoting important, new gene-based and esoteric
tests, which represent the fastest-growing part of our business.
In 2010, gene-based and esoteric testing revenues grew 4.5%. Much of the growth has been driven by Vitamin D testing, as well as testing for blood cancers, particularly our
LeumetaTM family of blood tests.
We made good progress building our innovation pipeline in our key focus areas of
cancer, infectious disease and cardiovascular disease.
In cancer diagnostics, we introduced ColoVantageTM, the first blood test for the detection of colorectal cancer. We also continue to see growing interest in OVA1TM, the
first blood test cleared by the FDA to help detect ovarian cancer before surgery.
   In infectious disease, our recently introduced SureSwabTM real-time PCR test for gynecologic infections was well received. In addition, our Focus Diagnostics unit continued to enhance and expand its SimplexaTM platform with new tests for influenza and a range of other infectious diseases.
    And in cardiovascular disease, we are pleased at the growing recognition of the value of our AccuType® CP test from physicians, patients and health plans. This test helps
assess a patient’s response to the anti-clotting drug Plavix®.

 We launched a new prescription drug monitoring service to help our physician clients ensure patient safety and compliance. Revenues continued to climb as we educated the
 marketplace about the benefits.
 We also made significant strides with our healthcare IT strategy, which helps drive
customer loyalty and growth.
 Our Care360® EHR was certified for “meaningful use,” which means our physician clients who use it can qualify for government incentives of up to $44,000. More than 1,600 doctors are using Care360® EHR. As we exited 2010, our customers were using the eprescribing feature of Care360® at an annualized rate of 22 million medications, up
70% compared to the end of 2009.
 We are also very proud of our new electronic patient health record, Gazelle®, which has now been downloaded 22,000 times and has more than 10,000 patients registered and
actively using it.
Work with health plans
Increase operating efficiency
Deploy cash effectively
 We see continued strong interest from health plans and employers in working
collaboratively on reducing high-cost and out-of-network lab utilization.
We extended several of our managed care contracts to increase access certainty and pricing visibility. As we look forward in 2011, we have good visibility into health plan
pricing with no major contract renewals through 2012.
  We continue to improve our operating efficiency, even after the significant cost reductions we have made in recent years. We have carefully managed costs to align
them with changing volume levels, and will continue to do so.
 We generate strong cash flow and are committed to deploying our cash to drive growth. Our preference is to invest in acquisitions, primarily in genetics, esoteric testing and
cancer diagnostics, including anatomic pathology.
When acquisitions are not available on reasonable terms, we will return cash to shareholders through share repurchases and dividends. In 2010, we returned $750 million dollars to our shareholders through share repurchases. In addition, following the release of our year−end earnings in January, we agreed to repurchase at a negotiated price 15.4 million shares of our common stock from our largest shareholder, an affiliate of GlaxoSmithKline plc (GSK). After the transaction, GSK no longer held any shares of common stock of Quest Diagnostics. That transaction enabled us to take advantage of a unique opportunity to enhance shareholder value and demonstrate confidence in the
long term outlook for our business.
 We continue to actively evaluate opportunities for acquisitions. Apart from fold-in acquisitions, we are focused on acquiring genetic and esoteric capabilities to further strengthen our positions in areas such as cancer, cardiovascular disease, and infectious disease.

  A Strong Reputation
A Special Thank You
Poised for Performance
Thank you for your continued support. Take care,
 Our company’s reputation continues to grow. We were named to FORTUNE Magazine's list of “World’s Most Admired Companies” for the fourth consecutive year. We were also ranked as a Platinum “Best Employer for Healthy Lifestyles” by the National Business Group on Health and were included on Corporate Responsibility Magazine’s 11th annual “Best Corporate Citizens” list. We also achieved Cancer Gold Standard
accreditation from the CEO Roundtable on Cancer.
 I would like to thank Rosanne Haggerty for her many contributions since she joined our Board of Directors in 2002. Rosanne is retiring from our Board. We will miss her
insights, experience and creativity.
 Despite a challenging environment in 2010, we exited the year with a stronger business
and solid prospects for the future.
We are the leader in our industry, which is positioned to benefit from a number of favorable trends. Our strategy is working. Our 40,000-plus employees remain firmly focused on putting patients first and finding new ways to enhance service, improve health outcomes and drive quality and efficiencies in our operations. They are the
reason I have confidence in our future.
 
  Surya N. Mohapatra, Ph.D.
Chairman, Chief Executive Officer and President
Quest Diagnostics Incorporated
