 The Dun & Bradstreet Corporation
 To Our Shareholders:
I am pleased to report that 2006 was a very good year for D&B, as our financial performance demonstrates. We delivered core revenue growth of 6%, with positive contributions from both our US and International segments. Operating income grew 8%, which increases to 12% excluding the impact of stock options, which we began expensing in 2006. Earnings per share grew 14%, marking our sixth consecutive year of double- digit earnings growth. And free cash flow grew to $298 million, before the impact of legacy tax matters.
To put this performance in context, it has been more than six years now since the spin-off that brought this historic company back to its roots. At that time, we announced our intention to transform D&B into a high- performing growth company. To deliver on that goal, we created a strategy that we called our “Blueprint
for Growth.” Our consistent focus on this Blueprint strategy has been very successful and, today, we are a high-performing growth company, as evidenced by our financial performance over time.
Specifically, we’ve increased core revenue by more than 40% since 2001. At the same time, we improved operating income by 65% and more than doubled our earnings per share. In addition, we increased our free cash flow by 82%, which has allowed us to repurchase more than $1 billion of D&B stock. As a result of this performance, shareholders who have been with us since the spin-off have realized a 370% return on their investment in D&B by year-end 2006.
We’re very proud of these results, and we intend to extend this track record of growth and performance. We’re very clear on how we’ll drive value going forward.
A Commitment to “Total Shareholder Return”
As we’ve emphasized over time, D&B is a company that’s committed to driving total shareholder return.
We deliver on this commitment by focusing on three key drivers:
■ First, ensuring the consistency of our performance. ■ Second, ensuring that we deliver profitable revenue
growth.
■ And third, maintaining our discipline around the deployment of cash.
These were the key drivers of our performance and growth in 2006, and they’ll continue to drive our progress in the future. Let me highlight what these drivers mean to us.
Consistency of Performance
First, consistency of performance at D&B means “doing what we say.” We’re pleased with the results we’ve delivered over time, and we’re proud of our unique track record of consistency. In fact, 2006 was another in a series of positive years along the way for D&B.
Looking ahead, we’re confident in our ability to once again deliver strong results and total shareholder return in 2007. That confidence is demonstrated by our 2007 financial guidance, which calls for ongoing profitable revenue growth and continued improvement in all of our key financial metrics. Specifically, we expect to deliver:
■ Core revenue growth of 6 percent to 8 percent, before the effect of foreign exchange, all of which will be organic.
■ Operating income growth of 8 percent to 10 percent, before non-core gains and charges.
■ Diluted EPS growth of 13 percent to 16 percent before non-core gains and charges.
                      2 D&B Annual Report 2006

   Steve Alesio, Chairman and CEO
“As we’ve emphasized over time, D&B is a company that’s
committed to driving total shareholder return.”
■ Free cash flow of $310 million to $325 million before legacy tax matters.
■ A tax rate before non-core gains and charges of approximately 37 percent to 38 percent.
Our ability to deliver this guidance in 2007 is enabled by the four core competitive advantages we’ve developed over time. These include our trusted brand, which
is increasingly associated with global
commercial insight; our financially
flexible business model, which allows
us to unlock savings that we can then
reinvest in growth; our winning culture,
which is strongly focused on leadership development; and our proprietary
DUNSRight quality process, which is the core value proposition we sell to our customers. A more detailed description of these core competitive advantages is presented on pages 6-7 of this Annual Report.
Profitable Revenue Growth
A second key driver of total shareholder return at D&B is delivering profitable revenue growth as we execute against the strategic stakes we’ve identified for the future.
At our September 2006 Investor Day event, we announced our fundamental strategic choice to continue being the world’s largest and best provider of commercial insight about businesses. Within
the commercial insight market, we identified three strategic stakes for the future:
■ First, growing our global Risk Management Solutions business by continuing to improve our data, analytics and platforms.
■ Second, growing our Sales and Marketing Solutions business by focusing on the higher growth space of commercial data integration.
■ And third, growing our Internet Solutions business by continuing to grow Hoover’s while investing in one or two new platforms to leverage the expertise we’ve developed at Hoover’s over time.
We’re only just beginning to execute against these stakes, and we are pleased with the early progress we’ve made.
■ From a Risk Management data perspective, in November 2006 we announced our creation of a new joint venture in China called Huaxia/D&B. We believe this partnership will significantly enhance our competitive position in China, and it will allow us to double the number of Chinese business records in our database over the next few years.
   D&B Annual Report 2006 3

The Dun & Bradstreet Corporation
 ■ From a Risk Management analytics perspective, in February 2007, we announced our signing of a joint venture agreement in Chennai, India, to create a new “D&B Predictive Analytics Center.” The joint venture is with our Indian partner company DBSAME (D&B South Asia Middle East), which has conducted analytics work for us and our customers in a number of markets over the past two years. We believe this joint venture will significantly enhance our ability to provide advanced analytic solutions to customers around the world.
■ From a Risk Management platforms perspective,
we continue to drive good results from DNBi, which is the interactive, Web-based application we rolled out
in the fourth quarter of 2005. By upgrading to DNBi, customers receive an enhanced risk management experience and virtually unlimited, real-time access to our global database. In return, we require an increased revenue commitment. Our target is a double-digit increase, which generates a sizable improvement in our average revenue per customer with each new contract. While we are still early in the DNBi adoption cycle, we’re seeing strong conversion rates, particularly in the small and middle markets where the need for this subscription- based solution is most acute. To build on this, we introduced new modules for DNBi in 2006, meeting customer needs for automated decisioning and portfolio management. These modules also generate a double- digit price lift for us while further embedding DNBi into our customers’ business. Moving forward, we’ll continue to expand our DNBi penetration. And we will continue to innovate – rolling out at least one new DNBi module per year. As a result, we expect DNBi to continue to be
a key growth driver for our Risk Management business.
■ We’re also making progress against our second strategic stake, to grow our Sales and Marketing Solutions by further penetrating the high-growth commercial data integration space. In the third quarter
of 2006, we signed product and technology agreements with The Acxiom Corporation that have significantly enhanced our data integration capabilities. By taking the best of our own “Customer Information Management” solution and linking it with Acxiom’s advanced computing power, we can now provide D&B customers with improved processing speed, increased capacity and higher levels of commercial insight. We made significant investments to establish this relationship
in 2006, and to introduce our advanced “Optimizer” commercial data integration solution, powered by Acxiom. We continue to work closely with the Acxiom team to build a robust sales pipeline for Optimizer, which we expect will progressively benefit us over the course of 2007.
■ Finally, with respect to our third strategic stake, to grow our Internet business, we are focused on growing our Hoover’s business organically, while also seeking
to acquire new platforms that will allow us to target business professionals seeking commercial information on the Web. These new platforms will allow us to take our current assets, such as our brand, DUNSRight, and our unique Web-marketing skills, and leverage them more broadly across the Internet.
Disciplined Deployment of Cash
The third key driver of total shareholder return at D&B is our highly disciplined approach to deploying our free cash flow, and we see 2007 as an important year for D&B as we focus on both organic growth and acquisitions to advance our strategy. We continue to target three key priorities for our use of cash:
■ First, we’ll continue to invest in the business to drive organic growth.
■ Second, we continue to look at smart, “value- accretive” acquisitions.
      4 D&B Annual Report 2006

                       ■ And third, we’re committed to returning excess cash to our shareholders.
In terms of acquisition spending, we anticipate completing between $300 million and $500 million
in total acquisitions between now and the end of 2010. We have a good pipeline of acquisition candidates we’re evaluating today. And you can count on our continued rigor around acquisitions, ensuring that
any candidate we pursue provides a good strategic fit, and delivers returns well above our cost of capital.
Finally, in terms of returning excess cash to shareholders, we have a strong track record of share repurchases at D&B. As I noted, we’ve completed more than $1 billion in special program share buybacks over the past several years. And, unlike a lot of companies, we’ve also completed every program that we’ve announced on
or ahead of schedule. Going forward, we remain committed to returning around $200 million per year to shareholders through our special repurchase program, while also making ongoing share repurchases to offset dilution from our compensation plans.
As we announced in February 2007, we have also initiated a quarterly cash dividend, representing an annualized 20% payout of our 2006 free cash flow.
We see this as a milestone event for D&B, and it carries a number of important messages:
■ First, it reflects our confidence in the sustainability of our free cash flow going forward.
■ Second, it allows us to offer a more complete total return package and attract a broader mix of investors.
■ And third, it underscores our commitment to deploying our cash strategically to drive total shareholder return.
Looking Ahead
We are pleased with our performance in 2006 and the progress we’ve made over the past six years, since we set out to transform D&B into a high-performing growth company. At the same time, we’re confident about our prospects for the future. While we continue to perform well, we think there’s lots of opportunity still ahead.
We have just begun to execute against the strategic stakes we identified for the future. And the core competitive advantages we’ve developed will continue to serve us well. Going forward, we will continue to invest in our business, leveraging organic growth
and acquisitions as we drive toward our longer term growth strategy. In doing so, we will remain highly disciplined in the use of our shareholders’ cash. Above all, we will maintain our commitment to driving total shareholder return.
On a personal note, it is a great honor for me to lead this storied company as your CEO. Every day,
I feel a tremendous amount of pride about what the D&B team has accomplished for our shareholders over the past several years. At the same time, I feel a great deal of responsibility and excitement for what is still possible.
I thank you for your continued support. And I look forward to reporting our further progress in 2007.
Steven W. Alesio
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
 D&B Annual Report 2006 5
