                DEAr shArEhOlDErs:
 Through the dedicated efforts of all of our employees, Dover had another successful year in 2011. During the year, we experienced growth across all of our segments, with particu- larly strong increases in the energy and handset markets. We set records for full-year revenue, earnings, earnings per share (EPS) and bookings:
nRevenue reached nearly $8 billion for the year, up
20% from the prior year, including organic growth of 11% and acquisition growth of 7%.
n EPS from continuing operations was $4.48, an increase of 23% for the year.
n Full-year segment margin was 17%, a very strong result considering the significant increase in acquisition related costs.
n Free cash flow remained strong at approximately 10% of revenue.
n And we increased our annual dividend 15% to $1.26, marking the 56th consecutive year it has been increased.
In addition to our outstanding financial results, we also executed on multiple strategic initiatives during the course
of the year to position Dover for long-term success. From an operating perspective, we realigned our segment structure
in late 2011, allowing us to better focus on our key growth spaces—energy, refrigeration and food service equipment, communication components, fluid solutions and product iden- tification. We also made significant changes to our business profile by investing $1.4 billion on nine important acquisitions, while divesting three businesses. Our focus on emerging and developing economies, especially China, remains firmly in place, and again this year we achieved significant progress in this area. Our sales across Asia reached approximately 19% of total sales. That figure is up 5 percentage points from just four years ago and now makes Asia our second largest market.
We will continue to build out our growth spaces in 2012, and we expect that our new segment structure will allow us to better leverage our strong position to drive increased value through organic growth and acquisitions.
It truly was an exciting year at Dover.
DOVEr COMMunICATIOn TEChnOlOGIEs (DCT)
DCT became the leading acoustic supplier to the handset mar- ket following the acquisition of Sound Solutions, Dover’s largest acquisition to date. The integration of Sound Solutions
Robert A. Livingston
President and Chief Executive Officer
is well under way and I’m pleased with the progress that our sales organization has made with our significantly broadened product portfolio. Our cross-selling initiatives are enabling us to serve our global customers at an even higher level.
It is currently estimated that approximately three billion peo- ple around the world either listen to or speak into one of DCT’s products each day. To that effect, it’s no surprise that revenue growth at Communication Technologies was extremely strong in 2011, rising 26% to $1.4 billion, while earnings increased 10% to $226 million. Driving these increases was strong de- mand in the global handset market where the opportunity for significant global expansion exists. Two major trends will lead this expansion: the ever-increasing demand for communica- tions and global connectivity, and the dramatically increasing amount of data being transferred via fiber, routers, cellular networks, Bluetooth and WiFi.
In addition to the opportunities in communications, we are making investments in emerging markets in life sciences and aerospace – two of our markets that also delivered
solid performances.
All of the brands and products within DCT are well-positioned in their markets. Through new product investment and global expansion, DCT will continue to expand its leadership position as growth in personal and wireless communications drives forward.
DOVEr EnErGy (DE)
DE had an excellent year with sales of $1.9 billion, represent- ing 46% growth, and earnings of $451 million, a 43% increase. All of our markets, including drilling, production and down-
6

“our focus will continue to be on growth and on
our customers’ needs as we strive to deliver another excellent
year of results for our shareholders.”
— Robert A. Livingston, President and CEO
 stream, showed strength, with production – the segment’s largest market – generating approximately half of the seg- ment’s revenue. Production will continue to gain strength with 94% of oil producing wells worldwide now utilizing some type of artificial lift technology.
dover engineered systems (des)
Both the Fluid Solutions and Refrigeration & Industrial plat- forms performed well in 2011, with total revenues increasing 11% to $3.1 billion and earnings increasing 16% to $445
million over the prior year. Margins also increased by 70 basis
Revenue vs. ContinuinRgeEvaernnuiengvs. ConFtirneueinCgasEhaFrnloinwgs Free Cash Flow
($ in millions) ($ in millions) ($ in millions)
($ in millions)
The demand for Dover Energy’s products is being driven by
points for the year. These strong results were driven by our
focus on productivity which enabled us to deliver value to
three key trends: the increased need for artificial lift due to
maturing fields; the growing demand for sustainable and more
our customers.
$8,000 $8,000 $900 $900
$900 $900 20% $8,000 20% $8,000 $1,000 $1,000
efficient products and solutions that allow customers to meet
In the Fluid Solutions platform, we further enhanced our
increasingly strict regulations; and the need for upgraded energy infrastructure worldwide, including fueling stations
6,000 6,000 675 675
675 675 15 6,000 15 6,000 750 750
and power plants. 4,000 4,000 450 450 2,000 2,000 225 225
product and technology offerings through the acquisitions
4o5f0Dosm4a50tic, Env10irogear a4n,0d00Red Sc1r0ew. These4,0a0c0quis50it0ions 500
broadened our global product offering and will accelerate
Market dynamics remain very favorable for our energy busi-
our growth. We expect to continue to build out this platform
nesses. With current wells producing less, we are experiencing
in 2012.
225 225 5 2,000 5 2,000 250 250
0 0000000000 0
an increased demand for our artificial lift products. Through
2007 2008 2009 2010 20210107 2008 2009 202100722001018 2009 2010 20210107 2008 2009 2010 2200171 2008 2009 2010 20210107 2008 2009 2010 2011
Within our Refrigeration and Industrial platform, our refrigera-
Revenue Revenue Free Cash Flow Free Cash Flow Revenue Revenue
the acquisitions of Harbison-Fischer and Oil Lift, we have
tion and food equipment businesses are key players in the $6
billion global retail refrigeration market, participating primar-
ily in North America, which represents about half of
Earnings from Continuing OpeErartnioingss from ContinuFinregeOCpaesrhatFilonws as a % of ReveFnruee Cash Flow as a % of ReEvaernuinegs from Continuing OpeErartnioingss from Continuing Operations
expanded our technologies in this exciting space. In addition, we have continued to expand internationally, especially in the
Revenue vs. ContinuinRgeEvaernnuiengvs. ContinuingFrEeaerCnainsghsFlow Free Cash Flow EPS Growth EPS Growth
Middle East and Australia.
($ in millions) ($ in millions) ($ in millions)
The growth in demand for cars and fuel in emerging markets is driving the need for fueling stations and distribution centers in
the ma(r$kinemtil.lioAnsl)though overall market activity was down for
the year, DES gained share through its unwavering focus on
$8,000 $8,000 $900 $900 $900
$900 20% $5.00 20% $5.00 $100 $100
the downstream market. This growth in demand, coupled with
mitment to technology and innovation is illustrated by the ac-
increasing clean air and water regulations, provides multiple
quisition of Advansor A/S in November. Advansor specializes in HFC-free, CO2 transcritical refrigeration systems, allowing
6,000 6,000 675 675 675
675 15 3.75 15 3.75 75 75
customer service and product innovation. Our continuing com-
opportunities for our products and capabilities. Dover Energy
0 0000000000 0
2007 2008 2009 2010 22001107 2008 2009 2010 20210107 2008 2009 2010 22001107 2008 2009 2010 20210107 2008 2009 2010 20210107 2008 2009 2010 2011
4,000 4,000 450 450 450
450 10 2.50 10 2.50 50 50
is in attractive markets with solid growth potential and is well- positioned for future growth.
us to offer a more comprehensive suite of products that address our customers’ key concerns, namely sustainability
2,000 2,000 225 225 225
225 5 1.25 5 1.25 25 25
and energy efficiency.
 Value Creation
($ in millions)
$12,000 9,00004,5001,1
6,000 3,000 7 3,000 1,500 3
00
2007 2008 2009 2010 20210107 2008 2009 2010 2011
Value Creation Lo
($ in millions)
($ in
$12,000 $6,000 $1,5
     9,00 6,00 3,00
                  0
            0
           0
         erm InvestmentLong-Term Investment Profitability MeasuresPro
ns) ($ in millions)
000 $1,500 $300 20% $300 20% 5001,125225522515 000750150015010 500 375 75 575 5
000000 2007 2008 2009 2010 20210107 2008 2009 2010 2011 2007 2008 2009 201
     1 1
                                2011 Revenue by Regi2o0n11 Revenue by Region
ng-T
millio
00$6,
254,
503,
751, 5
00
0 20210107 2008 20
Five Year Return* Five Year Return* Cash Dividends & StocCkasPhriDceividends & S 7
fitability Measu
20% 15 10
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            r
Market Capitalization
Revenue
Market Capitalization
Revenue
Stockholders’ Equity
Earnings from Continuing Operations Free Cash Flow
Acquisitions
Stockholders’ Equity
Earnings from Continuing Operations Free Cash Flow
Acquisitions
Capital Expenditures Return on Invested Capital
Free Cash Flow as a % of Revenue Dover
Capital Expenditures Return on Invested Capital
S&P 500
Return on Stockholders’ Equity
Free Cash Flow as a % of Revenue Dover

011
2007 2008 2009 2010 2011
011
■ United States 51% ■ Europe 17%
0
$8,000
6,000
4,000
2,000
$900
$900 20%
$5.00
Value Creation
markets, new product launches in marking and coding have
America and Europe. That model has shifted dramatically, as
450 450 Earnings from Continuing Operatio1n0s 2F.5re0e Cash Flow as a % of Revenue
($ in millions)
provided customers with better cost control and exceptional
75% of the pump products made in China2,0a0r0e now sold locally.
pri2n2t5ing perfor2m25ance, while also having a po5sitive envi1r.o25n-
We believe this shift is a telling example of the kind of growth
Revenue vs. Continuing Earnings Free Cash Flow
printing and marking applications that serve consumer goods
even stronger growth in our consumer goods and industrial
Revenue
Earnings from Continuing Operations
the potential for continued global growth. In addition, expo- sure to the consumer goods market, espe3c,0ia00lly as it relates to
and industrial markets, which we see as very attractive with
markets within DPI in 2012.
EPS Growth
global growth
1,500
emerging markets, bodes well for DPI’s growth outlook.
The geographic expansion of our end markets, especially in
2011 Revenue by Region
VFaliuveCYreatrioRn eturn*
DPI’s 2011 revenues grew by 8% to $1.6 billion, while earn-
the emerging and developing economies of the world, contin-
2007
$1.20
Cash Divide
.90 $1.20
$5.00 $100
ues to be a very important area of focus. In 2011, nearly $3.9
ings totaled $227 million, down 5% from the prior year. Solid results in our fast-moving consumer goods market were offset
$$121,,05000 $6,000 $1,500
2011 Revenue by Region by the weak alternative energy and semi-con markets, in
Five Year Return*
Asian market continued to be the fastest growing market for
3.75 75
ad2.d50ition to general economic50softness in Europe. However,
1,125 areexpanding6o,0u0r0sharedmanufacturingfaci3l,i0t0ie0sandopera-750
there is a solid mix of recurring revenue within DPI and the
750
5 1.25 25
1,125
.90
2007 2008 20
segment’s depth of product offerings and business mix will moderate the impact of a softer alternative energy market.
3,000
1,500 0
375 0
2007 2008 2009 2010 2011
■ Other Americas 10%
■ Total Asia 19% ■ United States 51%
2007 2008 375
2009
2010
2011
9,000
4,500
1,125
225 225
4,000 2,000
450 450 10
4,000 2,000
Free Cash Flow
($ in millions)
3.75
675 675
15
675 450
2007 2008 2009 2010 2011 Revenue
2007 2008 2009 2010 2011 Free Cash Flow
Free$C8a,s0h00Flow as a % of Revenue 6,000
Free Cash Flow
2007 2008 2009 2010 201 Revenue
$E9a0r0nings from Continuing Operation
Earnings from Continuing Operations
$900
Revenue vs. Continui2n2g5Earnings 225 ($ in millions)
($ in millions)
675 450
450 450
10 5
2.50 EPS G1.r2o5wth
225 225 5
Revenue vs. Continuing Earnings
($ in millions) 00000
This segment continues to grow in China and India where we One of DPI’s strengths is the ability to deliver a solutions-
00000
have invested in manufacturing facilitie$s8,,0w00hile greatly en- 2007 2008 2009 2010 2011
hancing our sales and engineering capabilities. For instance, in
6,000
4,000
2,000 225 225
our pumps business, when we opened our China facility three years ago we were exporting 80% of the products to North
675 675 15
3.75
00000
2007 2008 62,0009 2010 2011
0 0 0
.30
nt 0*
0
3,000
725007 2008 2009 2010 2011 150
375 75
10
2007 2008 2009 2010
5
Long-Term InvCesatsm
markets even better.
4,000
ba$s90e0d approa$c9h00, allowing the customer to2d0%erive high$e5.r00yield, 2007 2008 2009 2010 2011
increased throughput and quicker product launches. For
2007 2008 200
2007 2008 2009 2010 2
000
example, within the consumer goods and industrial end
2007 2008 2009 2010 2011
Revenue Free Cash Flow
Long-Term Investment
Profi
($ in millions)
mental impact. New and innovative mobile label printers are
($$in1m,5ill0ion0s) ($ in$m3il0lio0ns) 20% we expect to see in these markets. offering increased mobility solutions and new coding technolo-
2007 2008 2009 2010 2011 2007 2008 2009 2010 2011 2007 2008 2009 2010
$12,000 $6,000
20% $8,000 $1,000 0 0 0 0 0
gies within the retail and logistics markets. DPI’s new product Innovation,newproduc9t,d0e00velopmentandgrowthinemerging4,500 1,125 225 15
15 10 5 0
20% 15 10
.60 000 375750 .60.30
6,000 750
$8,000 $900 $900
economies will continue to drive the DES segment in the
500 Value Creation 6,000 ($ in millions)
offerings have gained traction across consumer and industrial
end markets, with moLorengla-TuenrmchIensvebsetminegnpt lanned for 2012. Profitability
4,000
years ahead.
6,000 675 675
2,000 250
The long-term growth potential in this market remains attrac-
1,500
dover printing & identification (dpi)
4,000 450 450
3,000 $12,000
Ne0arly 75% of the revenue i0n this segment is generated by
2,000
20% 5 225 15
3,000 750 ($ in millions) 150 10
tive, as energy demands and sustainability concerns continue to rise. Our investments in products and resources will drive
$6,000 375$1,500 $300 75
2007 2008 2009 2010 2011
00000 ($ in millions) ($ in millions)
2007 2008 2009 2010 2011 2007 2008 2009 2010 2011
billion of our sales occurred outside of the United States. The
9,000 4,500 1,125
Dover in 2011 with a growth rate of nearly 28%. In 2012, we
$1,500
tions in both China and India to help us serve these important
$300 225 150
15 15 10 10
■
■
■
■
Communi Technolo Energy Engineer Systems Printing Identifica
■ Rest of World 3% ■ Europe 17%
■ Other Americas 10%
2011 Revenue by Segme 20% 20%
 Profitability Measures
2011 Revenue by Segment
■ Total Asia 19%
■ Rest of World 3%
                                       755 5
000 2007 2008 2009 2010 2011
                    0
2007 2008 2009 2010 2011
2011 Reven0ue by Region Fiv
 $1,000 invested on 12/31/06 in Dover Stock or the S&P 500 including 2007 2008 2009 2010 2011
2011 Revenue by Region for fact sheet 8%
reinvestment of dividends
2011 Revenue by Region for fact sheet
$1,000 invested on 12/31/06 in Dover Stock or the S&P 500 including
rein
ve
stm
en
to
Technologies 17%
Energy ■■NorthAAmmereicraica
Engineered Systems Printing & Identification
■ Asia
■ Un1i9te%d States 51% ■ Europe 17%
■ Other Americas 10% ■ Total Asia 19%
■ Rest of World ■ Rest of World
37
$1,000 i reinvest
■ Rest of World 3%
2011 Revenue by Segment
f divi
den
ds
$1,50
1,12
 on Communication
56%
■ Asia 75
■ Europe ■ Europe
09 2010 2011
0
2007 2008 20
nvested on 12/31/06 in Dover St ment of dividends
2011 Revenue by Reg
Cash Dividends & Stock Price
nt
0
cati
5 ed■0
■
gies
■
&■ tion
8 ■ Communication Technologies
5
■ Energy
e Year Return
2007
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        2
e
1 s
9
2
2
he
n
0 o
i
Capital Expenditures Return on Invested Capital
Return on Stockholders’ Equity
Dover Corporation
S&P 500
S&P 500
Capital Expenditures
Free Cash Flow as a % of Revenue Dover
S&P 500
Market Capitalization Dover Corporation
Stockholders’ EquityRevenue Acquisitions
Earnings from Continuing Operations Free Cash Flow
Dover Corporation
Acquisitions
Annual Divdend
Annual Divdend
Capital Expenditures Return on Invested Capital
Stockholders’ Equity
Earnings from Continuing Operations Free Cash Flow
Free Cash Flow as a % of Revenue Dover
Free Cash Flow as a % of Revenue Dover
Acquisitions
Market Capitalization
Revenue
Market Capitalization
Revenue
Stockholders’ Equity
Earnings from Continuing Operations Free Cash Flow
Return on Invested Capital

$12,000 9,000 6,000
$6,000 4,500 3,000
$1,500$6,000 1,1254,500 7503,000
$1,500 $300 1,125 225 750 150
20% $300 15 225 10 150
20% 20% 20% 15 15 15 10 10 10
3,000 1,500 3751,500 375 75 5 75 5 5 5 00000000000
9 2010 20210107 2008 2009 2010 2011 2007 2008 2009 2010 20210107 2008 2009 2010 2011
gi2o0n11Revenue shD 0
2007 2008 2009 2010 20210107 2008 2009 2010 2011
 by Region
% 0%
by Segment
Five Year Return* $1,500
Five Year Return* Ca $1,500 $1.2 .9 .6 .3
   1,125 750 375 0
1,125
750 375 0
                                            2007 2008 2009 2010 20210107 2008 2009 2010 2011
  *$1,000 invested on 12/31/06 in Dover Stock*o$r1,t0h0e0Si&nvPe5s0te0dinocnlu1d2i/n3g1/06 in Dover Stock or the S&P 500 includi reinvestment of dividends reinvestment of dividends
2011 Revenue by Regi2o0n1f1orRfeavcetnsuhebety Region for fact s
 ividends&StocCkasPhriDceividends&StockPrice
$1.20 .90 .60 .30
$60 $60
45 45
30
15
                              3 1
0
            5
           00 2007 2008 2009 2010 20210107 2008 2009 2010 2011
t
0
         ■ United States 51 ■ Europe 17%
■ Other Americas 1 ■ Total Asia 19%
■ Rest of World 3% gm20e1n1t Revenue
■ Communication Technologies
0
0
0
0 ng
hee
■ Communication Technologies
■ North America
■ Engineered ■ Engineered ■ Asia ■ Asia
■ Energy
Systems Systems ■ Europe ■ Europe
■ Energy
In an effort to further strengthen our geographic expansion
closing thoughts
I’m proud of our achievements and results in 2011 and firmly believe we are very well-positioned as we enter 2012. Our new business structure enables us to better leverage the scale
of Dover and the expertise of our people in order to operate more efficiently and align ourselves more closely with our customers. Our focus will continue to be on growth and on our customers’ needs as we strive to deliver another excellent year of results for our shareholders.
In closing, I want to thank all of our nearly 34,000 employees for their tireless efforts and dedication. I also want to thank our customers and suppliers and pledge our continuing sup- port to maintaining true partnerships. In addition, thanks to the Board of Directors for their guidance and ongoing support as we continue to position Dover for growth and even greater successes in the future.
Sincerely,
Robert A. Livingston
President and Chief Executive Officer February 27, 2012
■ Printing & ■ Printing & ■ Rest of World ■ Rest of World efforts, we have also made significant sales and engineering
Identification Identification
investments in other key markets, including Brazil, Mexico, Russia, Australia and the Middle East.
investments for growth
With respect to acquisitions, we completed the most active year in our history by investing $1.4 billion to acquire nine businesses in our growth spaces, the most notable of these being Harbison-Fischer and Sound Solutions. On a full-year basis, these two acquisitions alone will add well over $700 million to revenue. Our acquisition pipeline remains active and we will certainly add additional businesses in 2012, primarily focused in our five growth spaces.
Besides acquisitions, we continued to invest aggressively in capacity expansion and productivity in several of our business- es. For example, we added significant capacity to our business serving the handset market in both Malaysia and China to support a very robust market. We expect additional invest- ments of this sort as the business continues to expand in 2012 and beyond. In the United States, we expanded capacity in our business that produces polycrystalline diamond cutters (PDCs) used in oil and gas exploration and drilling. Both expansion projects strengthened our customer positioning and allowed us to build on our market leadership. We also added impor- tant R&D and testing capabilities to support our refrigeration customers, and we opened a manufacturing facility in Oman to serve the Energy market.
■ North America
 9
                                                                                                                                                                                         0
Dover Corporation
Acquisitions
Dover Corporation
Acquisitions
S&P 500
Capital Expenditures Return on Invested Capital
Annual Divdend
S&P 500
Capital Expenditures Return on Invested Capital
Annual Divdend
Closing Stock Price
Return on Stockholders’ Equity
Closing Stock Price
Return on Stockholders’ Equity
Market Capitalization
Stockholders’ Equity
Stockholders’ Equity
