FIFTH THIRD BANCORP AND SUBSIDIARIES
Dear Shareholders and Friends:
We achieved record earnings for the 28th year in a row, despite a weak economy, while we simultaneously integrated the largest and most successful acquisition in our history. We have one of the strongest balance sheets in the industry, proven expense discipline and considerable market share growth potential.
  George A. Schaefer, Jr.
President & CEO
 We continued to grow throughout
2001 by adding to and expanding
relationships with customers in our existing
markets and by taking advantage of our opportunities in new markets provided by
four acquisitions. Our employees are to be
commended for their focus and dedication
in carefully completing the integration of
these acquisitions while maintaining our
p e r f o r m a n c e t r a c k r e c o r d . T h i s y e a r ’s
financial performance was marked by continued strong revenue growth, improved efficiency, stable credit quality despite the challenges of an uncertain environment and the successful integration of Old Kent. Compared to the year 2000,
􏹳 Operating earnings increased 15% to $1.4 billion, or $2.37 per diluted share;
􏹳 Revenue increased 12% to $4.2 billion;
􏹳 Transaction deposits rose 28% to $31.1 billion;
􏹳 Service revenues increased on double-digit growth from nearly each of our four main lines of business— Retail and Commercial Banking, Investment Advisors and Midwest Payment Systems (MPS), our electronic payment processing subsidiary. MPS led the growth with an annual increase in revenues of 38%. The successful sales of Retail and Commercial deposit relationships fueled an annual increase in deposit service revenues of 23%. Investment Advisors service revenues increased nine percent, while total revenues grew 11%, despite equity market weakness for much of 2001;
􏹳 The quality ratings on our senior debt and commercial paper remained at an all- time high. Moody’s awarded our senior debt an Aa3 rating, while our commercial paper received ratings of Prime–1 from Moody’s and A–1+ from Standard & Poors, which attest to our safety and stability;
Quarterly cash dividends, which have been paid for 105 consecutive quarters, were increased twice in 2001—from $.18 per share to $.20 per share last March and then to $.23 per share
last December, a 19% increase for the year;
􏹳 Our capital ratio improved to 10.28%, representing an additional billion dollars in shareholder equity and one of the best capitalized balance sheets in the industry; and
􏹳 Return on average equity was 19.2% on an expanded capital base and our return on average assets was 1.97%.
Growth Opportunities Continue
􏹳 Our four main lines of business continue to provide diverse income sources, and customer and revenue growth momentum is as strong as at any time in our history.
􏹳 We are also at the strongest capital position in our history as a result of acquiring only companies that quickly contribute to corporate earnings, a disciplined credit policy, productive expense controls and a fierce, competitive drive to win new customers—basic
􏹳
 2

2001 ANNUAL REPORT
  operating principles that are the foundation of our corporate culture.
􏹳 We expect to increase market share by taking advantage of the significant momentum building in our larger markets. Presently, only one in
16 residents in our market areas banks
with us. Further, our current 5.1 million customer base provides us ample room to grow profitably through the cross-sell of additional banking products.
􏹳 Finally, customers traditionally seek strong institutions in a weak economy. No other bank in our markets has a better record for strength or for delivering financial solutions.
Operating Model
Unlike most in our industry, we continue to execute a basic, yet proven, operating model that strives to make decisions closer to the customer. We remain a collection of decentralized banking operations centered in each of our major metropolitan markets. The challenges to grow and the competition are different in each of our markets, so the authority, responsibility and accountability for growth are placed in the hands of local managers. No matter how large we become, we believe this operating philosophy is the primary reason we consistently achieve the highest overall performance in the banking industry.
Acquisitions
We made four acquisitions last year: a money management firm, an electronic payment processor, and two bank holding companies. By far, the largest acquisition was Old Kent Financial, which was about half our size. Apart from acquiring many new customers and deposits, we obtained a formidable presence throughout Michigan, a stronger base in Chicago, greater market share across northern Indiana, and access to approxi- mately 16 million potential new customers.
We are well on our way to achieving the financial objectives from these transactions and look forward to their continued earnings
opportunities. More importantly, the 2001 results prove that we are unwilling to compromise the performance and balance sheet quality our shareholders have come to expect.
Directors
We welcomed three new members to our Board from Old Kent: James P. Hackett, President, CEO and Director of Steelcase, Inc.; Hendrik G. Meijer, Co-Chairman of Meijer, Inc.; and David J. Wagner, formerly Chairman, President and CEO of Old Kent and now Chairman of Fifth Third Bank Michigan.
Gerald V. Dirvin, former Executive Vice President of T he Procter & Gamble Company, and Brian H . Rowe, former President and CEO of GE Aircraft Engines, retired from our Board last year, after 12 and 21 years of service, respectively. T heir guidance and leadership were outstanding, and we will miss them greatly.
Conclusion
I would like to thank our Board members and employees for their hard work in producing another rewarding year for our shareholders. Their accomplishments created an even stronger growth company. The recognized financial strength of our balance sheet, the flexibility provided by $7.6 billion in equity capital, sales opportunities in both our new and existing markets and a culture of simply executing better on the basics serve to effectively position us to continue to deliver consistent earnings growth in the future. I look forward to the challenges that lie ahead in 2002.
Sincerely,
George A. Schaefer, Jr. President & CEO January 2002
 Market Capitalization
 (in billions)
$35.7
$34.0
$27.7 $26.5
$20.2
$10.5
96 97 98 99 00 01
                                                  Operating Earnings Per Diluted Share*
   2.37 2.10
1.83 1.63
1.37 1.20
96 97 98 99 00 01
* Excludes SAIF and Merger Charges
                                                 Total Equity
 (in billions)
$7.6 $6.7
$5.4 $5.6 $4.7 $5.0
                                                   96 97 98 99 00 01
3
28% Five Year Compound Growth Rate
15% Five Year Compound Growth Rate
10% Five Year Compound Growth Rate
