 Fluor Corporation 1999 Annual Report
 TO OUR SHAREHOLDERS
Fiscal 1999 marked significant progress towards achieving a number of impor­ tant objectives. We steered Fluor in a
new strategic direction to reposition the company as a knowledge-based professional services and engineering, procurement and construction (EPC) company, with a significant investment in low-sulfur coal.
 REPOSITIONING Fluor for enhanced
 shareholder VALUE
  Fiscal 1999 was a disappointing year in terms of achieving earnings growth and improving our return on investment. The environment was unfavorable for many of our EPC and global services businesses and for Massey Coal. Initiatives to mit­ igate this difficult environment were successful and allowed us to achieve profit expectations for the year. Net earnings, excluding the effect in total of a special provision, were $204.7 million, or $2.70 per share, compared with $235.3 million, or $2.97 per share in 1998.
New Strategic Direction
Our new strategic direction, which was announced in March, included a number of components. The company has been realigned into four principal Strategic Business Enterprises (SBE’s), each with clear performance accountability. Specific actions included clarifying roles and responsibilities as we implemented our new strategy, substantially reducing our costs, enhancing our project execution, and increasing selectivity in the projects and customers we serve.
The company’s engineering and construction segment is now managed as two distinct SBE’s: Fluor Daniel, which will focus purely on EPC opportunities; and Fluor Global Services, a diverse, but integrated portfolio of services designed to capitalize on increasing growth opportunities outside the traditional EPC value chain. Fluor Constructors, Inc. continues in its role as the union craft arm of Fluor Corporation. A.T. Massey, our Coal SBE, continues to focus on leveraging its exceptional management and market position to enhance shareholder value through emphasis on stronger cash flow and return on investment. Another SBE was cre­ ated with the formation of Fluor Signature Services (FSS). This new enterprise is an important element of our new strategic direction and represents a new approach to providing business and administrative support services to Fluor operating units. By assigning responsibility for the delivery of these important services to
     Page 2

 Fluor Corporation 1999 Annual Report
FSS, operating units are now able to devote their full energies on their core business activities. Additionally, the consolidation of business services within FSS will reduce costs, improve quality standards, and over time, provide an incremental earnings stream to the corporation.
Other key milestones achieved in 1999 included a reduction in gross overhead expenses by $160 million annually which is expected to result in cost savings beginning in 2000 of $100-120 million annually. Accomplishing this goal required closure of non­ strategic offices and a reduction in personnel of
approximately 5,000. This cost reduction is expected to translate into higher profit margins as our strategies and more selective market focus begin to stimulate renewed volume growth. A detailed business model process was implemented throughout the company to set priorities, assure financial discipline, enhance accountability and establish a culture of financial transparency. Meaningful progress was also achieved in driving increased selectivity towards higher-margin business opportunities. Selectivity is a continuing strategy across the company and will be supported by the recently formed global account management organization, reporting directly to me. Their primary objective is to broaden and strengthen relationships with our most important clients.
We also launched two important initiatives that will
significantly impact our businesses in the coming years:
processes and information management systems that will improve access to and use of company knowledge and the timeliness of financial and operating information; and a new brand architecture to create a visual identity for our new company structure and competitive strat­ egy, linking our diverse range of services under the Fluor name, while creating individual identities for each of our Strategic Business Enterprises.
While much has been accomplished in 1999, further improvement is required to achieve our goals for sustained long-term earnings growth and higher levels of profitability, leading to enhanced shareholder value. We remain committed to our goals of achieving a return on assets above our cost of capital and deliv­ ering earnings per share growth of at least 10 percent annually. We are also committed to growing the capa­ bility of our organization individually and collectively so that we can more profitably serve customer needs.
Financial Condition
Fluor’s financial condition remains strong, with both our debt ratio and interest coverage supporting a solid “A” investment grade credit rating. We significantly reduced short-term debt during the year which lowered our total debt to capitalization ratio to 26 percent from 32 percent a year ago. We are aggressively working to reduce the level of assets employed in our businesses to further enhance returns.
As a sign of our improving business outlook and continuing financial strength, Fluor’s Board of Directors declared a 25 percent increase in the quarterly divi­ dend for 2000 to 25 cents per share, compared with 20 cents in 1999. Additionally, our dividend policy was changed for the first time in many years. The payout
Knowledge@Work
SM
— a major revamping of our work
Page 3

 Fluor Corporation 1999 Annual Report
guideline was increased to 30-35 percent of earnings from the previous 25-30 percent, and will now be based on long-term operating performance expectations. Previously, our dividend payout was based on the company’s prior year’s earnings performance.
Fluor Daniel
Faced with continuing weakness in several global economic markets and abnormally low oil prices at the beginning of 1999, Fluor Daniel implemented actions to mitigate the effects of a deteriorating business envi­ ronment, as well as steps to reposition the company for long-term profitability and growth. Marketing and sales efforts were focused on a narrower client base where differentiated value could be delivered, offering higher margin potential. Backlog and new awards declined in 1999, as expected from a year ago, pri­ marily reflecting the market slow down experienced over the past two years, along with our emphasis on improving margins. However, increased selectivity, accompanied by cost reductions and increased account­ ability, began to produce positive results. Reported gross margin, along with new awards and backlog gross margins, all achieved meaningful improvement in 1999. Continuing improvement in global economic conditions which are favorable to increased capital spending by clients is creating growing optimism for new business in 2000 and beyond.
Fluor Global Services
Formed in 1999, Fluor Global Services brings together a variety of non-EPC services capabilities. These services
offer attractive incremental revenue growth and earnings for Fluor as the result of changing client needs and the continuing trend toward outsourcing. Importantly, Fluor Global Services has the potential to significantly broaden our participation in our clients’ total spending across the entire life cycle of their asset base. The majority of the services provided by Fluor Global Services have a more stable and predictable earn­ ings pattern which should help mitigate the more cycli­ cal nature of our traditional EPC business.
We are particularly encouraged by the outstand­ ing growth potential for Fluor Global Services’ Telecommunications unit, which was awarded several key contracts in 1999, with significant additional work anticipated in 2000. The Operations & Maintenance unit is also benefiting from its new strategic approach to delivering value in this large and growing market.
A.T. Massey Coal
A.T. Massey delivered commendable performance in 1999 despite an extremely challenging coal market. They are an acknowledged leader in the U.S. coal industry and continue to outperform industry peers on virtually every criteria, from financial results to safety performance.
Global economic conditions, unfavorable currency exchange rates, and mild weather created difficult con­ ditions in both Massey’s steam coal and higher-margin metallurgical coal markets. This resulted in softened demand and deteriorating prices for coal. To offset these conditions, Massey implemented a number of opera­ tional changes to reduce costs and maintain operating margins, as well as optimize return on assets. As the lowest cost producer in its geographic market, Massey is much better positioned to withstand these difficult times than its competition.
Page 4

 Fluor Corporation 1999 Annual Report
Fluor Signature Services
Fluor Signature Services is our newest Strategic Business Enterprise. It officially began operations at the start of 2000. Created as a distinct enterprise with profit-and­ loss accountability, its charter is to provide business and administration support services to Fluor’s operat­ ing units. Their immediate goal is to help the corpo­ ration further reduce costs, streamline work processes and to identify and measure where value is created within the company.
Management Changes
As part of the organizational restructuring, Alan Boeckmann has assumed leadership of Fluor Daniel, Jim Stein is now leading Fluor Global Services, and Don Blankenship continues to lead A.T. Massey Coal. Jim Rollans, our former chief financial officer, is head­ ing up Fluor Signature Services.
In June, we were pleased to welcome Ralph Hake as executive vice president and chief financial officer, suc­ ceeding Jim Rollans. Ralph joins us from Whirlpool where he served since 1987, overseeing various global business and financial operations, most recently as senior executive vice president and chief financial officer.
Thank You
I would like to extend my personal appreciation to our board of directors and employees for the tremendous effort that has been undertaken to reposition our company and achieve our goal to deliver improved shareholder value in the years to come.
I am confident that we are moving well down the path to realize the potential we envision from our new strategic direction.
Lastly, let me add my appreciation for the support and confidence of our shareholders who have stayed with us through our transition to a new Fluor in the new millennium.
Philip J. Carroll, Jr.
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer January 13, 2000
  Page 5
