o Our Share Owners, Employees and Customers
 Chairman and Chief Executive Officer John F. Welch, Jr. (center) and Vice Chairmen and Executive Officers Dennis D. Dammerman (left), Eugene F. Murphy (back) and John D. Opie (right) form GE’s Corporate Executive Office.
1998 was another terrific year for your Company — another record year.
  ▪ Revenues rose to $100.5 billion, up 11%. ▪ Earnings increased 13% to $9.3 billion. ▪ Earnings per share grew 14% to $2.80.
▪ Operating margin rose to a record 16.7%, up a full point from the record 15.7% of 1997. Working capital turns rose sharply to 9.2, up from 1997’s record of 7.4.
▪ This performance generated $10 billion in free cash flow, which, in combination with a “AAA” debt rating, allowed us to invest $21 billion for 108 acquisitions in support
of two of our three Company-wide initia- tives: Globalization and Services.
▪ Record cash flow allowed us to raise dividends by 17% and to further increase share owner value by repurchasing an additional $3.6 billion in GE stock.
▪ In 1998, GE was named Fortune magazine’s “Most Admired Company in America” and “The World’s Most Respected Company” by a worldwide business audience in the Financial Times.
               Our share owners — including our active and retired employees, who now own more than $17 billion in GE stock in their savings plans — were rewarded for these actions and this performance — the total return on a share of GE stock was 41% in 1998. GE has averaged a 24% per-year total return to share owners for the past 18 years.
        1
 T
         
 T his performance, year after year, is the product of Life and quickly became a force in the Japanese insurance
a diverse and powerful portfolio of leading global
businesses. This performance has been driven this decade by three big Company-wide growth initiatives: Globalization, Services and Six Sigma quality.
These initiatives, in turn, have been rapidly advanced by a General Electric culture that values the contributions of every individual, thrives on learning, thirsts for the better idea, and has the flexibility and speed to put the better idea into action every day.
We are a learning company, a company that studies its own successes and failures and those of others — a com- pany that has the self-confidence and the resources to take big swings and pursue numerous opportunities based on winning ideas and insights, regardless of their source.
That appetite for learning, and the ability to act quickly on that learning, will provide GE with what we believe is an insurmountable and sustainable competitive advantage as we pursue our three big growth initiatives.
Globalization is the first of those initiatives.
Last year we wrote to you as the difficulties in Asia were causing global uncertainty and unease.
We, like everyone else, had not foreseen these difficulties, but we quickly viewed Asia as similar in many respects to the Europe of the early 1990s — in need of various structural remedies but rich in opportunity. In the case of Europe — and in the case of Mexico in the mid-’90s — we moved decisively and were rewarded with significant and rapid growth. We have grown fourfold in Europe, from a relatively small GE presence in 1990 to $24 billion in revenues in 1998.
The GE of the next century must provide high- value global products and services, designed by global talent, for global markets.
We learned from our European successes and saw in Japan the opportunity to do it again — only faster.
We acquired the business infrastructure and sales force
of Toho Mutual Life, and — because of the high respect the Japanese have for Thomas Edison — we renamed it GE Edison
industry. We also acquired the consumer loan business of Japan’s Lake Corporation, with $6.2 billion in assets, and added it to our already rapidly growing consumer finance business there. These acquisitions, along with several other ventures, partnerships and buyouts by our industrial businesses, together with the growth of our ongoing existing businesses in Japan, should allow us to more than double our over $300 million in 1998 Japanese earnings within three years.
Our Japanese initiatives are part of an intense multiyear focus on globalization that produced $43 billion in revenues in 1998 and a growth rate for GE outside the United States that has been double our U.S. growth rate for 10 years.
 Growth Through Globalization
(In billions) $105
  Global 15%
Average Annual 84 Growth Rate
Domestic 6% Average Annual Growth Rate
    63
    42
     21
0
  1987 1991 1995 1996 1997 1998
    But market success is only part of globalization. We must globalize every activity in the Company. We’ve made some progress in sourcing products and components so critical to survive and win in a price-competitive deflationary world, but our challenge is to go beyond that — to capitalize on the vast intellectual capital available around the globe. In 1999, we will move aggressively to broaden our definition of globalization by increasing the intensity of our effort to search out and attract the unlimited pool of talent that is available in the countries in which we do business — from software designers in India to product engineers in Mexico, Eastern Europe and China.
The GE of the next century must provide high-value global products and services, designed by global talent, for global markets.
Product services is a second continuing growth ini- tiative. This initiative has already changed the headset of the Company from that of a provider of products augmented
  2

by ancillary services to a Company that is overwhelmingly a source of customer-focused, high-value, information technology-based productivity solutions — as well as a provider of high-quality products.
With this initiative, as with globalization, we are broadening our definition of services — from the traditional activities of parts replacement, overhauling and reconditioning high-value machines like jet engines, turbines, medical equipment
and locomotives, to a larger and bolder vision. We have the engineering, the R&D, the product knowledge, the resources and the management commitment to make the series of hun- dred-million-dollar investments that will allow us to truly change the performance of our installed base, and by doing so upgrade the competitiveness and profitability of our cus- tomers: utilities, hospitals, railroads, factories and airlines.
By adding higher and higher technology to the customers’ installed base of machines, we will have the capability of returning them to operation not just “overhauled” but with better fuel burn rates in engines, higher efficiency in turbines, better resolutions in CT scanners, and the like.
The ability to go beyond “servicing” to, in essence, “reengineering the installed base” will dramatically improve our customers’ competitive positions.
tional effects this science, this way of life and work, had on the few companies that pursued it, we plunged into Six Sigma with a Company-consuming vengeance just over three years ago. We have invested more than a billion dollars in the effort, and the financial returns have now entered the exponential phase — more than three quarters of a billion dollars in savings beyond our investment in 1998, with a billion and a half in sight for 1999.
The Six Sigma-driven savings are impressive, but it is the radical change in the overall measures of operating efficiency that excite us most. For years — decades — we have been straining to improve operating margin and working capital turns. Our progress was typically measured in basis points for margins and decimal points in working capital turns. Six Sigma came along in 1995 when our margins were in the 13.6% range and turns at 5.8. At the end of 1998, margins hit 16.7% and turns hit 9.2. These numbers are an indicator of the progress and momentum in our Six Sigma journey.
The ratio of plant and equipment expenditures to depre- ciation is another measure of asset efficiency. This number in 1998 dropped to 1.2 and will be in the .7–.8 range in the future, as “hidden factory” after “hidden factory”— literally “free capacity” — is uncovered by Six Sigma process improvements.
All this has taken place in just over three years, after the quarter million of us hurled ourselves into this unknown way of life and work.
 Growth Through Product Services
(In billions) $ 20
  16
12
  8
  4
0
  1995 1996 1997 1998 2000 estimate
  Six Sigma Progress
(In millions) $ 2500
 Cost Benefit
2000
   1500
 1000
 500
    0
  1996 1997 1998 1999
estimate
       In product services, as with globalization, the new expanding view of both initiatives is driven by the insatiable learning culture inherent in the Company today, learning from each other, across businesses, across cultures, and from other companies.
Six Sigma quality, our third growth initiative, is, in itself, a product of learning. After observing the transforma-
Year three of Six Sigma shows how far we have come in training ourselves — with 5,000 full-time “Master Black Belts” and “Black Belts” driving scores of thousands of quality
 3

projects around the globe, and with virtually every single pro- fessional in the Company a “Green Belt,” extensively trained and with a project completed.
As measured by internal performance improvements, and the enhancement of share owner value, Six Sigma has been an unqualified success.
The first major products designed for Six Sigma are just now coming into the marketplace and beginning to touch some of our customers. The new LightSpeedTM CT scanner and the new TrueTempTM electric range, to name two, are drawing unprecedented customer accolades because they were, in essence, designed by the customer, using all of the critical-to-quality performance features (CTQs) the customer wanted in the product and then subjecting these CTQs to the rigorous statistical Design For Six Sigma process.
The LightSpeed scanner, the first multislice CT to reach the market, is a godsend to patients who, for example, now have to endure a chest scan for only 17 seconds compared with the 3 minutes it takes with a conventional CT. A patient with a pulmonary embolism, usually in breathing distress, must lie in a conventional scanner for nearly half a minute com- pared with 6 seconds for the LightSpeed. A trauma patient, for whom time-to-diagnosis is a literal life-or-death matter, can have a full-body scan in 26 seconds instead of the 3 minutes a single-slice CT scanner requires. Hospitals, for their part, now get a much higher utilization rate and hence lower per-scan costs. The reception of this product has been remarkable, with $60 million in orders in the first 90 days and with customer acceptance levels and endorsements never before seen.
Every new GE product and service in the future will be “DFSS” — Designed For Six Sigma. These new offerings will truly take us to a new definition of “World Class.”
Yes, we’ve had some early product successes, and those customers who have been touched by them understand what this Six Sigma they’ve heard so much about really means. But, as we celebrate our progress and count our financial gain, we need to focus on the most powerful piece of learning we have been given in 1998, summarized perfectly in the form of what most of our customers must be thinking, which is: “When do I get the benefits of Six Sigma?” “When does my company get to experience the GE I read about in the GE Annual Report?”
Questions like these are being asked because, up to now, our Six Sigma process improvements have concen- trated primarily on our own internal processes and on internal measurements such as “order-to-delivery” or “shop turnaround time.”
And in focusing that way — inwardly on our processes — we have tended to use all our energy and Six Sigma sci- ence to “move the mean” to, for example, reduce order-to- delivery times from an average of, say, 17 days to 12 days, as reflected in the example below. We’ve repeated this type of improvement over and over again in thousands of GE processes and have been rewarded for it with less “rework” and greater cash flow. The problem is, as has been said, “the mean never happens,” and the customer who looks at this chart, or charts like it, is still seeing variances in when the deliveries actually occur — a heroic 4-day delivery time on one order, with an awful 20-day delay on another, and no real consistency. The customers in this chart feel nothing. Their life hasn’t changed; their profitability hasn’t increased one bit. These customers hear the sounds of celebration coming from within GE walls and ask, “What’s the big event; what did we miss?” The customer only feels the variance that we have not yet removed.
 Example
Customer Dashboard: Customer XYZ Dashboard Dial: Order to Delivery Time
 Order by Order Delivery Times
Performance Mean
Starting Point
29 Days 18
16
19
33
15
17 Days
After Project
11 Days 24
10
6 12 88
Mean — Big Change 17 Days 12 Days
Variance — Almost No Change
  7 19 6
  15 10 4 20
12 Days
   Customers Feel Variance!
4
Our challenge, as we move toward 2000, is to turn our Company vision “outside in,” to measure the parameters of the customers’ needs and processes and work toward zero variability in serving them. Variation is evil in any cus- tomer-touching process. Improvement to our internal processes is of no interest to the customer.

In 1999, our customers will feel and enjoy the same benefits of Six Sigma that we have been experiencing internally. We will improve variability. We will make this happen. The impetus for this change will come not only from the business leaders but also from the first of the pioneering Six Sigma GE leaders who have now completed their “tours” and have been pro- moted into leadership positions in the businesses. They are now General Managers, Directors of Finance, Vice Presidents of Sales, Vice President of the Audit Staff, President of GE Mexico, and the like — big jobs.
This next generation of senior GE leadership, and the suc- ceeding waves of Black Belts, share a camaraderie and an esprit forged by their Six Sigma training and the experiences of their tours. They are already predisposed toward hiring only those fluent in Six Sigma language and adept at its methodol- ogy. Within a few years, the work culture and the management style of General Electric will be indelibly, irreversibly, Six Sigma — and it will be focused on the customer’s success.
These new leaders are changing the very DNA of GE culture. Work-Out, in the ’80s, opened our culture up to ideas from everyone, everywhere, killed NIH (Not Invented Here) thinking, decimated the bureaucracy, and made boundaryless behavior a reflexive and natural part of our culture, thereby creating the learning culture that led to Six Sigma. Now,
Six Sigma, in turn, is embedding quality thinking — process thinking — across every level and in every operation in our Company around the globe.
Work-Out in the 1980s defined how we behave. Today, Six Sigma is defining how we work.
The two initiatives — Services and Six Sigma — have one common theme: Only when tomorrow’s product and service offerings from GE significantly reduce the plant and equipment expenditures of our customers and increase their productivity will we have fulfilled the GE Services and Six Sigma vision.
These, then, are the three initiatives — Globalization, Services and Six Sigma — fueling powerful growth in your Company and transforming its culture and its soul.
These initiatives are being driven across the businesses and across the globe by a unique brand of 21st century busi- ness leader — the GE “A” player, the leader who embodies
what we call the four “E’s”: high E nergy; the ability to E ner- gize others; “E dge,” the ability to make the tough calls; and finally E xecute, the consistent ability to turn vision into results.
These “A” players, driving these initiatives, have trans- formed the very nature of GE — what it does and how well and how quickly it does it.
The two initiatives — Services and Six Sigma — have one common theme: Only when tomor- row’s product and service offerings from GE significantly reduce the plant and equipment expenditures of our customers and increase their productivity will we have fulfilled the
GE Services and Six Sigma vision.
With our three initiatives, these “A” players will broaden our globalization vision beyond markets and products to the pursuit of the best intellectual capital in the world.
“A” players will see the mission of product services as investing in technology to change our customers’ productivity equation and enhance their competitiveness.
And finally, they will turn the face of Six Sigma outward toward the customer and make that customer’s profitability the number one priority in any process improvement.
What does a Company with an incredible array of leading global businesses, a learning culture and a depth of “A” player leadership talent have to worry about as we approach the next century? What should keep it awake at night?
Not much, but history points a warning finger toward the arrogance and complacency that have caused others to stum- ble. It points to the sheer size that has slowed them and limited their agility to change quickly in this era of rapid change.
Already, as we approach the millennium, the pundits are hard at work. Predictions of trends and megatrends are in full production. Their record for accuracy has been spotty, at best. Most recently, less than two years ago, the conven- tional view of Asia was still one of “onward and upward” without interruption.
  5

 Looking back much further, to 20 years ago, when a new GE team moved into leadership, the prognostications were, in many cases, spectacularly inaccurate.
􏰥 In 1980, with oil at $35 a barrel, the big questions were when would it hit $100 or if it would be available at all.
􏰥 Japan in 1980 seemed to be in inexorable ascendancy, invading and dominating complacent industry after industry. Future American generations were doomed to menial work. The U.S. was losing confidence, experiencing “malaise.”
􏰥 Twenty years ago, everything was predicated on the expectation of a never-ending double-digit inflationary environment.
Obviously, these trends did not play out — quite the reverse.
Oil is at record lows, Japan is struggling, and the U.S. has moved from “malaise” to exuberance — irrational or not. Inflation has yielded to deflation as the shaping economic force.
So what does this tell us about the future? It tells us that what’s as important as predicting trends is a company’s ability to cope with any trend.
Sure, early in the next century, Japan will rebound. Oil prices are bound to rise again. Inflation is probably not dead. But spending a lot of time putting too fine a point on the “how” and “when” any of these might happen is less impor- tant than growing a culture that is both challenged by the unexpected and confident in, as well as capable of, dealing with whatever comes along.
That’s why so much about leading a big company is about assuring that it stays agile, unencumbered by bureaucracy or lulled by complacency — keeping it a company that breathes information, loves change and is excited by the opportunity change presents. It means never allowing a company to take itself too seriously, and reminding it constantly, in the face of any praise or good press, that yesterday’s press clippings often wrap today’s fish.
Crossing the $100 billion mark in revenue, as we did in 1998, was a milestone, just as the $10 billion mark in earnings will be, but that’s all they are — good for a quick pat on the back.
Yes, GE has become a very big company, and with the growth initiatives we have under way, we have every inten- tion of becoming a lot bigger.
So what does this tell us about the future? It tells us that what’s as important as pre- dicting trends is a company’s ability to cope with any trend.
But bigger is only better if a company understands and is committed to using the unique advantages of size.
As a big, global, multibusiness company, we have access to an enormous amount of information — and with our learning culture, we have the ability to acquire, share and act rapidly on that information to turn it into marketplace advantage.
Size gives us another big advantage: our reach and resources enable us to go to bat more frequently, to take more swings, to experiment more, and, unlike a small com- pany, we can miss on occasion and get to swing again.
What size cannot be allowed to do to a big company is to let it fall to the temptation of “managing” its size rather than “using” it. We can never stop swinging! At the same time, we must always be striving to capture the best of a small company — its energy, excitement and speed.
We move into 1999 filled with high expectations and with the confidence that we have the right initiatives, the right culture and the right leadership teams — teams with the agility and speed to seize the big opportunities we know this changing world will present us.
Thanks for your continuing support.
   John F. Welch, Jr. Chairman of the Board and Chief Executive Officer
Eugene F. Murphy
Vice Chairman of the Board and Executive Officer
February 12, 1999
Dennis D. Dammerman Vice Chairman of the Board and Executive Officer
John D. Opie
Vice Chairman of the Board and Executive Officer
                  6
