    To our Stockholders:
In 2003 Humana continued to advance its strategy of disrupting the industry, transforming the company and accelerating our growth. In the process, each of our business segments – serving our diversified customer base of national accounts, middle-market, small group, individual, dental, senior products and military – was profitable, and revenue and membership reached record levels.
This breakthrough success reaffirms our view that the marketplace is looking for a company that parts ways with the industry and offers a sustainable solution to the problem of skyrocketing health benefit costs that reduce business investment and limit employee buying power. Humana saw this scenario unfolding several years ago, and in response we designed a total solution that represents the next step after managed care.
This design required replacing old notions with new ideas.
First, we rejected the conventional wisdom that,
given the health care system’s complexity, employees
are destined to remain disengaged from the kind of informed decision-making that they exercise in other aspects of their economic lives. Second, we determined that even innovative products that stand alone aren’t sufficient. We surround our plan designs with a process that includes coordinated electronic tools, high-touch member outreach and consumer education programs throughout the plan year. Finally, we recognized that our role has changed from a commodity claims-payer to a value-added benefits coordinator, offering expert guidance to our customers and members – on everything from pretax finance options to predictive modeling – while preserving their ability to make choices that are right for themselves and their families.
These efforts produced our success in 2003 and established a platform for sustained momentum in 2004.
In the course of the past year, we extended the ongoing improvement in our Commercial business segment, with substantial increases in membership and profitability. In the government sector, the Medicare Modernization Act, signed into law in early December, opened new opportunities for us. We were one of the first Medicare health plan contractors 20 years ago and we have a wealth of successful experience meeting the needs of our nation’s seniors. Financially, 2003 saw appreciable margin expansion and an increase in both operating cash flows and balance sheet liquidity.
For the year, our earnings per share of $1.41 increased 66 percent over the $0.85 recorded in 2002.
2003 Milestones
Among Humana’s many accomplishments in 2003 were these highlights:
Š We successfully positioned our Commercial segment as a meaningful contributor to our consolidated results, accounting for 35 percent of our pretax income in 2003, a record for this segment.
Š Sales of our unique, consumer-choice Smart product family continued to accelerate. Medical cost trend for the early adopting customers is averaging in the mid-single digits.
 Michael B. McCallister, Director, President and Chief Executive Officer (left) David A. Jones, Chairman of the Board (right)
    
    Š We launched our individual product, HumanaOne, in 14 states and currently have more than 50,000 members enrolled. Our expectations are for a continuation of this strong trend in growth.
Š The Department of Defense awarded us the TRICARE contract for the new South region, recognizing our leadership and expertise in the specialized business of providing health benefits to military families and retirees.
Š Our increased administrative efficiency led to the consolidation of seven service centers into four. The transition was effected seamlessly, with no disruption in service to our members.
Š We completed the sales and distribution infrastructure investments necessary to make us a leader in multiple segments of the health benefits industry.
Leading by Disruption
In terms of our relationship to the industry, in 2003 we continued our drive to redefine value in health benefits.
Our total solution – uniting wide choice in plan offerings with a robust menu of consumer-engagement tools, education and programs – is not a product in the traditional sense, but a new process-around-product. It achieves two breakthrough outcomes: it reduces double-digit health cost inflation to mid-single digits, and it empowers consumers to choose and use their benefits with confidence, producing a better health-plan experience for employees and their families.
Success in this new space was recognized in July when Forrester Research named Humana the industry leader in health benefits consumerism. In rating Humana first for both its strategy and current offerings, Forrester commented, “Humana positions its CDHP [Consumer Directed Health Plan] offerings as part of a broad spectrum of employer and employee product options and wraps them all with exceptional online services and tools.”
This “wrapping” is the essence of the process-around-product in the Smart family of Humana plans. By providing guidance and actionable information, much of it through Internet technology, Humana transforms passive health-care users into active health-care consumers. Employees then start for the first time making informed health spending decisions in their own economic self-interest – and thus by extension in their employer’s.
This total solution now involves more than 200,000 Smart members. In addition, we have been renewing 100 percent of the eligible early adopters. In a related extension of our consumer expertise, the technology-driven services that support consumer engagement within the Smart family are increasingly being applied across the board to our traditional Commercial, Medicare and TRICARE membership.
A Strategic Acquisition
In December, we announced our intent to acquire Ochsner Health Plan of Louisiana, a market leader both in New Orleans and throughout the state. The addition of Ochsner provides us the opportunity to enter a new market with critical mass, the support of solid provider contracts and the opportunity to introduce a host of innovative products to this market.
Ochsner is an excellent fit for us strategically from many perspectives. It provides an opportunity to broaden our footprint, making us more attractive in the mid-market and national account space. It enables us to leverage our existing presence in the Texas markets with our new presence in Louisiana – a key attribute due to the number of companies that have overlap between these two geographies. And it overlays with our soon-to-be- expanded TRICARE presence in the new South region.
    
    We anticipate the transaction to close early in the second quarter of this year, pending Department of Insurance approval. We will continue to evaluate opportunities for potential acquisitions that – like Ochsner – fit strategically and provide an appropriate return on our invested capital, thus adding to shareholder value.
Commercial Segment
While we are increasingly differentiating ourselves from other health benefit companies through our consumer-choice offerings, we are continuing to compete effectively with our traditional products as well.
Within our traditional book, the mix of our business is beginning to change as we migrate toward individual and small group, mid-market large group, administrative services only (ASO) and Smart products, while moving away from larger account insured business in general, and slice business in particular.
Growth in our ASO business has been a keen area of focus and, we believe, will contribute significantly to membership additions in 2004. This is an area in which employer customers select from an expansive list of potential services. Their choices can vary among such options as full service, network rentals, pharmacy, dental, disease management, utilization management, or call center services. We are now positioned to provide any and all of these services to meet market demand.
Total commercial medical membership – fully insured and ASO combined – has increased by over 200,000 on a net basis in January alone, substantially all of which is ASO.
Though we’re excited about our progress with traditional products, we’re particularly encouraged about the uptake in our Smart plans. Approximately 70,000 of the January membership additions relate to our innovative Smart products, with total Smart product membership now exceeding 200,000.
Not only have we transitioned to being a leader in all the traditional lines of business, we’re also succeeding in changing the rules of the game for the industry as a whole. Humana’s technology-powered “consumer-choice” offerings position us uniquely and attractively at the center of the commercial segment, between traditional insurers on the one hand and pure-play consumer-directed start-ups on the other.
Government Segment
We have long been contrarians to many in our industry with respect to Medicare, holding firm on our intent to continue our participation based on our company’s unique capabilities in administering Medicare HMOs and the huge scale of the market in the senior population. That commitment has now positioned us well to move quickly and effectively to respond to new opportunities offered by the Medicare Modernization Act of 2003.
From our perspective, the Medicare Modernization Act is not primarily a means of increasing short-term earnings. While changes brought about by this law permanently strengthen the traditional Medicare HMO product, they also introduce a variety of prospects for other areas of participation by the private sector.
As one of the first participants in the Medicare HMO program, we have long believed there would be new private sector opportunities for those who “stayed the course.” These opportunities are now upon us. For example, PPOs are the most popular form of health insurance in the United States; and yet, prior to this legislation, they were not widely available to seniors. Our senior PPO product will be positioned between HMOs and traditional Medigap policies and we expect will be very appealing to seniors.
Separately, we are complementing our existing array of senior products with the introduction of Medicare supplement plans. We are in the process of filing rate and benefit packages with approximately 20 states to sell this medically underwritten product, with plans to double that territory over time. We believe this is a firm step toward offering another option to the senior population.
    
    With respect to our TRICARE operations, the new “mega-regions” created in 2003 by the Department of Defense – with Humana awarded the new South Region – become effective during 2004. Our leadership team, with its breadth and depth of experience in this specialized business, is well positioned to ensure a smooth transition to the new contract for our TRICARE beneficiaries.
2003 Financial Highlights
We are pleased that our many accomplishments during 2003 have also translated into financial progress for our shareholders. Some of our significant 2003 financial milestones include:
Š Revenues now total more than $12 billion, an increase of more than 8 percent from 2002.
Š Medical membership in the commercial segment grew by 2.4 percent during 2003 despite a challenging
economic environment.
Š Commercial premiums, net of any benefit changes, increased more than 12 percent on a per-member basis compared to 2002.
Š The Commercial segment contributed a record 35 percent of the company’s pretax earnings.
Š Government segment profits held steady, despite a decline in Medicare membership in 2003 and the
impact of increased international conflict upon our TRICARE business.
Š Each of our business segments achieved strong operating earnings, evidencing the soundness of our customer diversification strategy.
Š Our balance sheet became more liquid than ever, with cash and investment securities accounting for more than 55 percent of total assets at December 31, 2003.
Š Our debt-to-total capitalization ratio decreased by 150 basis points during 2003 to 25.9 percent at the end of the year.
Corporate Governance
A strong sense of business ethics has always been a priority at Humana. Our Board of Directors represents the beginning point in the corporate governance process. During 2003, we added two new members to our Board: Frank A. D’Amelio, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer of Lucent Technologies Inc., and Kurt J. Hilzinger, President and Chief Operating Officer of AmerisourceBergen. Each brings a wealth of experience and expertise to the oversight and direction of our company.
Shareholders can read more detail about Humana’s corporate governance policies on the Investor Relations page at www.humana.com.
Leadership in Technology and Innovation
Humana’s leadership in technology and innovation accelerated in 2003. The company’s HumanaAccess MasterCard was heralded as the first combination health plan ID card and stored value card in the industry. Cardholders can access funds set aside in a flexible spending account or health-reimbursement account by swiping their card at their doctor’s office or pharmacy. Funds are then deducted directly from the member’s account, which eliminates the need for members to pay cash at the point of service, complete forms and await reimbursement checks.
In January 2003, we launched an improved version of our innovative Personal Nurse service that guides members through the health-care system, providing information to help them take control of their health conditions. Available to all of Humana’s commercial members, the Personal Nurse service is staffed by highly skilled registered nurses, who provide support, information and resources primarily to members who have acute
    
    or chronic health conditions or who have the propensity for illness. Nurses guide members to various Web-based company and community resources on a variety of topics, including diet control and medications.
Since the program’s inception, the nurses have interacted with nearly 30,000 members. Humana Personal Nurse differs from many traditional first-call or triage lines in that the majority of Humana calls are outbound to members. Advanced methodologies and predictive modeling tools are used to help identify and focus on members with targeted health conditions. Ultimately, we see a time when our high-tech data analysis combined with the high-touch Personal Nurse program could enable us to predict when someone with a chronic condition is likely to face hospitalization, and then make suggestions to that person for behavioral changes that could avoid such outcome.
In Summary
Our progress in 2003 is the result of the dedication, focus and commitment of Humana’s 13,700 associates. They strive to make a positive difference daily in the lives of our 6.8 million members and take pride in going the extra mile for the sake of a Humana member’s peace of mind.
2003 was a year of achievements from many perspectives, and we expect 2004 will again demonstrate how operational discipline, coupled with redoubled dedication to providing our members with “guidance when you need it most,” effectively translates to continued growth in earnings per share and value for our stockholders.
Sincerely,
David A. Jones
Chairman of the Board Significant Stockholder
Michael B. McCallister
Director, President and Chief Executive Officer Significant Stockholder
          