􏱟etter 􏴺rom 􏼪our CEO
In 2012, Intel delivered revenue of 􏱗53.3 billion, net income of 􏱗11.0 billion, and earnings per share of 􏱗2.13. We generated approximately 􏱗1􏱖.􏱓 billion in cash from operations, and our gross margin of 62.1􏱉 was at the top end of our historical gross margin range for the third
year in a row. We increased R􏼫􏹼 spending as we made investments across smartphones, tablets, UltrabookTM systems, the data center, and manufacturing. Worldwide economic growth in 2012 was significantly lower than we had anticipated entering the year, and the PC market segment was impacted by the growth of tablets. Although our financial results were below our initial expectations, we launched cutting-edge products in every ma􏱊or business segment and extended our manufacturing leadership.
Fulfilling our vision
Intel has an ambitious vision􏴮 Create and extend computing technology to connect and enrich the life of every person on Earth. We made tremendous progress toward achieving that vision in 2012 by delivering the world’s most advanced silicon technology. We ramped shipments of 22-nanometer 􏹐nm􏴷 processors with Intel’s breakthrough 3-􏹼 Tri-Gate transistor technology while building
our next-generation 1􏱔nm factory network and developing 10nm and smaller technologies. We estimate that we have about a 2-year process technology lead and about a 3.5-year lead in introducing revolutionary transistor technologies such as strained silicon, High-K Metal Gate, and Tri-Gate into high-volume manufacturing, compared to our nearest competitor.
No-compromise computing
The computing market is undergoing a radical transformation, with
a blurring of form factors and the adoption of new user interfaces. Convertible and detachable Ultrabook systems provide a two-for-one, no-compromise computing experience that eliminates the need to choose between a notebook and a tablet. The first Ultrabook systems were launched in 2011, and 100 were on the market by year-end 2012, with dozens more in the pipeline. We’re seeing unparalleled creativity in systems that combine our newest microprocessors with the touch-enabled Microsoft Windows* 􏱖 operating system.
We expect to see a new wave of Ultrabook system innovation with the 2013 launch of Intel’s first 22nm Tri-Gate processor designed from the ground up for Ultrabook systems. This processor, code-named “Haswell,” is designed to enable higher performance, the largest generation-to-generation increase in battery life in Intel’s history, thinner form factors, instant-on, and more lifelike interaction through touch, gesture, voice, and facial recognition.
Our mobile edge
We are moving Intel® AtomTM processors to our leading-edge manu- facturing technologies at twice our normal cadence. We shipped 32nm versions in 2012, and we expect to launch the 22nm generation
in 2013, and 1􏱔nm versions in 201􏱔. With each new generation of technology, we can boost performance while reducing costs and
power consumption􏼩great attributes for any market, but particularly for mobile computing.
Six ma􏱊or mobile providers launched Intel Atom processor-based smartphones in 2012. Intel Atom processor-based tablets and tablet convertibles running Windows 􏱖 are also shipping worldwide, offering thin and light designs, up to 10 hours of battery life in typical active usages, and compatibility with more than 􏱔 million Intel® architec- ture applications.
Data storage and high-performance computing
􏹼emand for transistors in servers, storage, and networking continues to grow. Between 200􏱓 and 2012, the total available market for cloud computing processors tripled, and by 2015 we expect that more than 3 billion connected users and 15 billion connected devices will be driving more than 1,500 exabytes of cloud traffic per year. Working with our McAfee subsidiary, we are helping to build confidence in private and public clouds through security solutions for the data center, network connections, and devices that connect to the cloud.
In 2012, we introduced the first Intel® Xeon PhiTM coprocessor,
a 60-core teraflop product designed for climate research, genomics, and other high-performance, highly parallel computing applications. We also launched an Intel® Xeon® processor family designed for lead- ership performance, security, and energy-efficiency demands in next-generation data centers. 􏴺or the data storage market segment, the Intel Atom processor powers micro servers that offer significant performance, software compatibility, and low-power advantages.
Our commitment to corporate responsibility
In addition to enriching people’s lives through technology, we do so through our corporate responsibility leadership, which creates value for Intel, our stockholders, and society. In 2012, Intel was included on the 􏹼ow 􏹍ones Sustainability Indexes for the 1􏱔th consecutive year, and we ranked number seven on 􏼧ewsweek’s annual Green Rankings U.S. 500 list. Our company also ranked number seven on the global Gartner Supply Chain Top 25 list for 2012, and we continued to lead the industry in addressing the issue of “conflict minerals” in the electronics supply chain. We helped empower our employees to donate more than 1 million hours of service to their communities through our Intel Involved volunteer program. Intel also continued to expand education opportunities for millions of students around the world, and partnered on the launch of the “Girl Rising” film and 10x10 social action campaign to help highlight the importance of investing in the education of girls and women to advance economic opportunity.
I will retire from Intel in May 2013 after almost 􏱔0 years at the company. Throughout my time here, I have marveled at Intel’s ability to move technology forward, empower people, and transform our world in ways we had never imagined. Intel employees are the best of the best. I can’t wait to see what they come up with next.
Paul S. Otellini, President and Chief Executive Officer
   
2012 Highlights
Letter From Your Chairman
After 30 years at Intel, I am honored to write my first letter as your Chairman. Intel is one of the world’s most innovative companies, known not only for its products and profits but also for its ethics and governance. I look forward to working with
the Board of Directors to extend that record of innovation while ensuring that the company continues to do the right
thing for stockholders, customers, employees, and communities.
As part of our commitment to increase stockholder value, the Board
began authorizing the return of cash to stockholders through the repurchase of Intel stock in the open market in 1990, and payments of dividends in 1992. Through year-end 2012, the repurchase and dividend programs had returned $118.4 billion to stockholders. Intel used $4.8 billion to repurchase 191 million shares of stock in 2012, and completed a senior notes offering of $6.2 billion, in part to fund the additional re- purchase of Intel stock. Intel’s dividend payout for 2012 was $4.4 billion, including a 7% increase in the dividend starting in the third quarter.
The Board also authorized significant strategic investments in 2012, so that Intel can continue to build innovative products at competitive costs. Most of Intel’s 2012 capital spending of $11 billion went toward building and equipping factories with leading-edge technologies. We also signed agreements with ASML Holding N.V. to invest approximately $4 billion in an effort to accelerate the deployment of 450mm wafers and extreme ultraviolet technologies. These investments help us create value for stockholders and customers by enabling us to optimize performance, die size, cost, and power consumption across our product line.
I would like to thank retiring CEO Paul Otellini for his extraordinary contributions to Intel’s success. During his tenure as CEO—from the second quarter of 2005 through the end of 2012—Intel generated cash from operations of $113.0 billion, increased annual revenue from $38.8 billion to $53.3 billion, achieved breakthrough innovations such as High-K Metal Gate and 3-D Tri-Gate transistor technologies, and dramatically improved the energy efficiency of Intel® processors.
As the Board has worked toward selecting Paul’s successor, we’ve been gratified to recognize that Intel’s strong culture and operational excellence have created value that extends well beyond a single leader. I’ve worked with four Intel CEOs and reported to three of them. Each has moved Intel forward, left an enduring legacy, and been a strong and unique leader. Each has also maintained Intel’s core values and a culture of integrity while embracing the change necessary for a vital future.
When Andy Grove retired as Chairman in 2004, he said that he wanted to be remembered for helping to build an organization that sustains itself long after his tenure. Succession planning does not begin or end with the selection of an individual. It is a continuing investment in culture, continuity, and change. The Board is committed to ensuring that Intel’s future is as bright as its past.
Andy D. Bryant, Chairman of the Board
    Two-for-one computing
Unprecedented innovation in UltrabookTM systems
Touch-enabled convertible and detachable UltrabookTM systems combine the productivity of a notebook with the convenience of a laptop. Intel expects another wave of Ultrabook device innovation in 2013, with the arrival of the company’s next-generation “Haswell” processor.
Intel powers the cloud
Ever-expanding data continues to create demand for transistors in servers, storage, and networking. Intel’s data center products range from teraflop processors for high-performance computing to milliwatt processors for energy-efficient micro servers.
Investing in the future
Intel continues to deliver the world’s most advanced silicon technology, ramping high-volume shipments of cutting-edge 22-nanometer (nm) processors while building our next-generation 14nm factory network and developing 10nm and smaller technologies.
  From teraflops
to milliwatts
  Manufacturing leadership
 