To Our Shareholders:
A Letter from the Chairman
Each year brings its own triumphs and challenges. In 2002, Interpublic’s accomplishments— of which there were many—went largely unheralded. This was attributable to the
intense public focus that we were the subject of, in part due to the recession that once again battered the advertising industry, but equally because of our own disappointing earnings, as well as credit and liquidity concerns surrounding the company. We are working hard and making progress in putting these issues behind us, so as to return attention to
our strengths and accomplishments. Notable among these last year were:
 ■ The continued vitality and competitive strength of our agencies in every communications discipline, as evident in their new business performance. Overall, our compa- nies won $3.2 billion of net new billings in 2002, from every region in the world.
■ Major awards and recognition from our peers. This included coveted “Agency of the Year” honors won in the United States by Campbell-Ewald, Deutsch and Univer- sal McCann and outstanding performance by Bozell and
Lowe at Cannes, the industry’s most prestigious creative competition, where we also won the Media Grand Prix. Not to mention an additional 22 “Agency of the Year” awards won in 12 markets around the world, by interna- tional offices of FCB, Lowe and McCann on every continent to specialist agencies ranging from healthcare communications to interactive digital marketing.
■ The flawless execution of the merger between Weber Shandwick and BSMG, which created the largest, most
 THE INTERPUBLIC GROUP OF COMPANIES ■ 2002 ANNUAL REPORT 1

CHAIRMAN’S MESSAGE (CONTINUED)
powerful player in public relations and constituent com- munications—one with dramatically higher profitability despite the shrinking revenue environment.
■ Finally, strong working capital disciplines and cash man- agement initiatives that helped reduce our debt by close to $300 million in 2002.
While we are proud of these accomplishments, it is unde- niable that our difficulties were what made news last year. Some of the challenges we faced reflected the harsh business environment. Some, notably the company’s unfortunate foray into venue ownership, were the vestige of acquisitions made in the exuberance of the nineties boom. Others were self-inflicted, such as the erosion
of cost disciplines at a number of our companies, and the internal accounting errors at McCann in Europe which we at Interpublic discovered and forcefully addressed.
All of these contributed to the company’s unacceptable financial performance.
In February, your Board of Directors elected me Chair- man and Chief Executive Officer. I welcome the challenge, to which I will bring enthusiasm, energy and the necessary humility. I feel a deep sense of responsibility to all of our stakeholders. And I harbor no illusions about the nature of the task at hand—there is significant work to be done.
But there are also significant potential rewards.
A strong vision, coupled with a great sense of urgency, will be required to set Interpublic on the right path. While the company has experienced recent reversals, I am confident that by aligning the needs of our clients, employees and investors we will, over time, return Interpublic to its long-standing position as the industry leader in delivering financial returns to its shareholders.
To that end, we are working on an aggressive turn- around plan built on these key strategic priorities: strengthening the balance sheet, bolstering financial reliability and accountability, as well as driving shareholder
value through the aggressive pursuit of margin improve- ment and organic growth. Of course, we will continue
to provide the ideas and solutions that have always made us the most client-centric organization in our industry.
The challenges of 2002 began with revenue. We started the year hoping for a recovery in the broader economy and
in our sector. Consequently, we planned for only a modest revenue decline and budgeted costs accordingly. As the year progressed and the recovery failed to materialize, rev- enue fell by 8.7% to $6.2 billion.
Our advertising and media business, particularly
in the United States, suffered declining revenue beginning in 2001. The trend continued into 2002, with revenue down 8.9%, as clients curtailed spending and delayed programs due to their own cost pressures. Client spend- ing on marketing and communications services, such
as public relations, direct marketing, sales promotion and event planning, resisted the revenue decline until well into 2002. This was in part due to the fact that returns on these efforts are often more immediate, or more
easily assessed. Ultimately, however, continuing economic malaise and reduced consumer spending prompted clients to postpone all forms of marketing support, which caused marketing and communication services revenue to decline 8.3%.
Our traditional cost discipline dictates that revenue declines must be matched by commensurate cost reduc- tions. When significant revenue is derived from project work, as Interpublic’s is, accurate revenue forecasting and proactive expense controls are imperative. Although many of our agencies moved aggressively to protect profit
  2 THE INTERPUBLIC GROUP OF COMPANIES ■ 2002 ANNUAL REPORT
2002
Results

margins in 2002, some of our largest operating units moved too slowly.
In 2002, salaries and related expenses declined by 6.8%—significantly lagging the rate of our revenue decline— and our resulting profit margin remained well below acceptable levels. Operating income was $405.8 million in 2002, compared to a loss of $243.6 million in 2001. Results in 2002 reflect the benefit of significantly lower restructuring and asset impairment charges, as well as the absence of goodwill amortization, in accordance with new accounting rules. So, although earnings per share of $.26 cents seemingly compared favorably to last year’s loss of $1.45 per share, we regard this performance as a disappointment.
Despite poor earnings performance, Interpublic generated significant cash flow in 2002. This allowed us to fund important expenditures related to efficiency improvements, finance modest strategic acquisitions that improved and expanded our service offerings, pay $145.6 million in cash dividends, and retire $271 million in debt. Debt reduction continues as a primary goal.
Looking to 2003, it is clear clients remain cautious. Revenue visibility will therefore be poor. Geopolitical risks appear to have stalled many sectors of the economy. As a result, marketers and consumers alike have settled into a “wait-and-see” attitude. We have limited confidence that a meaningful economic recovery will develop in 2003 and have built our operating budgets accordingly. Specifically, we are estimating that revenue will decline
between one and four percent in 2003, adjusted for asset sales or dispositions.
Our company faces significant challenges, stemming from the past two years of severe weakness in our sector, exacer- bated by the strategy of acquisition-driven growth that Interpublic pursued prior to the slowdown. To right the ship, we will focus on the financial fundamentals that pre- viously made us an industry leader, complemented by a company-wide commitment to organic growth.
A strong sense of purpose now drives Interpublic. The management team understands and is responsive to the needs of clients and shareholders alike. The new vision for our company is built on four strategic imperatives.
First, we will continue to be relentless in our efforts to strengthen the balance sheet. We have already made signif- icant strides in this area. Improvements in cash management and working capital disciplines have allowed us to reduce debt significantly, from 61.3% of capital
to 55.7% in just one year. Achieving the appropriate debt level is vital to our organization. As in any service busi- ness, a flexible balance sheet will give us the ability
to succeed in any economic climate. Equally important,
 The Road
Ahead
 “ We are working on an aggressive turnaround plan built on these key strategic priorities: strengthening the balance sheet, bolstering
financial reliability and accountability, as well as driving shareholder value through the aggressive pursuit of margin improvement and organic growth.”
 THE INTERPUBLIC GROUP OF COMPANIES ■ 2002 ANNUAL REPORT 3

CHAIRMAN’S MESSAGE (CONTINUED)
a strong financial position will allow us to best serve clients by attracting world-class professional talent.
Second, we will further upgrade our information sys- tems, communications and operating-unit financial man- agement to ensure financial reliability and accountability.
Third, we will focus on margin improvement. The exceptional quality of professional service being delivered by our companies to clients demands that we achieve margins equal to those of our leading competitors. Our people and our shareholders deserve this.
This is an area in which a number of our units
lost their way in 2002. Going forward, we will be single- minded in ensuring that we successfully re-establish the cost disciplines that historically produced industry-leading margins at Interpublic. Given the continued challenging business environment, we must also take a long and hard look at our infrastructure. We are fully prepared to be aggressive in taking costs out of the organization to pro- tect and improve profitability.
Finally, we must achieve improved organic growth. Our record of winning new business validates our asser- tion that Interpublic’s agency brands are strong. Internal tracking shows that we are regularly winning head-to- head pitches against major competitors, which is the key to success in the ongoing industry market share battle.
But new business contributes approximately 5% to revenue in a typical year. So, organic growth is also about getting new assignments from existing clients. It’s about collaboration among our varied companies to deliver complete marketing solutions to clients. And ultimately, it is about creating a growth culture. Organic growth flows from a focus at the top that inspires a genuine company-wide commitment to entrepreneurial, business- building behavior. Coupled with margin discipline,
organic growth is without doubt the most powerful driver of shareholder value.
An improved balance sheet, increased financial relia- bility, margin improvement and organic growth—these are the yardsticks we will use to measure our progress and our success.
In addition to these fundamental drivers, I pledge
to you that a sense of urgency will permeate everything we do, that we will promote accountability throughout the organization and that we will remain committed
to aggressively communicating with all internal and exter- nal constituencies.
A turnaround cannot—and will not—be immediate. But a turnaround is precisely what’s required. There is
new management in place. We have outlined a decisive plan of action and indicated a willingness to make the tough decisions required to see it through. Strong and vital agency brands continue to be our most important assets, as are our 50,000 people around the world. Their talent, commitment, and passion are what will return our overall performance to best in class.
It’s been said that a challenge is just an opportunity in work clothes. At Interpublic, we’ve already put them on and begun rolling up our sleeves.
David A. Bell
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
  4 THE INTERPUBLIC GROUP OF COMPANIES ■ 2002 ANNUAL REPORT
