 message to our
stockholders
 John W. Norris, Jr. Chairman of the Board
Robert E. Schjerven Chief Executive Officer
At Lennox International Inc. (LII) we define integrity as a firm commitment to a code of values. It’s how we define our way of doing business. But what impact has our integrity had on our history, our current performance, or the vision we want to share with you for LII’s future?
Before discussing how our traditions are still driving us today and how they will positively affect our performance in the years ahead, let’s review our 2001 performance.
2001 Performance
LII faced soft global economic conditions while we worked to integrate and consolidate our retail operations. These challenges were clearly reflected in our results for 2001. Total corporate sales were $3.1 billion, down 4% from 2000. Our operating margin before restructuring charges associated with consolidating some of our operations was 2.3%, down from 5.0% in 2000. Net income, before restruc- turing charges, was $14 million, compared with
$62 million the previous year. Earnings per share were $0.25 versus $1.10 last year. On a GAAP basis, after accounting for total pre-tax restructuring charges of $73 million, our reported net loss per share for the year was $0.75, compared with earn- ings per share of $1.05 in 2000.
While we are certainly not satisfied with these results, we did achieve some significant progress in several important areas during 2001:
• Despite strong competition and a weak econ- omy, our domestic air conditioning, heating, and refrigeration businesses—which represent almost half of our revenues—gained measurable market share and position us favorably for the next eco- nomic cycle.
 02 ANNUAL REPORT 2001

• Our emphasis on managing free cash flow throughout the organization enabled us to signifi- cantly improve performance on this key measure- ment. We generated $184 million in free cash in 2001—well ahead of our mid-year 2001 guidance of $80 to 90 million. We strengthened our balance sheet by using the additional cash primarily to reduce debt. As a result, we decreased our total debt to $518 million as of December 31, 2001 from $690 million the year before, reducing our debt-to-total-capital ratio to 44% from 48% over the same period.
• We appointed a new leader of our retail operations, Dennis Smith, who has a proven record of turning around similar businesses. He has made adjustments to right-size the organiza- tion, reducing the total head count at Service Experts by 15% from 12 months ago. We remain confident our retail operations offer significant earnings potential, and we are determined to begin realizing that potential in the near term.
• We announced restructuring initiatives designed to improve utilization of our manufac- turing and distribution assets. While these will involve one-time charges, we project an annual pre-tax benefit of $7 million in 2002, beginning in the second quarter, and $11 million annually beginning in 2003.
• We are expanding our served market for heat transfer surfaces through de-integration of heat transfer component production by OEMs. We have entered into a key alliance with Ingersoll- Rand’s Climate Control division that marks a significant success for LII in this area. The new agreement is expected to bring $11 million in incremental revenues to Lennox in 2002 and up to $25 million annually thereafter.
• We are serious about reducing our over- head. In the fourth quarter of last year we froze both salaries and hiring in our North American operations. Over the past 12 months, as cost reduction programs have been executed through- out the company, our total workforce has been reduced by over 10%.
LII has substantial strengths, including market leadership, strong brands, an experienced man- agement team, clear strategies focused on growth and operating improvement, and an emphasis on generating cash and paying down debt. We are confident that by sticking to our strategies and continuing our aggressive efforts to improve our performance, we will see every segment of our business move toward its full earnings potential.
Our 21,000 employees worldwide are more than capable of meeting our challenges with integrity, improving our performance, and increas- ing our value to our shareholders. Their continued hard work and resilient attitude in difficult times are proof of that. Our 107-year history—notable for success and growth through an economic depression and two world wars—is proof of that as well.
A model for over a century of success
Dave Lennox started the Lennox business model in what one observer described as “an overgrown blacksmith shop” in Marshalltown, Iowa, in 1895. He made an innovative and popular product: the first riveted steel furnace, far more efficient and durable than the cast-iron furnaces common at the time.
But innovation was only part of Lennox’ way of doing business. He also built a quality product, one that could deliver safe, economical comfort year after year. He sold his products directly to installing contractors, helping to build a personal bond of communication and trust with his cus- tomers. When things went wrong, he listened, took responsibility, and corrected them.
When D.W. Norris bought the business from Dave Lennox and became president in 1904, he built on what Lennox had begun, following his own simple but highly effective philosophy:
“Build me the best product, and get me the best salesman. The best salesman will get me the best dealer, and the best dealer will get me the most business.”
 ANNUAL REPORT 2001 03

“We continue our unwavering commitment to innovation and per- formance, treat our customers like true business partners, and learn from our past as we build for the future.”
We have since expanded our business strat- egy around the world to encompass multiple distribution channels. But Dave Lennox and D.W. Norris defined the basic values that helped Lennox grow to become a global leader in the climate control industry.
Building on tradition
Even in today’s far more complex business environment, we still find success and growth opportunities in following and expanding on our earliest values. For over a century, we have main- tained our integrity through:
• Innovation: Dave Lennox’ emphasis on practical innovation lives on in our commitment to expanding our fast-growing e-commerce systems with input from our customers. It is also evident
in our recent development of web-based controls for residential and commercial comfort systems. This year we are also introducing our Dave Lennox Signature􏺟 Collection of top-of-the-line home comfort equipment, utilizing our own SilentComfort􏺟 technology that allows us to produce the quietest air conditioners and furnaces on the market today.
• Performance: After growing in the midst of many difficult domestic and global challenges over more than a century, we are firmly committed to maximizing our performance in the public sec- tor. While our stock traded below its IPO price
in 2001, our return to shareholders for the year was strong at over 30%. This performance far exceeded the broader markets, which had nega- tive returns in 2001.
• Products and services: Our century-old commitment to quality products and services continues as we implement sophisticated lean manufacturing processes at many of our facilities, resulting in better products for our customers, built faster. We are developing highly sophisticated e-commerce systems that make it easier and faster for customers to communicate and do busi- ness with us. We are constantly exploring new ways to enhance our products and services by listening to our customers, refining our processes to improve quality and efficiency, and evaluating emerging technologies.
• Brands: Originally led by the trusted face
of “Dave Lennox,” we have carefully expanded our brand family to cover the entire depth and breadth of our industry. At the same time, we have ensured each name represents the tradi- tional Lennox standards of reliability and trust. Our brands—including Lennox, Armstrong, Ducane, Bohn, Kirby, Larkin, Heatcraft, and Service Experts—are well known and respected in the air conditioning and heating, refrigeration, heat transfer, and commercial refrigeration indus- tries around the world.
We further demonstrated our commitment to innovation and stronger financial performance
at the highest levels of our operations by making three key senior management appointments during the year:
• We announced Rick Smith’s appointment to chief financial officer in our letter to you last year. Rick joined us on January 15, 2001 and, as we
 04 ANNUAL REPORT 2001

predicted, has proven to be an excellent fit with our company. His emphasis on enhancing the basics of our balance sheet has resulted in sig- nificant improvement in many important areas of our financial operations.
• We appointed Linda Goodspeed to chief technology officer. Linda was president and chief operating officer for Partminer, Inc., a leading global supplier of electronic components and component information and a provider of inventory management services and enterprise solutions. Before coming to Partminer, Linda was product general manager of General Electric Appliances, responsible for $1.2 billion in cooking products sales and maintaining the company’s number one share position in that market. Her expertise in technology, product management, quality systems, and manufacturing best practices is helping accelerate improvement in these key areas.
• As we mentioned earlier, we appointed Dennis Smith to president of Service Experts Inc., our retail operation. Dennis was formerly chief operating officer for Simplex Time Recorder, a $900 million fire alarm and security systems busi- ness with 170 company-operated locations. Given Dennis’ impressive track record of helping compa- nies reach their fullest potential, we expect to see accelerated improvements in performance for our retail operations.
We are also proud to introduce our new cor- porate logo, which you can see on the cover of this annual report. The previous LII logo is associ- ated with our Lennox brand of heating and cooling products and dates from the 1950s, when LII did not even exist.
Introducing a distinctive corporate logo repre- sents our new role as a strong public company and our growth from a small-town furnace manu- facturer into a global leader in all aspects of climate
control technology. A key element in the new logo is “LII,” which stands for Lennox International Inc., reflecting our new identity. The logo’s simple and direct visual style is suggestive of our focus on business basics and the underlying integrity that has been part of our culture since 1895.
We continue our unwavering commitment to innovation and performance, treat our customers like true business partners, and learn from our past as we build for the future. As we have grown around the world, we have remained faithful to these core values, through good times and challenging ones—and have always emerged successful.
While we expect our revenues will be flat to modestly down for 2002, we are confident the initiatives we took during 2001 will enable us to improve earnings, which will be reflected in the quality of our free cash flow. We look forward to progress in 2002 in realizing our earnings poten- tial, and expect improvements will accelerate in the second half of the year.
For all of us at LII, “integrity” just means good business. Our integrity—the firm commitment we have to our code of values—will be key to meet- ing our challenges in the year ahead and the years to come.
Robert E. Schjerven Chief Executive Officer
John W. Norris, Jr. Chairman of the Board
   ANNUAL REPORT 2001 05
