 LETTER TO SHAREHOLDERS
    2
Michael T. Strianese
President and Chief Executive Officer
  
  Dear Fellow Shareholders:
2006 was one of the most successful years in L-3’s history. Our sales increased to $12.5 billion from $9.4 billion, a 32% increase over 2005.
I am grateful to L-3’s employees and management team for steadfastly executing the Company’s business strategy. At the same time, 2006 was a challenging year with the passing of Frank C. Lanza, one of the Company’s founders and former chairman and chief executive officer. As we approach our tenth anniversary as a Company, we are thankful for Frank’s leadership, foresight and friendship. Moving forward into the next decade, L-3 is well-positioned to meet financial goals, add key new customers, perform with excellence on programs, develop innovative new products and technologies and continue to make acquisitions that further strengthen L-3. And, we will continue to adhere to the highest ethical standards.
Highlights of our accomplishments throughout the year include:
•L-3 extended its decades-long record of providing C-130 modification and maintenance support – delivering the first of 12 MC-130 aircraft for use by Special Operations Forces.
•We maintained and upgraded the U.S. Air Force RC-135 airborne reconnaissance fleet, which was recognized for achieving more than 6,000 days of continuous service in Southwest Asia.
•L-3 delivered to the U.S. Navy the first of five EP-3E aircraft converted from the P-3C aircraft.
•We supported U.S. Government customers in executing many critical missions around the world.
•L-3 captured multiple strategic training system opportunities in the advanced fast jet training market, including the U.S. Navy five-year F/A-18C/D Roadmap Procurement Program (RPP), the Boeing F/A-18E/F and the EA-18G Growler Airborne Electronic Attack aircraft, as well as several F-16 contracts.
•We successfully teamed across multiple divisions to win the role of Propulsion Systems Supplier for the Cobra Judy Radar replacement program aboard the missile range instrumentation ship T-AGM􏵇.
•L-3 provided the warfighter with an up-armored High-Mobility Multipurpose Wheeled Vehicle (HMMWV) version of the Prophet signals intelligence/direction finding system in under a year, responding to urgent U.S. Government need.
•We were chosen by the U.S. Army to be the Product Support Integrator for transmissions on the Bradley Fighting Vehicle System.
•In October 2006, we shipped our 1,000th ROVER, which was named Utah’s Stole Rives Innovative
Product of the Year.
•L-3 delivered its 200,000th Secure Terminal Equipment (STE) to the U.S. Government.
•We were awarded a contract
to supply baggage screening equipment to the new Beijing International Airport, which will open in time to support the 2008 Summer Olympic Games.
In addition, given our strong free cash flow, our Board of Directors approved a 33% increase in our cash dividend in February 2007, and also approved a two-year $500 million share repurchase plan in December 2006. This demonstrates our confidence in L-3’s future financial performance.
Strong Financial Results
Sales not only increased 32% last year, but our organic sales growth was among the highest in the industry at 9.3%. Operating income was $1.1 billion and diluted earnings per share (EPS) was $4.22. Our results for 2006 were affected by two events discussed in our 2006 consolidated financial statements, which are included in this Annual Report. Excluding these items, operating income in 2006 increased by 28% to $1.3 billion, compared to $1.0 billion in 2005, and our EPS was $5.05, a 20% increase compared to $4.20for2005. (Seereconciliation of operating income and diluted EPS excluding these items on the front inside cover of this Annual Report.) L-3 also generated $1.1 billion of net
3
    
 LETTER TO SHAREHOLDERS (CONTINUED)
 4
cash from operating activities, compared to $847 million in 2005, an increase of 27%. Free cash flow for 2006 grew by 15% to $920 million, versus $798 million in 2005. Additionally, L-3’s net income-to-free cash flow conversion for 2006 was an industry-leading 146%. L-3 also ended 2006 with $348 million of cash on hand.
Similarly, L-3 generated $13.7 billion of funded orders in 2006, a result of strong performance in all business segments. Funded backlog was $8.7 billion at December 31, 2006. L-3 continued to have a strong balance sheet, with reduced leverage for the period at the close of 2006.
Business Acquisitions
An important element of L-3’s growth strategy has been the acquisition of businesses that provide state-of-the-art products and services that add key capabilities, technologies and customers. In 2006, we acquired fourteen businesses that enhanced our capability in defense, homeland security and international markets. We also added key competencies
in the areas of network-centric communications, aircraft modernization and maintenance and comprehensive explosives detection solutions.
L-3 is also expanding its global presence. For example, L-3 acquired two United Kingdom (U.K.)
businesses that have expertise in defense electronics, including electronic countermeasures (ECM), electronic warfare and communication technology.
Defense and Homeland Security Outlook
We believe that defense spending levels will continue to grow at least until the 2009 elections. The Global War on Terror and instability in Iraq and Afghanistan will require the support of U.S. forces along with the ongoing commitment to reinforce the military and civilian infrastructures of these nations. As a result, we expect that there will be a need for additional supplemental funding to support these efforts, though there may well be enhanced Congressional scrutiny and debate over the size and focus of spending.
Overall Department of Defense (DoD) spending is expected to
grow and be focused on a number of key areas, including products
and services for Special Operations Forces, Command, Control, Communications, Intelligence, Surveillance and Reconnaissance (C3ISR), and equipment and supplies related to the war effort. As a leader in providing solutions and services in each of these areas, L-3 is well- positioned for continued growth.
We provide specialized fleet management and support for signals intelligence and ISR special mission aircraft and airborne surveillance
systems, along with real-time secure communication systems in support of surveillance and reconnaissance programs. L-3 is also a leader in aircraft logistics support as well as comprehensive maintenance and depot services. In addition, L-3 offers a variety of high-end services, including support for the intelligence agencies, organizational development, security sector reform and law enforcement training.
We also anticipate continued growth in Homeland Security spending in 2007. L-3 provides a number of state-of-the-art solutions and services that respond to the security needs of both U.S. and international customers. L-3 has developed an integrated checkpoint system, which combines multiple detection technologies,
to screen carry-on bags and passengers for explosives and contraband. This system will improve security while greatly reducing the operational costs associated with today’s technology. L-3 also offers continued support
of U.S. Transportation Security Administration (TSA) explosives detection equipment. For the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), we provide communications, ground and airborne sensors and detectors for situational awareness. L-3 has also developed a handheld through-wall radar for the Defense Department and first responders that is capable of identifying human presence in buildings and rubble.
    
  L-3’s Prospects for 2007
The outlook for 2007 is very positive. L-3’s strengths are in its diversified business mix, which focuses on the growing segments of the defense budget, superior products and services, and last,
but certainly not least, strong performance. This strategy, combined with prudent financial management with an emphasis on earnings and free cash flow growth, ensures L-3’s successful future.
In implementing this strategy, L-3 has grown from performing programs primarily as a subcontractor to a more robust role as a prime contractor in many business areas. Indeed, L-3 now serves as a prime contractor in three of its business segments – C3ISR, Aircraft Modernization
& Maintenance (AM&M) and Government Services. In our Specialized Products area, we also offer one of the largest portfolios
of high-technology products and systems in the defense industry. These products are often supplied through multiple sales channels, including directly to the DoD and other government agencies, as
well as to other prime contractors and international customers.
We will continue to increase collaboration among L-3’s businesses, as well as undertake consolidation and integration actions with select operations
and administrative functions. In 2006, L-3 combined its intelligence
support, professional services and integrated solutions businesses under the management of the L-3 Services Group. As a result, L-3 achieved increased operating efficiencies, which will make us more competitive and provide additional resources to perform a greater variety of contracts. This, combined with a selective acquisition strategy, is designed to increase our shareholders’ returns.
With our extensive engineering and managerial skills, talented technical workforce, carefully targeted research and development and a focus on customer requirements, we will continue to develop product and service solutions that solve the challenging needs of our customers. We are using our expertise to develop competitive solutions on several major government programs, including those for ISR, in-theater tactical air transport and training and simulation, to name a few.
I am also pleased to report that we strengthened our executive management team. Curtis Brunson, formerly President of our Communication Systems-West division, was named Senior Vice President of Corporate Strategy and Development. In this newly created position, Curtis will bring his 35 years of experience in managing one of our most successful and fastest growing businesses to L-3’s long- term growth strategy, business development initiatives and research and development programs.
Ralph D’Ambrosio was promoted to Chief Financial Officer. Ralph has extensive experience with L-3’s financial operations and is a proven leader. And, David Butler was promoted to Senior Vice President of Business Operations, in order to provide more attention to the integration of L-3’s various businesses and improve operating synergies. Additionally, Kathleen Karelis joined L-3 as our Senior Vice President, General Counsel and Corporate Secretary. She was formerly a partner with one of the top private law firms in the country. Finally, Fred Piccirillo was appointed the L-3 Corporate Ethics Officer. In recognition of our continued commitment to ethics, Fred will report directly to me.
In summary, we had a successful 2006 and know that 2007 will have many opportunities and achievements. All of us at L-3 are committed to our customers, our shareholders and our future.
Sincerely,
Michael T. Strianese
President and Chief Executive Officer
 5
    