 DEAR FELLOW SHAREHOLDERS,
With our management team united behind a straightforward and keenly focused strategy of disciplined growth, Lockheed Martin was, and continues to be, distinguished by robust operational and financial performance in 2003. As a result, we enter 2004 well positioned to fulfill the potential and promise of this innovative corporation of 130,000 dedicated men and women.
This strategy of disciplined growth is to increase shareholder value by:
■ Putting operational performance and customer satisfaction at the top of our priorities.
■ Maintaining consistent financial performance including strong cash flow and increasing financial strength and flexibility.
■ Focusing on profitable growth in our core markets of Defense, Homeland Security and Government Information Technology (IT). We also look forward to working with NASA to support America’s reinvigorated commitment to space exploration.
Successful execution of this strategy was demonstrated in the numbers with a third straight year of positive momentum. Net sales in 2003 grew 20 percent to $31.8 billion. We have grown segment operating profit faster than sales, reflecting steadily improving margins. For the third consecutive year, orders remain strong with a backlog of $76.9 billion at the end of 2003. Our Aeronautics business enjoyed a record year for sales and our Electronic Systems business completed a seventh consecutive year of organic growth.
We continued our record of consistent cash flow generation that reached $1.8 billion in 2003, and deployed cash to enhance shareholder value through:
■ Debt reduction. We reduced debt by $1.4 billion in 2003 and $3.7 billion since 2000. Our ratio of debt to total capital, at 48 percent, is now within our goal of 40 to 50 percent. We also restructured about $1 billion of debt to achieve lower interest expense.
■ Share repurchase. We have been buying back our shares periodically. Since we started our share repurchase activity about a year ago, we have retired approximately 11 million shares.
■ Dividends. Financial flexibility and vitality are also reflected in our doubling the annual dividend rate from 44 cents to 88 cents per common share.
■ Acquisitions. Growing business in our core markets is key to competing successfully, and we have made selective acquisitions to continue strengthening our position in defense and civil government IT.
Lockheed Martin last year completed strategic transactions with ACS and Orincon, and announced the proposed acquisition of The Titan Corporation. We expect these transactions will bring additional capabilities, a talented workforce and customers. These transactions will help us be more competitive in the defense and civil government IT markets.
About 25 percent of our sales are from IT solutions and services to defense, intelligence and civil government agencies.
The Titan acquisition, when completed and integrated with Orincon, will bolster our core capabilities in critical intelligence, knowledge management and data fusion that are applicable to national defense. In the ACS transaction, we acquired the defense and most of the civil government IT business of ACS, while ACS acquired Lockheed Martin’s commercial IT business.
LOCKHEED MARTIN ANNUAL REPORT 2003 — 3

 Financial performance and portfolio shaping are only part of the picture; Lockheed Martin consistently works to be a trusted and valued partner with our customers in the United States and worldwide. Consequently, last year we registered some impressive operational achievements:
■ In 2003, the F/A-22 team continued to address avionics stability challenges, operational testing began on schedule, high quality aircraft are being delivered, and the team continues to make solid progress in the transition from development to production.
■ In 2003, Lockheed Martin saw a resurgence in its space business with 11 new launches awarded and orders placed for five new commercial satellites.
■ The Patriot Advanced Capability (PAC-3) missile, the world’s first operational weapon system to employ hit-to-kill technology, made its operational debut during Operation Iraqi Freedom, defending troops and installations against ballistic missile threats.
■ We recorded two successful launches of our Atlas V in 2003. In all, there have been 68 consecutive suc- cessful Atlas launches. NASA also selected the Atlas V to launch the first space probe to Pluto in 2006.
■ The F-35 Joint Strike Fighter successfully completed its Preliminary Design Review and is proceeding toward the Design Integration Maturity Review this spring and the Critical Design Review in 2005.
■ The Spitzer Space Telescope we built for NASA was launched and began providing extraordinary infrared images of the universe.
■ The U.S. Air Force gave operational certification to the stealthy Joint Air to Surface Standoff Missile. ■ We received a vote of confidence from the U.S. Air Force and Marine Corps for the C-130J airlifter,
which was reflected in a multi-year acquisition of 60 aircraft.
We reorganized our business areas last year to better address the changing and increasingly complex needs of our defense customers, especially in the critical area of Information Superiority.
By creating a new business area, Integrated Systems & Solutions, we are leveraging technical expertise across the breadth of Lockheed Martin to address our customers’ requirements for highly integrated, networked solutions. Integrated Systems & Solutions provides customers with the benefit of focused collaboration for solutions that are technically sound, cost effective, and that enhance operational performance.
As part of this effort, we are creating the Global Vision Network to enable collaboration among cus- tomers and Lockheed Martin. The central node of this high-bandwidth engineering network is the Global Vision Integration Center in Suffolk, Virginia, which will lead our development, simulation and analysis of network-centric solutions for the Department of Defense and other national security customers.
Without the people of Lockheed Martin, the achievements of the past year would not have been possible. We are proud of the men and women who bring a passion for invention to their work each and every day.
Our efforts to recruit and retain the best people continue apace. A diverse and talented workforce is fundamentally important to our future competitiveness. Also fundamental to this corporation are the values that inspire our management team. Ethics is not simply an add-on to our management strategy; it is inherent in the Lockheed Martin culture through regular training at all levels of the organization. We also apply these principles to meeting the highest standards of corporate governance and transparency in our financial disclosure practices.
LM21 represents the commitment of all our employees to Operating Excellence and is based on the two pillars of superior development processes (and process improvement), and lean manufacturing techniques.
4 — LOCKHEED MARTIN ANNUAL REPORT 2003

 Lockheed Martin’s values are translated into action through our community and educational activities that help ensure that we as a corporate citizen give back to the communities where we work and live. The people of Lockheed Martin stood as one company in our response to the shootings in Meridian, Mississippi, and assisted those families affected by the tragedy. A year after the loss of the Space Shuttle Columbia, we honor the memory of the heroes who flew aboard that mission and stand with NASA in their commitment to manned and unmanned space exploration to the moon and beyond.
As a corporation with a long history of serving the armed forces of the United States, we are acutely aware of the sacrifices our servicemen and women make every day in the defense of freedom. Our manage- ment team and the entire corporation salute those who are serving abroad and in the United States, including the nearly 300 Lockheed Martin employees now on active military duty, as well as the Lockheed Martin employees working in Iraq and worldwide.
In summary, we are confident your company is well positioned for the future with:
■ Leadership in Defense, Homeland Security, Government Information Technology and Services growth markets, as well as space systems and exploration.
■ A broad portfolio of capabilities and programs that provide total systems solutions for customer challenges.
■ A strong backlog plus substantial new business opportunities.
■ Consistent financial performance and strong cash flow.
■ Cash deployment to enhance shareholder value.
Lockheed Martin’s reputation as a dynamic enterprise serving our customers’, our nation’s and our allies’ most important priorities will be enhanced by adhering closely to a strategy that focuses on financial and operational performance, as well as the highest standards of business ethics. At the same time, we remain keenly aware of opportunities to grow our core businesses.
On a closing note, I recently announced my retirement as CEO, effective in August 2004. My 37 years with Lockheed Martin have been filled with challenge, wonder and tremendous gratification. The personal pride I feel for this company is exceeded only by the deep appreciation I have for its amazing 130,000 employees. The consolidation of the defense industry has led us through a challenging period in our history. All of you — our shareholders, customers and employees — have seen our corporation meet those demands and become stronger as a result.
Having served seven years at the helm, it is now time for new leadership to take us to the next level of performance. Bob Stevens will assume leadership of Lockheed Martin upon my retirement and his energy, skill and business acumen will continue to serve you well. I am sure Bob will be a great leader, bringing fresh thinking and perspective to our company and our industry. I leave confident that the future of Lockheed Martin is indeed bright and the best years are ahead.
March 1, 2004
 Vance D. Coffman
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
LOCKHEED MARTIN ANNUAL REPORT 2003 — 5
