SOUTHWEST AIRLINES CO. ♥ FIVE SYMBOLS OF FREEDOM
TO OUR SHAREHOLDERS: 1997 WAS SOUTHWEST AIRLINES’ 25TH CONSECUTIVE YEAR OF PROFITABILITY IN AN INDUSTRY LONG NOTED FOR ITS VULNERABILITY TO ECONOMIC CYCLES. OUR PEOPLE’S ABILITY TO PRODUCE PROFITS IN BAD, AS WELL AS GOOD, ECONOMIC TIMES HAS REWARDED THEM WITH JOB SECURITY AND INCREASING PROSPERITY.
It has also produced bountiful returns for our Shareholders, including, of course, our Employee-Shareholders. Put very simply, on behalf of our Employees and our Shareholders, our goal for the next 25 years is to replicate our successes of the last 25 years.
Our 1997 earnings of $317.8 million (diluted net income per share of $1.40) surpassed the $207.3 million of 1996 (diluted net income per share of $.92) by 53.3 percent, as our operating revenues increased 12.1 percent while every category of operating expenses, except salaries, wages, and benefits (up 13.7 percent), increased by a lesser percentage, resulting in an aggregate operating expense growth of 7.8 percent on a 9.2 percent expansion of available seat mile capacity.
Our first Boeing 737-700s were placed in commercial service in January 1998, and we anticipate receiving 22 of these greatly advanced and most economical and efficient new model aircraft in 1998. Because of our confidence in the 737-700 and its importance to the future competitive success of Southwest Airlines, in December 1997 we exercised options, and placed purchase orders, for 59 additional aircraft, raising our total firm orders to 129 and providing ample coverage, through options, of our potential fleet needs through 2006.
4

SOUTHWEST AIRLINES CO. ♥ FIVE SYMBOLS OF FREEDOM
At present, we anticipate devoting approximately one-third of our 1998 incremental capacity to opening two new cities and the other two-thirds to augmenting service levels in our existing markets.
Our People have made Southwest Airlines an enjoyable and exciting place to work, filled with an immense feeling of pride in accomplishment, by them and for our nation. Every new city that Southwest enters — from Providence to San Diego and from Seattle to Tampa — immediately experiences enormous increases in air travel for both business and personal reasons. The air service provided by our People frees Americans to move about their country; enshrines Southwest as a Symbol of Freedom for the United States; and honors our People as our industry’s foremost Freedom Fighters. Fortune magazine, after an extensive survey and evaluation, recently pronounced Southwest Airlines the “best place to work for in America.”Our People make it that way: they do well for themselves through doing good for others. I salute their humanistic and
altruistic spirits —
their goodness that has led to greatness.
Most sincerely,
Herbert D. Kelleher Chairman, President, and Chief Executive Officer February 1, 1998
5
