 July 15, 2015
Fellow shareholders,
In Q2, we eclipsed 65 million members, with over 42 million in the US and 23 million internationally. We are at the forefront of a wave of global Internet TV adoption and intend to make our service available throughout the world by the end of 2016. Our summary results and Q3 forecast are below.
  1

 Q2 Results and Q3 Forecast
We added a Q2 record 3.3 million new streaming members, compared to 1.7 million in the previous year quarter. As a reminder, the quarterly guidance we provide is our actual internal forecast at the time we report and we clearly under-forecast in Q2 (forecast was 2.5 million net adds). We strive for accuracy in the forecast and our Q3 estimates are based on everything we know up to today.
We gained 0.9 million members in the US and added 2.4 million members internationally in Q2. We believe the higher than anticipated level of acquisition was fueled by the growing strength of our original programming slate, which in Q2 included the first seasons of M​arvel’s Daredevil,​S​ense8, Dragons: Race to the Edge a​nd G​race and Frankie​as well as season 3 of O​range is the New Black.​US revenue growth was also driven by a 5% year over year increase in ASP due to uptake in our HD 2-stream plan. We continue to target a 40% US contribution margin by 2020, even though we are running ahead of plan given stronger than expected top line performance and lower content and other streaming costs. We are forecasting Q3 US net adds of 1.15 million, slightly higher than the year ago period.
Our international segment is growing at a rapid pace. We did not add additional markets in Q2 but saw continued improvement across existing markets, including a full quarter of additions from our successful March 24, 2015 launch in Australia/New Zealand. We project Q3 international net adds of 2.4 million.
International revenue grew 48% year over year, despite an -$83 million impact from currency (+5% ASP growth x-F/X). As we expected, international losses increased sequentially with a full quarter of operating costs in AU/NZ. We expect this trend to continue in the second half as we launch additional markets (Japan in Q3 and Spain, Italy and Portugal in Q4) and prepare for further global expansion in 2016, including China as we continue to explore options there.
EPS for Q2 amounted to $0.06 after adjustment for our 7-for-1 stock split (EPS would have been $0.42 using pre-split share count). We remain committed to running around break-even globally on a net income basis through 2016, and to then deliver material global profits in 2017 and beyond.
Content
We are making great progress shifting to exclusive content and expanding our original content, which differentiates our service, drives enjoyment for existing members and helps motivate consumers to join Netflix.
In Q2, we launched our largest number to date of high profile Netflix original series. On April 10, Marvel’s Daredevil d​ebuted to strong audience engagement, particularly for a new show. G​race and Frankie,​the bittersweet comedy starring Lily Tomlin and Jane Fonda which launched on May 8, also has found a broad and appreciative audience around the world. Both series have already begun their second season of production.
 2

 Our global expansion extends to our content strategy as well. S​ense8, t​he mind-bending cinematic thriller from the Wachowski siblings and J. Michael Straczynski that debuted June 5, is an ambitious, truly international show with talent behind and in front of the camera from multiple countries. Similarly, on August 7, we will launch in all territories our first non-English language original, C​lub de Cuervos,​a​family comedy set in the world of f​utbol​from Mexican filmmaker Gaz Alazraki, and on August 28, ​N​arcos,​a​gripping account of the roots of the cocaine trade, shot in Colombia and starring the great Brazilian star Wagner Moura as Pablo Escobar.
The original documentary C​hef’s Table​and our latest DreamWorks Animation series D​ragons: Race to the Edge​are among our most viewed new originals to date. They are the perfect example of what we strive for in our original programming; an elevated version of popular genres that reach a large audience globally.
We closed the quarter with season 3 of O​range is the New Black,​which went live on June 11 and set off a social media shockwave around the world. On the following Sunday, Netflix members globally watched a record number of hours in a single day, led by O​range,​despite the season finale of HBO’s Game of Thrones​and game five of the NBA finals also falling on that Sunday. Global enthusiasm for the third season of O​range​underlines our ability to create franchise properties that bring new members to Netflix as well as delighting current ones. Nearly ninety percent of Netflix members have engaged with Netflix original content, another indicator that we are on the right path.
We anticipate that as our global content spend approaches $5 billion in 2016 on a P&L basis (over $6 billion cash), we will devote more investment to originals both in absolute dollars and percentage terms. This includes not only series, documentaries and stand-up but also original feature films.
We are moving into the original film business in order to have new, high-quality movies that our global members can find only on Netflix. As with series, we’ve chosen to take a portfolio approach covering a wide variety of genres and based around creators with great track records and stories they are passionate about. The first of our films, B​easts of No Nation, a​gripping war drama from the award-winning director Cary Fukunaga (T​rue Detective) a​nd starring award-winning Idris Elba (Mandela, Luther, The Wire)​will be available to all Netflix members and in select theaters in October. In June, we announced W​ar Machine,​a provocative satirical comedy starring Brad Pitt, which will be exclusively available to Netflix members and in select theaters next year. The release schedule for our s l a t e o f o r i g i n a l f i l m s c a n b e f o u n d h​e r e .​
Product
In June, we unveiled the new Netflix website, our first major update in over four years. T​he new experience has been built from the ground up to make it faster and easier for our members to discover great content to watch. The UI is a richer and more visual experience with improved title art and a better details view. It also works more like an app and less like a series of linked web pages. Early feedback has been positive from both members and the media, and retention should benefit.
     3

 In support of expanding our service globally, we are focused on adding more languages, optimizing our personalization algorithms for a global library in local markets, and expanding support for a range of device, operator and payment partnerships. We are also placing a greater emphasis on optimizing for mobile, which is the main means for Internet access in many emerging markets where we will be expanding in the future.
Strong Net Neutrality
Charter Communications made net neutrality history today by committing to open and free interconnection across the Charter/TWC network, if their pending merger is approved. This move ensures that all online video providers can aggressively compete for consumers' favor, without selective and increasing fees paid to ISPs. Charter's interconnection policy is the right way to scale the Internet. It means consumer will receive the fast connection speeds they expect. The Charter/TWC transaction, with this condition, would deliver significant public interest benefits to broadband consumers, and we urge its timely approval.
Competition
We compete with linear TV, PPV, video piracy, other Internet networks, video gaming and many other sources of entertainment. The recent Sandvine results from North America show that, looking at just the Internet networks segment, we continue to improve faster than others. Note that this data measures peak megabits, not peak viewing hours, so YouTube, for example, with more modest average video quality, is underrepresented in terms of hours.
      4

 DVD
Our DVD-by-mail business in the US continues to serve 5.3 million members and provided $77.9 million in contribution profit in Q2. The broad selection of titles, including new release movies and TV shows, remains appealing to a core user base and means that the tail on this business should be quite long.
Free Cash Flow & Capital
Free cash flow in Q2 amounted to -$229 million, compared with -$163 million in Q1. As we have previously detailed, our investment in originals is working capital intensive, which results in higher cash spent upfront relative to content amortization, and, we anticipate this trend to continue given our increased investment in originals. At the end of Q2, gross debt totaled $2.4 billion, which represented 4.6x LTM EBITDA and we ended the quarter with $2.8 billion in cash & equivalents and short term investments.
Reference
For quick reference, our eight most recent investor letters are: A​pril 2015,​J​anuary 2015,​O​ctober 2014,​J​uly 2014,​A​pril 2014,​J​anuary 2014,​O​ctober 2013,​J​uly 2013.​
Summary
We’re pleased to see the growing momentum of our original programming driving strong growth in the US and abroad. With our first set of international markets having achieved contribution profitability, we’ll be making our first foray into Asia this Fall with our Japan launch, and are gearing up to offer our service around the globe.
Sincerely,
Reed Hastings, CEO David Wells, CFO
              5

 July 15th, 2015 Earnings Interview
Reed Hastings, David Wells and Ted Sarandos will participate in a live video interview today at 1:30
p . m . P a c i f i c T i m e a t ​y​o u t u b e . c o m / n e t f l i x i r .​T h e d i s c u s s i o n w i l l b e m o d e r a t e d b y M a r k M a h a n e y , R B C Capital Markets and Rich Greenfield, BTIG Research. Q​uestions that investors would like to see asked should be sent to​mark.mahaney@rbccm.com or michael@moffettnathanson.com.
Use of Non-GAAP Measures
This shareholder letter and its attachments include reference to the non-GAAP financial measures of net income on a pro forma basis excluding the re​lease of tax reserves,​free cash flow and EBITDA. Management believes that the non-GAAP measures of net income on a pro forma basis excluding the release of tax reserves provides useful information as these measures exclude effects that are not indicative of our core operating results. Management believes that free cash flow and EBITDA are important liquidity metrics because they measure, during a given period, the amount of cash generated that is available to repay debt obligations, make investments and for certain other activities. However, these non-GAAP measures should be considered in addition to, not as a substitute for or superior to, net income, operating income, diluted earnings per share and net cash provided by operating activities, or other financial measures prepared in accordance with GAAP. Reconciliation to the GAAP equivalent of these non-GAAP measures are contained in tabular form on the attached unaudited financial statements.
Forward-Looking Statements
This shareholder letter contains certain forward-looking statements within the meaning of the federal securities laws, including statements regarding US contribution margin growth; international expansion; content launches; product improvements; content spend, including investments in originals; lifespan of our DVD business; member growth domestically and internationally, including net, total and paid; revenue; contribution profit (loss) and contribution margin for both domestic (streaming and DVD) and international operations, as well as consolidated operating income, net income, earnings per share and free cash flow. The forward-looking statements in this letter are subject to risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results and events to differ, including, without limitation: our ability to attract new members and retain existing members; our ability to compete effectively; maintenance and expansion of device platforms for streaming; fluctuations in consumer usage of our service; service disruptions; production risks; actions of Internet Service Providers; and, competition, including consumer adoption of different modes of viewing in-home filmed entertainment. A detailed discussion of these and other risks and uncertainties that could
   IR Contact:
Spencer Wang
Vice President, Finance & Investor Relations 408 540-3700
     PR Contact:
Jonathan Friedland
Chief Communications Officer 310 734-2958
  6

 cause actual results and events to differ materially from such forward-looking statements is included in our filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission, including our Annual Report on Form 10-K filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission on January 29, 2015. The Company provides internal forecast numbers. Investors should anticipate that actual performance will vary from these forecast numbers based on risks and uncertainties discussed above and in our Annual Report on Form 10-K. We undertake no obligation to update forward-looking statements to reflect events or circumstances occurring after the date of this shareholder letter.
 7

Netflix, Inc.
Consolidated Statements of Operations
(unaudited)
(in thousands, except per share data)
Cost of revenues
Marketing
Technology and development Operating income
Other income (expense):
Interest expense Income before income taxes
Net income Basic
Diluted
Weighted-average common shares outstanding:
Basic
Diluted
Three Months Ended
March 31, 2015
1,046,401
Six Months Ended
June 30, June 30, 2015 2014
         June 30, 2015
1,121,752
June 30, 2014
             Revenues   $ 1,644,694
$ 1,573,129
$ 1,340,407
$ 3,217,823
914,848 2,168,153 1,784,034
$ 2,610,496
             General and administrative   95,906
91,489
60,014
187,395
115,914
                 Interest and other income (expense) 872
(32,293)
1,100
(31,421)
2,501
             Provision for income taxes   14,155
$ $
$
155,061 74,835
(35,217) 40,490
26,335 0.06
$ $
143,106 97,456
(26,737) 38,426
23,696 0.06
0.05 423,624
433,809
$ $
$
197,140 194,677
120,763 391,817
115,182 298,167 129,600 172,291
(13,328) (61,954) 117,372 78,916
71,018 $ 50,031 $ 0.17 $ 0.12 $
0.16       $ 0.12     $ 419,974       424,486
431,441 434,958
257,861
225,492 227,195
(23,380) 206,316
124,133 0.30
0.29 419,349
431,141
          14,730
46,354
28,885
82,183
                        Earnings per share:
 0.06       $ 425,340
436,097
       8

Netflix, Inc.
Consolidated Balance Sheets
(unaudited)
(in thousands, except share and par value data)
Current assets:
Cash and cash equivalents
Short-term investments
Current content library, net
Other current assets Non-current content library, net
Property and equipment, net
Other non-current assets
Liabilities and Stockholders' Equity
Current liabilities:
Current content liabilities
Accounts payable
Accrued expenses
Total current liabilities
Non-current content liabilities
Long-term debt
Total liabilities
Stockholders' equity:
Common stock
Accumulated other comprehensive loss
Retained earnings
Total liabilities and stockholders' equity
As of
    June 30, 2015
December 31, 2014
1,113,608
494,888
2,125,702
206,271 2,773,326
149,875
192,981
2,117,241
201,581
69,746 2,663,154
1,575,832
900,000
5,198,943
1,042,870
(4,446)
819,284 7,056,651
     Assets
$
2,293,872       $
        Total current assets 5,600,510
3,940,469
    Total assets   $ 9,654,861
    $ 7,056,651
      $
502,886
2,510,946
292,806 3,640,767
171,396
242,188
2,556,180
211,729
150,406 3,220,069
1,942,624
2,400,000
7,622,786
1,200,880
(38,120)
869,315 9,654,861
$
     Deferred revenue   301,754
274,586
       Other non-current liabilities   60,093
59,957
          Total stockholders' equity 2,032,075
   1,857,708
  $
$
     9

Netflix, Inc.
Consolidated Statements of Cash Flows
(unaudited) (in thousands)
Net income
Additions to streaming content library
Change in streaming content liabilities
Amortization of streaming content library
Amortization of DVD content library
Depreciation and amortization of property, equipment and intangibles
Stock-based compensation expense
Excess tax benefits from stock-based compensation
Other non-cash items
Deferred taxes
Changes in operating assets and liabilities:
Other current assets
Accounts payable
Accrued expenses
Deferred revenue
Other non-current assets and liabilities
Cash flows from investing activities:
Acquisition of DVD content library
Purchases of property and equipment
Other assets
Purchases of short-term investments
Proceeds from sale of short-term investments
Proceeds from maturities of short-term investments
Cash flows from financing activities:
Proceeds from issuance of common stock
Proceeds from issuance of debt
Issuance costs
Excess tax benefits from stock-based compensation Net cash provided by financing activities
Net (decrease) increase in cash and cash equivalents Cash and cash equivalents, end of period
Non-GAAP free cash flow reconciliation:
Net cash (used in) provided by operating activities
Acquisition of DVD content library
Purchases of property and equipment
Other assets
Three Months Ended
Six Months Ended
        June 30, March 31, 2015 2015
26,335 $ 23,696 (1,273,677) (1,611,925)
191,154 626,325
822,600 749,518
20,813 21,185
15,581 15,167
28,590 27,441
(39,427) (29,001)
6,682 6,306
(4,232) (37,042) (39,614) 23,109
6,447 (10,625)
41,624 35,922
16,414 10,754
(633) 21,788
(19,786) (22,906)
(27,538) (13,036)
(639) 225
(67,949) (90,940)
48,412 51,948
19,170 31,887
23,804 10,916
— 1,500,000
(397) (17,232)
39,427 29,001
62,547 1,522,434
(160,905) 1,341,169
June 30, June 30, 2014 2015
June 30, 2014
              Cash flows from operating activities:
$
$
71,018 $ 50,031
(813,314)     (2,885,602) (1,562,713)
$
817,479       120,603
124,133
         Adjustments to reconcile net income to net cash (used in) provided by operating activities:
    78,359
639,037
16,923
12,977
29,285
(14,628)
3,251
(16,569) (20,685)
(3,086)
59,008
11,315
3,133
(20,981)
(19,869)
1,129
(170,908)
89,662
92,014
14,469
—
(353)
14,628
28,473
56,794
1,572,118
1,239,772
      41,998       33,044
30,748
25,359
      56,031       55,110
(68,428)
(47,360)
      12,988       5,447
(41,274)       (29,672)
      (16,505)
14,381
      (4,178)       19,726
77,546
58,566
      27,168       25,563
21,155
10,424
  Net cash (used in) provided by operating activities (181,343)
    (127,382)
    56,024
    (308,725)
    92,383
       (42,692)       (35,895)
(40,574)
(33,203)
      (414)       1,424
(158,889)
(231,454)
      100,360       232,710
51,057
95,104
  Net cash (used in) provided by investing activities (48,330)
    (42,822)
    (28,953)
    (91,152)
    28,686
       34,720       46,917
1,500,000
400,000
      (17,629)       (7,080)
         Principal payments of lease financing obligations (287)
(251)
(271)
(538)
(538)
                   Effect of exchange rate changes on cash and cash equivalents 6,221
(11,061)
1,250
(4,840)
1,551
         Cash and cash equivalents, beginning of period 2,454,777
$ 2,293,872
$ 2,454,777
$ 1,214,244
$
68,428
1,584,981
1,180,264
2,293,872
47,360
486,659
609,279
$ 1,214,244
1,113,608
1,157,450
1,113,608
604,965
               Three Months Ended
Six Months Ended
        June 30, 2015
(181,343)       $
(19,786)
(27,538)
(639)
March 31, 2015
(127,382)     $
June 30, 2014
June 30, 2015
(308,725)     $
(42,692)
(40,574)
(414)
June 30, 2014
92,383
(35,895)
(33,203)
1,424
     $
56,024     $
(22,906) (20,981)
(13,036) (19,869)
225 1,129
          Non-GAAP free cash flow     $ (229,306)
    $ (163,099)
     $ 16,303
     $ (392,405)
     $ 24,709
   10

Netflix, Inc.
Segment Information
(unaudited) (in thousands)
Total memberships at end of period
Paid memberships at end of period Revenues
Cost of revenues
Contribution profit
International Streaming
Total memberships at end of period
Paid memberships at end of period Revenues
Cost of revenues
As of / Three Months Ended
As of/ Six Months Ended
         June 30, 2015
42,300
March 31, 2015
41,397
June 30, 2014
36,244
June 30, 2015
42,300
June 30, 2014
36,244
              Domestic Streaming
41,057       40,315     35,085     41,057     35,085 $ 1,025,913       $ 984,532     $ 838,225     $ 2,010,445     $ 1,636,842
612,691 339,795
582,529 312,452
546,223 227,275
1,195,220 652,247
1,063,317 428,540
        Marketing   73,427
89,551
64,727
    23,251       20,877     13,801     23,251     13,801
21,649
$ 454,763
19,304
$ 415,397
12,907 $ 307,461
21,649 $ 870,160
12,907
$ 574,579
          Marketing 123,713
105,126
5,564
56,036
6,261
228,839
5,314
112,876
6,261
422,966       375,278     266,697     798,244     511,964
          Contribution profit (loss) (91,916)
     Domestic DVD
Total memberships at end of period
Paid memberships at end of period Revenues
Cost of revenues
Consolidated
Revenues
Cost of revenues
Contribution profit
Operating income
Other income (expense)
Provision for income taxes
5,314
5,219       5,470     6,167     5,219     6,167 $ 164,018       $ 173,200     $ 194,721     $ 337,218     $ 399,075
86,095
88,594
101,928
174,689
208,753
         $ 1,644,694       $1,573,129     $ 1,340,407     $ 3,217,823     $ 2,610,496
1,121,752
325,802
74,835
1,046,401
332,051
97,456
914,848
304,796
129,600
2,168,153
657,853
172,291
1,784,034
568,601
227,195
162,978
(156,923)
144,985
              (65,007)
(15,272)
(50,261)
            Contribution profit     77,923
84,606
92,793
162,529
190,322
            Marketing   197,140
194,677
120,763
391,817
257,861
              Other operating expenses 250,967
234,595
175,196
485,562
341,406
     (34,345)       (59,030)     (12,228)     (93,375)     (20,879)
14,155
14,730
46,354
28,885
82,183
Net income       $ 26,335
    $ 23,696
     $ 71,018
     $ 50,031
     $ 124,133
   11

Netflix, Inc.
Non-GAAP Information
(unaudited)
(in thousands, except per share data)
GAAP net income
Add:
Interest and other (income) expense
Provision (benefit) for income taxes
Depreciation and amortization of property, equipment and intangibles
June 30, 2014
September 30, 2014
Three Months Ended
December 31, 2014
March 31, 2015
23,696 59,030
14,730
15,167 140,064
June 30, 2015
26,335 34,345
14,155
15,581 119,006
                           Non-GAAP Adjusted EBITDA reconciliation:
                           Stock based compensation
Adjusted EBITDA
$
$
71,018 $ 12,228
46,354
12,977
29,285
171,862 $
59,295 12,870
38,242
14,357 154,642
$
$
83,371 19,530
(37,855)
14,312 109,609
$
$
$
$
29,878
30,251
27,441
28,590
          Three Months Ended
December 31, 2014
     Non-GAAP net income reconciliation:
GAAP net income Non-GAAP net income
Basic
Diluted
$ $
83,371
44,759
0.11
0.10
422,244
432,514
   Less: Release of tax accrual
(38,612)
     Non-GAAP earnings per share:
   Weighted-average common shares outstanding:
Basic
Diluted
    12
