 April 18, 2016 Fellow shareholders,
We are off to a great start in 2016, expanding the Netflix service to 130 new countries in January and finishing Q1 with over 81 million members on the strength of our fast growing slate of original content. Since 2010, we have offered unlimited streaming for $7.99 per month in the US, and we hope to maintain this affordable entry­price for a long time. As we’ve made vast improvements in our service and content, consumers see even more value and our membership grows. Q1 was no exception and our summary results are below.
  1

 Q1 Results
Net additions in Q1 ‘16 amounted to a record 6.74 million, surpassing our prior high water mark of 5.59 million in Q4 ‘15 and against 4.88 million in the year­ago period. Of our 81.5 million members, 42% are now outside of the US. Operating income was $49 million vs. $97 million in the year ago quarter, as we continue to invest in international markets.
Performance in the quarter benefited from the launch of several series, including M​aking a Murderer (a late December debut), F​uller House​(February), H​ouse of Cards S​eason 4 (March) and D​aredevil Season 2 (March), complemented by a diverse mix of new films, documentaries, series and kids shows available globally.
In the US, we added 2.23 million members in Q1, against 2.28 million a year ago, and 2.25 two years ago. Our forecast for the quarter was low (at 1.75 million) because we underestimated the positive acquisition impact of our major original content debuts.
US revenue rose 18% year­over­year, reflecting 14% growth in average paid memberships and a 3% increase in ARPU. US contribution profit totaled $413 million, or a 35.5% margin, compared to 31.7% a year ago.
International revenue increased 57% year­over­year, including the negative impact of currency (­$82 million on a y/y basis). Excluding F/X, international ARPU rose 7% year­over­year. Our Q1 international contribution loss of $104 million came in better than forecast due to the timing of content spend.
Our established markets around the world are all growing, and in early Q1 we added 130 more countries. By expanding broadly at once, we are learning more quickly about how best to please consumers across a wide variety of cultures and markets. In most of these markets, so far, Netflix is offered only in English and payment methods are limited primarily to international credit cards. In the coming quarters, we will add more local languages, content, payment options and customer support.
We are pleased Netflix is finding acceptance around the world. Consumers worldwide are delighted to be able to enjoy our original and exclusive series and films instantaneously. We have lots of work to do to make Netflix more relevant market by market, but the opportunity is amazing.
Q2 Forecast
As a reminder, the guidance we provide is our actual internal forecast at the time we report. For the second quarter, we expect to add 2.5 million members with 0.5 million in the US and 2.0 million internationally (versus prior year 2.4 million).
In the US, our Q2 net adds forecast of 0.5 million is in­line with prior years (0.5, 0.6, 0.6, and 0.9 million from 2012­2015), taking into account a modest impact from the beginning of un­grandfathering.
 2

 Our international forecast for fewer net adds than prior year is due to a tough comparison against the Australia/New Zealand launch. The ANZ growth spike in Q2 last year resulted in international Q2 net adds more than doubling year over year (from 1.12 million to 2.37 million). While ANZ is growing steadily this Q2, it is less than the launch spike last year. Ex­ANZ, international net adds would be forecast up this quarter. International net adds are down sequentially both due to standard seasonality and our launch in 130 countries at very beginning of Q1 (so Q1 captured the initial surge of sign­ups).
In the US, we are forecasting flat Y/Y contribution margin in Q2, due to a large slate of content releases and associated marketing. We expect strong y/y margin growth to resume in Q3 and we remain on track to achieve our 40% US contribution margin target by 2020.
We expect Q2 international contribution loss to improve sequentially primarily due to recent favorable currency movements. We anticipate that international contribution losses in the second half of 2016 will be similar to the first half, as ongoing investments offset improved profitability in our more mature markets.
On China, we are continuing discussions but have no material update on our approach or timing. Whatever we do will have only a modest financial effect in the near term.
With respect to un­grandfathering, currently, more than half of our US members pay only $7.99 or $8.99 for our $9.99 HD 2­screen plan. We will phase out this grandfathering gradually over the remainder of 2016, with our longest­tenured members getting the longest benefit. To reinforce brand trust, we won’t change anyone’s price without their acknowledgement of the new price in their member experience, where they will see a dialogue box about their options. Members can choose our $7.99 SD 1­screen plan, our $9.99 HD 2­screen plan or our $11.99 UHD 4­screen plan. We are rolling this out slowly over the year, rather than mostly in May, so we can learn as we go. Most of our grandfathered members are in the US, but we’ll take the same approach internationally.
We expect only modestly increased churn from un­grandfathering, partially because these members have been with us for a reasonable period already, and because our content continues to improve. The increase in ARPU will allow us to invest more in content next year, and we are taking up our expected spend from about $5B in 2016 to over $6B on a P&L basis in 2017 (more on a cash basis).
Content
In Q1, we had our most ambitious slate of content releases to date. Since the February 19th premiere of Judd Apatow's L​ove,​we have debuted at least one new show or feature film every single week of the quarter. This includes five new seasons of original series as well as several original feature films, documentaries, kids shows and stand­up specials. We launched the second season of M​arvel’s Daredevil​and the fourth season of H​ouse of Cards​to strong c​ritical reviews.​
In addition to stepping up the pace, we’re also broadening our programming to appeal to a large global membership base with diverse tastes. We expanded into the multi­camera sitcom format in Q1
  3

 with F​uller House,​a family comedy that met with overwhelmingly p​ositive viewer reception.​F​uller House,​and the late Q4 release of true crime documentary M​aking a Murderer,​are excellent examples of how Netflix is breaking through the cultural zeitgeist and how our portfolio of original content continues to be a great driver of membership growth for Netflix.
We are maintaining a fast pace of content launches in Q2, starting with the recently released sitcom T h e R a n c h , ​s t a r r i n g A s h t o n K u t c h e r . W e ’ l l l a u n c h s e v e n n e w s e a s o n s o f o r i g i n a l s e r i e s , i n c l u d i n g Unbreakable Kimmy Schmidt,​B​loodline,​G​race and Frankie​and O​range is the New Black.​We will also premiere the original films T​he Do­Over,​Adam Sandler’s second film for Netflix, S​pecial
C o r r e s p o n d e n t s ​f e a t u r i n g R i c k y G e r v a i s a n d E r i c B a n a , T ​ h e F u n d a m e n t a l s o f C a r i n g , ​ s t a r r i n g P a u l R u d d and B​rahman Naman f​rom the maverick Indian director Q.
Q2 will also mark our initial foray into the talk show genre with C​helsea,​starring Chelsea Handler. This talk show will be a bit of a departure from the normal “all episodes at once” model of our other originals. C​helsea w​ill premiere new episodes nightly, three nights per week, shortly after the show is recorded in front of a live audience and will incorporate stylistic elements from her well­received
N e t f l i x d o c u m e n t a r y s e r i e s ​C​h e l s e a D o e s .​ ​W e a r e e x c i t e d t o b r i n g C h e l s e a H a n d l e r a n d t h i s n e w s h o w to our global platform that opens up our original content offering to include more topical programming that merges our already successful comedy and documentary efforts.
Our investment in original content for kids and families has helped make Netflix a destination for great creators of live action and animated television. Our original series were nominated for 33 Daytime Emmy nominations across 7 of our original shows, including A​ll Hail King Julien,​P​roject MC2 and D​ragons: Race to The Edge.​In Q2, we are releasing nine new seasons of original series for kids including K​ong: King of The Apes​and a re­boot of V​oltron.​
With our footprint now virtually global, Netflix is uniquely positioned to bring stories from all over the world to people all over the world. We’ve stepped up production of non­English language series following up on last year’s success of C​lub de Cuervos​from Mexico and N​arcos,​which was filmed in Colombia in Spanish and English. Our first French series M​arseille,​a political drama starring Gerard Depardieu, premieres globally on May 5, while our new Japanese original series H​ibana​p​remieres globallyinJune.Wearealsoworkingon3​%​inBrazil, S​uburra​i​nItaly,D​ark​inGermany,an
a s ­ y e t ­ u n t i t l e d p e r i o d s e r i e s i n S p a i n , a s e c o n d s e a s o n o f C​l u b D e C u e r v o s ​a​n d o u r s e c o n d M e x i c a n original series, I​ngobernable, s​tarring Kate Del Castillo in Mexico,​a​s well as our first fully global
o r i g i n a l J a p a n e s e a n i m e s e r i e s P​e r f e c t B o n e s .​ ​T h e s e s e r i e s h e l p b o t h t o c e m e n t t h e p o p u l a r i t y a n d relevance of Netflix in the territories where they originate and, in success, will reach a broad global audience.
We are investing about 5% of our cash content budget in original films. As we learn, we may spend beyond that, once we’ve established that new, fully­exclusive movies debuting on Netflix creates more consumer excitement and member viewing than the territory­by­territory licensing of nine­month­old “Pay One” movies that are also available on TVOD and DVD. Upcoming original films in the second half of 2016 include W​ar Machine,​a satirical comedy starring Brad Pitt and directed by
            4

 David Michod, and M​ascots,​the latest ensemble comedy from Christopher Guest.​Our 2017 lineup includes Bong Joon­Ho’s O​kja,​and B​right,​an epic action film starring Will Smith and directed by David Ayer.
T h e r e l e a s e s c h e d u l e f o r o u r a n n o u n c e d u p c o m i n g o r i g i n a l c o n t e n t c a n b e f o u n d o n o u r P​R s i t e .​
To highlight the expansion of our original content offering, we recently hosted an event in Paris for press and influencers from across Europe, the Middle East and Africa. Below is a photo of Kevin Spacey and Ted Sarandos, surrounded by our titles, before a large audience.
  Product
At Netflix, we strive to deliver the best video experience for our members and picture quality is an important element of this. In 2014, we began streaming in 4K with the debut of H​ouse of Cards Season 2. Today, we have one of the largest catalogues of 4K content available, with the number of 4K titles increasing 10x since inception. Not surprisingly, streaming of 4K content is growing as a share of total viewing.
We are also continuing to push the boundaries of visual impact and we're excited about High Dynamic Range (HDR). While 4K offers more pixels, HDR provides greater depth with brighter highlights and a wider color range. Today, you can experience HDR on Netflix with Season One of M​arco Polo,​if you have an HDR­enabled TV and subscribe to our 4­screen UHD plan. We are expanding our HDR content catalogue rapidly.
 5

 It wasn't too long ago that online video was associated with grainy images and constant buffering. But today, the Internet, not cable or broadcast distribution, is actually home to the cutting edge of video quality and it will only get better from here as Internet TV replaces linear television.
We started rolling out new and more efficient encodes during Q1, offering either 20% savings in data, or a commensurate increase in quality, depending on whether a consumer is bandwidth­limited or not. This will be reflected in our ISP speed index reports as a small reduction in average bitrate across all ISPs, but most of the value is realized in improved quality for our customers. We are now turning our attention to mobile­specific encodes, with a desire to deliver better video at lower bandwidth to these devices, which are increasingly important in our newest markets.
Partnerships
Similar to our content portfolio, our partnerships have expanded in scope over the years, growing in importance with the launch of our service across the world. Originally focused on consumer electronics device integration, Netflix partnerships now span a wide array of relationships with pay TV and mobile operators, Internet service providers, mobile device and set top box manufacturers, and brick and mortar retailers (gift cards).
We integrate Netflix to make it easier for members to sign up, access and pay for the service. In addition, our partners benefit through customer acquisition, the opportunity to upsell higher value packages of speed/data/content, lower churn and increases in brand affinity. Recently, Canadian operator Telus said:
"Nearly half of Optik TV customers are also Netflix subscribers. Making Netflix available was a simple but powerful innovation to make our customers’ entertainment experience better, and far easier. Not only has this driven deeper engagement with our Optik customers who have Netflix, these same customers are actually consuming more content on Optik, including more on demand content, than ever before.”
As Internet TV grows, it is exciting to be a part of a vibrant ecosystem driving innovation and value for consumers all over the world.
Competition
If you think about your last 30 days, and analyze the evenings you did not watch Netflix, you can understand how broad our competition really is. Whether you played video games, surfed the web, watched a DVD, TVOD, or linear TV, wandered through YouTube, read a book, streamed Hulu or Amazon, or pirated content (hopefully not), you can see the market for relaxation time and disposable income is huge, and we are but a little boat in a vast sea. For example, while we’ve grown from zero to 47 million members in the USA, HBO has also grown, which shows how large the entertainment market is. We earn a tiny fraction of consumers’ time and money, and have lots of opportunity ahead to win more of your evenings away from all those other activities if we can keep improving.
 6

 Free Cash Flow and Capital Structure
At the end of Q1, we had cash and equivalents totaling $2.1 billion. In Q1, free cash flow was ­$261 million, compared with ­$276 million in Q4 ‘15. As we have written in the past, our investment in original programming (particularly owned content) is more cash intensive upfront, resulting in a timing­driven gap between net income and free cash flow. We currently have $2.4 billion of long term debt. With our low debt to enterprise value of 5%, our plan is to raise additional capital through the high yield market later in 2016 or in early 2017. Given the attractiveness of our business model in a growth area relative to other large cap companies, as well as our low debt to EV ratio, investors view our bonds as quite secure; they t​rade​better than the BB index, despite our single B credit rating, (but not yet as well as media firms like V​iacom​or D​iscovery)​. Over time, the ratings agencies may catch up to the buyside in their views of the credit risk for Netflix.
DVD
Our DVD service ended Q1 with 4.7M members and $72M in contribution profit.
Reference
For quick reference, our eight most recent investor letters are: J​anuary, 2016,​O​ctober 2015,​J​uly 2015,​A​pril 2015,​J​anuary 2015,​O​ctober 2014,​J​uly 2014,​A​pril 2014.​
Also, investors may want to read our L​ong Term View​document as we make small changes in most quarters.
April 18th 2pm PT Earnings Interview
Reed Hastings, David Wells and Ted Sarandos will participate in a live video interview today at 2:00 p . m . P a c i f i c T i m e a t ​y​o u t u b e . c o m / n e t f l i x i r .​T h e d i s c u s s i o n w i l l b e m o d e r a t e d b y B e n S w i n b u r n e , Morgan Stanley and and Peter Kafka, Re/code. Q​uestions that investors would like to see asked should be sent to​benjamin.swinburne@morganstanley.com or peter@recode.net.
                IR Contact:
Spencer Wang
Vice President, Finance & Investor Relations 408 809­5360
     PR Contact:
Jonathan Friedland
Chief Communications Officer 310 734­2958
 Use of Non‐GAAP Measures
This shareholder letter and its attachments include reference to the non­GAAP financial measure of net income on a pro forma basis excluding the re​lease of tax reserves,​and to free cash flow and EBITDA. Management believes that the non­GAAP measure of net income on a pro forma basis excluding the release of tax reserves provides useful information as this measure excludes effects that are not indicative of our core operating results. Management believes that free cash flow and EBITDA
 7

 are important liquidity metrics because they measure, during a given period, the amount of cash generated that is available to repay debt obligations, make investments and for certain other activities or the amount of cash used in operations, including investments in global streaming content. However, these non­GAAP measures should be considered in addition to, not as a substitute for or superior to, net income, operating income, diluted earnings per share and net cash provided by operating activities, or other financial measures prepared in accordance with GAAP. Reconciliation to the GAAP equivalent of these non­GAAP measures are contained in tabular form on the attached unaudited financial statements.
Forward‐Looking Statements
This shareholder letter contains certain forward­looking statements within the meaning of the federal securities laws, including statements regarding investments in international markets; localization of our service; expansion to China and the financial impact of such expansion; end of grandfathered pricing and its impact on churn and ARPU; price change process; content spending; future content offerings; original content strategy; product developments such as HDR content and encode efficiency improvements; future capital raises and timing of such raises; member growth domestically and internationally, including net, total and paid; revenue; contribution profit (loss) and contribution margin for both domestic (streaming and DVD) and international operations, as well as consolidated operating income, net income, earnings per share and free cash flow. The forward­looking statements in this letter are subject to risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results and events to differ, including, without limitation: our ability to attract new members and retain existing members; our ability to compete effectively; maintenance and expansion of device platforms for streaming; fluctuations in consumer usage of our service; service disruptions; production risks; actions of Internet Service Providers; and, competition, including consumer adoption of different modes of viewing in­home filmed entertainment. A detailed discussion of these and other risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results and events to differ materially from such forward­looking statements is included in our filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission, including our Annual Report on Form 10­K filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission on January 28, 2016. The Company provides internal forecast numbers. Investors should anticipate that actual performance will vary from these forecast numbers based on risks and uncertainties discussed above and in our Annual Report on Form 10­K. We undertake no obligation to update forward­looking statements to reflect events or circumstances occurring after the date of this shareholder letter.
 8

Netflix, Inc.
Consolidated Statements of Operations
(unaudited)
(in thousands, except per share data)
Cost of revenues
Marketing
Technology and development Operating income
Other income (expense):
Interest expense Income before income taxes
Net income Basic
Diluted
Weighted-average common shares outstanding:
Basic
Diluted
Three Months Ended
             Revenues   $ 1,957,736
$ 1,823,333
$ 1,573,129
         General and administrative   127,225
109,042
91,489
             Interest and other income (expense) 25,963
(3,734)
(32,293)
       Provision (benefit) for income taxes   12,221
$ $
$
March 31, 2016
1,369,540
208,010
203,508 49,453
(35,537) 39,879
27,658 0.06
0.06 428,117
437,993
$ $
$
December 31, 2015
1,249,365
224,173
180,859 59,894
(35,429) 20,731
43,178 0.10
$ $
March 31, 2015
1,046,401
194,677
143,106 97,456
(26,737) 38,426
23,696 0.06
0.05 423,624
433,809
(22,447)
14,730
              Earnings per share:
  0.10       $ 427,668
438,257
      9

Netflix, Inc.
Consolidated Balance Sheets
(unaudited)
(in thousands, except share and par value data)
Current assets:
Cash and cash equivalents
Short-term investments
Current content assets, net
Other current assets Non-current content assets, net
Property and equipment, net
Other non-current assets
Liabilities and Stockholders' Equity
Current liabilities:
Current content liabilities
Accounts payable
Accrued expenses
Total current liabilities
Non-current content liabilities
Long-term debt
Total liabilities
Stockholders' equity:
Common stock
Accumulated other comprehensive loss
Retained earnings
Total liabilities and stockholders' equity
As of
    March 31, 2016
December 31, 2015
1,809,330
501,385
2,905,998
215,127 4,312,817
173,412
284,802
2,789,023
253,491
140,389 3,529,624
2,026,360
2,371,362
7,979,445
1,324,809
(43,308)
941,925 10,202,871
     Assets
$
1,605,244       $
        Total current assets 5,543,836
5,431,840
    Total assets   $ 11,262,274
    $ 10,202,871
      $
467,227
3,258,641
212,724 5,260,160
166,254
292,024
3,145,861
231,914
181,634 3,933,632
2,586,098
2,372,218
8,945,041
1,382,051
(34,401)
969,583 11,262,274
$
     Deferred revenue   374,223
346,721
       Other non-current liabilities   53,093
52,099
          Total stockholders' equity 2,317,233
   2,223,426
  $
$
     10

Netflix, Inc.
Consolidated Statements of Cash Flows
(unaudited) (in thousands)
Net income
Adjustments to reconcile net income to net cash used in operating activities:
Additions to streaming content assets
Change in streaming content liabilities
Amortization of streaming content assets
Amortization of DVD content assets
Depreciation and amortization of property, equipment and intangibles
Stock-based compensation expense
Excess tax benefits from stock-based compensation
Other non-cash items
Deferred taxes
Changes in operating assets and liabilities:
Other current assets
Accounts payable
Accrued expenses
Deferred revenue
Other non-current assets and liabilities
Cash flows from investing activities:
Acquisition of DVD content assets
Purchases of property and equipment
Change in other assets
Purchases of short-term investments
Proceeds from sale of short-term investments
Proceeds from maturities of short-term investments
Cash flows from financing activities:
Proceeds from issuance of common stock
Proceeds from issuance of debt
Issuance costs
Excess tax benefits from stock-based compensation
Net cash provided by (used in) financing activities
Net (decrease) increase in cash and cash equivalents Cash and cash equivalents, end of period
Non-GAAP free cash flow reconciliation:
Net cash used in operating activities
Acquisition of DVD content assets
Purchases of property and equipment
Change in other assets
NOTE - Certain prior year amounts have been reclassified to conform to the current year presentation.
$
Three Months Ended
March 31, December 31, 2016 2015
27,658 $ 43,178 (2,316,599) (1,550,326)
905,723 240,250
1,058,521 961,861
20,441 18,793
14,798 15,488
42,422 35,860
(11,316) 25,683
12,757 7,774
(16,603) 12,036 14,308 (62,755)
(19,898) 49,031
41,232 (39,619)
27,502 16,982
(29,536) (18,981)
(23,207) (20,799)
(8,425) (12,854)
(356) 2,262
(34,962) (146,582)
8,188 114,832
63,025 22,580
3,536 8,171
— —
—       —
11,316 (25,683)
14,907 (17,458)
(204,086) (306,107)
$
March 31, 2015
23,696 (1,640,217)
626,325
749,518
21,185
15,167
27,441
(29,001)
6,306
(37,042) 51,401
(10,625)
35,922
10,754
21,788
(22,906)
(13,036)
225
(90,940)
51,948
31,887
10,916
1,500,000
(17,232)
29,001
1,522,434
1,341,169
2,454,777
March 31, 2015
(127,382)
          Cash flows from operating activities:
                                         Net cash used in operating activities   (228,590)
    (244,745)
    (127,382)
                  Net cash provided by (used in) investing activities 4,263
    (40,561)
    (42,822)
            Other financing activities   55
54
(251)
           Effect of exchange rate changes on cash and cash equivalents 5,334
(3,343)
(11,061)
    Cash and cash equivalents, beginning of period   1,809,330
$
$
1,605,244
March 31, 2016
$ 1,809,330
Three Months Ended
December 31, 2015
$
$
2,115,437
1,113,608
                 (228,590)       $
(23,207)
(8,425)
(356)
(244,745)
(20,799) (22,906)
(12,854) (13,036)
     2,262
225
 Non-GAAP free cash flow     $ (260,578)
    $ (276,136)
     $ (163,099)
   11

Netflix, Inc.
Segment Information
(unaudited) (in thousands)
Total memberships at end of period
Paid memberships at end of period Revenues
Cost of revenues
Contribution profit
International Streaming
Total memberships at end of period
Paid memberships at end of period Revenues
Cost of revenues
As of / Three Months
Ended
March 31, 2015
41,397
40,315 $ 984,532
582,529 312,452
20,877
19,304 $ 415,397
375,278
105,126
5,564
5,470 $ 173,200
88,594
$ 1,573,129
1,046,401
332,051
97,456
      March 31, 2016
46,967
December 31, 2015
44,738
        Domestic Streaming
  45,714       43,401 $ 1,161,241       $ 1,105,933
  666,546 412,753
647,059 379,041
    Marketing   81,942
    34,533       30,024
31,993 $ 651,748
27,438 $ 566,405
        Marketing 126,068
144,340
4,904
629,899       530,880
    Contribution profit (loss)     (104,219)
   Domestic DVD
Total memberships at end of period
Paid memberships at end of period Revenues
Cost of revenues
Consolidated
Revenues
Cost of revenues
Contribution profit
Operating income
Other income (expense)
Provision (benefit) for income taxes
4,741
  4,647       4,787 $ 144,747       $ 150,995
  73,095
71,426
       $ 1,957,736       $ 1,823,333
1,369,540
380,186
49,453
1,249,365
349,795
59,894
79,833
(108,815)
89,551
        (65,007)
      Contribution profit     71,652
79,569
84,606
      Marketing   208,010
224,173
194,677
       Other operating expenses   330,733
289,901
234,595
   (9,574)       (39,163)     (59,030)
12,221
(22,447)
14,730
Net income       $ 27,658
    $ 43,178
     $ 23,696
   12

Netflix, Inc.
Non-GAAP Information
(unaudited)
(in thousands, except per share data)
GAAP net income
Add:
Interest and other (income) expense
Provision (benefit) for income taxes
Depreciation and amortization of property, equipment and intangibles
March 31, 2015
June 30, 2015
Three Months Ended
September 30, 2015
December 31, 2015
March 31, 2016
27,658 9,574
12,221
14,798 106,673
                           Non-GAAP Adjusted EBITDA reconciliation:
$
$
23,696 $ 26,335 59,030 34,345
14,730       14,155
$
$
29,432 31,403
12,806
16,047
122,522
$
$
43,178 39,163
(22,447)
15,488 111,242
$
$
                        Stock-based compensation expense 27,441
28,590
32,834
35,860
42,422
      Adjusted EBITDA
15,167
140,064
15,581
$ 119,006
      Three Months Ended
December 31, 2015
     Non-GAAP net income reconciliation:
GAAP net income Non-GAAP net income
Basic
Diluted
$ $
43,178
29,740
0.07
0.07
427,668
438,257
   Less: Release of tax accrual
(13,438)
     Non-GAAP earnings per share:
   Weighted-average common shares outstanding:
Basic
Diluted
    13
