 January 19, 2016 Fellow shareholders,
On January 1st, just a few hours after the quarter closed, we crossed 75 million members. Our quarter‐end 74.76 million members put us at over 17 million net additions for the year, showing how much the world is embracing Internet TV. We think we’ll grow by over 6 million members in Q1 given our expansion of Netflix to virtually everywhere but China. We bring great stories from all over the world to people all over the world. Our summary results and Q1 forecast are below.
  1

 Q4 Results and Q1 Forecast
In the fourth quarter, we added a record 5.59 million members as our big shows such as Narcos and Marvel’s Jessica Jones helped us grow membership to 74.76 million. This 5.59 million compares to a forecast of 5.15 million and to prior year net additions of 4.33 million. For Q1, we are forecasting 6.10 million net additions vs. prior year of 4.88 million. On earnings, we stayed profitable in Q4 despite foreign exchange headwinds, and delivered operating income of $60m and net income of $43m. We expect similar modest operating income results for Q1, assuming current foreign exchange, as we invest in our international expansion. As a reminder, the guidance we provide is our actual internal forecast at the time we report, and we strive for accuracy in our guidance.
In September, we launched in Japan, followed by Spain, Portugal and Italy in October. We are very pleased with the first few months of membership growth in these markets. Our international contribution loss of $109 million in Q4 increased sequentially due to these launches. We anticipate Q1 international losses of about $114 million.
In early January at CES, we announced the availability of Netflix everywhere in the world except China. Pricing is comparable to our existing plans and we have added support for Korean, Arabic, and Simplified & Traditional Chinese languages. Our move into 130 additional countries broadens our addressable market by 190 million broadband homes, on top of the 360 million we counted at the end of 20151. While the opportunity is large, our growth in these new markets will unfold over many years as we improve our service. We are starting by primarily targeting outward‐looking, affluent consumers with international credit cards and smartphones. As with every market we’ve launched, our approach is to listen, learn and improve rapidly, adding more content, additional languages and a better Netflix experience over time. Our global availability sets us up for continued growth for many years and we continue to expect material global profits beginning in 2017.
In Q4, average subscriber price grew 4‐5% y/y around the world, excluding the impact of foreign currency (‐$106 million y/y impact on revenue). In the US it was 4.3%, leading to 21% year over year growth in streaming revenue. We are seeing increased adoption of our Ultra‐HD plan ($11.99) as more UHD TVs are purchased and as we are a leading source of UHD content for consumers.
In the US, we ended 2015 with nearly 45 million members, although our Q4 US net adds were down year over year, as expected (1.56m actual versus 1.90m prior year). Our high penetration in the US seems to be making net additions harder than in the past. Our forecast for Q1 US net additions is 1.75m, against a prior year actual of 2.28m. New credit/debit card rollover continues to be a background issue. In Q2 and Q3, we’ll be releasing a substantial number of our US members from price grandfathering on the HD plan and they will have the option of continuing at $7.99 but now on the SD plan, or continuing on HD at $9.99 a month. Given these members have been with us at least 2 years, we expect only slightly elevated churn. Our 2020 US contribution target remains at 40% and we are already at 34%.
1 Source: SNL Kagan and Euromonitor.
  2

 In the last remaining major market, China, we have work and uncertainty ahead. We are building relationships, understanding the market, and seeking the conditions we require to provide our service to entertainment lovers there. Our expectations are modest and long‐term. We may be able to get started this year and thus deliver on “whole world by end of 2016” or it may take longer. Most of our focus is on the 130 countries we launched on January 6, which are now embracing Netflix as a new entertainment option.
Content
In Q4 ‘15, we launched an unprecedented number of original series and films, while maintaining a high bar on quality. We unveiled five new original series in Q4, including Marvel’s Jessica Jones and Master of None, starring Aziz Ansari. Both combined with Narcos, Sense8, Marvel’s Daredevil and Bloodline to claim six of the Top 10 new TV shows of 2015 according to IMDB. In late December, we debuted a ten‐part documentary series Making a Murderer, which has enthralled audiences and critics alike and triggered a national conversation on fairness of the American criminal justice system.
Our first original feature films also premiered in Q4. Beasts of No Nation, a gripping journey into the world of African child soldiers from writer and director Cary Fukunaga and starring Idris Elba, was a favorite of critics and has picked up several major awards nominations. Adam Sandler’s first Netflix original film The Ridiculous Six, which debuted globally on December 11, was the most viewed movie on Netflix in every territory the week of its debut and the most‐viewed movie ever on Netflix in the first 30 days on service. Two of our original documentaries, What Happened, Miss Simone? and Winter on Fire, are both nominated for Academy Awards, our third and fourth nominations in three years for best documentary feature.
In 2016, we plan to launch over 600 hours of original programming, up from about 450 hours in 2015. Beyond the sheer volume of content, the breadth of our original programming will continue to expand with current plans for new seasons of 30 or so original series (including The Crown and The Get Down), eight original feature films, 35 new seasons of original series for kids, a dozen documentaries, and nine stand up comedy specials.
We are now in our fourth year of original programming and we are putting special emphasis on shows that families can enjoy together, including the upcoming Fuller House, new seasons of Unbreakable Kimmy Schmidt, and Stranger Things. We are also stepping up our non‐English language original productions, including Marseille, a French political drama starring Gerard Depardieu, and then, shows from Italy, Japan, Mexico and Brazil. We expect some of these series to gain fans well beyond the markets in which they were made.
Increasingly, our goal is to own more of our original programming to allow for greater creative and business control and to ensure global access to content. We are currently actively managing productions spanning the globe from Cambodia to Venice Beach.
      3

 The growth of Netflix has created some anxiety among TV networks and calls to be fearful. Or, at the other extreme, an NBC executive recently said Internet TV is overblown and that linear TV is “TV like God intended.” Our investors are not as sure of God’s intentions for TV, and instead think that Internet TV is a fundamentally better entertainment experience that will gain share for many years. The challenge for traditional media companies, most of whom see the future pretty clearly, is to use the revenue from Netflix and other SVOD services to fund both great content and their own evolution into Internet TV networks. Seeso, BBC iPlayer, Hulu, CanalPlay, HBO Now, and CBS All Access are the beginnings of these efforts.
Our titles are watched on the go and at home on a wide range of devices, making measurement of the viewing of any given title difficult for third parties. We don’t release title‐level ratings as our business model is not dependent on advertising or affiliate fees. Instead, we release “ratings “ for Netflix as a whole every quarter with our membership growth report (75 million and counting!). It is member viewing and satisfaction that propels our growth.
Product
We have been innovating in support of our global launch, focusing on adding new languages, new payment options and fine‐tuning our algorithms for our growing number of content catalogs. Additionally, this involves expanding and deepening our partnerships with device makers and mobile and TV operators to reach and serve our members around the world.
We recognize that in some parts of the world, mobile is the primary way many people access the Internet. We are improving our mobile experience, including sign up, credentials & authentication, the user interface, and streaming efficiency for cellular networks.
In Q4, we began rolling out complexity based encoding. By encoding videos based on the type of content (a visually complex action movie vs. a simpler kids animated title, for example) rather than just based on the amount of bandwidth available to a member, we can deliver higher resolution streams at lower bit rates, resulting in bandwidth savings.
We have long used a blacklist to prevent cross‐border content viewing via proxies and “unblockers.” Recently, we have begun to use a new blacklist and other techniques, as are other SVOD services, as desired by content licensors. Ultimately, our goal is to let members around the world enjoy all the content we have through global licensing.
Marketing
Promoting high quality, exclusive titles continues to be the best driver of consumer demand for Netflix. Our recent new market launches reflect this philosophy, and our all‐digital, content‐led marketing approach is working. Our brand strength is rising in many studies, including a #2 ranking reported in AdWeek for the USA. Around the world, our all digital approach makes us efficient and relevant to active Internet users everywhere.
      4

 Competition
Our focus on “winning moments of truth” means that we compete with all of the activities that consumers can engage in during their leisure time, such as reading a book, playing videogames, watching linear TV, movie theatre‐going, etc. Given the broad array of options, we are privileged that our members around the world continue to devote more time to Netflix, streaming 42.5 billion hours in 2015, up from 29 billion hours in 2014.
In addition, looking at just the online segment, the most recent Sandvine data illustrates that our share of peak North American downstream Internet traffic continues to grow. Please note that the deployment of complexity based encoding, as described above, will result in what appears to be slower growth in Netflix traffic in future third‐party reports such as Sandvine (which measures peak megabits, not peak viewing hours).
 As we have said previously, Internet TV will likely have multiple winners as the various services are not direct substitutes for each other given differing sets of content. A closer look at the Sandvine data shows that the entire Over‐the‐Top category is growing as consumers increasingly embrace Internet TV and on demand viewing and, even better, this growth is coming at the expense of piracy.
 5

  Free Cash Flow and Capital Structure
Free cash flow amounted to ‐$276 million in Q4 and ‐$921 million for the full year 2015. As a reminder, our investment in originals, particularly owned content, requires more cash upfront relative to licensed content, which will continue to dampen free cash flow. We finished Q4 with debt of $2.4 billion, unchanged from the prior quarter, and with cash & equivalents and short‐term investments of $2.3 billion.
Given our expected cash needs, we are likely to raise additional debt in late 2016 or early 2017. We are managing our balance sheet to lower our blended cost of capital over time, while maintaining financial flexibility. Despite being FCF negative as we grow our original content and invest in international, our bonds trade like a BB credit (vs. their single B rating) due, in part, to the long‐term growth of Internet TV globally and our low debt to market cap ratio, which provides bond investors with a very thick cushion of protection.
DVD
Our DVD‐by‐mail business in the US continues to serve more than 4.9 million members. We are pleased that our DVD business is managing the decline well, despite increasing postal costs, generating $80 million in contribution profit in Q4.
Reference
For quick reference, our eight most recent investor letters are: October 2015, July 2015, April 2015, January 2015, October 2014, July 2014, April 2014, January 2014.
         6

 Summary
We are thrilled to be available worldwide ex‐China. What fun we are having making our service popular in Thailand, Poland, Australia, Chile, France and over 180 other countries.
Sincerely,
Reed Hastings, CEO David Wells, CFO
January 19th, 2016 Earnings Interview
Reed Hastings, David Wells and Ted Sarandos will participate in a live video interview today at 2:00 p.m. Pacific Time at youtube.com/netflixir. The discussion will be moderated by Ben Swinburne, Morgan Stanley and and Peter Kafka, Re/code. Questions that investors would like to see asked should be sent to benjamin.swinburne@morganstanley.com or peter@recode.net.
Use of Non‐GAAP Measures
This shareholder letter and its attachments include reference to the non‐GAAP financial measure of net income on a pro forma basis excluding the release of tax reserves, and to free cash flow and EBITDA. Management believes that the non‐GAAP measure of net income on a pro forma basis excluding the release of tax reserves provides useful information as this measure excludes effects that are not indicative of our core operating results. Management believes that free cash flow and EBITDA are
         IR Contact:
Spencer Wang
Vice President, Finance & Investor Relations 408 809‐5360
   PR Contact:
Jonathan Friedland
Chief Communications Officer 310 734‐2958
  7

 important liquidity metrics because they measure, during a given period, the amount of cash generated that is available to repay debt obligations, make investments and for certain other activities. However, these non‐GAAP measures should be considered in addition to, not as a substitute for or superior to, net income, operating income, diluted earnings per share and net cash provided by operating activities, or other financial measures prepared in accordance with GAAP. Reconciliation to the GAAP equivalent of these non‐GAAP measures are contained in tabular form on the attached unaudited financial statements.
Forward‐Looking Statements
This shareholder letter contains certain forward‐looking statements within the meaning of the federal securities laws, including statements regarding growth of international markets; expansion to China; churn related to price changes; volume and titles of future content offerings; original content strategy; growth of internet TV; raising capital; member growth domestically and internationally, including net, total and paid; revenue; contribution profit (loss) and contribution margin for both domestic (streaming and DVD) and international operations, as well as consolidated operating income, net income, earnings per share and free cash flow. The forward‐looking statements in this letter are subject to risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results and events to differ, including, without limitation: our ability to attract new members and retain existing members; our ability to compete effectively; maintenance and expansion of device platforms for streaming; fluctuations in consumer usage of our service; service disruptions; production risks; actions of Internet Service Providers; and, competition, including consumer adoption of different modes of viewing in‐home filmed entertainment. A detailed discussion of these and other risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results and events to differ materially from such forward‐looking statements is included in our filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission, including our Annual Report on Form 10‐K filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission on January 29, 2015. The Company provides internal forecast numbers. Investors should anticipate that actual performance will vary from these forecast numbers based on risks and uncertainties discussed above and in our Annual Report on Form 10‐K. We undertake no obligation to update forward‐looking statements to reflect events or circumstances occurring after the date of this shareholder letter.
 8

Netflix, Inc.
Consolidated Statements of Operations
(unaudited)
(in thousands, except per share data)
Cost of revenues
Marketing
Technology and development Operating income
Other income (expense):
Interest expense Income before income taxes
Net income Basic
Diluted
Weighted-average common shares outstanding:
Basic
Diluted
Three Months Ended
September 30, 2015
1,173,958
Year Ended
         December 31, 2015
December 31, 2014
1,014,332
December 31, 2015
4,591,476
824,092
650,788
305,826 (132,716) 141,885
122,641 0.29
December 31, 2014
3,752,760
607,186
472,321 402,648
(50,219) 349,369
266,799 0.63
0.62 420,544
431,894
             Revenues   $ 1,823,333
1,249,365
$ 1,738,355
$ 1,484,728
$ 6,779,511
$ 5,504,656
             General and administrative   109,042
110,892
75,803
407,329
269,741
                 Interest and other income (expense) (3,734)
3,930
(6,177)
(31,225)
(3,060)
             (Benefit) provision for income taxes   (22,447)
$ $
$
180,859 59,894
(35,429) 20,731
43,178 0.10
$ $
171,762 73,641
(35,333) 42,238
29,432 0.07
$ $
125,876 65,046
(13,353) 45,516
83,371 0.20
$ $
$ $
224,173 208,102 203,671
          12,806
(37,855)
19,244
82,570
                        Earnings per share:
0.10       $ 427,668
438,257
0.07     $ 426,869
437,606
0.19     $ 422,244
432,514
0.28     $ 425,889
436,456
          9

Netflix, Inc.
Consolidated Balance Sheets
(unaudited)
(in thousands, except share and par value data)
Current assets:
Cash and cash equivalents
Short-term investments
Current content assets, net
Other current assets Non-current content assets, net
Property and equipment, net
Other non-current assets
Liabilities and Stockholders' Equity
Current liabilities:
Current content liabilities
Accounts payable
Accrued expenses
Total current liabilities
Non-current content liabilities
Long-term debt
Total liabilities
Stockholders' equity:
Common stock
Accumulated other comprehensive loss
Retained earnings
As of
    December 31, 2015
December 31, 2014
1,113,608
494,888
2,166,134
152,423 2,773,326
149,875
192,246
2,117,241
201,581
69,746 2,663,154
1,575,832
885,849
5,184,792
1,042,870
(4,446)
819,284 7,042,500
     Assets
$
1,809,330       $
        Total current assets 5,431,840
    Total assets   $ 10,202,871
    $ 7,042,500
     Deferred revenue   346,721
$
501,385
2,905,998
215,127 4,312,817
173,412
284,802
2,789,023
253,491
140,389 3,529,624
2,026,360
2,371,362
7,979,445
1,324,809
(43,308)
941,925 10,202,871
$
3,927,053
      274,586
       Other non-current liabilities   52,099
59,957
          Total stockholders' equity 2,223,426
   1,857,708
  Total liabilities and stockholders' equity
NOTE - Certain prior year amounts have been reclassified to conform to the current year presentation.
$
$
     10

Netflix, Inc.
Consolidated Statements of Cash Flows
(unaudited) (in thousands)
Net income
Additions to streaming content assets
Change in streaming content liabilities
Amortization of streaming content assets
Amortization of DVD content assets
Depreciation and amortization of property, equipment and intangibles
Stock-based compensation expense
Excess tax benefits from stock-based compensation
Other non-cash items
Deferred taxes
Changes in operating assets and liabilities:
Other current assets
Accounts payable
Accrued expenses
Deferred revenue
Other non-current assets and liabilities
Cash flows from investing activities:
Acquisition of DVD content assets
Purchases of property and equipment
Other assets
Purchases of short-term investments
Proceeds from sale of short-term investments
Proceeds from maturities of short-term investments
Cash flows from financing activities:
Proceeds from issuance of common stock
Proceeds from issuance of debt
Issuance costs
Excess tax benefits from stock-based compensation
Net cash (used in) provided by financing activities
Net (decrease) increase in cash and cash equivalents Cash and cash equivalents, end of period
Non-GAAP free cash flow reconciliation:
Net cash (used in) provided by operating activities
Acquisition of DVD content assets
Purchases of property and equipment
Other assets
December 31, 2015
Three Months Ended
September 30, 2015
Year Ended
December 31, December 31, 2015 2014
$ 83,371
(1,013,822) (5,771,652) (3,773,019)
125,770 1,162,413       593,125
        December 31, 2014
              Cash flows from operating activities:
$
43,178 (1,550,326)
240,250
961,861
18,793
15,488
35,860
25,683
7,774
12,036 (62,755)
49,031
(39,619)
16,982
(18,981)
(20,799)
(12,854)
2,262
(146,582)
114,832
22,580
8,171
—
—
(25,683)
(17,458)
(306,107)
$
29,432 (1,304,466)
104,684
871,403
18,589
16,047
32,834
(37,726)
10,866
(29,417) 66,695
6,762
10,883
27,985
(20,540)
(14,467)
(37,820)
(3,760)
(66,444)
43,887
31,125
35,089
—
—
37,726
72,754
(178,435)
$ 122,641 $ 266,799
         Adjustments to reconcile net income to net cash (used in) provided by operating activities:
      730,353 3,405,382
2,656,279
      20,178 79,380       71,491
14,312 62,283
54,028
      30,251 124,725       115,239
(20,921) (80,471)
(89,341)
      6,475 31,628       15,282
7,501 (58,655)       (30,063)
      (30,539) 18,693
(9,198)
      51,083 51,615       83,812
4,050 48,810
55,636
      21,630 72,135       58,819
(68,153) (18,366)
(52,406)
  Net cash (used in) provided by operating activities (244,745)
    (195,969)
    (38,461)
    (749,439)
    16,483
       (23,365) (77,958)       (74,790)
(15,491) (91,248)
(69,726)
      (431) (1,912)       1,334
(71,597) (371,915)
(426,934)
      45,022 259,079       385,300
14,721 104,762
141,950
  Net cash used in investing activities (40,561)
    (47,479)
    (51,141)
    (179,192)
    (42,866)
       3,750 77,980       60,544
— 1,500,000
400,000
               Principal payments of lease financing obligations 54
(61)
(280)
(545)
(1,093)
                  Effect of exchange rate changes on cash and cash equivalents (3,343)
$ 1,809,330 $ 2,115,437
Three Months Ended
December 31, September 30, 2015 2015
$ (244,745) $ (195,969)
20,921 80,471
24,391 1,640,277
(69,609) 695,722
$ 1,113,608 $ 1,809,330
89,341
541,712
508,643
$ 1,113,608
Ended
December 31, 2014
(7,741)
(4,398)
— (17,629)       (7,080)
 (15,924)
(6,686)
         Cash and cash equivalents, beginning of period 2,115,437
2,293,872
1,183,217
1,113,608
604,965
                       December 31, 2014
Year
December 31, 2015
           (20,799)
(12,854)
2,262
(14,467)
(37,820)
(3,760)
(23,365) (77,958)
(15,491) (91,248)
(431) (1,912)
(74,790)
(69,726)
1,334
$ (38,461)       $ (749,439) $ 16,483
           Non-GAAP free cash flow $ (276,136)
     $ (252,016)
     $ (77,748)
     $ (920,557)
     $ (126,699)
  NOTE - Certain prior year amounts have been reclassified to conform to the current year presentation.
 11

Netflix, Inc.
Segment Information
(unaudited) (in thousands)
Total memberships at end of period
Paid memberships at end of period Revenues
Cost of revenues
Contribution profit
International Streaming
Total memberships at end of period
Paid memberships at end of period Revenues
Cost of revenues
Marketing
Domestic DVD
Total memberships at end of period
Paid memberships at end of period Revenues
Cost of revenues
Consolidated
Revenues
Cost of revenues
Contribution profit
Operating income
Other income (expense)
(Benefit) provision for income taxes
As of / Three Months
December 31, September 30, 2015 2015
44,738 43,181
43,401 42,068 $ 1,105,933 $ 1,063,961
Ended
December 31, 2014
39,114
As of/ Year Ended
         December 31, 2015
44,738
December 31, 2014
39,114
              Domestic Streaming
        647,059 644,914 379,041 344,212
30,024 25,987
27,438 23,951 566,405 $ 516,870
530,880 451,251
144,340 133,267
4,904 5,060
573,193 256,826
2,487,193 1,375,500
2,201,761 936,220
$
$
37,698       43,401     37,698 917,442       $ 4,180,339     $ 3,431,434
        Marketing   79,833
74,835
87,423
317,646
        18,277       30,024     18,277
          $
16,778 387,797
27,438 $ 1,953,435
16,778 $ 1,308,061
    350,211       1,780,375     1,154,117
116,248
5,767
506,446
4,904
313,733
5,767
          Contribution profit (loss) (108,815)
(333,386)
         4,787 4,971 $ 150,995 $ 157,524
71,426 77,793
$ 1,823,333 $ 1,738,355
1,249,365 1,173,958
349,795 356,295
59,894 73,641
5,668       4,787     5,668 $ 179,489       $ 645,737     $ 765,161
    90,928
323,908
396,882
             $ 1,484,728       $ 6,779,511     $ 5,504,656
1,014,332
266,725
65,046
4,591,476
1,363,943
305,826
3,752,760
1,144,710
402,648
293,453
              (67,648)
(78,662)
(159,789)
            Contribution profit     79,569
79,731
88,561
321,829
368,279
            Marketing   224,173
208,102
203,671
824,092
607,186
              Other operating expenses 289,901
282,654
201,679
1,058,117
742,062
     (39,163)       (31,403)     (19,530)     (163,941)     (53,279)
(22,447) 12,806
(37,855)
19,244
82,570
Net income       $ 43,178
    $ 29,432
     $ 83,371
     $ 122,641
     $ 266,799
   12

Netflix, Inc.
Non-GAAP Information
(unaudited)
(in thousands, except per share data)
Three Months Ended
         December 31, March 31, 2014 2015
June 30, 2015
September 30, 2015
December 31, 2015
                  Non-GAAP Adjusted EBITDA reconciliation:
GAAP net income $
Add:
Interest and other (income) expense
Provision (benefit) for income taxes
Depreciation and amortization of property, equipment and intangibles
Stock-based compensation expense
Adjusted EBITDA $
GAAP net income Non-GAAP net income
Basic
Diluted
Weighted-average common shares outstanding:
Basic
Diluted
83,371 $ 23,696 19,530 59,030
(37,855)       14,730
14,312 15,167
30,251
109,609 $ 140,064
$
$
26,335 $ 34,345
14,155
15,581
119,006 $
29,432 31,403
12,806
16,047
122,522
43,178
29,740
0.07
0.07 427,668
438,257
$
$
43,178 39,163
(22,447)
15,488 111,242
                        27,441
28,590
32,834
35,860
          Three Months Ended
   December 31, 2014
December 31, 2015
        Non-GAAP net income reconciliation:
$ $
83,371
44,759
0.11
0.10 422,244
432,514
$ $
     Less: Release of tax accrual
(38,612)
(13,438)
           Non-GAAP earnings per share:
           13
