 10°
20°
30°
40°
50°
           DEAR FELLOW SHAREHOLDERS,
Whenwechosetheracing-boatimageryand“thewindisat our back” theme last fall, the threat of economic recession was still remote and we had no idea that corporate chieftains across the country would borrow nautical terms like “headwinds” to describe the challenges now confronting business.
But, while the waters ahead may be a little turbulent, NRG
does indeed have wind in our sails. There are powerful shifting dynamics underway in our industry and most of them naturally favor NRG’s business—including declining reserve margins
in the domestic wholesale electricity business, substantially increased costs of new generation and global demand-driven pressure on natural gas prices. Other dynamics are less naturally favorable like the prospect of a federal carbon-regulatory regime intended to address the causes of global warming. But we have been hard at work for two years turning even these to our advantage.
In this regard, our corporate strategy is not unlike a skilled sailing captain’s. We seek to capture the strength of the societal and industry trends that favor us while tacking aggressively to turn challenging dynamics into corporate opportunities that move us forward.
I n O u r W a k e : a G r e a t Y e a r
What really motivates us at NRG is talking about where we are headed. We are looking forward relentlessly, plotting our course over the horizon. But as this is our annual report for 2007, let’s stop for a moment to look back at this past year.
SafetY fIrSt
Nothing we do at NRG would matter if we weren’t absolutely committed to ensuring that our employees go home safely each and every night. In 2007, we did very well in this regard. Our record-low injury rate placed us in the top quartile for our industry based on OSHA (Occupational Safety and Health Administration) standards. I am proud of how many of our plants have earned or are seeking Star status with OSHA’s Voluntary Protection Programs (VPP), its most stringent certification.
MOvInG StrOnG and faSt
Just as safety is our commitment to employees, financial performance is our primary responsibility to you, our shareholders. At NRG, near-term financial results principally are a function of two groups: Plant Operations and Commercial Operations. In 2007, both performed admirably.
✯ CLEAR DIRECTION ✯
     10°
   0°
    10°
20°
30°
40°
    1
                        
    50°
40°
30°
20°
10°
10°
               FIRSTS IN SAFETY
· lowest OSHa recordable Injury rate: 1.63 · lowest dart1 rate: 0.82
· lowest lost time Injury rate: 0.41
Compared to the industry average, NRG plants had only a small fraction of incidents. We applaud the 14 NRG plants that had no injuries at all in 2007—an exemplary feat. But, as always, true success means zero injuries fleetwide. This is our goal.
NRG Texas became 100% VPP Star in 2007, earning OSHA’s highest recognition at every plant in the region. Five other NRG plants are actively seeking VPP status.
1 days away, restricted or transferred
PerfOrMance revIeW: Plant OPeratIOnS
Even in an average year, there is nothing routine about
our plants’ performance. Our nearly 23,000 MW of U.S. generation spans almost every type of technology and configuration deployed in the domestic utility sector. The demands we make on our plants in terms of reliability required, constant cycling up or down of our units, fast-start requirements, environmental compliance and utilization of non-design specification fuels, have never been greater.
On August 1, in time for summer's peak energy needs, Long Beach Generating Station became the first repowering project to go live—capable of providing power for up to 200,000 Southern California homes. Pictured here is NRG West Environmental Specialist, Alex Sanchez, giving a tour of the new
plant to coworkers and invited guests.
When added up, it means you need a first rate “crew” to make a company like NRG hum. Fortunately, that is what we have.
Last year, our plants set new unit records both for generation and continuous days online. With over 74,000,000 total MWhrs, NRG’s U.S. net generation was up nearly 4% from 2006—the direct result of strong performance at our baseload facilities.
Of the many notable achievements we saw across all parts of our fleet in 2007, several were particularly gratifying to me, including the record performance of South Texas Project (STP) unit 1; the exceptional reliability of Arthur Kill in New York; the response of our Long Beach and San Diego plants to California’s emergency needs and a significant improvement in performance at our Indian River plant in the second half of the year.
PerfOrMance revIeW: cOMMercIal OPeratIOnS
Our commercial operations strategy always has been to
1) opportunistically sell forward, or “hedge,” our baseload generation for three-to-five years, 2) capture the extrinsic value of our generating assets in the electricity markets and 3) procure and trade the commodities closely associated with wholesale electricity (coal, natural gas, fuel oil and emission credits). In 2007, the Commercial Operations group performed superbly on all fronts.
This team’s commendable success directly increased NRG’s 2007 margin in several ways. For example, by substantially hedging our baseload units in Texas, the group helped buoy up the value of our ERCOT portfolio. Despite a mild and unusually wet summer, they protected the value of our gas assets in a period of low price volatility and weak clearing heat rates by selling these positions forward prior to the summer. Conversely, in the Northeast, a “bullish” view on our gas-fueled peaking units prior to the summer kept this market position relatively
          In November, NRG took top honors at the Platts Global Energy Awards—the most celebrated of energy industry awards—capturing both the Industry Leadership Award and the night’s highest award: Energy Company of the Year. Platts, a major provider of energy information, praised NRG for its “management excellence, coupled with incisive strategy and an unparalleled sense of corporate responsibility.” David Crane and Bob Flexon received the honors on behalf of the Company.
       0°
10°
20°
30°
  40°
   SHAREHOLDER’S LETTER
 2
                          
    10°
20°
30°
40°
50°
             The Cedar Bayou Generating Station expansion is the first RepoweringNRG initiative in Texas to break ground. This efficient and flexible natural-gas-fueled, combined cycle generating unit will add 550 MW of clean power to the Texas grid, enough to power 440,000 homes, in time for peak demand during the summer of 2009.
  open, helping us to capture higher spot electricity prices during the hottest months.
fInancIal reSultS
A strong operating performance leads to a good financial result—and that is exactly what we achieved in 2007. Cash flow from operations (CFFO) reached $1.5 billion and adjusted EBITDA topped out at $2.24 billion (excluding discontinued operations). These numbers are impressive on their own, but they’re truly remarkable when you think that just two years ago, during another a great year, we ended at less than half those results ($68 million CFFO and $554 million adjusted EBITDA in 2005).
Our robust cash-flow generation enabled us not only to reinvest close to $500 million into capital expenditures for maintenance, environmental initiatives and growth, but also to pay down $408 million of debt and return substantial funds to our shareholders. During the year, we spent $353 million buying back the Company’s shares (at an average price of $39.09/share). This increases
our running total to $1.7 billion of share buybacks and $3.2 billion of debt reduced over our first four years and continues our enviable streak of both returning capital to our shareholders and paying down debt in every year of the new NRG.
Certainly, it is our hope and expectation to continue this impressive capital allocation streak in 2008.
SHIftInG WIndS
Our notable financial performance provided us with relatively smooth sailing through the very choppy waters of an
unfavorable economic environment. After years of thriving credit markets—which we used to our advantage by financing and refinancing at attractive interest rates—things turned downright ugly about halfway through the year and then, after a brief recovery in the fall, grew even uglier by year end.
These conditions frustrated our plans to keep moving toward maximum efficiency in our capital allocations (through greater buybacks and/or dividends), but those objectives were in the “nice to have” not “need to have” category. Our continually prudent balance sheet management and the relentless efforts of our financing team have put us in a position to ride out the current storms safely. At year end, our total liquidity stood at $2.7 billion, an amount which, in the current credit-constrained environment, represents a welcome safety blanket for our shareholders.
rIGHt On cOurSe
Those of you who are “veteran” NRG shareholders may remember that last year’s letter described our five major corporate initiatives: FORNRG, RepoweringNRG, econrg, Future NRG and NRG Global Giving. All of these long-term initiatives made measurable and meaningful progress during 2007. I hope you’ll take the time to read about some of the successes and milestones highlighted throughout this report.
InItIatInG tHe nuclear renaISSance
Undoubtedly, the most noteworthy of these accomplishments in 2007 was our application for a new nuclear plant—the first filed with the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) since 1979. The NRC accepted our application for docketing in December, formally beginning their extensive review of our Combined Operating License request.
   10°
0°
10°
  20°
30°
40°
    3
                           
0°
50°
40°
30°
20°
           It is still in the early days for our proposed new nuclear plant, which will be built as South Texas Project (STP) units 3 and 4. As I have said often, neither developing nor constructing the first new nuclear plant to be built in the United States in a generation is for the “faint of heart.” But our nuclear development initiative iswellthoughtoutfromariskperspectiveandproceedsonthe principle that we intend to avoid scrupulously “the unknown, unproven and unconstructed.”
Under the most favorable of circumstances, our first new nuclear unit will be online in 2014. Yet, you should not underestimate the significance of what our South Texas team—including our partners CPS Energy and STPNOC (South Texas Project Nuclear Operating Company)—has achieved in getting us to the leading position in which we find ourselves today on this project. Whether you are concerned about
American energy security, global warming or having affordable and reliable electricity, new nuclear delivers on all fronts and delivers big. Its time has come and STP units 3 and 4 will be on the vanguard.
P r e P a r e d t O t H r I v e I n uncHarted WaterS
The U.S. power industry underwent a “sea change” in 2007. With the confluence of political and scientific factors—neatly symbolized by the co-awarding of the Nobel Peace Prize
to Al Gore and the Inter-Governmental Panel on Climate Change—and vivid physical observations, such as unexpected massive melting of the polar ice caps, it has become clear that our Company, our industry and our country must learn how to survive and then thrive in a carbon-constrained world.
   10°
   10°
    30°
40°
$250 $200 $150
$100 $50 $0
$39
•
$1
44
•
$220
•
$250
•
FORNRG: Full SpEEd AhEAd ★★★
Since launching in 2005, the focus On return on Invested Capital at nrG (FORNRG) program has been a steady source of profit- building projects and money-saving ideas for NRG. In 2007, thanks to FORNRG initiatives implemented across the Company, we again surpassed our targets.
The original goal of FORNRG was to achieve a bottom line effect of $250 million by 2009. We now expect to reach that milestone in 2008, one year early, and we are not letting up in our quest for more money-saving corporate and plant initiatives. Here are some examples from the plant floor in 2007:
San Jacinto: low-load Operation
Until recently, gas units at San Jacinto continually operated at baseload levels, even during off-peak periods. In 2007, the plant made enhancements to back down from 70 MW to 50 MW during periods of low demand. This low-load cycling adjustment saved NRG an estimated $3 million in 2007 and ensures that Commercial Operations avoids selling energy for less than our cost of fuel.
Wa Parish: Online Water Blasting
Over time, boiler tubes develop hard-mineral deposits, called slags, which can cause overheating. Left too long, “slagging” can lead to imminent boiler tube failure, header damage, unplanned outages and extensive repairs. Previously, slag removal required a two-to-five day unit outage while the boiler was cooled and dynamite was used to remove hardened slag. In 2007, WA Parish instead engaged an outside firm to hydro-blast the slag while the unit was still online. This new process saved over $4 million and prevented a loss in generation.
10°
  20°
        SHAREHOLDER’S LETTER
 4
                                 FORNRG taRGets:
Annual Run Rate Benefits (in millions)
★★★
            2005 2006 2007 2008
AMOUNT OF INCREASE PREVIOUS TARGET
      
     10°
20°
30°
40°
50°
               10°
     NRG made history on September 24, 2007, when it became the first Company in nearly 30 years to file for a license with the NRC to build a new nuclear plant. Senator Pete Domenici (R-NM) proudly holds up the license application while STPNOC President and CEO, Joe Sheppard, and David Crane look on.
0°
 These are uncharted waters. The various players in our industry are responding very differently and, in many cases, their response is no response at all—just wait-and-see. That is emphatically not the tack NRG is taking and you deserve to know why and what we are doing. Accordingly, I want to spend the remainder of this letter explaining how NRG is positioning itself to navigate the shoals of the climate-change landscape that lay ahead.
To carry this sailing metaphor a little further, when you enter uncharted waters on the high seas, it behooves you to have the biggest and most rugged vessel possible. That is what we have strived to build at NRG, through our geographic diversity, our scaling up of the asset base and our prudent balance-sheet management. But you need a boat that is swift and nimble, and a crew that is highly skilled, motivated and responsive to fast- changing conditions. At NRG, those are the attributes that we strive to strengthen and sustain every day.
Today, we are sailing as hard and as fast as we can, not merely reacting to today’s carbon constraints, but pushing onward
to where we believe the carbon constraints will be over the medium- to long-term. This means we are working now, through projects being developed under the aegis of our RepoweringNRG and econrg programs, to reduce our fleet’s carbon intensity significantly.
leadInG tHe WaY tO decarBOnIzatIOn
As we enter these uncharted waters, it seems sensible to us that both the safest and the most potentially profitable course for NRG is to transform ourselves from being a significant part of the problem into being a critical part of the solution.
Our next-generation nuclear development is central to this effort. Given that we can achieve enormous capacity
(2,700 MW at STP units 3 and 4) and zero-carbon emissions with nuclear generation, this project is essential to our decarbonization strategy.
But there is another technological solution that rises above nuclear and all other options: “clean” coal. Rather than emitting carbon dioxide (CO2) into the earth’s atmosphere, clean coal technology captures and stores it in suitable underground formations. Taken together, clean coal and advanced nuclear are a formidable duo in the fight against global warming.
How important is clean coal? Think of it this way: we cannot solve global warming with clean coal alone; but without clean coal, we cannot solve global warming.
While less well-publicized than our nuclear development project, we continue to progress plans for clean coal facilities, including the Huntley Integrated Gasification Combined
Cycle (IGCC) plant. The plant is in the engineering phase
in partnership with the New York Power Authority, with particular focus on the carbon capture and sequestration (CCS) “downstream” component of the project. Once it moves forward, this facility stands to be the biggest coal-gasification plant in the world and, as such, it should be momentous for NRG, the State of New York and the people of Erie County.
As we pursue IGCC projects like Huntley, which will capture carbon in the pre-combustion phase, we are simultaneously working on post-combustion carbon capture options, which involve adding cutting-edge technology to existing coal plants.
Our goal is to secure “first mover” status for NRG as a developer and operator of one or all three of the critical technologies—advanced nuclear, pre-combustion clean coal
10°
20°
30°
40°
       5
               u.S. Senate PHOtO
            
    50°
40°
30°
20°
10°
           (IGCC), and post-combustion clean coal—which will need to be deployed at scale if our country seeks to combat global warming. Each of these technologies represents a market opportunity which ultimately will measure in the tens of billions of dollars, making the tens of millions that we are investing now entirely sensible.
Rounding out our diverse new technology portfolio is wind energy—a zero-fuel, zero-emission, renewable resource. Through our subsidiary, Padoma Wind Power, we plan
to construct about 500 MW of new wind generation over the next 12-24 months to meet the increasing demand for additional power in California and Texas.
full SaIl aHead
When we recruited our management team, we sought people who had the experience and the competence, but who also had the audacity, to transform the way our Company was doing business. One of the recruiting arguments I used at the
time was to point out to prospective new hires that few people working in the private sector get the opportunity to transform a company and even fewer can transform an entire industry. Yet, given the rebirth of NRG amongst the continuing disarray in the competitive power generation industry, this is exactly what I believed we would do. And it is what we have done: transformed the Company; and, through the strength of our example, transformed an industry. Not bad.
Now I am telling our team that I see even more in store for NRG. As the global warming era heats up, all of us at NRG recognize that we have a unique opportunity to create shareholder value by pioneering new ways of generating power which allow us
to serve our customers reliably and affordably, but also which enable us to pass on this beautiful earth in the same condition in which we inherited it to the generations to come.
That’s what motivates us at NRG.
 NAmE
T I T L E President and Chief Executive Officer
DATE 3-1-2008
         10°
   0°
10°
20°
   40°
NRG CARBON
★ PRiNCiPles ★
keY eleMentS Of ★ SucceSSful ★ clIMate cHanGe POlIcY
★ It is a moral imperative that we take steps to reduce CO2 emissions and limit its concentration in the earth’s atmosphere
★ The U.S. generation sector needs to take a leading role on carbon
★ Carbon emissions need to have a global price
★ As technology improves, carbon rules should toughen
★ We must be pragmatic about early reductions of carbon emissions to avoid drastically increasing the price of natural gas
★ Significant expansion of loan guarantees and other incentives provided in the Energy Policy Act of 2005 for nuclear and other low- carbon technologies
★ We need to ensure necessary government support for all viable zero-emission technologies, particularly baseload nuclear and clean coal with carbon capture and sequestration
★ We need a national public-private partnership to accelerate the deployment of carbon capture and sequestration for coal
  30°
     SHAREHOLDER’S LETTER
 6
                             