 1
 o Our Shareholders:
Every great enterprise is rooted in one fundamental and transcending
idea. Henry Raymond and George Jones, who published the
first issue of The New York Times on September 18, 1851, embraced
the basic premise that long-term business success could be achieved by
consistently providing quality journalism to a demanding audience. History has repeatedly taught us that these two visionaries were absolutely correct.
Investment, Innovation and Reinvention Our founders, and each successive generation of Times Company leadership, have also understood the critical importance of staying ahead
of change, and over the past 12 months, we carried on this valuable legacy by engaging in a productive process of investment, innovation and reinvention.
We did all this in a very challenging environment. Beginning with 2001, the media industry in general and The New York Times Company in particular have been coping with the collapse of the technology bubble, the September 11 terrorist attacks and continued unsettled economic conditions. We also contended with an uneven advertising market, which has continued in 2005.
 Consequently, we have had to adapt to a new set of operating premises in our businesses as we have closely re-examined every part of our operations, identified new revenue sources, controlled expenses, expanded our reach and developed new tactics to enhance shareholder value.
Positioned for Growth While our earnings
per share declined slightly in 2004, to $1.96 from $1.98, we believe that the journalistic and business initiatives we have been carrying out throughout 2004 and early 2005 have positioned us for long-term growth.
As in previous years, we have been guided by a disciplined commitment to our long-term strategy, which is to operate the leading news and advertising media in the national and global “quality audience” market served by The New York Times, and in each of our local markets.
Relaunching Our Flagship An appropriate place to begin a review of 2004 is by focusing on the advertising and circulation achievements of The New York Times newspaper:
• Our flagship property reported more than $1 billion in ad revenue for the seventh straight year. No other newspaper or magazine has matched this record.
  NYT Annual Report 2004
   
 2
We believe that the journalistic and
business initiatives we have been carrying out position us for long-term growth.
 • The Times’s September 2004 Statement to the Audit Bureau of Circulations marked the third consecutive period of daily and Sunday circulation growth, the 11th positive daily result in the last 12 ABC periods, and the 10th such result for Sunday over the same time frame.
Over the past year, The Times relaunched its Sunday Business, Real Estate, Book Review, Culture, Travel and special Sunday Magazine sections, rebranded as “T.” This year we will be redesigning the Main News section, Business Day and Sports. Other sections are currently under evaluation, and more announcements will be coming in the months ahead as part of our continuing effort to keep our newspaper current and vibrant.
We also expect to add a total of eight new or expanded print sites to serve our growing customer base outside the New York metropolitan area by increasing availability of The Times: the first was launched last October, four are expected this year and the rest
by late 2006. As a result of its national expansion initiative, The Times is now available in 315 markets and 59,600 retail outlets in the U.S. During 2004 The Times opened 1,363 new ZIP codes for home delivery across the country where this service was previously not available.
A Focused Multimedia Strategy We have stayed ahead of news consumption habits by bolstering our multimedia strategy, which is designed to reach
millions of people who would like access to our quality journalism, whether it is in print, online or broadcast.
In 2004 NYTimes.com, the world’s most popular newspaper-owned Web site, relaunched its Travel, Theater, Personal Technology and Real Estate sections, offered streamlined navigation and integrated user-generated content and more multimedia features. In 2004 NYTimes.com averaged 1.6 million unique visitors a day, worldwide.
The Discovery Times Channel, our digital television joint venture with Discovery Communications Inc., continued to produce award-winning programming as
it attracted one of the most demographically appealing cable audiences. It is now available in 36 million homes, and advertising revenues grew 50% last year.
A Pre-eminent Brand The Times’s brand reputation delivers premium value, and the U.S. Opinion Leaders study, conducted by
Erdos & Morgan, revealed that the
weekday edition of The New York Times now ranks first among
156 print, broadcast and cable media in reaching U.S. opinion leaders. The weekday New
York Times was cited as the most “influential” of all media outlets measured.
In October The Times introduced an expanded and redesigned arts section with a greater focus on its specialty coverage areas: architecture, art, books, classical music, dance, film, pop culture, television and theater.
      NYT Annual Report 2004
  
 Arthur Sulzberger, Jr.
Chairman
Janet L. Robinson
President and CEO
 3
 Next Generation Outreach As a result of a comprehensive program of Next Generation initiatives, The Times has been expanding its share of young readers, a critically important audience. According to a semi-annual study of national newspaper readership by the Student Monitor, The New York Times reaches nearly one in four U.S. college students during a typical week – a much larger percentage than any other American newspaper. It also found that NYTimes.com reaches
one in eight college students in a typical week.
2004 Journalistic Accolades The deep respect for our brand was also underscored by the many journalistic accolades that we received throughout 2004: • The New York Times was awarded the Pulitzer Prize
for public service journalism for Lowell Bergman and David Barstow’s joint print and television production, “Dangerous Business,” which investigated the horrific working conditions at McWane Industries.
This was the first time that a joint print and broadcast submission won, and the third year in a row that one of our Company properties earned the most prestigious of Pulitzers, for Public Service.
• The Times also received an Emmy for Outstanding Documentary on a Business Topic, “Follow the Money,” a look at the dynamics of campaign cash in the 2004 election, which aired on the Discovery Times Channel.
• The National Press Foundation recognized NYTimes.com for its general excellence in online journalism.
Our Global Outreach The international newspaper market, which experienced substantial softness in 2004, presented additional challenges for the International Herald Tribune, the centerpiece of our global outreach. The IHT responded by adding new journalists, enhancing content, opening four print sites, developing new publishing partnerships and introducing daily editorial color to its pages.
These investments are paying off:
• The IHT has had the highest readership growth in both
Europe and Asia of any international daily or weekly publication measured.
• Revenues were up for the year and combination advertising buys with The Times doubled.
• And the IHT’s color advertising revenue increased by 36% in 2004.
To build on this momentum, the IHT opened a news bureau and sales office in Frankfurt, as well as a newsroom in Hong Kong, at the beginning of 2005.
The New York Times won the Public Service Pulitzer for its series that examined workplace safety rules.
   NYT Annual Report 2004
  
 4
In 2004 the IHT added new journalists, enhanced content, opened four print sites, developed new publishing partnerships and introduced daily editorial color to its pages.
Moving Forward in New England The Boston Globe responded to advertising softness with its own investment, innovation and reinvention. In 2004 it relaunched The Boston Globe Magazine, the Thursday Calendar and the Sunday Business section. The Worcester (Massachusetts) Telegram & Gazette added two new weekly newspapers, enabling it to reach adver- tisers that do not normally appear in its pages.
The Globe also benefited from the expansion of its mailroom, which accommodates the continuing growth in part-run and preprint advertising. And Boston.com, which is celebrating its 10th anniversary this year, redesigned its home page, introduced more premium ad positions and offered added visibility for its classified advertisers.
A truly historic and exciting highlight was provided by our minority interest in New England Sports Ventures, which includes the Red Sox, Fenway Park and an 80% interest in the cable television channel, New England Sports Network. Finally, we shared the joy of seeing the Red Sox end their 86-year curse and win the World Series.
   In 2004 NYTimes.com relaunched four major sections: Travel, Theater, Personal Technology and Real Estate. These redesigned sections offer streamlined navigation, integrated user-generated content and more multimedia features.
 Expanding Local Markets Our Regional Media Group, which recorded increases in weekday and Sunday circulation, offers further examples of investment, innovation and reinvention. The Group expanded its market reach by introducing 10 new magazines since 2002, with five of them making their debuts last year. These titles, which produced 34 issues in 2004 – up from five magazines and nine issues in 2003 – have been profitable since they first appeared.
In addition, six weekly newspapers have also
been launched over the past two years. As the demography of our nation shifts, it has become increas- ingly important to speak effectively to new audiences. Our new Spanish-language weekly newspaper, Visión Latina, is targeting the growing Hispanic population in the greater Lakeland market of central Florida.
Extending Broadcast Markets Our Broadcast Media Group, whose advertising benefited from substantial political campaign spending and the Summer Olympics, has been building on its core business through its local news expansion strategy
and multimedia approach. In 2004 the Group produced 285 hours of local news each week, which delivered over half of its advertising revenue. This year the
Group plans to increase its online offerings, add news programming and create sponsorships for special projects at all of its stations.
   NYT Annual Report 2004
  
 In March 2004 the International Herald Tribune introduced editorial color on its front page, which has been well received by both readers and advertisers.
A Top Priority: Controlling Costs
Throughout 2004 we worked hard to produce new sections and products, build our
core businesses, expand our markets and reach new audiences. We have also been disciplined in controlling costs. This effort is especially important in such an unpredictable operating environment.
Important examples of this commitment are the agreements we reached last year with two of our
major unions: the Newspaper Guild at The Boston Globe and the Pressmen at The New York Times.
These two agreements limit wage increases to approximately 2% per year, increase operating efficiency and flexibility and, in the case of The Times, allowed
us to reduce staffing on the presses by 37% in 2004 with an additional 9% reduction scheduled in 2010. Both agreements are precedent-setting and are already contributing to our expense management efforts.
We also made progress in 2004 on workers’ compensation costs, which have been rapidly escalating across American industries in recent years. By improving safety, preventing accidents and helping people to return to work sooner when accidents do occur, we have reduced workers’ compensation expenses by approximately 44%, or $11.5 million, since 2003, while improving the well-being of our employees.
  5
 Our Company continues to take a broad-based and strategic approach to cost control across the range of our businesses. We are in the process of re-examining all of our properties and their associated costs to determine the appropriate level of resources.
Optimization Councils In previous Annual Shareholder Letters, we have discussed our optimization councils – cross-functional teams looking for ways
to reduce costs in areas such as newsprint, production, telecommunications, joint contracts and systems.
By adopting their insightful and innovative recommen- dations, we have already been able to save approximately $25 million a year. In 2005 four new councils have been created, allowing us to achieve additional significant savings in areas such as circulation acquisition, outside services, consulting contracts and Webification, which is using the Web to reduce the cost of transactions and to lower expenses for printing and disseminating information.
A New Approach
to Stock-Based Compensation So that we can continue to motivate and reward employees while improving the impact of compensation plans on shareholder returns,
The redesigned Boston Globe Magazine made its debut in March 2004 with more service features, more varied content and an increased number of articles. These enhancements have attracted new luxury and fashion advertisers to the Magazine.
      NYT Annual Report 2004
    
  6
 Looking Ahead
In 2005 The Times Company plans to pursue growth through new products and services, new customers and new geographic markets.
■ More sections of The New York Times will be redesigned.
■ The Times expects to add four more national print sites and increase color capacity 40% by year end.
■ NYTimes.com will be enhancing its search capabilities and broadband content.
■ The Worcester Telegram & Gazette will be introducing Worcester Quarterly, a lifestyle magazine targeting upscale households.
■ Site registration at Boston.com will enable advertisers to better target users.
■ Three more new magazines will be launched by our Regional Media Group.
■ Our planned acquisition of About.com is expected to add a fast-growing, highly profitable Web site to complement the Company’s existing portfolio of digital properties.
 NYT Annual Report 2004

We have been disciplined in controlling costs, which is especially important in such an unpredictable operating environment.
 7
 we have also revised our approach to stock-based compensation. At the beginning of 2005, we started to expense the cost of options and our employee stock purchase plan. In anticipation of this step, the Company took a series of actions over the last two years to help decrease the cost of its stock-based compensation, including modifying its employee stock purchase plan and reducing the number of options granted across the board by almost 65%, a saving only slightly offset by an increase in restricted stock grants.
Enhancing Shareholder Value As always, we focused on enhancing shareholder value. In 2004 we made a significant contribution to this effort by employing our cash flow in productive ways.
Investing in High-Return Capital Projects Our investment in high-return capital projects provides a good example of this approach.
We have been expanding The Times’s color capacity. This has been a tremendous growth story for The Times, and color advertising now represents 27% of our ad revenues, up from 23% in 2003. And because of strong demand, we plan to increase our color printing capacity by 40% by year end 2005.
We are also expanding color capacity at our Sarasota, Fla., and Santa Rosa, Calif., papers to meet advertiser demand.
Another example is the classified advertising system that is being installed at our Regional Media Group. It replaces the multiple classified systems currently in place across the Group’s newspapers with a new common system. This self-service system will provide incremental revenue by enabling advertisers to add logos and
other features and to place the same ad in multiple newspapers in just one order. The expected return on the project is more than twice our cost of capital.
Stock Repurchase We have been aggressive buyers of our stock, spending $2.9 billion from 1997 through 2004 to repurchase nearly 77 million shares. This total includes the $293 million we spent to repurchase 6.8 million shares in 2004.
A Competitive Dividend
We provide our shareholders with a competitive dividend. Last April
we increased our dividend by
7%. For the five-year period
ended in 2004, our dividend has grown at a compound annual growth rate of
8.3%, which is 43%
higher than the average for our peers.
Boston.com Apartments, which launched
in June, was created to improve both our print and online position in the competitive Boston rental market by providing advertisers with broader exposure and access to more targeted distribution.
      NYT Annual Report 2004
  
 In 2004 the Regional Media Group introduced five new magazines, which have all been profitable since they first appeared. In December the Group also created Visión Latina, a Spanish-language weekly newspaper, in one of its Florida markets.
  We would also like to thank
two retiring board members, Donald Stewart and Jacqueline Dryfoos, for their dedication, their service and their innumerable contributions.
Our Employees, Customers, Shareholders and Communities And, of course, we thank our employees, our customers, our shareholders and our communities for their continued loyalty and support throughout 2004.
Looking Ahead Turning to 2005, we anticipate that the business environment will be economically challenging and our marketplace will continue to evolve in ways both expected and unexpected. Yet, we also believe that the demand for news insight and analysis will be strong and that we are well prepared with our portfolio of exciting and useful offerings in print, online and broadcast. These include more cross-platform initiatives, further growth of the Times national expansion plan, greater use of broadband technology and a continued aggressive outreach to the Next Generation.
We believe through these and other initiatives, we can further grow our revenues and provide our shareholders with greater value in 2005.
 8
 New Investments We will continue to look for investments that are a strong strategic fit with our existing businesses or that allow us to expand into complementary markets. At the same time, we will remain very disciplined and mindful of our obligations to our shareholders. A good example is About, Inc., which provides “practical solutions for everyday problems” through its Web site, About.com. Ranking in the
top 15 most frequently visited sites, About.com plays
a valued role in the lives of millions of Internet users. This acquisition broadens the Company’s online content offering, strengthens and diversifies its online advertising, extends its reach among Internet users and provides an important platform for future growth.
Our Board of Directors Helping to guide us through this demanding year has been our Board of Directors, and we want to express our gratitude to these men and women for their many contributions. The directors’ experience, insight and guidance
have been invaluable as we chart our course through the media marketplace.
Our newest board member, Doreen Toben, executive vice president and chief financial officer of Verizon Communications, Inc., has already greatly assisted our efforts with her financial acumen, strategic planning skills and operating experience.
  Arthur Sulzberger, Jr. Janet L. Robinson
Chairman President and CEO
   NYT Annual Report 2004
   