A LETTER TO OUR INVESTORS
UNIQUELY POSITIONED.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN? For ONEOK and ONEOK Partners, it’s simple. We are able to create value for investors and customers through a uniquely positioned, extensive, integrated network of natural gas and natural gas liquids (NGL) assets.
  As you will read in the following pages, our commitment to creating value guided us through 2015 as we navigated a challenging commodity price environment, and resulted in a strong year-end finish and positive outlook for 2016.
Despite prevailing low commodity prices that led to a lot of uncertainty and volatility in the energy industry and financial markets, ONEOK Partners achieved higher adjusted earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization (adjusted EBITDA) in 2015, spurred by natural gas and NGL volume growth on our 37,000-mile integrated network of natural gas and NGL assets. In fact, the partnership’s 2015 adjusted EBITDA increased slightly compared with 2014 and increased
24 percent since 2013.
In 2015, we achieved this adjusted EBITDA and volume growth by focusing on increasing our fee-based earnings, reducing commodity risk in our business and making prudent financial decisions, while continuing to operate our assets safely, reliably and environmentally responsibly.
These proactive efforts helped distinguish us from other companies in our industry and resulted in:
▪ The natural gas liquids segment, one of the largest of its kind in the U.S., finishing 2015 strong with NGL volumes gathered increasing 44 percent, compared with 2014;
▪ The natural gas pipelines segment continuing to deliver consistent, predominantly fee-based earnings; and
▪ The natural gas gathering and processing segment recording its highest volumes ever in the fourth quarter 2015, and 2015 natural gas volumes gathered and processed increasing approximately 12 and 10 percent, respectively, compared with 2014.
ONEOK Partners finished 2015 strong and is well- positioned in these challenging times to grow earnings in 2016 and beyond.
Similarly, ONEOK ended 2015 in a strong financial position, due largely to increased cash distributions from ONEOK’s limited and general partner interests in ONEOK Partners. Distributions declared from the partnership increased more than 16 percent in 2015 compared with 2014, driven by ONEOK’s purchase of an additional
21.5 million ONEOK Partners units in August 2015.
 1
 
  2
Construction crews prepare land in West Texas for the Roadrunner Gas Transmission Pipeline.
In 2015, we strengthened ONEOK Partners’ business model by engaging in projects and initiatives that increased fee-based earnings and decreased exposure to commodity price volatility.
   
  STRENGTHENING OUR POSITION
In challenging times, we rely on our strengths, which for the partnership are our predominantly fee-based structure and uniquely positioned, integrated network of natural gas and NGL assets that allow us to provide nondiscretionary services to our customers from North Dakota to the Texas Gulf Coast.
In 2015, we strengthened ONEOK Partners’ business model by engaging in projects and initiatives that increased fee-based earnings and decreased exposure to commodity price volatility. Contract restructuring in our natural gas gathering and processing segment resulted in increased fee-based earnings, providing a contract mix that we expect
will be greater than 75 percent fee-based in 2016 – up from 44 percent in 2015. The average fee rate in this segment increased to 55 cents in the fourth quarter 2015, compared with 36 cents in the fourth quarter 2014.
Companywide, we anticipate our 2016 fee-based earnings will increase to approximately 85 percent from 66 percent in 2014, which we expect will positively impact our full-year 2016 earnings.
These restructuring efforts made our business model more durable and sustainable than before, while also enabling us to continue providing the nondiscretionary services and critical infrastructure that our customers need.
NATURAL GAS LIQUIDS
NGL Pipelines NGL Fractionator NGL Storage
50 percent interest
NATURAL GAS LIQUIDS: CAPITALIZING ON
OUR POSITION
Our unique asset position in key NGL-rich plays
and flexible, nondiscretionary, fee-based services continue to drive success in our extensive natural gas liquids business, which is the second-largest in the country. Capitalizing on largely fee-based exchange, storage and transportation services, this segment provides unique transportation and fractionation capabilities to major markets.
Systemwide, we connected eight new natural
gas processing plants to our NGL system in 2015 and expect an additional four third-party plant connections in 2016, which will bring our total to more than 180 processing plant connections in the Mid-Continent, Barnett Shale, Rocky Mountain region and Permian Basin.
We continue to benefit from our extensive position in the Williston Basin, where our Bakken NGL Pipeline provides transportation takeaway from the region.
MINNESOTA
                  IOWA
ILLINOIS
MISSOURI
                                           OKLAHOMA
TEXAS
              3
 MONTANA
NORTH DAKOTA
SOUTH DAKOTA
WYOMING
NEBRASKA
KANSAS
COLORADO
NEW MEXICO

Added de-ethanization facilities at our Stateline natural gas processing plants in Williams County, North Dakota, will produce an expected 26,000 barrels per day (bpd) of ethane to be delivered to a third-party pipeline to serve markets in Canada. These de-ethanization facilities are expected to be completed in the third quarter 2016.
We also continue to benefit from our 2014 acquisition of the West Texas LPG Pipeline system, which established an NGL presence in the Permian Basin and added 2,600 miles of gathering pipelines with
a gross capacity of 285,000 bpd to our system.
As we look forward to 2016 and beyond, a significant opportunity is emerging for our natural gas liquids segment as we serve the growing petrochemical demand for ethane, another NGL.
The competitive pricing of ethane is leading to increased exports, as well as the construction of additional world-class petrochemical facilities on the Gulf Coast that will utilize ethane as a feedstock during the manufacturing process.
We anticipate that basins closest to market hubs will be the first to recover ethane, and our NGL assets in and around these areas are ideally positioned to serve this growing U.S. demand, which is expected to accelerate in 2017.
NATURAL GAS PIPELINES
Natural Gas Pipelines Natural Gas Storage 50 percent interest Roadrunner
This is particularly true because approximately one-third of the incremental ethane supply sources needed to serve this demand are connected to our NGL system for transportation and fractionation services that will serve the new petrochemical plants.
We expect the impact of the increased ethane demand on our NGL throughput to begin in 2017.
NATURAL GAS PIPELINES: DIVERSIFYING OUR POSITION
In 2015, we diversified our asset mix through key growth projects in the Permian Basin that enhanced our fee-based portfolio and will connect us to emerging markets. These projects included:
▪ ROADRUNNER GAS TRANSMISSION PIPELINE Roadrunner is a 200-mile pipeline that connects our WesTex natural gas pipeline system near Coyanosa, Texas, to a new international border- crossing connection at the U.S. and Mexico border near San Elizario, Texas.
▪ The project is a 50-50 joint venture with Mexico City-based natural gas infrastructure company
                                           OKLAHOMA
TEXAS
                                       4
 MONTANA
WYOMING
NORTH DAKOTA
SOUTH DAKOTA
NEBRASKA
COLORADO
KANSAS
MINNESOTA
WISCONSIN
IOWA
ILLINOIS
INDIANA
MISSOURI
ARKANSAS
KENTUCKY
TENNESSEE
NEW MEXICO

 Fermaca. The project will be completed in phases – the first phase was placed in service in March 2016 providing 170 million cubic feet per day (MMcf/d) of capacity. The second phase is expected to increase the pipeline’s capacity to 570 MMcf/d and to be completed in the first quarter 2017. The third and final phase of the project is expected to be completed
in 2019 and to increase the total capacity of the pipeline to 640 MMcf/d.
▪ The initial design capacity of Roadrunner is fully subscribed and supported by 25-year, take-or-pay transportation agreements.
▪ WESTEX PIPELINE EXPANSION
The expansion of this intrastate natural gas pipeline system is expected to add approximately 260 MMcf/d of capacity to our system by 2017.
▪ The total capacity is 90 percent subscribed with 25-year, take-or-pay transportation agreements.
Together, these projects provide markets in Mexico access to upstream supply basins in West Texas and the Mid-Continent, which adds location and price diversity to their supply mix, while increasing the natural gas pipelines business’ fee-based earnings.
NATURAL GAS GATHERING AND PROCESSING: ENHANCING OUR POSITION
Our strong natural gas gathering and processing position in high-producing crude oil and NGL-rich resource plays, like the Williston Basin, continues to drive volume growth.
Our Williston Basin assets are uniquely positioned to capture growing volumes from:
▪ New well connections;
▪ A substantial backlog of wells drilled but not
completed; and
▪ An inventory of natural gas currently flaring.
An employee monitors natural gas flow at a facility in West Texas.
 NATURAL GAS VOLUME GROWTH
 Billion British thermal units per day (BBtu/d)
VOLUMES GATHERED
2016 Guidance
2,200 – 2,300
     2011
1,030
2 015 2014 1,932
1,733
2013
1,347
2012
1,119
  2016 Guidance
1,900 – 2,000
  VOLUMES PROCESSED
2013
1,094
2015
2011
1,687 1,534
2014
  2012
 866 713
    5
  
 MONTANA
WYOMING
NORTH DAKOTA
SOUTH DAKOTA
NEBRASKA
COLORADO
KANSAS
6
NATURAL GAS GATHERING AND PROCESSING
Natural gas production in core areas has historically exceeded the capacity of existing natural gas processing infrastructure causing natural gas to
be flared by oil producers in many cases.
To capture and process these volumes, we continue to invest in critical infrastructure, including:
▪ LONESOME CREEK PLANT
A 200-MMcf/d natural gas processing facility in McKenzie County, North Dakota; Completed November 2015
▪ NATURAL GAS COMPRESSION INFRASTRUCTURE Added approximately 100 MMcf/d of natural gas processing capacity; Completed December 2015
▪ BEAR CREEK PLANT
An 80-MMcf/d natural gas processing plant in Dunn County, North Dakota; Expected completion: third quarter 2016
The completion of Lonesome Creek and the natural gas compression infrastructure increased our total natural gas processing capacity in the Williston Basin to approximately 900 MMcf/d and alleviated field constraints in the basin.
Natural Gas Gathering Pipelines Natural Gas Processing Plant Bear Creek Plant
OKLAHOMA

 ONEOK’S 2015 FINANCIAL PERFORMANCE AND
2016 GUIDANCE
At ONEOK, 2015 cash flow available for dividends was $641 million, driven by increased distributions from approximately 21.5 million common units we purchased for approximately $650 million in a private placement from ONEOK Partners in August 2015. This was part of a $750 million offering by ONEOK Partners to meet the partnership’s equity needs and increased ONEOK’s aggregate ownership interest to 41.2 percent from 36.8 percent.
ONEOK’s dividend coverage ratio was 1.29 times in the fourth quarter 2015, which we achieved through
increased distributions from our limited and general partner interests in ONEOK Partners.
ONEOK expects to generate $160 million of free cash flow after dividends in 2016, which along with $90 million of cash on hand and an unutilitized $300 million credit facility provides ONEOK with significant flexibility to support ONEOK Partners, if needed.
ONEOK expects to have a dividend coverage ratio of 1.3 times in 2016 and no long-term debt maturities until 2022.
ONEOK has a long history of prudent financial decision-making, and we will continue to make decisions that are in the best long-term interest of our investors at both ONEOK and ONEOK Partners.
2016 Guidance*
$2.46
$2.44 $2.33
2014
2015
   DIVIDEND GROWTH
   ONEOK annual dividends declared per share (split adjusted) * Pending ONEOK board approval
2012
$1.325
2013
$1.52
2011
$1.125
   Construction at the Lonesome Creek natural gas processing facility in McKenzie County, North Dakota
  7
  
 ONEOK PARTNERS’ 2015 FINANCIAL PERFORMANCE AND 2016 GUIDANCE
In 2015, ONEOK Partners’ adjusted EBITDA was $1.57 billion, a slight increase compared with 2014.
ONEOK Partners’ distribution coverage ratio was 1.03 times in the fourth quarter 2015, which we achieved by processing higher volumes and increasing fee-based earnings.
An employee closes a valve at our West Texas LPG natural gas liquids pipeline assets near Big Spring, Texas.
In January 2016, the partnership entered into a
$1 billion three-year unsecured term loan agreement that effectively refinanced 2016 long-term debt maturities and further enhanced financial flexibility, providing ample liquidity to fund capital-growth projects. We also expect this to eliminate the need to access public markets for debt and equity until well into 2017.
Looking forward, we expect ONEOK Partners’ 2016 earnings to increase compared with 2015, primarily from volume growth and enhanced fee-based earnings, resulting in increased distributable cash flow.
2014
$3.07
2015
$3.16
2016 Guidance*
$3.16
   DISTRIBUTION GROWTH
ONEOK Partners annual distributions declared per unit (split adjusted)
* Pending ONEOK Partners board approval
2013
$2.89
  2012
$2.69
  2011
$2.365
   8
 
The partnership expects to maintain our investment-grade credit ratings, sustain our current distribution and achieve distribution coverage of 1.0 times or better for 2016. We also expect
to maintain our solid balance sheet and ample liquidity, which includes access to our commercial paper program and $2.4 billion credit facility.
OUR THANKS
Our achievements in this challenging environment would not have been possible without the tremendous contributions of our many employees, whose efforts to operate our network of assets safely, reliably and environmentally responsibly have enabled us to continue to provide quality and reliable service to our customers. Their hard work and commitment delivered solid results for the company, our customers and you, our investors. We thank them for their continued dedication.
Amid many headwinds, we executed well in 2015 and enter 2016 well positioned to continue to strengthen our unique asset position and reinforce our balance sheets at both ONEOK and ONEOK Partners.
As always, thank you for your continued trust and investment in ONEOK and ONEOK Partners.
JOHN W. GIBSON
Chairman
            TERRY K. SPENCER
President and Chief Executive Officer March 9, 2016
 9
 