   Dear Shareowners,
A.G. Lafley
Chairman of the Board, President and Chief Executive Officer
  At P&G, we are focused on building consumer-preferred brands and products that create value for consumers and shareowners. Everything begins with consumer understanding and winning at the zero moment of truth when consumers search for our brands, at the first moment of truth when they choose our brands, and at the second moment of truth when they use our products. Winning these moments of truth leads to consumer purchase, preference, regular usage and long-term loyalty. This is how we create value for consumers, build leadership brands and businesses, and create value for P&G shareowners.
We met our business and financial objectives for fiscal year 2014. Organic sales grew 3%, in line with the market. Core earnings per share increased 5%. We generated $10.1 billion of free cash flow, with 86% free cash flow productivity. We increased the dividend 7%—the 58th consecutive year that P&G’s dividend has been increased—and we returned $12.9 billion in cash to shareowners through $6.9 billion in dividends and $6 billion in share repurchase.
We delivered commitments, but we know we can do better. We need to continue to lead innovation, drive productivity, and improve execution in brand building, product innovation, selling and sourcing. When we do, we will generate stronger sales growth and more reliable value creation —profit and cash flow.
To accelerate performance improvement, we are taking an important strategic step forward in the Company’s business and brand portfolio.
    
   2 The Procter & Gamble Company
A Focused Company of Leading Brands
P&G will become a simpler, more focused Company of 70 to 80 brands, organized into about a dozen businesses and four industry-based sectors. We will compete in businesses that are structurally attractive and best leverage our core capabilities. Within these businesses, we will focus on leading brands or brands with leadership potential, marketed in the right countries where the size of prize and probability of winning is highest, with products that sell. We will discontinue or divest businesses, brands, product lines, and unproductive products that are structurally unattractive or that don’t fully play to our strengths.
Every brand we plan to keep is strategic, with the potential to grow and deliver value creation. These core 70 to 80 brands are leaders in their industries, businesses or segments. They offer differentiated products and have a track record of growth and value creation driven by product innovation and brand preference. They generate nearly 90% of current P&G sales and more than 95% of current profit. They have grown sales one point faster, with a higher profit margin than the balance of the Company during the past three years. The 90 to 100 brands we plan to exit have declining sales of −3%, declining profits of −16% and half the average Company margin during the past three years.
This strategic step will focus our innovation efforts, brand building, and supply network on fewer, more important brands. It will focus our selling resources on brands that really matter to consumers and retail customers, on businesses where we know how to win. It will provide consumers with a better shopping experience by simplifying shelf sets. It will improve service and
Joining Tide* and Ariel* in the unit dose laundry detergent segment, one Gain Flings!* pac offers twice the cleaning ingredients of one dose of original Gain liquid. Our unit dose detergents span more than 50 countries worldwide, with well over $1 billion in retail sales.
growth for retail customers. All of these outcomes will accelerate growth and value creation.
We will create a faster growing, more profitable Company that is far simpler to manage.
A Far More Productive Company
As a result of the Company’s strategic focus on leading brands, we will accelerate and over-deliver the original $10 billion productivity plan we announced in 2012. We see significant savings potential ahead across all spending elements—cost of goods sold, marketing spending, and overhead—for the next several years.
In cost of goods sold, we are already achieving productivity improvements beyond our original savings objectives. Better manufacturing reliability and adherence to quality standards are resulting in less raw material usage and reduced finished product scrapping. Increasing localization of the supply chain is driving savings in transportation and warehousing costs.
Earlier this year, we initiated what is probably the biggest supply chain redesign in the Company’s history, starting in North America. We’re moving from primarily single-category production sites to fewer multi-category production plants. We’re simplifying, standardizing and upgrading manufacturing platforms for faster innovation, qualification and expansion, and improved product quality.
We’re transforming our distribution network, starting with North America. We’re moving from shipping products to retail
Head & Shoulders*, the world’s #1 selling shampoo, has been
a leader for over 60 years with products such as Classic Clean shampoo and conditioner. This year, we introduced Fresh Scent Technology, which delivers an enhanced sensorial experience without compromising superior scalp and hair care efficacy.
                                 
      We see significant savings potential ahead across all spending elements—cost of goods sold, marketing spending, and overhead—for the next several years.
      customers from many different points—as if they were coming from different companies—to consolidating shipping into fewer distribution centers. These centers are located strategically closer to customers and key population centers in the U.S., enabling about 80% of the business to be within one day or less of the store shelf and the shopper. This will allow both P&G and our customers to optimize inventory levels while improving service and product availability for consumers.
To manage and operate this simpler brand portfolio, we have made several important organization design choices —four industry-based sectors; streamlining business units and selling operations; recombining four brand building functions into one; and reducing hierarchy, with all of the business unit and selling
operations leaders reporting to the CEO. Each of these changes reduces complexity, and creates clearer accountability for performance and results. We’re just beginning to benefit from the productivity opportunities that these organization changes create. We’ve reduced roles by 16% —more than 50% above the original objective, and two years sooner than planned. This is strong progress, and we see more opportunity ahead.
We’re starting to improve marketing efficiency and effectiveness through an optimized media mix with more digital, mobile, search and social presence, improved message clarity and greater savings in non-media spending. We believe we have more opportunity to improve marketing efficiency —in both media and non-media areas—while increasing overall marketing effectiveness and improving sales growth.
A Company Driven by Innovation
When we get brand and product innovation right, source and sell brands and products effectively and efficiently, we grow and drive meaningful value creation. We generate higher sales and profit per unit, which enables us to capture a greater share of the value —profit and cash —where we choose to compete.
It is this share of value —the share of profit generated in a category —that we want to capture. We have about a 60% share of U.S. laundry market sales, but earn approximately 85% of the profit and cash generated in the category. We have a nearly 70% share of blades and razors sales globally —and a 90% share of value or profit. We earn a higher share of profit as a direct result of our innovation-focused business strategy and business models.
The Procter & Gamble Company 3
    Pampers* continues to upgrade the comfort, absorbency and design of its line-up. Pampers Swaddlers—the #1 choice† of hospitals —recently expanded into sizes 4, 5 and 6, and now holds a 10% value share of the U.S. diaper category. †Based on sales of newborn hospital diapers
Gillette* is once again changing the face of shaving with Gillette Fusion ProGlide* with FlexBall* Technology, which allows each cartridge to make maximum contact over contours† and get virtually every hair—addressing a top shaving need mentioned by 8 out of 10 men. †vs. Fusion

   4 The Procter & Gamble Company
We are consumer led. Their needs and wants come first. We meet those needs with differentiated brands and better-performing products —priced to deliver real and perceived consumer value. In all four industry sectors and in most of our businesses, there is as much, and often more, sales growth and value creation — profit and cash —in the premium and super-premium segments. We’ve been very successful in these segments.
In the grooming market, premium products generate about 43% of sales. Gillette has an 88% share of this segment. Four years ago, we introduced Fusion ProGlide, priced at the higher end of the premium segment. Fusion grew global share for 31 consecutive quarters, reaching $1 billion in sales faster than any other P&G brand in history. Last month, we launched the newest product in the Fusion line-up —Fusion ProGlide with FlexBall* Technology, the first razor designed to respond to the contours of a man’s face, maintaining maximum contact and delivering a closer, more complete and comfortable shave. Men prefer this new razor 2-to-1 versus the best-selling razor in the world —our own Fusion ProGlide. FlexBall is off to a very good start, and appears to be revitalizing consumer interest in the category, driving an increase in U.S. male razor market sales, and acceleration in Gillette’s sales and shares.
Crest 3D White*, a premium oral care regimen, was also launched in the U.S. and has grown market share for 17 consecutive quarters. On its own worldwide, 3D White is a billion-dollar business.
3D White has also been an important driver of toothpaste market share growth in developing or emerging markets, for example, adding about a point-and-a-half share in Brazil and one point in Mexico last year. We recently launched 3D White in Europe,
P&G launched seven of the top 10 most successful non-food products of the year in the U.S. (Source: 2013 IRI New Product Pacesetters list)
driving category growth in a region where many other categories are declining. Following the 3D White launch, we introduced Crest 3D White Luxe* toothpaste and Whitestrips*. The Luxe Glamorous White* toothpaste removes up to 90% of surface stains on teeth in just five days and protects against future stains with our proprietary WHITELOCK* technology. The Whitestrips with FlexFit* Technology stretch and mold to your teeth for a completely custom fit.
Tide, Gain and Ariel three-chamber unit dose laundry detergents have been an innovation breakthrough in the laundry detergent category —resetting the bar for delightful consumer usage experience, product performance and convenience. Tide PODS* are priced at a 20% premium to liquid Tide and have grown to more than 7% of the laundry category. In March, we launched Gain Flings!* —priced at a 60% per use premium to Gain liquid detergent. Combined, Tide PODS and Gain Flings! now hold more
       Introduced in the U.K. in July 2014 and North America in August 2014, Always Discreet* marks our significant entry into the Adult Incontinence category —revolutionizing the way women manage sensitive bladders.
The manliest grooming brand is also the smartest.
Old Spice Re-Fresh* Body Spray’s unique Re-Fresh Technology releases bursts of fragrance throughout the day, giving guys superior freshness when they need it most.
 
    than a 10% value share of the U.S. laundry category and over 80% of the unit dose segment. We now offer this innovative product form in over 50 countries.
We are currently entering the female Adult Incontinence category. This is an attractive $7 billion category worldwide, growing at an annual rate of 7%. We’re entering the category with superior products that deliver significant consumer benefit advantages from Always, a brand that women trust and prefer. We began shipments of Always Discreet in the U.K. last month, and will start shipments in North America and France this month.
We are setting the brand and product innovation agenda in our industry. When we do this well, we build consumer preference for our brands, extend our brands’ competitive advantage, grow sales and market share cumulatively over time, and capture a larger share of category value —profit and cash.
A New P&G
In summary, we delivered commitments in fiscal year 2014, and we are taking an important strategic step forward by focusing the Company’s business and brand portfolio to accelerate performance. All of this will take time to execute, and the pace will be driven by our ability to create the most value for consumers and shareowners.
In effect, we are creating a new P&G. We will win consistently with 70 to 80 leading brands organized into about a dozen businesses in four industries marketed in the right countries with products that sell. We will create value through consumer- preferred brands and products that win at the zero, first and
We are creating
a new P&G—a Company that will grow sales faster and more sustainably, will create value more reliably, and will be far simpler to manage.
second moments of truth. The new P&G will grow sales faster and more sustainably, and create value —profit and cash — more reliably for P&G shareowners.
A.G. Lafley
Chairman of the Board, President and Chief Executive Officer
The Procter & Gamble Company 5
            Metamucil* is launching a new family of products named Meta*, with a range of forms and wellness benefits —Metamucil,
Meta Health Bars with psyllium fiber and MetaBiotic*, a 2-in-1 probiotic supplement. To learn more about our new consumer-significant, clinically proven benefits, visit metawellness.com.
Available at U.S. retailers in September 2014,
Crest Sensi-Stop* Strips is a revolutionary way to get tooth sensitivity relief. One strip applied for 10 minutes provides immediate relief and up to one month of protection.
 