Progress in Parker’s global growth strategy
Letter To Shareholders
P arker made major strides in its drive for global growth during fiscal 1998. Sales and earnings were
at an all-time high, with vigorous worldwide cus- tomer service efforts increasing market penetration and shareholder value.
Record sales, earnings
Parker achieved record sales and earnings for the fiscal year ended June 30. Sales were 13.2 percent higher and income was 16.6 percent above last year.
International Industrial sales were 8.2 percent above the previous year, while operating income rose 12.8 per- cent. Acquisitions represented two- thirds of the sales increase. Without the effect of currency rate changes, volume increased more than 17.0 per- cent over the prior year.
Soaring aerospace markets
Sales Industrial– International Millions of Dollars
 1,200 900 600 300
       Strong demand continued
The year’s excellent financial re- sults reflected Parker’s ability to lever- age continued strong demand for both aerospace and industrial products while providing premier customer ser- vice. The results contributed to a five- year compound growth rate of 13.2 percent.
Strong industrial markets
operating income exceeded the prior year by 45.3 percent.
The Aerospace Segment reflected high volumes of commercial aircraft deliveries, a favorable product mix and global expansion of commercial repair and overhaul business.
Acquisition activity continues
Sales Aerospace Millions of Dollars
94 95 96 97 98
1,200 900 600 300
Parker’s Aerospace Segment sales were robust during the year, 15.1 percent ahead of last year’s pace. Segment
94 95 96 97 98
 1997 1998 Increase
 Total sales ($ millions) $4,091 $4,633 Net income ($ millions) 274 320 Earnings per share (dollars)$ 2.44 $ 2.85
13.2% 16.6% 16.8%
   Sales
Total Parker Worldwide Millions of Dollars
4,800 3,600 2,400 1,200
Parker continued to fuel its growth through the recent acquisition of 11 companies. Each provides quality prod- ucts that enhance and broaden the Company’s product lines. Together, they represent nearly a quarter-billion dollars in additional annual sales.
As detailed on page 3, these acquired businesses not only added to Parker’s product depth, they enhanced its global presence. For example, the UCC group of compa- nies is an innovative developer of technology-based fil- tration products in England. Sempress Pneumatics in the Netherlands added to our pneumatic cylinder and valve offerings, while in Sweden, Temeto AB provided a major distributor of connector components there.
The Asia-Pacific region’s troubled economies also offered timely opportunities for Parker. In Korea, the
    Industrial customer demand was strongest among manu- facturers of heavy-duty trucks, agricultural and con-
struction equipment, machine tools plus refrigeration, telecommunications and processing industries.
North American Industrial sales were up 15.0 percent over last year, and operating income was 11.6 per- cent higher. Acquisitions accounted for about one-fifth of the sales increase.
Sales Industrial– North America Millions of Dollars
94 95 96 97 98
2,800 2,100 1,400 700
94 95 96 97 98
           2

Company became 100 percent owner of two joint ven- tures: H.S. Parker Company Ltd. and H.S. Parker Air Conditioning Components Company Ltd. These manu- facturers of hydraulic hose and fittings and air condition- ing assemblies are now helping to improve Parker’s
customer service and product support in this region.
In the U.S., the acquisition of Skinner Valve, and Lucifer S.A. in Europe, extended Parker’s solenoid valve lines, while the recent acquisition of Veriflo Corporation in July and EWAL Manufacturing gave Parker precision fittings and valves for the ultra-high-purity and semicon-
ductor markets.
The addition of Computer Technology Corporation
(CTC) to the Automation Group elevated Parker to the next level of motion control technology. CTC is a pioneer in developing industrial PC workstations bundled with software to produce advanced human-machine interface solutions for the factory floor. CTC’s product line, com- bined with Parker’s Compumotor, Daedal, actuator and pneumatic products, enables the Company to provide total system solutions.
Parker’s proven growth objectives
Three major objectives drive Parker’s strategy for profit- able growth that will increase shareholder value:
■ Deliver premier customer service
■ Sustain solid financial performance
■ Expand product lines, globalize
First and foremost of these is customer service. Deliv- ering outstanding service is the vital step in building the Company’s market share. Parker strives to be the pre- ferred supplier; the company called first by customers because of its reliable performance record. This is in- creasingly important as the number of suppliers declines and customer expectations rise.
Outstanding service helps Parker grow from a solid core of highly satisfied customers who become “advo- cates.” The objective is to make each of our 400,000 customers enthusiastic supporters of Parker Hannifin.
 Recent Parker acquisitions
 ■ Skinner Valve (U.S.) and Lucifer S.A. (Europe) solenoid valve business acquired from Honeywell (9/97).
■ EWAL Manufacturing Co., Belleville, N.J., producer of precision fittings and valves for ultra-high-purity and semicon- ductor markets (8/97).
■ H.S. Parker Ltd., Yangsan, Korea, maker of fluid connectors (3/98).
■ H.S. Parker Air Conditioning Com- ponents Co. Ltd., Chonan, Korea, designer and manufacturer of air condition- ing hose assemblies and accumulators (3/98).
■ UCC group of companies, Thetford, England, maker of technology based filtra- tion products (4/98).
■ Temeto AB, Flen, Sweden, a major distributor of hydraulic components (3/98).
■ Computer Technology Corporation, Milford, Ohio, developer of industrial PC workstations bundled with software for operator-machine interfaces for factory floor applications (2/98).
■ Sempress Pneumatics, Rotterdam, the Netherlands, leading maker of pneu- matic cylinders and valves (4/98).
■ Extrudit, a Buxton, England, tubing company (5/98).
■ Dynamic Valves, Inc., Palo Alto, Calif., maker of high-performance electrohydraulic and electropneumatic servo valves (4/98).
■ Veriflo Corp., Richmond, Calif., maker of high-purity valves and regulators (7/98).
 3

  Financial Goals and Performance
 Five-year compound sales growth (%)
Net income on sales (%) Average assets/sales ($) Return on average assets (%) Return on average equity (%) Debt to debt-equity (%) Dividend payout ratio (%)
Goal
7.5 6.0 .70 7.2
14.0 30 - 33 33.0
1995 1996
5.6 8.0 6.8 6.7 .66 .72
10.3 9.2 20.2 18.6 21.9 30.7 22.9 22.2
1997 1998 11.5 13.2
6.7 6.9 .72 .70 9.3 9.8
18.7 19.8 24.5 31.6 20.6 20.8
Elements
of sound financial performance Parker’s sustained
growth is due in
large part to man-
agement’s emphasis on several strategic financial goals. The measurement universally applied to both the Com- pany and its individual business units is the extent to which returns exceed the cost of capital.
In fiscal 1998, Parker exceeded its target 14.0 percent return on equity by achieving a 19.8 percent return. Other goals and the Company’s performance for recent years are reported in the accompanying table.
Strong cash flows have long been a powerful growth engine for Parker, enabling it to make important invest- ments in efficient plants and equipment as well as acquir- ing attractive companies. The largest source of cash is provided by operating activities, which over the past three years have provided more than $1 billion.
It is this solid foundation of financial performance and healthy cash flows that supports Parker Hannifin’s growth.
Elements of Parker’s growth:
A three-pronged strategy
The record of Parker’s growth over the past five years shows that sales almost doubled from $2.5 billion to $4.6 billion. Three main initiatives are responsible for this growth:
■ Internal growth — best products and services
■ Acquisitions — fill niches and markets
■ Globalization — geographic penetration
Internal growth
One of the rewards for consistently delivering outstand- ing customer service is internal growth, which is often reflected in better market shares. Parker also strives to
grow by develop- ing innovative new products: the “bet- ter mousetraps” that meet or ex- ceed customers’
ever-increasing expectations. A number of such exciting new product developments are featured in the Group business reviews starting on page 10.
Acquisitions
Historically, acquisitions have accounted for about a third of the Company’s growth. Internal activities repre- sent two-thirds. Over the last five fiscal years, the Com- pany made more than 40 acquisitions that added more than $1 billion in annual sales.
Parker has traditionally focused on friendly acquisi- tions that fit comfortably with its core businesses. These “bolt-on” companies generally are assimilated quickly and soon begin contributing to results.
Globalization
As Parker enters more markets worldwide, globalization is increasing. Both acquisitions and new facilities are helping the Company serve customers in over 120 coun- tries from our operations in 38 nations. And, through upgraded systems, Parker will be able to conduct its worldwide business in either dollars, local currencies or the new Euro.
Year 2000 update
The Company’s program to assure that its computer systems are capable of processing periods for the year 2000 and beyond is on schedule. Conversion efforts have been underway since early 1996 and we expect that our standard application systems will be compliant by July 1999.
 4

 Employees are pivotal in delivering premier customer service
More than 39,000 Parker
Hannifin employees, who own
over 10 percent of the Com-
pany’s stock, are responsible
for making premier customer
service a reality. Progress at
Parker is a very personal thing.
It is our employees who create
the new products, identify and
negotiate valuable acquisi-
tions, manufacture quality products, and consistently meet or exceed our customers’ expectations.
We are proud of Parker people and salute them for their outstanding accomplishments.
In memoriam
As this report was being completed, the Company was saddened to learn that Larry Hopcraft, President of the Climate & Industrial Controls Group, and his wife Polly, died in a plane crash while en route to Europe. An im- portant member of our management team for 25 years, he made innumerable contributions to the success of Parker Hannifin. We mourn his passing, and extend our sympathy to his family and friends.
The outlook for Parker:
Momentum for the 21st century
Parker’s sustained and healthy financial performance validates our strategy and provides a proven blueprint for continued success. All the ingredients are in place for Parker Hannifin to build on this year’s outstanding finan- cial performance during fiscal year 1999 and beyond.
For the short term, indications are that the recent robust rates of economic growth will slow to a more moderate pace because many market segments are peaking. We do not expect to see recent double-digit growth rates continue. Many of our core markets remain
sound, and we are optimistic that certain global economic problems will be resolved.
The current disinflationary environment, in which price in- creases are resisted, makes maintaining margins difficult. Successful companies, there- fore, are ones that manage their costs effectively, a prac- tice that Parker has stressed for many years.
Parker is in business for the long-term, and its strategy remains to pursue attractive opportunities that beckon from many markets of the world. Such markets as auto- mation and motion-control are destined to grow, as are maintenance, repair and overhaul activities. The $18.5 billion in Parker aerospace components installed on aircraft flying today, for example, assures a solid base for our future repair and overhaul activity.
In the meantime, Parker Hannifin will aggressively pursue attractive acquisition opportunities, enlarge our worldwide network of manufacturing plants, sales and service offices, while stressing new customer-pleasing products. Recent investments made in highly efficient plants in Poland, China, the Czech Republic and else- where will continue. Further progress is expected in expanding our businesses in target geographic markets worldwide. Typical is the Asia Pacific region, where long- term prospects are very attractive.
In summary, Parker is a sound Company, with a sound financial record and sound future prospects.
Parker’s new headquarters, which houses the Company’s advanced electronic communications hub, was built to facilitate global growth and improve the speed of administrative functions. Chairman Patrick Parker, right; with members of the Office of the President: left to right, Vice President Lawrence Zeno, Executive Vice President Dennis Sullivan and President and Chief Executive Officer Duane Collins.
Respectfully Submitted,
Patrick S. Parker Chairman of the Board
September 2, 1998
Duane E. Collins President and Chief Executive Officer
   5
