                Delivering shareowner value begins with an unrelenting focus on our customers and a commitment to innovation; this is what sustains our ability to meet and exceed our customers’ expectations today and fuels our future growth.
Keith D. Nosbusch Chairman & CEO
 To Our Shareowners:
Fiscal 2013 was another solid year for Rockwell Automation and we’re proud to have delivered record results in a low growth environment. On sales of $6.35 billion, Adjusted EPS1 grew 8 percent to $5.71 and return on invested capital was 31.4 percent. We expanded segment operating margin almost a full point while continuing to invest for growth.
As the world’s largest company dedicated to industrial automation, we improve the standard of living for everyone by making the world more productive and sustainable. For decades, our customers have relied on us to help them improve their productivity, quality, safety and sustainability.
With operations in more than 80 countries, our 22,000 talented employees possess a deep understanding of global markets and local challenges so they can respond to our customers’ changing business needs rapidly, efficiently and effectively.
The results in fiscal 2013 demonstrate the success of our growth and performance strategy, especially our ability to execute exceptionally well in all market environments. I am proud of our performance and I believe our success is
fueled by our strategy, deep domain expertise, relentless focus on technology innovation and passion for helping our customers succeed.
3
Our proven track record of returning cash to shareowners continues:
• Paid out $679 million of cash in dividends and share repurchases in fiscal 2013
• Raised the dividend by 11% in fiscal 2013 and another 12% in the first quarter of
fiscal 2014
• Doubled our dividend per share in the last four years and returned $2 billion of cash to shareowners
       
                                    at a glance
80+ countries
20+ inDustries
$6.35B Fiscal 2013 sales
22,000 employees
Serving Customers for 110 Years
The Right Strategy
While we report our results as two business segments – Control Products & Solutions and Architecture & Software – we go to market as one business across geographic regions, markets and industries.
Our products, services and solutions address a broad range of challenges in every major industrial sector, from automotive and tire to mining and oil and gas, from pharmaceuticals to food and beverage.
Evidence of the diversification of our served market is our expansion into oil and gas. We offered only motor control in this industry a decade ago. Now we sell our entire portfolio as oil and gas has grown to over 10 percent of our sales.
The automation market will grow in excess of GDP and we believe we can grow a point or two above that by expanding our served market and gaining share. Based on that, we expect to drive double-digit earnings per share growth.
We are confident that we can deliver an after-tax return on invested capital in excess of 20 percent long term. We’ve been tracking well above that for several years now. We have proven that we can generate strong free cash flow during all phases of an economic cycle.
I am confident we have the right strategy in place. We expect that strategy, combined with our ability to execute exceptionally well, will enable us to continue to deliver superior returns to our shareowners.
Growing from a Strong Foundation
We have a strong foundation of competitive differentiation that includes our deep domain expertise, a unique market access model and three innovative growth platforms – Integrated Architecture, Intelligent Motor Control, and Solutions and Services. New growth will be built on this strong foundation.
Our best growth opportunities continue to be in process, OEMs (machine builders), emerging markets, safety, and services, and we believe we can further expand our offerings and do even more for our customers.
With our strong foundation and ongoing technology innovation, we are creating new value for our customers through the convergence of contemporary technologies such as cloud computing, big data analytics and mobility, with traditional control technologies.
  World’s largest company dedicated to industrial automation
                     ■ ■ ■
technology innovation Domain expertise
culture of integrity & corporate responsibility
4

                 We are developing a more interconnected production environment that is rich in actionable information and opportunities to further optimize plants and supply chain networks. We are evolving our Integrated Architecture to deliver this actionable information from the large volume of real-time data that we manage in industrial plants.
We call this evolution Integrated Control and Information. It will create new business opportunities for us in areas such as industrial network infrastructure, industrial security, remote automation, active energy management and industrial intelligence. The evolution of our growth platforms to address these opportunities has helped us expand our served market to about $90 billion, an increase of $10 billion over last year.
We believe Integrated Control and Information will accelerate the seamless flow of information between a company’s production plants, headquarters, supply chain, and customers, leading to The Connected Enterprise. You will read more about this later in the report.
Culture of Integrity
Our culture of integrity is reflected in the choices we make, and I am proud of
our employees who consistently do the right things, the right way, every day.
We were honored this year to be named for the fifth time to the Ethisphere Institute’s annual “World’s Most Ethical Companies” list. Our commitment to integrity, reflected in how we engage our employees, partners and customers, is the cornerstone of everything we do.
As we proudly celebrate our 110th anniversary, we look back on a long history of unwavering customer focus and a commitment to technology innovation. Our success is fueled by our employees around the world whose dedication has driven our ability to create long-term shareowner value.
In closing, I want to thank all of our shareowners for the trust you place in us with your investment.
        Our support of STEM (science, technology, engineering and math) and FIRST (For Inspiration and Recognition of Science and Technology) enables youth to expand their capabilities in the disciplines that lie at the heart of our ability to innovate and compete globally.
We were honored in 2013 to receive the FIRST Founder’s Award, which recognizes an organization or individual for exceptional service in advancing the ideals and mission of FIRST.
  5
Expanding our capabilities
In 2013, we acquired
the medium voltage drives business of Harbin
Jiuzhou Electric Co., Ltd., headquartered in Harbin, China. This acquisition strengthened our presence in the Asia Pacific motor control market – the world’s largest and fastest growing medium voltage drives market.
   