  4 sf n annual report | fy 2016
message from the president | sf n annual report | fy 2016 5
 Message From the President: Serving Science, Expanding Reach & Impact
 ↓
Hollis Cline, SfN president
Just as the neuroscience field has evolved tremendously over the past 47 years, so too has the Society for Neuroscience. Today, SfN is rapidly expanding the reach and impact of its programs to serve a highly diverse, global, multidisciplinary field.
This dynamism keeps pace with the evolving needs of the neuroscience community by helping scientists share their excellent research, enabling members to develop their skills and careers, advocating aggressively for science funding and animal research around the world, and engaging the global public about exciting brain science. In 2016, SfN is also embracing new technologies and data systems to make its programs more accessible to the entire community, improve communications, and share science more effectively.
The neuroscience field is making extraordinary strides to expand knowledge about the brain despite challenges that strain individual researchers and the larger research ecosystem. On the one hand, new scientific discoveries and tools are revealing insights — and also more questions — about the incredible organ that we study. Governments around the world are showing greater levels of support for brain research initiatives, and new waves of the world’s brightest young minds are drawn to study the most complex biological structure in the universe, giving me great hope for the future.
At the same time, funding pressures, regulatory burdens, animal rights extremism, and uncertain futures for young trainees challenge us all and our ability to realize the full potential of our field. Moreover, like the broader scientific community, we have much work to do to ensure full participation of women and minorities in our field and scientific rigor in our methods.
SfN’s programs, values, and advocacy advance the field on all of these topics, serving nearly 38,000 members worldwide. This report offers an overview of SfN’s programs, and I encourage you to visit SfN.org regularly to learn more and take part in these programs.
sharing great science and creating learning platforms
In FY 2016, SfN created increased value for members and the field. Our annual meeting in Chicago drew 29,000 researchers, clinicians, advocates, and exhibitors, with more than a third of scientific attendees from outside the U.S. eNeuro,
SfN’s open-access journal, thrived in its first full year, joining SfN’s flagship publication, JNeurosci, as a venue for outstanding research across the broad
range of neuroscience. Scientists who attend the annual meeting and publish in SfN journals are investing in the future of the field, as the Society’s nonprofit programming supports the global neuroscience community.
  Fig. 2
Different types of potassium channels (green and red) cluster in distinct regions of cultured spiral ganglion neurons.

  6 sf n annual report | fy 2016
enhancing scientific rigor | sf n annual report | fy 2016 7
  ↓
From right: SfN President Hollis Cline talks with U.S. Rep. Jan Schakowsky, former SfN President Carol Mason, and Walter Koroshetz, deputy director of the National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke, at the Advocacy Reception at SfN’s annual meeting.
“SfN is uniquely positioned to bring together neuroscientists, funding agencies, and publishers
to think deeply about this problem, brainstorm solutions, and influence the dissemination of those solutions across the field.”
— Rita Balice-Gordon, scientific rigor training module organizer
SfN continues to take the lead in addressing the issue of
scientific rigor in neuroscience.
Science only succeeds in advancing knowledge and improving human health when scientists consistently apply the highest research standards. Recently, reports documenting lower-than-expected replication rates have raised questions about the self-correcting nature of science. SfN is serving the field with efforts to strengthen scientific rigor — including experimental design, statistical analysis and reporting, and scientific communication.
SfN convened the Scientific Rigor Working Group in 2013 — led by Council members Emanuel DiCicco-Bloom of Rutgers University and Oswald Steward
of the University of California, Irvine — to recommend proactive strategies
to improve scientific practices. Their work resulted in “Research Practices for Scientific Rigor,” a foundational guideline for both trainees and experienced researchers to reference and use as the basis for conversation, training, and practice.
The Society’s publications took up the charge this year as JNeurosci Editor- in-Chief Marina Picciotto and eNeuro Editor-in-Chief Christophe Bernard participated in a webinar and Twitter chat focused on how to peer review a manuscript and eNeuro published an editorial and two commentaries on scientific rigor.
The Society also partnered with the National Institute on Drug Abuse and leading neuroscientists to offer the series “Promoting Awareness and Knowledge to Enhance Scientific Rigor in Neuroscience.” This series kicked off at Neuroscience 2015 with a professional development workshop “Tackling Challenges in Scientific Rigor: The (Sometimes) Messy Reality of Science.” The project is funded under a grant as a part of NIH’s Training Modules to Enhance Data Reproducibility and is available to all on Neuronline.
The series features six training modules composed of webinars, curated reading lists, Q&As, and group discussions addressing various aspects of scientific rigor, including planning experiments and data collection, minimizing bias in experimental design and execution, post-experimental data analysis, and data management and reporting.
The project culminates at Neuroscience 2016 with the workshop “Meeting Expectations: NIH Review Criterion on Scientific Rigor,” organized by Cheryl Sisk of Michigan State University.
“These efforts will strengthen the scientific enterprise and improve public recognition of the self-correcting nature of science,” SfN Past President Steven Hyman said. “Attention to scientific rigor is something we owe to our field, our funders, and especially to our students.”
This programming includes scientific training, professional development, and career opportunities to meet the evolving needs of SfN’s members throughout their careers. After a successful first year, the new Neuronline — SfN’s members- only home for learning and discussion — now features an extensive library of more than 550 articles, videos, webinars, and other resources on research methods, careers beyond the bench, mentoring tips, diversity in the field, and more. SfN continues to develop this exclusive content and networking, which members worldwide can easily access online.
supporting neuroscience through advocacy and outreach
SfN also supports its members and the field by encouraging an informed public and knowledgeable policymakers who understand the vital nature of neuroscience and its contributions to uncovering pathways to solve public health challenges. SfN serves as an aggressive and consistent advocate for greater research funding
in the U.S. and around the world, and also works to protect and convey the importance of animal research. In addition, the Society disseminates accurate, compelling information about “the universe between our ears” to a global audience through BrainFacts.org, a public information initiative guided by SfN that topped 10 million page views in 2016.
During my time as SfN president, I stressed the particular importance of communicating with elected officials about the need to fund basic science research as well as the necessity of responsible animal research. I also emphasized that greater efforts in science diplomacy — such as the building of relationships with international colleagues — can not only benefit the scientific enterprise, but also international diplomatic relations that strengthen nations and collaborations.
sfn is stronger thanks to our community
As SfN president, I’ve greatly enjoyed the opportunity to contribute to the Society’s goal of advancing the field I love. None of this would be possible without my fellow members who have volunteered time as councilors, committee members, journal editors, science advocates, and more. Your service to SfN and its mission ensures that the field remains a strong, vibrant community ready to tackle the challenges and opportunities ahead, including securing robust funding for research that will unlock the mysteries of the brain. I thank you for this opportunity to serve and strongly encourage all neuroscientists to get involved with SfN for the benefit of both your own career and the future of the field.
Hollis Cline, president
Enhancing Scientific Rigor
    