  To our Snap‐on SharehoLderS
 2
our performance in 2012 further validates Snap‐on’s strengths in solving the critical . . . delivering unique productivity solutions that make work easier for serious professionals.
Throughout 2012, we continued to execute on those strategic areas of importance we’ve identified as being decisive to our future, achieving higher year-over-year sales and operating income. For the year, net sales
of $2.94 billion increased 2.9% compared to 2011; excluding foreign currency translation, organic sales increased 4.6%. As a percentage of sales, operating earnings before financial services of 13.9% improved 40 basis points from 13.5% a year ago, including an adverse 50 basis point impact from higher mark-to- market expense resulting from the year-over-year increase in Snap-on’s year-end stock price. Operating
earnings from financial services grew to $106.7 million
in 2012, reflecting the continued growth of our on-book finance portfolio. Net earnings of $306.1 million in 2012 increased $29.8 million over 2011 levels, and we achieved a new record high for diluted earnings per share of $5.20 for the year.
We believe our 2012 operating performance testifies
to the significant and continued progress on our strategic priorities, including the realization of ongoing improvements through Snap-on Value Creation, a suite of principles and processes we employ every day. These runways for improvement, as we call them, have served us well the past several years, in a variety of macroeconomic environments. In that regard, our disciplines around safety, quality, customer connection, innovation and rapid continuous improvement (RCI) yielded benefits again in 2012.
    
   Snap‐on’s strengths in solving the critical play out in repair facilities around the world every day.
chairman and chief executive officer nick pinchuk and Julio Morales, Snap‐on Tools crystal lake product center,
hear from this technician how Snap‐on’s capabilities help him with the critical task of servicing and
repairing emergency vehicles. Joining them are darin coats, Snap‐on industrial, and Jon carley,
Snap‐on Tools elizabethton plant, who discuss the breadth and depth of Snap‐on’s product line
in heavy duty vehicle maintenance and repair.
 This year we achieved safety incidence rates that are not onlyhistoricallylow,butcontinuetocompareveryfavorably to external benchmarks. Our commitment to both uncompromising quality and to connecting with customers and translating that insight into winning innovation
was once again illustrated with awards from MOTOR Magazine and Professional Tool & Equipment News for multiple Snap-on products in each publication. Snap-on was also again recognized by Frost & Sullivan in its 2012 survey of U.S. automotive technicians as the most preferred brand in
multiple product categories. Finally, since the formalization of our RCI framework
in 2005, this powerful tool has
become ingrained in the Snap-on
culture and has helped to deliver
runwayS for growTh
Building upon more than 90 years of providing repeatability and reliability
in the automotive repair arena, Snap‐on’s coherent growth strategy seeks to broadly deploy our value proposition of making work
easier for a wide range of professionals both within and beyond vehicle repair. Our runways for growth, illustrated throughout these pages, are to:
enhance The fRanchiSe neTwoRk expand in The gaRage
exTend To cRiTical induSTRieS Build in eMeRging MaRkeTS
3
3
 
enhance
the Franchise Network
we’re working more closely than ever with our franchisees to improve their profitability and increase their sales. The Snap‐on Masters of Metal TourTM, our customized mobile marketing showcase, held over 90 events in 2012, offering new and veteran customers the opportunity to experience, first‐hand, Snap‐on’s latest innovations and hottest big ticket tool offerings. The tour celebrates automotive technicians as masters of their trade and Snap‐on factory associates as masters of their craft. The events include one of our new specially equipped trucks, a Rock ‘n Roll cab express, which showcases a wider range of tool storage units and accessories, presented with a visibility and variety that’s not possible on a typical franchisee van.
  4
a 740 basis point improvement in operating margin before financial services.
Beginning with the invention of the original Snap-on interchangeable socket set in 1920, we’ve established a strong track record of repeatability and reliability in the vehicle repair arena. We like this position . . . . as we believe industry fundamentals such as the aging of the car parc and increasing vehicle complexity make this an attractive market in which to further expand our presence. At the same time, our value proposition is broadly applicable both within and beyond vehicle repair. To reach even more professionals performing critical tasks wherever and whenever the costs and penalties for failure can be high, we’re advancing along our runways for coherent growth: enhancing the franchise network, expanding in the vehicle repair garage, extending to critical industries and building in emerging markets. We achieved considerable progress along each of these runways in 2012.
In our Commercial & Industrial Group (C&I), where
we serve a broad range of industrial and commercial customers, net sales of $1.13 billion in 2012 increased 2.2% organically and the operating margin of 11.3% increased 30 basis points from 11.0% last year. We saw higher sales to customers in critical industries and in the emerging markets of Asia. These gains allowed us to more than offset lower sales in our European-based hand tools business, which reflected the continued economic weakness in that region. We incurred increased restructuring expense during the year to improve our cost structure in Europe, primarily in response to current market conditions.
C&I made considerable progress along two of our growth runways in 2012: extending to critical industries and building in emerging markets. Sales gains to customers in critical industries, such as aerospace and natural resources, resulted from our growing focus on developing solutions specifically for professionals in
 
  expand
in the Garage
we see opportunities to expand our
presence with owners and managers
of vehicle service and repair facilities by providing them with the solutions they need to perform better and more efficiently in their shops. This year we introduced the integrity Test drive by John Bean—a unique system that performs a detailed vehicle inspection
in a matter of minutes. a 2012 MOTOR Magazine Top 20 Tools award winner, the integrity Test drive combines several productivity‐enhancing products that
work together, allowing the shop
to quickly diagnose problems, fix
vehicles on the first visit and
generate more shop revenue.
 these areas. In Asia-Pacific, we continued to expand our product line capabilities, distribution reach and manufacturing capacity. For example, in November, we further increased our physical presence when we dedicated our fourth factory in Kunshan, China, which brings our total to five in the Asia-Pacific region.
Comprised of our franchised mobile van network, whose primary customers are vehicle repair technicians, the Snap-on Tools Group posted net sales of $1.27 billion in 2012, representing an organic sales increase of 10.7%, with higher sales in both our U.S. and international franchise operations. We believe this double-digit increase is testimony that our investments in enhancing the franchise network, another of our runways for growth, are paying off. Operating earnings in the Snap-on Tools Group also posted gains in 2012, increasing to $176.4 million from $158.5 million in 2011.
Beyond the overall financials, franchisee productivity, profitability, satisfaction, and commercial health continued to trend favorably. We continue to aim special RCI efforts toward helping franchisees increase their productivity, enabling them to serve more customers more effectively, and more profitably. In addition to ongoing investment in innovative new products and improved manufacturing capabilities, we’ve also developed unique programs to further expand the market coverage and penetration of our network. The Snap-on Masters of Metal TourTM and the Rock ‘N Roll Cab Express featured on the previous page are excellent examples.
We believe more than ever that our strong brand, capable franchisees, premium products, network coverage and financing programs are significant competitive advantages with automotive technicians. As further evidence of that belief, the strength of Snap-on’s franchise proposition again received external validation in 2012, with Snap-on
5
 
moving up ten spots in Franchise Business Review’s annual satisfaction survey and with our network ranking #11 among over 5,000 global franchises in Franchise Direct’s annual Top 100 Global Franchises report.
The Repair Systems & Information Group (RS&I), which serves owners and managers of independent repair shops and OEM dealership service facilities, achieved net sales of $917.1 million in 2012. The 1.7% organic sales increase primarily reflects higher sales of diagnostics and repair information products. Operating margin of 22.4% increased 230 basis points from 20.1% last year, driven by a more favorable sales mix as well as benefits from ongoing RCI initiatives as the group continued its focus on productivity advancements.
Dedicated to helping repair shop owners and managers perform better and more efficiently in their shops every day, RS&I launched several new products across its businesses that do just that. This year we introduced a
new full-function, hand-held unit—the VERUS® PRO—that includes enhanced diagnostic capabilities and faster performance in a thinner and lighter design, setting a new industry standard. Another move forward in helping our customers increase productivity was Mitchell 1’s new ProDemand® repair information system, which offers faster and more accurate searches as well as improved access to extended data such as wiring diagrams and technical-service bulletins. RS&I also expanded in end markets adjacent to automotive repair, such as the medium and heavy duty truck segment, and in emerging markets, where the group’s undercar equipment business saw gains in Eastern Europe, the Middle East and Brazil.
Financial Services revenue was $161.3 million in 2012 compared to $124.3 million in 2011 and loan originations of $677.1 million increased 11.7% year over year. Operating earnings from financial services of $106.7 million in 2012 increased from $90.9 million last year,
    6
exTend
to Critical Industries
Snap‐on’s ability to solve the critical
reaches beyond automotive repair. our value proposition applies broadly across critical industries where tasks require precision and control, are conducted in complex and punishing environments, and have a high consequence
of failure. customers in natural resources industries, like those in the oil and gas industry pictured here, are benefiting
from Snap‐on’s strengths in bringing value‐added solutions in areas such
as safety and productivity.
 
which included an $18.0 million arbitration settlement gain. Our financial services portfolio continues to maintain healthy performance and we firmly believe our ability to provide financing solutions to our franchisees and customers, both in the U.S. and internationally, gives us significant strategic and competitive advantages.
In November 2012, the Board of Directors approved an 11.8% increase in the quarterly dividend to $0.38 per share. Snap-on’s dividend is an integral component of our approach to capital allocation, as demonstrated by our payment of consecutive quarterly cash dividends, without interruption or reduction, since 1939.
In closing, we were encouraged again by our performance in 2012, which we believe is further evidence that Snap-on’s capabilities in solving the critical resonate with our customers. We made considerable progress
in furthering our strategic position and improving our operating execution, and we demonstrated our ability
to overcome external headwinds, which are simply a fact of life when operating in diverse markets and geographies. We believe the strength of our businesses coupled with the further potential of our runways for growth and improvement are a powerful combination that will continue to create long-term value for our shareholders. Finally, we thank our franchisees and associates worldwide for their efforts and dedication, our Board of Directors for its guidance and support, and our customers and shareholders for their confidence and commitment.
Nicholas T. Pinchuk
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
    buiLd
in Emerging Markets
we’re seeking to expand our
capabilities as repair industries
develop in the rapidly growing economies
and infrastructures of emerging markets.
in 2012, we opened our fourth manufacturing facility in kunshan, china. The 118,000 square foot facility, pictured here, manufactures undercar equipment, an important, high‐ value product line for the local market. kunshan is also home to several other Snap‐on facilities, including power
tools, cutting tools and tool storage manufacturing plants, as well
as a modern engineering and
R&d center.
 7
 