 2 Simon PropertyGrroup,,IInc..
2011 was a tremendous year for our Company. Our passionate pursuit of operational excellence once again led to industry-leading results and we exceeded our own expectations. Although we do not always get where we want to on all aspects of our business, we do know where we want to go and will work hard to get there.
Our consolidated revenue grew a robust 8.8% for the year, to $4.3 billion. We generated Funds from Operations (“FFO”) of $2.4 billion in 2011, the highest ever recorded in the industry, and nearly $670 million higher than in 2010. Our 2011 FFO was nearly two times greater than FFO reported by any other U.S. real estate company. FFO per share was $6.89, an increase of 37% from the prior year and also a record for our Company. We have now outgrown the great recession and for that I am very proud of the organization.
A continued focus on improving our busi- ness is ingrained in our culture. Our people work tirelessly to increase profitability, to improve the assets within our portfolio, and to mine new opportunities for growth. This mindset and our conservative financial structure position us to deliver impressive results, year after year. This focus is not just within senior management, but ex- ists throughout our entire organization of 5,500 strong employees.
Our high-quality portfolio continued to strengthen in 2011 as demonstrated by key financial and operational statistics:
 Total sales on a rolling 12 month basis increased by 10.7% to $536 per square foot.
 Occupancy improved by 30 basis points to 94.8%.
 The releasing spread for the rolling 12 months was $5.20 per square foot, an increase of 10.5%.
 Comparable property net operating income (NOI) growth was 3.4%.
Our common stock outperformed the rel- evant indices, generating a total return to our stockholders of 33.6%, as compared to the MSCI U.S. REIT Index (RMS) return of 8.7% and the S&P 500 Index return of 2.1%.
Our historical returns are quite impressive:
Growing Dividend
As a result of our increased profitability and cash flow, our dividend is growing. In the fourth quarter of 2011, we increased our quarterly dividend from $0.80 to $0.90 per share, and in the first quarter of 2012, we increased the dividend again, to $0.95 per share. I am pleased to report that the SPG common stock dividend has grown 18.8% since the third quarter of 2011, and we are on a trajectory to pay dividends of at least $3.80 per share in 2012 — a record amount for the Company.
Growth Strategy
When we went public in December of 1993, our equity capitalization was $1.8 billion and we owned a portfolio of primarily middle-market malls in the Midwest and Texas. We could have been content with our status quo or “our roots,” excelling at that which we knew best — but were not. We determined that this was not the best way to create long-term shareholder value. It is in our DNA at Simon Property Group to grow, improve, and never be satisfied with where we are.
We have redefined Simon Property Group from a Midwest-based, mall-centric company to a retail real estate company that can operate anywhere in the world. Over the past 18 years we have trans- formed our company through opportunistic acquisitions, development, and opera- tional achievements to our position to- day as the world’s largest real estate company and one of the S&P 100’s most valuable companies. We own a portfolio of high-quality, irreplaceable assets that encompass the entire retail spectrum — malls, Premium Outlets®, The Mills®, and community/lifestyle centers.
Cumulative Total Return
1 Year
SPG 33.6% S&P 500 2.1% RMS 8.7%
5 Year
54% –1% –7%
10 Year
583% 33% 163%
 From the Chairman & CEO

     King of Prussia Mall– Philadelphia, PA
 ABQ Uptown – Albuquerque, NM
 ACQUISITIONS
We completed $1.8 billion of acquisitions in 2011. The most significant transactions were:
 An increase in ownership interest in King of Prussia from 12% to 96%
– King of Prussia is one of the largest and most productive malls in the U.S.
 Acquisition of 100% ownership in ABQ Uptown, a lifestyle center in Albuquerque, New Mexico
In March of 2012, we invested $3.5 billion in two additional acquisition transactions.
    2011 Annual Reporrtt 3
       
Our strategy has led to industry-leading growth and improvement in our overall portfolio quality, productivity and diversity. Remarkably at the same time we strengthen our financial position. From our first full year as a public company in 1994 through year-end 2011, financial and operational measures improved dramatically.
 Annual consolidated revenue increased 808%, from $474 million to $4.3 billion.
 FFO increased nearly 1,300%, from $176 million to $2.4 billion.
 Annual FFO per diluted share increased 230%, from $2.09 to $6.89.
 Sales per square foot grew 107%, from $259 to $536.
 Portfolio occupancy improved by 860 basis points, from 86.2% to 94.8%.
Our equity capitalization has increased from $1.8 billion in 1993 to $53 billion today (an increase of more than $51 billion!), and most importantly, we have delivered industry- leading stockholder returns. From our December 1993 IPO through today, SPG’s total stockholder return was 1,723%, or a compound annual return of 17.2%.
Financial flexibility has also been a cornerstone of our growth strategy. We have the strongest balance sheet in the industry with the highest investment grade ratings among U.S. real estate companies, and we are one of only two U.S. REITs with “A” ratings from all three major agencies.
Our debt maturities are well balanced by year with a current weighted average interest rate of 5.2% and a weighted average term of 6.3 years. We also have the benefit of a significant unencumbered portfolio of properties with more than 160 wholly owned assets that generate annual NOI in excess of $2.1 billion.
Our financial and operational perfor- mance has created a virtuous cycle of capital. This performance allows us to drive down our cost of capital which enables us to invest in opportunities which increase our profitability and, in turn, drive down our cost of capital yet again. We have worked tirelessly to get here, and we will not take this for granted.
Global Expansion
As the Chairman and CEO of one of the largest companies in the U.S., I believe it is vital in today’s flat world to be a global organization. In today’s environment, it is a competitive advantage to be able to compete globally. Our retailers are global, many of our shoppers travel the globe, capital moves globally, and opportunities for growth exist worldwide.
We have invested abroad on several oc- casions, in Asia and Europe, in our effort to create a global footprint for our business. This strategy has produced several suc- cessful projects and we have profited finan- cially from these investments. In Europe, we never had the appropriate platform that we desired — a company that could pursue growth across the European continent.
Earlier this month, we invested in a public retail real estate company that has the scale to compete profitably across all of Europe. We acquired a 28.7% interest in Klépierre from its founding shareholder, BNP Paribas, with the purchase of 54.4 mil- lion shares at a price of €28.00 per share, for a total transaction value of approximately $2.0 billion.
Klépierre is headquartered in Paris and focuses on the ownership, management and development of high-quality shopping centers across Continental Europe. As a long-term admirer of Klépierre and its pan- European footprint, I believe in its potential.
This transaction represents an attrac- tive growth opportunity for our company and it advances our strategy of investing in high-quality retail real estate on a world- wide basis. While these are challenging times in Europe, I expect that this will be a profitable investment. The current un- certainty in Europe allowed us to invest in a terrific company at a discount to its net asset value.
Though the work has just begun, I look forward to working closely with their management team to create value for all of the Klépierre shareholders. As part of our investment, I became Chairman of Klépierre’s nine member Supervisory Board and will help guide and develop the strategy of the company going forward. We expect the SPG and Klépierre organizations to work closely together to create value for each of us.
Enhancement of Portfolio through Operations and Capital Investment
We continue to pursue operational ex- cellence. We strive to be as efficient as possible in our operations as we focus on the day-to-day management and leasing of our centers to ensure that they are the best venues for our shoppers and our retailers. This is a priority for us each and every day.
We challenge our managers and leasing agents to achieve the best merchandise mix at their properties, balancing the goals of higher occupancy and best pricing of retail space. Our highly productive malls, outlets and value-oriented centers are proven locations for successful retailers wanting to grow their business. Additionally, we expect to benefit from increasing sales and NOI upside as the economy continues to recover.
 4
Simon Property Group, Inc.
Johor Premium Outlets – Johor (Singapore), Malaysia

 DEVELOPMENT
In 2011, we invested $400 million in new development and redevelopment projects. Projects completed during the year:
 Two new assets – Paju Premium Outlets and Johor Premium Outlets
 Expansions at Ami Premium Outlets, Las Vegas Premium Outlets – South, Pheasant Lane Mall and Tosu Premium Outlets
 Renovations of Coddingtown Mall, Fashion Valley, Great Lakes Mall, McCain Mall and Town Center at Boca Raton
Based upon our pipeline of development and redevelopment projects, we currently expect our share of invested capital to approximate $1 billion annually for 2012 through 2014.
 Coddingtown Mall – Santa Rosa, CA
   Consolidated Revenue
$ in billions
$3.78 $3.78 $3.65
’07 ’08 ’09 ’10 ’11
FFO Per Diluted Share
$4.31
$3.96
       $6.45 $5.90
$6.89
  $5.50 $5.03
    ’07
’08 ’09
’10 ’11
 Equity Market Capitalization
$ in billions
$45.8
$35.2 $28.1
  $25.8 $15.9
    ’07
’08 ’09
’10 ’11
2011 Annual Report 5
Paju Premium Outlets – Paju (Seoul), Korea
         
SPG has a long history of success- ful development projects — new projects as well as expansions and renovations — which have contributed to our growth. Our development and redevelopment program in the U.S. and abroad is accelerating. We will only build where demand exceeds sup- ply and we can do so profitably. The good news for SPG is that there is very little supply coming onboard over the next few years, which will only make our real estate more valuable.
Our focus for new ground up develop- ment is in our Premium Outlets platform. We currently have three projects under construction with opening dates in 2012 and 2013 — located in New Hampshire, Texas and Korea. Other identified projects, with start dates planned in 2012, are lo- cated in Phoenix, St. Louis, Tampa, Toronto and Japan. We will begin construction in Tempe (Phoenix) and Shisui (Japan) later this month.
We invest capital in our existing properties to make them the best they can be for their marketplace. We have more than 20renovationandexpansionprojectsunder construction in the U.S. with completion dates in 2012 and 2013. The cost of these projects is approximately $700 million (our share) and the expected stabilized return on our invested capital is 10%. We have also identified 16 additional expansions and renovations where we expect to begin construction in 2012 and 2013.
Based upon our robust pipeline of development and redevelopment projects, we currently expect our share of capital spend to approximate $1 billion annually for 2012 through 2014, and believe we are building the great projects of tomorrow where the retailers will want to aggregate, creating the critical mass required for a successful retail project.
Now let me touch on some notable 2011 activities.
Acquisitions
We continued to demonstrate our ability to strategically invest capital in 2011 with $1.8 billion of acquisitions. The most significant of these transactions was the August acquisition of a controlling interest in King of Prussia – The Plaza and The Court. Our ownership interest increased from 12% to 96%, and we have the ability to acquire the remaining 4% in the fall of 2013.
Wrentham Village Premium Outlets – Wrentham (Boston), MA
 6 Simon Property Group, Inc.
King of Prussia is one of the truly iconic shopping destinations in the U.S., serving the greater Philadelphia market. It is one of the country’s largest shopping centers at 2.4 million square feet and also one of the country’s most productive centers, generating total annual retail sales in excess of $850 million.
The King of Prussia acquisition was immediately accretive to our earnings and the property has excellent growth prospects. A major redevelopment of the center is currently underway, converting a former department store into 100,000 square feet of specialty stores. In November, we announced an additional multi-level expansion connecting the five-anchor Plaza and the two-anchor Court. The 140,000 square foot expansion will include approximately 40 exciting new retailers, several restaurants and an upscale dining pavilion.
Development
In 2011, we opened two new assets: Paju Premium Outlets, our second Premium Outlet in Korea, located approximately 50 minutes northwest of downtown Seoul, and Johor Premium Outlets located in Malaysia, our first Premium Outlet in Southeast Asia, less than an hour’s drive from Singapore. Both centers are fully leased and performing well. Importantly, we once again demonstrated our ability to successfully export our know-how to international markets for the benefit of our stockholders.
Several redevelopment projects were completed during the year including:
 Expansions at Ami Premium Outlets (Japan), Las Vegas Premium Outlets – South, Pheasant Lane Mall (Nashua, New Hampshire) and Tosu Premium Outlets (Japan),
Renovations of Coddingtown Mall (Santa Rosa, California), Fashion Valley (San Diego, California), Great Lakes Mall (Cleveland, Ohio), McCain Mall (Little Rock, Arkansas) and Town Center at Boca Raton (Boca Raton, Florida) , and
 The opening of 38 new anchors and big box tenants, aggregating 1.7 million square feet of activity across all of our U.S. platforms.
Our leasing activity of 17 million square feet enhanced our merchandise mix and increased our rents and occupancy.
Balance Sheet Strength and Capital Market Transactions
Our strong access to capital was demon- strated again in 2011 by the sale of $1.2 billion of unsecured notes in November at a weighted average interest rate of 3.6% and weighted average term of 8 years. We also completed a new $4.0 billion revolving credit facility during the year that can be increased to $5.0 billion.
Our strategy of pruning the portfolio and recycling capital continued with the disposition of interests in 59 properties for approximately $930 million.

  SouthPark – Charlotte, NC
      Grapevine Mills – Garland (Dallas), TX
       We have been very successful in our efforts to retenant department store and big box spaces with more viable retailers, opening approximately 150 new department stores, big boxes, theatres and restaurants over the last five years. In 2011, we opened 38 new anchors and big boxes aggregating 1.7 million square feet of leasing activity including retailers such as Bloomingdale’s Outlet, Carson Pirie Scott, Discovery Center by Legoland, Forever 21, Herberger’s, Kohl’s, Last Call by Neiman Marcus, Sea Life Center, T.J.Maxx, and Ulta.
2011 Annual Reporrtt 7
    
    STRONG HISTORICAL RETURNS TO STOCKHOLDERS
(Cumulative Total Return) 600%
500% 400% 300% 200% 100%
0%
-100%
2001 2002 2003 2004
2005 2006
2007 2008
2009 2010 2011
             m Simon Property Group
m MSCI U.S. REIT Index (RMS) m S&P 500
Total return for the 10-year period (12/31/01 – 12/31/11) was 583% for SPG, 163% for the RMS and 33% for the S&P 500.
          2012
The year is off to an excellent start. In addition to the Klépierre transaction, we acquired our joint venture partner Farallon Capital’s stake in 26 Mills assets for $1.5 billion. The acquisition will be immediately accretive to FFO.
This was a compelling opportunity for us to expand our investment in a portfolio of assets that we know well and already manage. These properties have considerable consumer brand equity and large trade areas, and they generate significant cash flow and total sales volume.
We now own 100% of several of these high-quality, well-positioned properties, including Sawgrass Mills in Miami. Sawgrass Mills comprises over 2.2 million square feet of outlet, value-oriented and entertainment retailers and generates total annual retail sales in excess of $1 billion. This center is one of the most visited tourist destinations in the U.S.
Upside exists throughout this portfolio through redevelopment opportunities. For example, we are replacing an anchor tenant at Sawgrass Mills with over 90,000 square feet of big box and small shop space. In addition, a 36,000 square foot expansion of The Colonnade Outlets at Sawgrass Mills, which houses the luxury outlet retailers, is well underway.
We completed two successful offerings in connection with the Klépierre and Mills transactions–wesold9,137,500common shares at $137.00 per share and sold $1.75 billion of senior unsecured notes in three series. The weighted average interest rate for the notes is 3.39% and the weighted average term is 14.7 years. The coupon on all three series of unsecured notes was the
lowest ever achieved by a REIT, once again proving our industry leadership position. All three rating agencies affirmed their SPG ratings subsequent to the Klépierre and Mills transactions. Never willing to sacrifice the balance sheet for the sake of growth is a mantra from which I will not waiver.
On March 16th, Simon Property Group was added to the S&P 100 Index. We are delighted and honored to be included in this prestigious index, a sub-set of the S&P 500 Index that measures the performance of large cap companies in the U.S. It is comprised of 100 major, blue chip companies across multiple industry groups. Simon Property Group is the only real estate company in the index.
In Summary
Our management team is highly respected and capable. We have an infrastructure that enables execution at consistently high levels across all aspects of our business. We want to improve, we are never satisfied, and we like to compete.
We will continue to seek additional op- portunistic transactions. I believe that we have the expertise, the discipline, the capital, and the organization to identify, evaluate and successfully execute transactions better than anyone else in the real estate business.
We have the strongest balance sheet in the industry. This affords us excellent access to low-cost capital, which was evident earlier this month when we successfully accessed the debt and equity markets to prudently fund the Klépierre and Mills transactions.
Our returns are growing, which will enable us to pay higher dividends and still reinvest in our portfolio, generating
higher returns and continuing to reduce our cost of capital. I firmly believe that we will continue to grow our company and deliver excellent results, as we have demonstrated consistently since our IPO in 1993. We are very well positioned for 2012, with our portfolio of strong- performing, irreplaceable assets, and our focus remains on enhancing long-term stockholder value. As a result of this, I am confident we can deliver another year of record earnings growth.
I would like to thank all of my colleagues at Simon Property Group for their contribution to our many achievements in 2011 and ask for their continued dedication in producing a great 2012. Their hard work and commitment to our Company is critical to our success.
I would also like to thank our Board of Directors for their strategic guidance. Linda Walker Bynoe will retire from our Board at the 2012 Annual Meeting. Linda has served the Company with dedication throughout her nine year tenure and we thank her for her many contributions.
I thank you, our stockholders, for your continued support. We value your comments, insights and questions.
Sincerely,
David Simon
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
March 26, 2012
  8 Simon PropertyGrroup,,IInc..
