  2
To Our
Shareholders
At St. Jude Medical, we believe that investing in purposeful innovation is instrumental to our success. St. Jude Medical has become and will continue to be one of the largest and most successful medical device companies in the world by excelling at delivering high-quality, innovative products that reduce health care costs and improve outcomes for patients who suffer from expensive, epidemic diseases such as atrial fibrillation, heart failure, hypertension, stroke, and chronic pain.
One of the major social challenges of our time is determining how to provide high-quality, affordable health care to an aging population on a universal basis. A commitment to helping patients while reducing the cost of health care is critical to success for a high-tech medical device company, and is a significant competitive advantage for our product portfolio.
While St. Jude Medical continued to deliver on this commit­ ment in 2012, I want to acknowledge that we did not fully deliver on our growth expectations last year. Our sales growth was lower than expected due to a number of factors, but the two primary limitations were continued weakness in European markets, and a greater impact than we expected on our cardiac rhythm management business associated with the recall of certain products. However, our strong operating discipline enabled us to deliver adjusted earnings per share* (EPS) in 2012 that exceeded expectations. Although we expect sales growth in 2013 to remain challenging due to macro-economic factors, structural changes in health care,
*Adjusted earnings per share is a non-GAAP measure and excludes certain charges. See page 8 for a reconciliation.
Daniel J. Starks
Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer
 St. Jude Medical is developing cost-effective technology for many epidemic diseases, including:
• Atrial fibrillation • Stroke
• Vascular disease • Hypertension
• Valvular disease
• Heart failure • Chronic pain • Migraine
• Depression

and the emerging nature of many of our growth drivers,
we are firmly committed to delivering superior growth in EPS during 2013 without sacrificing investment in research
and development.
There were three key operational highlights during 2012 that give us confidence and optimism about our ability to grow our business and continue delivering value to shareholders moving forward:
1. We restructured our company in 2012 – combining our former Atrial Fibrillation (AF) and Cardiovascular Divisions into the new Cardiovascular and Ablation Technologies Division, and our Cardiac Rhythm Management and Neuromodulation Divisions into the new Implantable Electronic Systems Division, as well as centralizing certain administrative functions such as Information Technology, Human Resources and Legal – which we expect to improve costs, quality, and speed-to-market by capturing additional product development and manufacturing synergies. This restructuring generated more than $100 million in incre­ mental cost savings and strengthened our ability to fund disciplined acquisitions or return cash to shareholders.
2. We were able to initiate two stock buy-backs totaling $1.3 billion in the fourth quarter of 2012, which we estimate will generate a benefit of $0.36 EPS for 2013. We also returned $284 million to shareholders as we increased our annual dividend by 10 percent.
3. We delivered adjusted EPS growth of 11 percent on a constant currency basis in 2012, while investing 12.3 percent of our revenue in research and development. Our guidance for 2013 reflects that we expect to deliver adjusted EPS growth greater than sales growth again this year due to the benefit of the restructuring activities, our ongoing expansion of manufacturing in cost advantaged locations, and our share repurchase program.
Despite these operational benefits to our business, the challenge in 2013 will be to accelerate sales growth. In order to do this, we are focused on delivering a balanced portfolio of established, fast-follower, and pioneering technologies that will provide St. Jude Medical with both near-term and long-term revenue growth.
Product Updates
During 2012, we launched several new technologies that will support our return to sales growth.
EnligHTNTM Renal Denervation System
Given St. Jude Medical’s long history in ablation technologies for cardiac arrhythmias, we have been able to leverage technologies and expertise to optimize costs, quality and speed-to-market in our renal denervation program for treatment-resistant hypertension. This support allowed us to launch our first-generation EnligHTN renal denervation system in Europe during the first half of 2012, two quarters ahead of expectations.
Using the EnligHTN system, an ablation catheter delivers radiofrequency (RF) energy to create lesions (tiny scars) along the renal sympathetic nerves – a network of nerves
St. Jude Medical EnligHTN Renal Denervation System
near the kidneys that help to regulate pressure; the inten­ tional disruption of the nerve supply has been clinically found to decrease systolic blood pressure. The system is the industry’s first multi-electrode ablation technology for renal denervation. Compared to single electrode ablations, the EnligHTN multi-electrode system has the potential to improve consistency and procedural reliability, save time, and result in workflow and cost efficiencies. Additionally, the minimal catheter repositioning required of a multi-electrode system may result in a reduction of contrast and fluoroscopic (X-ray) exposure. The second-generation EnligHTN system is expected to launch in Europe in mid-2013, and will further simplify and speed the procedure through simultaneous multi-electrode activation.
 3

During 2012, St. Jude Medical also generated clinical evidence in our EnligHTN I trial that demonstrated the EnligHTN system provided rapid and significant reduction in blood pressure over at least a six-month timeframe. In addition to our existing data, we have implemented a robust clinical trial program to help develop the clinical evidence needed to obtain reimbursement and influence physician referrals. This program will include additional one-year data from our EnligHTN I trial; a 500-patient EnligHTN II observa­ tional trial that is already underway; the EnligHTN III trial to evaluate our second-generation system; and our landmark, randomized, controlled EnligHTNment trial, which is the first large-scale study that will examine whether this technology can ultimately reduce the risk of major cardiac events such as heart attack, stroke and death in patients who have uncontrolled or treatment-resistant hypertension. The U.S. pivotal Investigational Device Exemption (IDE) trial, to support U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approval of this technology, is expected to begin enrolling patients in the second half of 2013.
MediGuideTM Technology
A highlight of our AF business in 2012 is the progress we continue to make advancing our MediGuide program. The MediGuide technology is the first and only three-dimensional navigation system intended for the evaluation of vascular and cardiac anatomy on a recorded fluoroscopic image instead of live fluoroscopy (a series of X-ray images). Similar to a global positioning system (GPS) that automobile drivers use to determine the location of their car on a map, MediGuide technology allows physicians to see the precise location and orientation of MediGuide EnabledTM devices inside the heart.
St. Jude Medical MediGuide Technology
St. Jude Medical launched the first MediGuide system in 2011, and during 2012, we expanded our limited launch of MediGuide systems to four additional centers in Europe and two centers in the United States. Initial customer feedback is encouraging and reinforces our optimism that our MediGuide system has the potential to become disruptive technology in the electrophysiology cath lab by improving procedural effectiveness while also reducing patient and clinician exposure to radiation. In 2013, we will be focused on expanding our portfolio of MediGuide Enabled devices – including ablation catheters and CRT delivery tools – generating clinical evidence documenting the value of the technology, launching MediGuide systems into at least 12 new centers, and preparing for full commercial release of this product platform in 2014.
While the company’s early focus with MediGuide technology has been in the EP lab, this platform will ultimately be synergistic across our broad portfolio, including optimization of percutaneous coronary intervention procedures, left atrial appendage closure, transcatheter heart valve repair and replacement, and neurostimulation lead placement.
PorticoTM Transcatheter Aortic Valve Implantation System
At the end of 2012, St. Jude Medical
began a limited launch of our 23 mm
Portico transcatheter aortic valve
and transfemoral delivery system in
Europe. Designed for patients with
severe aortic stenosis who are
considered to be inoperable or at
high risk for conventional open-heart
valve replacement surgery, the Portico valve is implanted through a small incision in the femoral artery (the main artery of the leg). The procedure uses a catheter to deliver and position the valve in the heart and occurs while the heart continues to beat. This avoids the need to place the patient on cardiopulmonary bypass, a process in which a machine takes over heart and lung function during surgery. The Portico device is the only approved transcatheter valve that can be completely resheathed (the process of bringing the valve back into the delivery catheter), repositioned at the implant site or retrieved before it is released from the delivery system. The approval of this first valve size gives St. Jude Medical access to approximately 20 percent of the $1.9 billion market opportunity for transcathether valve replacement.
 St. Jude Medical 23 mm Portico Transcatheter Aortic Valve
  4

                                                             St. Jude Medical also announced the first implant of the Portico valve via the transapical approach, in which a small incision is made between the patient’s ribs and the valve is delivered through the apex (or lower tip) of the left ventricle of the heart; as well as the first patient implant of its 25 mm Portico valve in its ongoing European trial. European approval of both the transapical delivery system and the 25 mm valve are expected in 2013. Approval of the 25 mm valve would give the company access to an additional 40 percent of the market.
The Portico valve is not yet approved for use in the United States. A U.S. clinical trial evaluating the Portico valve is expected to start in the second half of 2013. The trial will be conducted under an FDA IDE.
Summary and Looking Forward to 2013
With the progress we have made toward accelerating our growth in 2012, and the more than 20 unique technologies and product families that will launch during 2013 at St. Jude Medical, we believe we are well positioned to bring best-in­ class technologies to the market that will become standard-of­ care in important, impactful markets.
We thank our Board of Directors for their continued support and direction, particularly through the challenges we have faced in the last year. We also thank all of our St. Jude Medical employees, who have maintained their dedication and strong work ethic through a difficult year of organizational change. Whether working directly with products, customers or patients, or supporting our business in other ways, our employees make it possible for St. Jude Medical to save and improve lives each and every day.
There are a lot of things for St. Jude Medical stakeholders to be excited about this year. The last year certainly had a number of challenges, but our operating discipline and the continuity of our balanced portfolio of technologies are key strengths and competitive advantages that position us well for a return to growth. We know that if we continue our focus on delivering innovative technology that improves patient out­ comes and reduces the cost of health care, we will be successful and will ensure our place as a vital contributor to the future health care industry.
Sincerely,
Daniel J. Starks
Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer St. Jude Medical, Inc.
   FORTUNE Magazine names
St. Jude Medical among the
TOP 50
“World’s Most Admired Companies”
                                                                                                             Net sales
(in billions)
$6 $5 $4 $3 $2 $1
Operating profit
(in billions)
$1.50 $1.25 $1.00 $0.75 $0.50 $0.25
March 8, 2013
Diluted net earnings per share
(in dollars)
$3.00 $2.50 $2.00 $1.50 $1.00 $0.50
Research and development expense
(in millions)
$800 $600 $400 $200
                                              08 09 10 11 12
08 09 10 11 12
08 09 10 11 12
08 09 10 11 12
5
