 TO OUR SHAREHOLDERS: Tenneco Automotive recorded 􏵤 Favorably amended our debt covenants with a beneficial
its most successful year as a stand-alone company in 2002.
We did so by maintaining our strategic focus on reducing debt and improving cash flow through four primary means: keeping selling, general, administrative and engineering (SGA&E) costs in check; improving our working capital position; maintaining gross margin levels; and strengthening business relationships. In addition, our team capitalized on the opportunities presented by a surprisingly robust North American vehicle production rate. At the same time, we dealt effectively with challenging economic and market conditions in Europe and other regions by rapidly cutting spending and optimizing assets.
By adhering to our 2002 strategic focus, we:
􏵤 Strengthened business relations, winning important new original equipment (OE) business, expected to launch over the next three years;
􏵤 Maintained SGA&E expenses at our objective of
12 percent of revenues despite higher investments in sales promotion and engineering;
􏵤Improved cash flow from working capital by $67 million, exceeding our goal by 34 percent;
three-year package; and,
􏵤 Paid down $70 million in total borrowings, thereby help- ing to lower interest expense last year by $29 million, and reducing our overall borrowings since 1999 by $270 million.
As a result, our company reported its first year of operating profitability since becoming an independent entity in late 1999. We also delivered a 98 percent total return to shareholders in 2002, substantially outperforming both
the industry average and the S&P 500. Unfortunately, like the stocks of most auto suppliers, at the time this report went to press, our stock was trading below year-end 2002 levels, which we believe is due to skepticism about 2003 vehicle production levels and economic uncertainty.
We are pleased with the overall progress we’ve made
and are determined to stay firm on the strategic direction that has brought the success achieved so far. However, we are aware that further improvements are needed and the future holds challenges as well as opportunities.
Working within the context of our four-pronged strategy, we are taking steps to sharpen our competitive edge by further enhancing manufacturing quality, increasing efficiency and streamlining processes.
At the same time, we are striving to expand our revenue base by developing advanced products and leveraging business relationships.
EFFICIENCIES DRIVE COST SAVINGS We are targeting substantial cost savings in 2003 to more than offset poten- tial increases in material and labor costs, contractual price concessions and possible volume declines in replacement and original equipment markets worldwide.
 Mark P. Frissora Chairman and
Chief Executive Officer
2 Tenneco Automotive
  
 Our primary initiative for improving our global manufac- turing and distribution efficiency is Project Genesis. Since launching the first phase of Genesis in December 2001,
we have reduced excess capacity and costs by closing eight facilities and streamlining the workflow at 21 plants world- wide.These moves generated approximately $12 million
in savings last year at about two-thirds the anticipated cost. We plan to complete the Phase I activities in 2003 and recognize an additional $15 million in savings this year. Starting in 2004, we expect $30 million in annualized savings as a result of Project Genesis.
Six Sigma and Lean manufacturing also provide long-term cost savings. Six Sigma, a quality methodology designed to eliminate process variability, product defects and waste that undermine customer loyalty, generated $25 million in cost savings last year and we expect similar results in 2003.
Our Lean manufacturing initiatives, modeled on the well- regarded Toyota Production System, are effectively reducing costs, inventories and customer lead times while improving on-time delivery.
Cost management is another key element of our strategy. Since 1999, we have reduced our total workforce by 17 percent and slashed overhead spending by $136 million. SGA&E as a percent of sales has improved to 12 percent from about 17 percent over the three-year period. Our 2003 goal is to reduce our SGA&E costs to 11.5 percent of sales, primarily by cutting overhead expenses by about $24 million.
We have also organized a global, centralized supply chain management team that is working to offset expected price increases and reduce our overall material costs
by leveraging our worldwide purchases, increasing sourcing in low-cost areas and using alternative materials when appropriate.
Finally, we’ve improved our working capital balances
by $416 million since 1999 — primarily by better managing
receivables, inventories and payables. Based on industry benchmarking studies, we believe there is still a $150 million opportunity for improvement. In 2003, we expect to reduce working capital by $50 million, generating additional cash flow for debt reduction.
NEW PRODUCTS AND MARKETS CREATE GROWTH
Our growth strategy emphasizes increasing revenues and capturing greater efficiencies.We continue to commercialize innovative technologies for OE customers.These advanced products achieve improved emission control performance that meets more stringent environmental regulations and provide safer vehicle handling to address growing safety issues, while adding content per vehicle.
For example, we were awarded one production and three development OE contracts in Europe for our Continuously Controlled Electronic Suspension (CES) system in 2002. We also won contracts for advanced emission control systems for two major European-based luxury brands that are launching in 2004, and are expected to generate some $200 million in total revenues over four years.
Moreover, we continue to transfer product technologies from our OE business to the aftermarket.This practice extends the marketing reach of each product, spreads the development costs and enhances the return on our invest- ment. Offering products with premium benefits helps further distinguish us and our customers from competitors.
In 2002, we launched our premium ReflexTM shock absorber — originally developed for OE applications —
in the European aftermarket, having previously introduced this advanced ride control product in North America. As a result, our European business increased its sales mix of premium products by three percentage points for the year. We hope to see similar success when we roll out ReflexTM in Australia in 2003.
3 Tenneco Automotive

 Besides increasing sales through new products, penetration of additional markets provides enormous opportunities. China, for example, represents the world’s fastest-growing automotive market. We are already capitalizing on this exciting trend with our majority-ownership joint ventures in Shanghai and Dalian for emission control and Beijing
for ride control. Overall, revenues from China in 2002 increased 83 percent over 2001. Going forward, our strategy is to continue to identify and establish partner- ships in China and other key growth markets.
Joint ventures and strategic alliances have also enabled us to capture an increasing share of the Japanese OE business. Sales to Toyota, Honda and Nissan in North America are 26 percent higher today than in 1999.
Another market offering strong growth potential is heavy- duty trucks. Our current sales to large truck manufacturers make up only about 6 percent of our total OE sales. However, we recently won several important development contracts based on our leading-edge exhaust products, such as diesel particulate filters and DeNox converters. Our high-margin North American elastomer business — which was awarded $60 million in new business in 2002 — draws a large portion of its sales from this market as well.
PREPARED FOR UNCERTAINTY At present, the economic outlook for 2003 is tenuous. Political tensions are con- tributing to consumer caution and a restrained outlook
for business conditions throughout the world. In North America, generous incentive programs buoyed light vehicle sales in 2002, which may have negative consequences this year if the programs either expire or simply lose impact with consumers.
We believe we are well prepared to deal with these uncertainties. Our lean manufacturing philosophy, featuring increased speed and quality, improved workflow and processes, and a relentless cost management focus, will help us respond rapidly to changing sales trends.
Events of the past year necessitate addressing the issue of corporate integrity. I can assure shareholders that Tenneco Automotive not only zealously adopts Securities and Exchange Commission mandates and corporate governance best practices, but we have made many of them our standard operating practice for years.
We have properly attributed our improvement in 2002 to proven strategies for working capital management and repayment of borrowings. Even the most potent tactics, however, cannot deliver results without the dedication, enthusiasm and skill of the people charged with their execution.
During 2002, we recognized the optimistic, “can do” spirit of the Tenneco Automotive workforce in our new motto, Our Mission is GO!
We believe the capabilities of the people of Tenneco Automotive — coupled with our strategies and a renewed emphasis on execution and discipline — will continue to propel our company forward to new levels of success.
Mark P. Frissora
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer April 2003
 4 Tenneco Automotive
