     ALLMERICA FINANCIAL OPERATING COMMITTEE
(FRONT ROW FROM LEFT): RICHARD M. REILLY; JOHN F. O’BRIEN; ROBERT P. RESTREPO, JR.
(BACK ROW FROM LEFT): EDWARD J. PARRY, III; MARK A. HUG; J. KENDALL HUBER; MARK R. COLBORN; BRUCE C. ANDERSON; GREGORY D. TRANTER; JOHN P. KAVANAUGH
To Our Shareholders
 2
The past year was an extraordinary one for all Americans, as world events impacted our lives as never before. The tragedy of September 11 touched all of us with a sense of profound loss and tested our confidence in our personal and financial security. Americans responded to these challenges with courage, conviction, and a renewed sense of pride and unity that will carry us forward, stronger than ever.
At Allmerica, we were fortunate to suffer no human loss among our own family and to experi- ence only a modest financial impact as a result of September 11. However, like many American businesses, we were further tested by the difficult economic and business conditions and volatile stock market that persisted during 2001.
Allmerica reported lower earnings for the year, for the first time since we became a public company in 1995. In 2001, net operating earnings per share were $3.10, compared to $5.58 per share in 2000. Rather than simply attributing this earnings decline to the confluence of extraordinary circumstances, we seized the opportunity to review our strategy and our operating plans. As a result of our analysis, we are confident that our strategy remains sound, but we made necessary changes to adapt to the volatile stock market and the changing industry conditions in the property and casualty business. Our challenge is to translate these changes into improved operating results and higher returns as soon as possible. Most of these changes were implemented during 2001, so we fully expect to see improvement reflected in our 2002 results and a greater positive impact on earnings in future years.
Asset Accumulation
Our Asset Accumulation business consists of Allmerica Financial Services, which markets life insurance and retirement products, and Allmerica Asset Management, our investment manage- ment business.
 
   􏵢􏵢􏵢“The past year was an extraordinary one for all Americans, as world events impacted our lives as never before.” 􏵢􏵢􏵢
      3
During 2001, we improved our position as a leading provider of variable annuities and variable life insurance in the United States. We currently rank as one of the industry’s top 20 providers in the $100 billion variable annuity market. We also are one of the top 30 underwriters in the smaller, but faster-growing variable life insurance market.
Pre-tax operating earnings in our life insurance, retirement products, and asset management businesses were $163.7 million in 2001, compared to $245.3 million a year earlier. The earn- ings decline was due to lower asset-based fees and transaction-based income, resulting from a lower level of assets under management due to the equity market’s decline. Additionally, annuity death benefit costs, credited interest and operating expenses were higher.
Allmerica’s variable annuity market share improved in 2001, both for new sales and assets, based on industry data published by VARDS (The Variable Annuity Research and Data Service). We achieved strong sales of variable annuities through our multiple-channel distribution network. In spite of the challenging equity market, we focused many of our new sales activities on the rapidly expanding regional broker/dealer and financial planner market. Allmerica Select, our fastest-growing distribution channel in 2001, which focuses on this market, accounted for nearly 38 percent of our $2.9 billion of variable annuity sales. Our well-established and highly successful career agency and mutual fund partners channels together accounted for about 62 percent of variable annuity sales.
New sales of variable life insurance generated premiums of almost $117 million in 2001. We expect sales of variable life insurance to continue to grow quickly in the future, in light of the product’s inherent tax advantages, both for asset accumulation and wealth transfer purposes.
Market research and demographic studies confirm that the retirement savings market will continue to grow. The disappointing equity market in 2001 may have reduced the value of retirement accounts for many Americans. However, this reduction only intensifies the need for

  􏵢􏵢􏵢“...we are confident that our strategy remains sound, but we made necessary changes to adapt to the volatile stock market and the challenging industry conditions in the property and casualty business.”􏵢􏵢􏵢
      4
additional savings and for Allmerica’s products, which focus on long term retirement objectives rather than short term market performance.
For many decades, Allmerica’s career agency organization has focused on long term financial planning. We continue to invest in the training and recruitment of Allmerica financial advisors. During 2001, we made major enhancements to our marketing and sales distribution model, capitalizing on the best practices of our top performers. We implemented a regionally-focused sales platform, which will accelerate sales growth through consistent new agency recruiting, as well as turnkey lead generation and marketing programs that can be leveraged across all distribution channels. This new approach to distribution also gives us an excellent way to expand into new geographic regions and to serve profitable new markets in the United States.
Allmerica Asset Management had another productive year in 2001. Spread-based assets under management reached a new high, due to the continued strong market acceptance of our fund- ing agreement and stable value investment products. In particular, funding agreements issued in connection with sales from our European Medium Term Note program exceeded $1.2 billion.
In addition, our fee-based asset management business continued its strong record of growth. Assets under management for external clients more than doubled during the year and reached a record level of $6.2 billion. Our record of performance in managing fixed income assets contin- ues to attract new clients and we expect further growth in assets under management in 2002.
When evaluating our strategy, it is important to recognize that even with the setback in 2001, our Allmerica Financial Services and Allmerica Asset Management businesses have grown sub- stantially since 1995. Therefore, we have established a solid base that will enable us to take advantage of the opportunities that emerge as more and more people plan for their retirement.
During 2001, we continued to strengthen an organization that has in place all of the key
 
  􏵢􏵢􏵢“We achieved strong sales of variable annuities through our multiple-channel distribution network.”􏵢􏵢􏵢
       5
building blocks required for future success—broad distribution, an expert financial planning capability, a flexible portfolio of variable products, a solid technology platform, and high-quality customer service. With the changes that we have made, we are confident that our competitive position has been strengthened.
Risk Management
In our Risk Management business, we market property and casualty insurance with a regional strategy that consistently has enabled us to rank among the top 30 providers in the United States, even including the large national carriers.
Pre-tax operating earnings in our Risk Management business were $93.5 million, compared to $190.0 million a year earlier. This earnings decline was due primarily to disappointing under- writing results and deteriorating loss ratios in a relatively small segment of our overall proper- ty and casualty business. We concentrated management focus on eliminating this portion of our business and implemented the necessary corrective actions to improve earnings growth in 2002.
While we clearly are not satisfied with our performance in 2001, it should be noted that the property and casualty business is inherently volatile. However, despite reduced earnings, we outperformed the industry in underwriting profitability. Our combined ratio, a key measure of underwriting performance, was over six points better than the estimated industry average. The company’s combined ratio has been better than the industry average in eight of the past 10 years, due in large measure to our record of satisfactory risk selection and effective underwriting overall.
We are one of the leaders in the sponsored market business, marketing insurance products to individuals through their employers or associations. This business continues to generate strong
 
  􏵢􏵢􏵢“While we clearly are not satisfied with 2001’s performance, it should be noted that...we outperformed the industry in underwriting profitability.”􏵢􏵢􏵢
     6
revenue growth and good underwriting results for Allmerica. Annual net premiums written of sponsored business have grown by more than 25 percent over the past three years, and by year-end 2001 had increased to more than $660 million, representing almost 30 percent of our total property and casualty insurance premiums.
We also continue to emphasize small commercial accounts. This business presents an excellent opportunity to continue to grow low-hazard classes of business, which also should reduce earnings volatility. Our regional strategy and strong relationships with our core base of independent agents and the Dimension 2000 Plus small business insurance program provide Allmerica with a competitive edge in this market.
We have taken significant steps to accelerate the pace of change in our agency management program, which will enable us to focus more effectively on the most profitable lines of business, best markets, and those agents whose strategies are most closely aligned with our regional strength. In 2002, we will de-emphasize business in the large and middle commercial markets and specialty insurance programs, which are not core to our strategy.
The fundamental strategy of our property and casualty business is sound, our distribution platform and expense structures are solid, and the underwriting cycle is improving rapidly. As the market hardens and pricing improves, we expect to take advantage of these favorable industry conditions and to leverage our corrective internal actions into earnings growth.
Industry data reinforces our own research, indicating that the market will readily accept substantial price increases for the first time in several years. We are being careful not to rely solely on price increases to improve earnings. The management and organizational changes that we made in 2001 were designed to take full advantage of the industry environment.
 
  􏵢􏵢􏵢“We entered 2002 in a strong competitive and financial condition, with positive momentum in each of our businesses.”􏵢􏵢􏵢
     7
2002 Outlook
We entered 2002 in a strong competitive and financial condition, with positive momentum in each of our businesses. In Asset Accumulation, our overall goal for 2002 is to achieve strong variable product sales through our existing distribution channels and to develop new opportu- nities through strategic marketing initiatives. While earnings in this business always will be influenced by the equity market’s performance, our actions over the last year ensure that we are well positioned to benefit from any market improvement. In Risk Management, we have increased our focus on improving operations and carefully managing the relationship between revenue growth and profits. In the property and casualty business, earnings growth does not always follow premium growth. Our strategy is now much more focused on a commitment to those agents that will provide us with profitable growth. By more carefully managing these rela- tionships we expect to resume earnings growth in our Risk Management business in 2002.
At Allmerica, our corporate vision is To Make People Secure, which is a promise we have kept for 158 years, through World Wars, the Great Depression, and during 2001, a year when the security of our country and our economy were severely tested. We are proud of the manner in which our industry responded to its financial obligations in the wake of the recent tragedy and we also are proud of the way that our company and our employees joined fellow Americans in responding with generosity and caring.
We are confident that our commitment To Make People Secure will serve our customers well and will continue to create long term value for our shareholders.
John F. O’Brien
President and Chief Executive Officer
  