TO OUR VALUED SHAREHOLDERS:
PROGRESSING IN A CHALLENGING MARKET
We operated The Timken Company with great intensity in 2015, driving efficiencies, reducing costs, protecting margins and generating strong cash flow, all while competing to
win our customers’ bearings and power transmission business. We will remember the year as a challenging one, but also as one that validated our strategy and proved our many strengths.
Around the world, we faced downward pressures head-on, including those from declining end markets and unfavorable moves in foreign currencies. We countered these shifts by increasing our market penetration, removing more than
$60 million in costs, producing $269 million in free cash flow and delivering double-digit adjusted EBIT margins of 10.7 percent.
The Timken management team responded to significant macro-economic events throughout 2015 with agility and speed, mitigating the impact of the cyclical decline across many of our end markets. While revenue declined
6.6 percent to $2.9 billion, we achieved adjusted earnings per share of $2.21 and increased our quarterly dividend by 4 percent.
In Mobile Industries, our 2015 sales were $1.6 billion, with adjusted EBIT margins of 10 percent, and we generated 42 percent of this revenue outside the United States. Although Mobile Industries sales were down 7.5 percent, 5.2 percent was attributable to unfavorable currency.
We countered the very difficult off-highway equipment end-market demand by continuing to grow our business in rail, launching several new platforms in the automotive sector and acquiring the Carlisle® belts product line.
Our Process Industries business delivered adjusted EBIT margins of 15.9 percent on 2015 sales of $1.3 billion, with 50 percent of this revenue outside the United States. Process Industries sales were down 5.5 percent, which includes
WE OPERATED THE TIMKEN COMPANY WITH GREAT INTENSITY IN 2015, DRIVING EFFICIENCIES, REDUCING COSTS, PROTECTING MARGINS AND GENERATING STRONG CASH FLOW, ALL WHILE COMPETING TO WIN
OUR CUSTOMERS’ BEARINGS AND POWER TRANSMISSION BUSINESS.
 1

4.6 percent from unfavorable currency. While the broad slowdown across industrial end markets during the year certainly impacted Process Industries, we continued to gain market share in wind energy and benefited from acquisitions.
Across our business segments, we navigated market headwinds while setting sights on future growth. Through continued investments in DeltaX, our multi-year global initiative to fuel organic growth in bearings, we are accelerating our product development rate, expanding our best-in-class technical sales model and increasing global market penetration.
Given the environment, we achieved solid performance, invested in our business and took decisive actions to position the Company to deliver greater shareholder value in future years.
EXECUTING ON STRATEGY WITH OPERATIONAL EXCELLENCE
Our ability to navigate the complexities of 2015 resulted
from our strong commitment to customers, our strategy and the Timken Business Model. This framework keeps Timken management centered on long-term value creation and achieving our vision of being the global leader in bearings and power transmission products and services.
The Timken Business Model defines the strengths that differentiate Timken: technology and know-how in friction management and power transmission, business capabilities that provide excellent customer service at world-class efficiency levels, operational excellence and the best talent
in our industry. With these at our core, we effectively pursue opportunities to solve our customers’ most challenging applications, across fragmented markets, to original equipment manufacturers and end-users through aftermarket channels, with a relentless focus on service.
As this model guides us across the enterprise, the Timken team performs within an operating framework that drives industry-leading quality, customer service, environmental health and safety, and cost competitiveness. Combined
with our continuous improvement culture, we innovate our manufacturing, engineering and quality processes to benefit Timken customers and drive improvements to the bottom line.
To competitively address global demand, we continue to optimize our footprint while expanding our reach for future growth. In 2015, this included investments in our Chennai and Jamshedpur bearing manufacturing facilities in India, a joint venture for rail bearings in Russia, expansion of our China operations and the announcement of the construction of a tapered roller bearing plant in Romania.
The year also brought continued focus on improving our cost structure. Through our business processes and operational excellence, we continued to reduce our SG&A costs in total and as a percent of sales. In operations, we reduced costs over $60 million through productivity improvements, new manufacturing process technologies and product designs, lower material costs and restructuring. Our emphasis on costs will continue in 2016, with an additional $60 million in savings expected as we work to improve our operating margins.
  THE TIMKEN BUSINESS MODEL
Challenging Applications
Aftermarket & Rebuild
Fragmentation
High Service Requirements
GROWTH MARKETS DRIVEN BY STRONG MACROS
VALUE CREATION
Technology & Know How
Business Capabilities
Operational Excellence
Talent
           EXPAND GLOBAL REACH WITH ADJACENT PRODUCTS & SERVICES
 2
EXPANDING A DIVERSE PORTFOLIO WITH PURPOSE
A recognized industry leader in engineered bearings, the Company generates 77 percent of revenue from this core product line. Today, Timken is No. 1 in tapered roller bearings and we aspire to achieve the same in industrial bearings.
We will accomplish this by collaborating with original equipment and end-user customers to develop next-
DISCIPLINED FILTER FOR ATTRACTIVE OPPORTUNITIES
TIMKEN COMPETITIVE DIFFERENTIATORS

 generation products and services that improve the reliability and efficiency of their capital equipment. DeltaX will help accelerate this effort, providing the organization with the strategic focus and resources to fuel outgrowth in our bearing product lines.
The balance of the Timken portfolio is comprised of adjacent power transmission products and services. This includes gear drives, chain, belts, lubrication systems and an expanding aftermarket services group, Timken Power Systems. Through accretive bolt-on acquisitions, we will continue to develop our offerings in this attractive space.
In late 2015, we added Carlisle belts to our lineup, bringing a new category of power transmission products into the Timken portfolio. To this business, we bring our unique capabilities and industrial distribution channel strength to offer customers even greater options. The acquisition is on track to be accretive in the first year and generate attractive returns for Timken over the long-term.
MANAGING OUR CAPITAL ALLOCATION STRATEGICALLY
Our commitment to shareholders is reflected in our disciplined approach to capital allocation. Our priorities
are to invest in our core business, grow earnings, pay an attractive dividend, pursue acquisitions that add strategic value and generate solid returns, and return capital to shareholders through share buybacks. The goal: To build the Timken bearing and power transmission global brand while generating high returns on invested capital for our investors.
In addition to our belts acquisition, we paid $87 million in dividends, representing an increase of 4 percent per share on an annualized basis in 2015. We also repurchased an additional 8.6 million shares of outstanding stock. At the same time, we protected margins, drove cost reductions and committed approximately 3.7 percent of our 2015 sales to capital expenditure, investing $106 million back into our businesses to expand our market position and improve our cost structure.
In 2015, we also made several moves to significantly decrease our gross pension and retiree healthcare liabilities, while respecting our financial commitments to our retirees.
TODAY, TIMKEN IS NO. 1
IN TAPERED ROLLER BEARINGS AND WE ASPIRE TO ACHIEVE THE SAME IN INDUSTRIAL BEARINGS.
3

 BY LEVERAGING OUR ENGINEERING KNOW-HOW AND TECHNOLOGY,
WE ARE INCREASING OUR PRODUCT BREADTH AND CAPTURING OPPORTUNITIES THAT MAXIMIZE GROWTH.
Through the course of the year, we reduced our gross pension liability by more than 50 percent and our remaining plans continue to be well-funded. The dramatic changes in our liabilities and assets considerably reduce our exposure to volatilities in asset markets.
With our actions in 2015, we ended the year with a net debt-to-capital ratio of 28.2 percent, just below our 30 to
40 percent target. Our balance sheet and cash flow will continue to provide the Company with opportunities to drive shareholder value through effective capital allocation.
THE YEAR IN CONTEXT
Over the course of 2015, Timken faced significant challenges, with cyclical declines across many of our end markets and further negative effects of a strengthening U.S. dollar. Despite this, our performance was notable, as we delivered solid margins and strong free cash flow reflective of the actions taken over the last few years.
We remain true to our strategy and confident in our collective ability to achieve even stronger results. By leveraging our engineering know-how and technology, we are increasing
our product breadth and capturing opportunities that maximize growth, targeting those geographies, markets and applications where our products and services improve customer performance.
With resolve, we are rigorously managing costs and investing to drive growth. These−along with operational excellence and a focus on capital allocation−will further illustrate why Timken remains a compelling investment as well as valued supplier and employer.
As always, our people remain our most vital and valuable resource. They allow us to win in the marketplace by bringing to life the know-how, innovation and global teamwork that create value for customers. We thank them as well as our directors, shareholders and customers for their confidence in the Company and in our path ahead.
Sincerely,
Richard G. Kyle
President & Chief Executive Officer February 24, 2016
 4
