 2
These are tough times, make no mis- take about it.
An uncertain economy, corporate governance breakdowns, and conflicts around the world. An apparent reluctance in 2002 to invest in new productivity tools produced gloomy results for the overall soft- ware industry -- of less than 3% growth, according to International Data Corporation.
Against that backdrop we’re extreme- ly proud of the results achieved by the Tyler team.
In a difficult environment we have not backed off our strategic initia- tives. To the contrary, we’ve strengthened our competitive posi- tion – expanding geographically, adding sales resources, and improv- ing the competitiveness of our prod- ucts. Built on the critical mass we achieved in 2001, our record results in 2002 are a testament to the finan- cial and operational leverage inher- ent in our business model. Revenues grew by 13% and we met or exceeded our key earnings targets. The out- look for the year 2003 and beyond is for sustained growth in revenues

  and profits. Why? Because Tyler’s business model works.
Tyler works: Continued demand for our products and services. Despite concerns over state and local government budgets, our results in the past year give us reason to continue to be opti- mistic about the market for our local government software and services. Our position in the market continued to strengthen, and our revenue mix shifted to a greater proportion of higher margin software-related rev- enues. Our software license revenues were exceptionally strong in 2002,
ing year. As a result, we expect to see a somewhat lower overall growth rate with a more strategic revenue mix.
Tyler works: New business signed at a good pace. During 2002, we success- fully penetrated new geographic markets and signed contracts with larger cities, counties and a state. Our broad product line now opens more opportunities for cross-selling and additional business with exist- ing customers. Significant new con- tracts in 2002 include:
That we’re in tough times is not exactly breaking news. So we’re extremely proud of the
Tyler team whose efforts resulted in 13% revenue growth.
with 25% growth over 2001. We also posted solid growth in software serv- ices and maintenance revenues. Our appraisal services revenues have nearly doubled in the last two years, growing from $20.9 million in 2000 to $37.3 million in 2002. While we have strengthened our position as the nation’s leading provider of these services with our highly successful project in Nassau County, NY, we don’t expect that our appraisal serv- ices revenues will continue to grow at the same rate. We believe that soft- ware – related revenues will be the primary driver of growth in the com-
. The State of Minnesota
. Allegheny County (Pittsburgh), . Pennsylvania
. Lee County, Florida
. Fairfax County, Virginia
City and County of Denver, . Colorado
Wayne County (Detroit), Michigan, .Airport Authority
Lake County (Gary), Indiana
Tyler works: Innovative product develop- ment. In 2002 we signed our first two contracts for Tyler’s Odyssey court case management system. This new Web-based courts system is being

installed statewide in Minnesota as well as in Lee County, FL. In addition to our new-generation courts and justice products, Tyler is devoting significant development resources to Orion, our new Web-based appraisal system,
and to the enhancement of our finan- cial and recording suites of products.
Tyler works: Our core strengths remain key to our success and to our customers. An exceptionally customer-oriented staff and a deep and experienced manage- ment team played a large role in Tyler’s 2002 success. A wider array of products and services that work well
approximately $39.3 million, against a cost basis of about $16 million. We expect the transaction to close in the first quarter of 2003. The cash proceeds from this investment pro- vide additional flexibility to take advantage of opportunities to build value for our shareholders, includ- ing further stock repurchases.
Tyler works: By the numbers –  financial highlights:
. .
We are the only company in our industry that does it all. positive impacts on the communities we serve and reinforce our reputation
 for—and anticipates—our customers’
needs. This translates into an ever- growing, broad base of loyal cus-
tomers. In a market that requires the . right technology and a mandate to
25%. 2002’s fourth quarter was our best quarter ever for software license revenues at $7.2 million.
Software services revenues were up 19% to $25.7 million.
operate more efficiently – from the courthouse to the statehouse.
Tyler works: Building shareholder value.
. Gross margin improved more than two percentage points to 35.8%.
Revenues grew 13% to $133.9 million. Software license revenues grew
   4
Our balance sheet is solid. During . 2002, we used free cash flow to
repurchase 1.5 million shares of our
stock and authorized the repurchase . of up to one million additional
shares. We agreed at year-end to . sell our 35% stake in HTE, Inc., for
SG&A expense declined to 25.3% of revenues from 25.9% in 2001
EBITDA grew 41% to $18.6 million. Pretax income from continuing

   operations grew to $10.0 million from $1.8 million in 2001.
.
.
.
services offer greater efficiencies for almost every aspect of the day to day management of local government. Coast to coast. We continue to reinforce our reputation for getting the job done right regardless of the complexity.
We are the only company in our indus- try that does it all. We will continue to bring new products to the market that create positive impacts on the communities we serve. These products will increase opportunities to grow revenues and profits. Our team is committed; their customer focus is intense. Tyler works.
Income from continuing operations rose to $6.2 million, or 12 cents per share, up from $272,000, or one cent per share, last year.
After income from discontinued operations of $1.8 million, we had net income of $8.0 million, or 16 cents per share.
  We ended the year with nearly $14 million in cash and no bank debt. For the year 2002 free cash flow
 We will continue to bring new products to the market that create for getting the job done right.
   (cash generated from operations minus capital expenditures) was over $10 million.
.Our year-end backlog of signed contracts remained solid at $89.1 million.
We anticipate another very success- ful year in 2003, notwithstanding the uncertainties ahead. Having all the right components in place for profit- able growth should increase value for all stakeholders. Local govern- ments’ mandate to be more efficient continues. Tyler’s products and
Stuart Reeves, Chairman
John Yeaman, President & CEO
     