 MESSAGE TO
SHAREHOLDERS
FOCUSED EXECUTION DEFINED DOMTAR IN 2014. WE SUCCESSFULLY DELIVERED ON OUR PLAN TO ACHIEVE MEANINGFUL PERFORMANCE IMPROVEMENTS COMPARED TO 2013, AND WE MADE SIGNIFICANT PROGRESS IN EXECUTING OUR GROWTH STRATEGY FOR THE COMPANY’S FUTURE.
JOHN D.
WILLIAMS
PRESIDENT AND CHIEF EXECUTIVE OFFICER
  With consolidated sales of $5.6 billion, we generated $765 million of EBITDA before items, a considerable improvement when compared to 2013. This performance, combined with our confidence in the execution of our growth strategy, enabled us to increase our dividend by 36% in April 2014 and to further execute on our share buyback program.
Since the start of 2011 we have returned a combined $1.1 billion, or 70% of our free cash flow, to our shareholders through dividends and share buybacks. Looking specifically at 2014, cash flows from operating activities amounted to $634 million and free cash flow amounted to $398 million.
EXECUTING OUR GROWTH STRATEGY
Our progress in growing new fiber-based businesses reached a convincing “tipping point” in 2014. We realized our most significant progress thus far in our plan to deliver between $300 and $500 million of annual EBITDA from fiber-based businesses for which there is growing market demand.
In 2014, Indas, one of Spain’s leading manufacturers of adult incontinence products and baby diapers, became the fifth business to join Domtar’s Personal Care division. By adding the deep brand equity
of Indas to our already strong product mix, we are now well positioned to expand our share of the European market.
DOMTAR • 2014 ANNUAL REPORT  3

 We successfully advanced the integration of five acquired businesses with some 2,000 employees
and seven manufacturing and distribution sites
into our Personal Care division in 2014. We are now executing our plans to provide our customers with innovative, differentiated product solutions supported by an expanded, state-of-the-art, low-cost, global manufacturing platform. We successfully installed four new production lines at three locations in 2014, and we are excited to launch several innovative products in our core markets.
This combination of expanded, low-cost production capacity and innovation is building our momentum. We realized growth with channel leaders in both North America and Europe, and we gained national distribution at major North American retailers with shipments set to begin in early 2015.
Also in 2014, we announced our plans for additional capacity expansions in our Personal Care division, and we began the significant work of transforming our largest paper-making machine at our Ashdown, Arkansas, mill to the production of high-quality fluff pulp to meet growing global demand.
This converted machine at Ashdown will come on-line in the fall of 2016, and will have the capacity to produce more than half-a-million metric tons of high-quality fluff pulp or baled market softwood pulp in line with changing market conditions. This strategic repurposing of assets, combined with our reliable network of softwood suppliers in the southeastern United States and our longstanding relationships with the world’s leading absorbent hygiene product manufacturers, will make Domtar one of the world’s largest suppliers to this market.
Our approach to the transformation of our Ashdown mill also signals our commitment to remaining the supplier of choice in North American uncoated freesheet paper markets. The $160 million asset conversion plan we are now executing leverages the flexibility of Ashdown’s two remaining paper machines to produce both paper and papergrade pulp in line with changing demand.
WE BELIEVE OUR STRATEGY OF IMPROVING OUR OWN COMPETITIVE POSITION
THROUGH EFFICIENCY GAINS WHILE KEEPING THE PLAYING
FIELD LEVEL IS THE WAY TO WIN.
Our Pulp and Paper business continues to be central to our value proposition. Despite a continuing trend
in 2014 of softer demand for uncoated freesheet, our shipments trended better than those of the industry. Moreover, our specialty paper volumes grew compared to 2013, mostly driven by strong sales to Appvion, and we realized additional EBITDA from our rebranded Xerox® Paper and Specialty Media Products.
Despite a recent influx of imported cut-size paper in the North American market, we remain convinced that our Pulp and Paper business will continue to be
a strong generator of cash for our shareholders and a provider of a sustainable livelihood for our employees. That is why we continue to pursue efficiency improvements to make our manufacturing operations more sustainable, and it is why Domtar joined the United Steel Workers and other U.S. producers in filing a trade case to address foreign government subsidies and unfairly priced paper products.
We believe our strategy of improving our own competitive position through efficiency gains while keeping the playing field level is the way to win. It also prompts us to ask the marketplace the thought- provoking question: “Where does your paper
come from?”
Sustainable sourcing of certified wood fiber and transparent business practices have long been part
of our Company’s fiber. This record now serves as
a compelling point of differentiation. For example, Domtar’s direct greenhouse gas emissions to produce a ton of pulp and paper products are approximately half that of many Asian producers.
4  DOMTAR • 2014 ANNUAL REPORT

MESSAGE TO SHAREHOLDERS
 Moreover, we are not resting on our laurels. In 2014, we commissioned a new biomass boiler built in a partnership with We Energies at our Rothschild, Wisconsin, mill. The cogeneration power plant uses waste wood and bark from our mill and surrounding communities as fuel to generate renewable steam and electricity. This enabled us to shut down two less- efficient boilers, improving the mill’s cost position and reducing our overall emissions.
It is worth noting, while we were improving our sustainability and protecting our competitive position, 2014 also became the second consecutive year in which we achieved a total injury frequency rate below 1.0 – world-class safety performance in our industry sector. It is clear evidence of highly engaged employees, now numbering nearly 10,000, differentiating themselves and our Company
in a number of important ways from the global competition.
We believe that in today’s world of hyper-transparency, these differences matter – and they serve Domtar
well. That is why we updated our award-winning tool, The Paper Trail website, to provide our customers
with unparalleled insights into the impacts we make on our communities. It is also why Domtar has looked to its own employees to tell the story of why it really does matter where your paper comes from. I hope you agree that the story told in the video found at domtar.com/PaperMadeHere makes you proud to be an investor in and a user of Paper Made Here.
EVOLVING FOR THE FUTURE
Helping to meet the world’s growing material needs of the future is rewarding. Being able to do so by leveraging our experience and know-how in turning sustainable wood fiber into useful products that everyone uses every day is fulfilling.
While caring for personal hygiene needs has been part of the human condition for millennia, the innovations we are driving today are offering affordable solutions that deliver meaningful quality-of-life improvements to millions.
Reference to EBITDA before items
and free cash flow in this message are NON‐GAAP financial measures. Consult the Reconciliation of NON‐GAAP Financial Measures at the end of this document or at domtar.com.
One year after start-up, we are now selling 100% of
our production from our commercial-scale BioChoiceTM lignin extraction plant in Plymouth, North Carolina
to internal and external customers. This material, refined from renewable wood fiber, is being used as
an intermediary chemical by a number of customers
in a number of new and innovative products.
Similarly, our involvement in CelluForce, a 50-50 joint venture with FPInnovations, is identifying how the renewable and non-toxic nanocrystalline cellulose bioproduct produced from wood fiber can be used to make new products and improve existing ones.
At the same time we are focused on innovation in wood fiber technology, we celebrate what is already working well. A number of different, independent research initiatives released in 2014 confirm that the cognitive and memory retention benefits of reading and writing on paper compared to our electronic screens are compelling. That is why educators, students and even professional sports teams are turning to paper for teaching and learning the material and the plays that matter most.
With the execution of our growth strategy on course and the competitiveness of our Pulp and Paper business being sustained, we think it is useful to reflect on what is being accomplished today at Domtar in
a historical context. Today’s work is in line with what Domtar has successfully done since our founding in 1848 – evolve and adapt to meet changing market demands.
We are reminded daily of the connection that exists between the values we hold and the value we create. We believe our success in managing this evolution, concurrently generating returns for our shareholders while delivering on our commitment to sustainable growth, can be traced back to our core values of Agility, Caring and Innovation – what we call the fiber of Domtar.
John D. Williams
President and
Chief Executive Officer
DOMTAR •
 2014 ANNUAL REPORT  5
