 to our Shareholders, Customers and Colleagues
In many ways the Unum story for 2014 sounds much like one you’ve heard before, which, in my view, is a very good thing. We strive for steady, consistent performance in all that we do – in the quality of service we provide our customers, in the profitability and returns we generate in our core businesses, and in our commitment to returning capital to our shareholders – not just in one year, but over the longer term.
   that’s exactly what we did again in 2014.
thomas R. Watjen Chief executive officer
our steady, consistent performance doesn’t just happen. It’s a result
of staying focused on a few very basic principles – principles that have served us well in the past and will continue to do so in the future. the most important of these is remaining disciplined in all that we do – in our business focus, in our commitment to superior customer service, in our prudent financial and risk management, in our precise execution of our business plans (delivering on what we say we will do), and in our commitment to creating a high-performance environment where our people can flourish and make a difference.
While we enjoyed another strong year, the general environment remained very challenging. Persistently low interest rates continue to create headwinds for us and our competitors, putting pressure on our profit margins and testing our industry’s ability to operate profitably. Although steady improvement in the overall economy softened the blow somewhat in 2014, operating in this prolonged period of low interest rates requires discipline – and a considerable measure of patience.
As I mentioned earlier, these have been hallmarks of this company
for some time and it is therefore no surprise to me that, despite a challenging environment in 2014, we generated the ninth consecutive year of operating earnings-per-share growth, or that over this period we repurchased $2.8 billion of stock and increased our dividend by 120 percent, or that we did all this while significantly strengthening our position in all of our key markets. We are exceptionally proud of that track record, especially considering the unprecedented economic and market volatility we experienced during that nine-year span.
 UnUm • 2014 AnnUAl RePoRt 1

  this past year, many of the same solid operating trends we have
seen in the past continued, including strong profitability across most of our businesses, excellent customer retention and solid investment performance – despite the challenging interest rate environment. Additionally, the growth trends that emerged in 2013 accelerated in 2014, as we saw very positive sales and premium increases in all of our core businesses. this growth clearly hasn’t come from any meaningful economic recovery, but rather from the quality and competitiveness
of our product and service offerings, our strong relationships in the marketplace, and generally favorable employee benefit market conditions.
Again, steady and consistent results don’t just happen – it’s our people who are behind our success and set us apart from our competition. It should be no surprise, then, that we focus a great deal of attention on attracting, retaining and developing the absolute best people in the industry – people to both deliver on today’s commitments and help us meet the demands of the future. this past year was no exception, as we continued to invest heavily in our people at all levels, with a sustained
ever-changing needs of our customers and the marketplace are deeply embedded within the company.
moving forward, we intend to stick to the time-tested script of remaining disciplined in all that we do, which has allowed us to deliver steady, consistent results for our customers and shareholders.
2014 perFormAnce
As has been the case over much of the last decade, we were fortunate in 2014 to have two sources of value for our shareholders: our solid business operations and our ability to return capital to our shareholders
through share repurchases and dividend increases.
our core businesses – Unum US, Colonial life and Unum UK – once again performed well. this past year we benefited, too, from the retrenching actions taken by a number of our competitors, who had been aggressively growing their businesses in an unsustainable manner. our discipline and patience was rewarded. As I mentioned
focus on leadership development and succession planning across the company. I think we have proven that we can transition leadership very effectively without skipping a beat, which I’ll come back to in
a moment.
looking back on 2014, we accomplished much of what we set out to do and are well-positioned for another solid year in 2015, in spite of the headwinds. We have very good operating businesses and positive long-term trends in our markets. In fact, the need for our products and services has never been greater. We also have strong profit margins in all of our operating businesses and a solid financial foundation that gives us significant flexibility. And, perhaps most importantly, we have created a culture where doing the right thing and striving to meet the
earlier, we saw solid sales growth in all three businesses in 2014, including a 21 percent improvement for Unum US and a nearly
12 percent increase for Colonial life – its highest growth rate since 1990.
Among the year’s other highlights*:
• Operatingearningsincreased6.9percentto$3.55pershare,
marking Unum’s ninth consecutive year of operating ePS growth;
• Operating return on equity for our principal businesses was
14.7 percent, again exceeding the average for our industry, while
total company operating return on equity was 11.4 percent;
• Bookvaluepershareł,ameasureofenterprisegrowth,increased 2.8 percent to $33.24 – an average increase of 8.2 percent annually
over the past six years.
*In analyzing performance, the company sometimes uses non-GAAP financial measures that differ from what is reported under GAAP. Refer to the Financial Highlights and pages 23,24, 153, 154 and 168 for reconciliations of the non-GAAP financial measures used in this report, including operating income, operating revenue, operating earnings per share, operating return on equity, and book value per share (excluding accumulated other comprehensive income, or AoCI), to the most directly comparable GAAP measures.
łexcludes AoCI.
2 UnUm • 2014 AnnUAl RePoRt
   2014 Financial performance highlights
OPERATING EARNINGS PER SHARE
10 11 12 13 14
BOOK VALUE PER SHARE (EXCLUDES AOCI)
10 11 12 13 14
                $33.24 $32.32
$29.55 $26.33
$3.55 $3.32
$25.69
$3.15 $2.98
$2.73

   CONSOLIDATED OPERATING RETURN ON EQUITY
10 11 12 13 14
           this success comes despite the impact today’s low interest rate environment continues to have on our investment results, especially on our group long-term disability and long-term care lines of business. During the year we strengthened our long-term care reserves by nearly $700 million to better reflect a continuation of this low interest rate environment. I’m confident that we are doing all the right things to manage this business (a product that we no longer sell but continue to service). We are also taking the appropriate pricing actions in those product lines that are more sensitive to interest rates, such as group long term disability. While we never like to raise prices, it is the most prudent thing to do in this environment.
During 2014, with strong capital generation from our core operations, we continued our practice of returning excess capital to our shareholders. We repurchased another $300 million of our stock, bringing our total since 2007 to $2.8 billion, or nearly 32 percent of our outstanding shares. Additionally, we increased our dividend nearly 14 percent, marking the sixth consecutive year of double-digit dividend increases.
our capital position remains strong, again exceeding most of our targets in 2014, giving us the flexibility to both support the needs of our business while also returning capital to shareholders.
Although our longer-term total shareholder return continues to outperform our industry and the
broader market, I am disappointed that our stock’s performance in 2014 was below that of our peers. We believe the uncertainty around interest rates and our long-term care business impacted investors’ views of our company more so than the strong financial and operating results we achieved throughout the year. I’m confident, though, that these factors remain important to investors and will ultimately be recognized in the market, and that we are on the right path to continue to create long-term value for our shareholders.
A growIng need For whAt we do
At Unum, we are well aware of the important role we play in helping to protect the financial futures of individuals and their families, as well as in helping employers better manage their businesses. last year, we paid more than $6.7 billion in benefits and, in our group disability business alone, enabled more than 230,000 individuals to return to work and a productive lifestyle, while giving millions of others the peace of mind that comes with protecting themselves and their loved ones.
In addition, more than 178,000 companies large and small have entrusted us to help their employees protect their futures.
Challenging economic conditions in recent years combined with shifting employee benefits trends have created an even greater need for our products and services. the value of what we do becomes especially clear when you consider:
• Withnearly70percentofconsumersintheU.S.andU.K.living paycheck-to-paycheck, most consumers lack the resources to support themselves should a significant illness or injury occur.
• Yetlife-changingeventsoccurmorefrequentlythanmanypeople expect. In fact, one out of four of today’s 20-year-olds will be out of work for at least six months due to a disability over the course of their working years, with little to fall back on.
• Unfortunately, most consumers are under-insured against these very real risks. For example, 66 percent of working Americans lack basic disability coverage, and the situation is even bleaker in the U.K., where 92 percent lack basic disability coverage. this lack of coverage can have devastating financial consequences on the goals and aspirations of individuals and their families.
As we know all too well, governments lack the financial resources to expand their welfare programs to provide adequate coverage for those facing these issues. often the best, and only, opportunity for workers to obtain basic financial protection is through the workplace. In fact, nearly 90 percent of all disability insurance is purchased at the workplace, while roughly 80 percent of all life insurance coverage is acquired there – facts that have changed very little in spite of health- care and other market reforms.
As a leading provider of workplace benefits, we see a tremendous opportunity to grow the market and believe we are in a strong position to do so – in part by building from our 165 years of industry expertise, and the strong customer relationships and reputation we have established over the years, but it goes beyond that.
last year in the U.S., in an attempt to reduce the uninsured population, we proposed legislation that would make it easier for employers to offer disability insurance on an “opt-out” basis, or, in other words, to provide coverage at the time of employment, with the employee able to decline it later if they so choose. this approach has proven highly successful in increasing the participation in 401(k) or retirement saving plans, and we believe this proposed legislation can help to fill a critical protection gap in this country. We remain hopeful that this legislation will gain the necessary support it needs in Congress.
We are also continuing to invest heavily in our consumer research capabilities to better understand and engage consumers. there’s a reason so few consumers elect not to purchase this coverage when it’s offered in the workplace. We’ve already taken a number of critical
UnUm • 2014 AnnUAl RePoRt 3
11.4%
11.4% 12.3% 12.2%
11.9%

steps to address the root causes of this longstanding industry challenge, with much of the focus being on simplifying our products and services, and creating an even better customer experience – not just by “insurance industry standards,” but across all industries.
While in 2014 we enjoyed some of the strongest growth rates we’ve seen in many years, we believe that there are even greater opportunities ahead. the quality of our offering, the strength of our relationships in the market, and the potential to grow our markets are exciting opportunities within our grasp. But rest assured, unlike some in our industry, we will not grow our business at the expense of future profitability. Instead, we are committed to maintaining the disciplined approach to growth that has so successfully guided us over my 12 years as Ceo.
2015 outlook
Hoping for higher interest rates or a more robust economic environment in 2015 is one way to plan for the future, but it’s not how we’ve gone about doing it. We don’t believe that we will get any material help from the environment this year, and therefore we are taking the steps needed to operate in a setting not dissimilar from the one we are in today.
In 2015, our focus will remain on profitably growing our business, maintaining strong margins through disciplined pricing, underwriting and expense management, and effectively managing our capital – just as it has been in the past. even in this persistently low interest rate environment, we expect to maintain solid operating margins and significant financial flexibility to support the needs of our businesses, while also continuing to return capital to our shareholders.
I am very confident that we will be able to achieve these objectives because we have solid plans in place and a track record of delivering on our commitments to our customers, to our shareholders and to all of our stakeholders.
I mentioned earlier that for many years we have been committed to a rigorous leadership development and succession planning process at all levels of the organization. While we emphasize internal advancement, we also leverage Unum’s track record and reputation to attract outside talent for particular expertise, and to help assure that we bring fresh perspectives and insights to our company. looking back over the past five or so years, this commitment has paid dividends as we have seamlessly transitioned the responsibilities of a number of retiring executives without impacting our performance. We are fortunate to have such a deep and talented group of leaders ready to take on new roles in the future.
Which brings me to my decision to retire as Ceo at this year’s Annual meeting. I’m as healthy and energized as ever, but it’s simply time to step away from active management. I wouldn’t do so if I didn’t believe
we were well-positioned for the future, and I step back knowing that Unum is in very good hands and poised for even greater things ahead. Rick mcKenney, who will be succeeding me as Ceo, has made significant contributions to this company since joining as chief financial officer in 2009, and the board and I have tremendous confidence Unum will continue to thrive under his leadership. With the work we have done these past five years to put in place the leadership team of the future, Rick will be flanked by a deeply talented, well-established executive leadership team.
As I make my transition, I want to thank you for your support over these past 12 years as Ceo of this great company. We’ve enjoyed a number of successes over that time, as well as a few challenges along the way that tested the resolve of our organization and each of us as individuals. We not only met each challenge but emerged a stronger, more vibrant company. While I will miss being Ceo, I am looking forward to my new role as non-executive chairman of the board for the next two years – and to lending my support wherever I can.
In closing, I’d like to thank our employees, who never fail to amaze me with their commitment to our customers, and with their enthusiasm for developing better and more efficient ways to do their jobs and move our company forward. they are well aware of the larger purpose of our business – to provide our customers with peace-of-mind and, when necessary, the financial support to help them navigate through challenging, sometimes tragic experiences. We owe our success and the optimism we have for the future to them.
I’d like to also thank our board of directors and my management team for the strong leadership they’ve provided, including never shying away from making tough decisions. they’ve also had the courage to stick with the principles that have been so important to our past success and will most certainly guide us over the long term.
It has been a privilege to lead this great company for the last 12 years. Unum is today well-positioned strategically and financially to capitalize on the opportunities that lie ahead, and we believe the steps we’ve taken to ensure management continuity and an orderly leadership transition will enable the company to continue to generate outstanding results well into the future.
on behalf of all of us at Unum, thank you for your continued support.
thomas R. Watjen Chief executive officer
 4 UnUm • 2014 AnnUAl RePoRt
